<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Maxwell &#38; India</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-03T14:50:09Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu" />
	<id>http://india.syr.edu/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.8.2">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sai Vikas Gopal</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Celebrating More Than 60 Years of Maxwell’s Partnership with India]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/appleby-nehru-moynihan/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=760</id>
		<updated>2014-07-02T18:43:09Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-02T18:42:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Featured" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jawaharlal Nehru, Dean Paul Appleby, and Sen. Daniel Patrick Moynihan pioneered Maxwell's India Program.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/appleby-nehru-moynihan/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/appleby-nehru-moynihan/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/appleby-nehru-moynihan/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sai Vikas Gopal</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Fifth year in a row, Maxwell welcomes India’s Senior Foresters]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/fifth-year-in-a-row-maxwell-welcomes-indias-senior-foresters/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=6071</id>
		<updated>2014-07-02T18:45:18Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-02T18:39:42Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Featured" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Newsboard" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the fifth consecutive year, Maxwell is pleased to welcome a delegation of over 34 high-level administrators from the Indian Forest Service (IFS)]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/fifth-year-in-a-row-maxwell-welcomes-indias-senior-foresters/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The Maxwell School of Syracuse University hosted two out of three delegations of high-level administrators from the Indian Forest Service (IFS) in 2014. The first IFS delegation arrived in Syracuse in April, followed by second delegation in May this year. The IFS Phase V Mid-Career Training Program is part of an educational program combining forestry and public policy skills that is targeted toward senior IFS officers with approximately 24 to 28 years of service. This program focuses on developing the foresters’ understanding of the changing scene for formulation and implementation of environmental policy with a focus on developing leadership and management skills to help them implement these changes. The next IFS delegation is expected to arrive in Syracuse in September.</p>
<p><img class="colorbox-6071"  src="http://india.syr.edu/wp-content/uploads/1SU_11011.jpg" width="555"></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The four weeks training program consists of three parts that is being organized in three different locations. The first part of the program took place in Indian Institute of Management-Bangalore (IIMB), followed by two-week exposure in the U.S. or Canada. The first week of the program in the U.S. concentrates on sessions led by academics, forestry practitioners, and policy makers who shared their experience of various policy processes. The IFS delegation then traveled to Watkins Glen Park to meet with the U.S. Forest Service, visited the Finger Lakes National Forest Office Facility, and met with the U.S. Fish &#038; Wildlife Service at the Montezuma National Wildlife Refuge. In the second week of the program, the IFS delegation traveled to the Adirondacks to learn about the roots of the great conservation movement in U.S. history. After meeting with the New York State Department of Environmental Conservation in Hamilton, the delegation went to Grey Tower and visited Catskills to review the working arrangement of the NYC watershed. The program in the US is concluded in Washington D.C., where the delegation met their counterparts in the U.S. Forest Service. The entire program came to a conclusion at the Indira Gandhi National Forest Academy in Dehradun, India.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The Maxwell School of Syracuse University partnered with the Indian Institute of Management-Bangalore (IIMB), SUNY College of Environmental Science and Forestry, and the University of British Columbia to deliver multiple mid-career training programs for these senior IFS officials.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/fifth-year-in-a-row-maxwell-welcomes-indias-senior-foresters/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/fifth-year-in-a-row-maxwell-welcomes-indias-senior-foresters/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sai Vikas Gopal</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Maxwell India Alumni working on improving Indian Railways]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-india-alumni-part-of-the-team-working-on-gois-vision-for-improving-indian-railways/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=6053</id>
		<updated>2014-07-02T18:36:41Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-02T16:53:18Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Featured" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Newsboard" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sandeep Silas says his team is working on realizing prime minister Narendra Modi’s ‘achhe din’ dreams in terms of passenger facilities. ]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-india-alumni-part-of-the-team-working-on-gois-vision-for-improving-indian-railways/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Sandeep Silas (53), Delhi division manager of the Northern Railway, says his team is working on realizing prime minister Narendra Modi’s ‘achhe din (good days)’ dreams in terms of passenger facilities. He shared with HT on Wednesday what the Capital can expect from this year’s rail budget.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">What does the change of guard at the center mean for the Railways? For us, &#8216;achhe din&#8217; means improving safety, punctuality, cleanliness and redressing passenger complaints. Various departments are working in isolation. This pushes back the organisational objectives. We’re a work force of 45,000 people. You cannot be leader from your office. You have to be out there in the field and seen working with your colleagues.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">What all is being done to improve services? On Tuesday, I conducted an inspection of the New Delhi Railway Station with special focus on cleanliness. On Wednesday, I held a meeting of all branch officers including those dealing with on board housekeeping. I also inspected Old Delhi station. We’re also doing night inspections. We have started a 15-day drive to monitor officers’ punctuality. We’re installing eight escalators and booster pumps, replacing water and sewage pipelines across the division.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">There are a lot of expectations from the budget… We’re hoping to have more escalators. We’re also aspiring to have travelators &#8211; seen at airports &#8211; at New Delhi Station. We’re exploring places on the Ajmeri Gate side where these travelators could be laid. Cars will come, drop passengers and go. Passengers can use these moving walkways to get inside platforms. This will reduce vehicular congestion that has been one big problem. I have told officials to prepare a plan. We also want high-quality food courts at our stations.
</p>
<p>Read original article here -> <a href="http://www.hindustantimes.com/india-news/aspiring-to-have-travelators-at-new-delhi-station-says-railway-manager/article1-1234858.aspx">Link</a></p>
<p><i>Source: Hindustan Times, June 2014</i></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-india-alumni-part-of-the-team-working-on-gois-vision-for-improving-indian-railways/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-india-alumni-part-of-the-team-working-on-gois-vision-for-improving-indian-railways/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sai Vikas Gopal</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Former Syracuse Graduate named CEO of Infosys, India’s pioneering IT company]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/former-syracuse-graduate-named-ceo-of-infosys-indias-pioneering-it-company/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=6045</id>
		<updated>2014-06-27T17:52:51Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-27T17:52:31Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Newsboard" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[IT major Infosys has appointed Vishal Sikka as its CEO and MD. Here is all that you need to know about the new CEO of India&#8217;s most talked about IT company: Sikka completed his schooling from Rosary High School, Baroda where his father worked as an officer in Indian Railways. After his Computer Engineering from [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/former-syracuse-graduate-named-ceo-of-infosys-indias-pioneering-it-company/"><![CDATA[<p>IT major Infosys has appointed Vishal Sikka as its CEO and MD.</p>
<p>Here is all that you need to know about the new CEO of India&#8217;s most talked about IT company:</p>
<p>Sikka completed his schooling from Rosary High School, Baroda where his father worked as an officer in Indian Railways.</p>
<p>After his Computer Engineering from MS University, Baroda, Sikka finished his BS in Computer Science from Syracuse University and his doctorate from Stanford University in artificial intelligence.</p>
<p>Sikka is a well known figure among the Silicon Valley elite and was the closest to Hasso Plattner, founder of SAP.</p>
<p>Here is a link to know more about Vishal Sikka -> <a href="http://www.business-standard.com/article/companies/5-things-to-know-about-infosys-ceo-vishal-sikka-114050600745_1.html">Link</a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/former-syracuse-graduate-named-ceo-of-infosys-indias-pioneering-it-company/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/former-syracuse-graduate-named-ceo-of-infosys-indias-pioneering-it-company/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sai Vikas Gopal</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Maxwell School’s Prakhar Sharma writes for Foreign Policy on ‘How long should Afghanistan matter?’]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-schools-prakhar-sharma-writes-for-foreign-policy-on-how-long-should-afghanistan-matter/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=6040</id>
		<updated>2014-06-27T17:51:00Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-27T17:48:03Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Newsboard" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The third-ever democratic presidential election in Afghanistan and its run-off takes place at a moment when a new form of conventional wisdom is congealing in the West. It concerns the rising pessimism about the U.S.-led intervention in Afghanistan. Skeptics assert that the loss of lives in the thousands, and that of taxpayers&#8217; dollars in the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-schools-prakhar-sharma-writes-for-foreign-policy-on-how-long-should-afghanistan-matter/"><![CDATA[<p>The third-ever democratic presidential election in Afghanistan and its run-off takes place at a moment when a new form of conventional wisdom is congealing in the West. It concerns the rising pessimism about the U.S.-led intervention in Afghanistan. Skeptics assert that the loss of lives in the thousands, and that of taxpayers&#8217; dollars in the billions, was not worth it, if all that resulted was a corrupt, ineffectual, and predatory state apparatus in Afghanistan. While it is true that Afghanistan today is far from what the international community may have desired it to be &#8211; if ever there was a coherent plan in place &#8211; it is nonetheless naive to dismiss the international engagement in Afghanistan as worthless, imperialistic, or a colonial enterprise.</p>
<p>The reality is quite the contrary. Afghanistan is not a war; it is a country. Afghanistan matters not just today; it will continue to resonate in the international community&#8217;s collective consciousness for a long time to come. Progress in Afghanistan will influence other global interventions aimed at enabling state building in different contexts. Afghanistan is a telling depiction of the choices we make as a civilization to ensure our survival against our permanent ideological foes: violent extremism, terrorism, and totalitarianism. Three arguments illustrate why Afghanistan matters and will continue to do so.</p>
<p>Read more here -> <a href="http://southasia.foreignpolicy.com/posts/2014/06/02/how_long_will_afghanistan_matter">Link</a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-schools-prakhar-sharma-writes-for-foreign-policy-on-how-long-should-afghanistan-matter/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-schools-prakhar-sharma-writes-for-foreign-policy-on-how-long-should-afghanistan-matter/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sai Vikas Gopal</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[India’s IT Commissioners meet with U.S. Internal Revenue Service]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-hosts-another-delegation-of-indian-revenue-officers/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=5959</id>
		<updated>2014-06-27T17:46:47Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-21T19:02:32Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Featured" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Maxwell School of Syracuse University is hosting a delegation of Commissioners of Income Tax from the Indian Revenue Service (IRS) for the international component of their mid-career training program]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-hosts-another-delegation-of-indian-revenue-officers/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The Maxwell School of Syracuse University is hosting a delegation of Commissioners of Income Tax from the Indian Revenue Service (IRS) for the international component of their mid-career training program. The four week program which commenced with two weeks sessions at the Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Bangalore is followed by two weeks of international exposure in the U.S. from May 19 &#8211; May 31, 2014. This training program has been tailored to develop commissioners’ understanding of tax policy and leadership issues. The mid-career training program for the IRS Income Tax has been co-developed by the Maxwell School and the IIM &#8211; Bangalore under the direction of IRS Human Resource Department.</p>
<p><img class="colorbox-5959"  src="http://india.syr.edu/wp-content/uploads/Group-Shot1.jpg" width="555" height="370"></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The two weeks program in the United States focus on sessions led by academics, practitioners, and policy makers who share their experience of various policy processes. After attending sessions in Syracuse University, the delegation visits the New York State Department of Tax and Finance in Albany, NY. The last week of the program is held in Washington, D.C., where the delegation meet with representatives from various organizations. The first stop is a visit to Georgetown University Law Center where the delegation learn about three ways in which tax policy decisions are made in the U.S. The delegation then meet with Chief Human Capital Officers from the US Internal Revenue Service and Managing Director for Strategic Issues at the U.S. Government Accountability Office (GAO) to discuss key strategic issues on human capital management. After visiting IMF to learn about the work of Fiscal Affairs Department on modernization of revenue administration in many countries, the IRS IT commissioners attend a presentation on how World Bank operates touching upon International co-operation on tax matters at the World Bank office. The delegation also visits Congressional Budget Office to learn about the work of Tax Analysis Division.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-hosts-another-delegation-of-indian-revenue-officers/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/maxwell-hosts-another-delegation-of-indian-revenue-officers/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sai Vikas Gopal</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Newhouse students Travel to Mumbai for a Bollywood Immersion]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/newhouse-students-travel-to-mumbai-for-a-bollywood-immersion/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=5948</id>
		<updated>2014-05-21T18:39:18Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-21T18:34:38Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Newsboard" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For the fifth time, students from the Newhouse School will have the opportunity to study with filmmakers and production companies in Mumbai, India.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/newhouse-students-travel-to-mumbai-for-a-bollywood-immersion/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">Summer Program: Bollywood Practicum is an SU Abroad course led by Newhouse adjunct Mark Bennington, a renowned photographer and actor with ties to Bollywood. Twelve students will participate in this year’s program, which was developed by Newhouse associate professor Tula Goenka in 2008. </p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">“The program has been extremely successful, but we decided to try something a little different for our fifth trip,” says Goenka. “SUBollywood 2014 is going to be a hands-on production experience, with our students learning how to shoot a Bollywood song, and then working with a local NGO to create a short documentary.” </p>
<p><img class="colorbox-5948"  src="http://india.syr.edu/wp-content/uploads/bollywood.jpg" width="551"></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The course is taught at leading Bollywood director Subhash Ghai’s Whistling Woods International (WWI) Institute for Film, Fashion &#038; Media, and various other locations in Mumbai. Students will also visit the Taj Mahal in Agra.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Participating students include seniors Whitney Marin, Nathaniel Carlson, Aaron Goldsmith, Kyung Seo Han, William Limpert, Kadisha Phillips and Wayne Smith III; juniors Losa Meru, Lara Rogers Benchoam and Veronica Ortiz; and sophomores Sarah Grabman and Erika Douglass. They departed May 16 and will return June 11.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">Carlson will remain in Mumbai an extra month after the other students have left to intern at production company Trace VFX, where he will work with Newhouse alumnus Jonathan Mason ’06.</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The students will blog about their experiences at http://subollywood2014.wordpress.com. Follow them on Twitter via #SUBollywood</p>
<p>Read the full article, <a href="http://news.syr.edu/newhouse-students-travel-to-mumbai-for-a-bollywood-immersion-49265/">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/newhouse-students-travel-to-mumbai-for-a-bollywood-immersion/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/newhouse-students-travel-to-mumbai-for-a-bollywood-immersion/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tejas Chaphalkar</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[American Institute of Indian Studies Fellowship Competition]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/american-institute-of-indian-studies-fellowship-competition/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=5850</id>
		<updated>2014-05-21T18:32:11Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-11T19:57:54Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Newsboard" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The American Institute of Indian Studies (AIIS) invites applications from scholars from all disciplines who wish to conduct their research in India. Junior fellowships are given to doctoral candidates at universities in the U.S. to conduct research for their dissertations in India for up to eleven months. Senior long-term (six to nine months) and short-term [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/american-institute-of-indian-studies-fellowship-competition/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">The American Institute of Indian Studies (AIIS) invites applications from scholars from all disciplines who wish to conduct their research in India. Junior fellowships are given to doctoral candidates at universities in the U.S. to conduct research for their dissertations in India for up to eleven months. Senior long-term (six to nine months) and short-term (four months or less) fellowships are available for scholars who hold the Ph.D. degree. Scholarly/Professional development fellowships are available to scholars and professionals who have not previously worked in India. Creative and Performing Arts fellowships are available to practitioners of the arts of India. Eligible applicants include 1) U.S. citizens; and 2) citizens of other countries who are students or faculty members at U.S. colleges and universities (this rule does not apply to U.S. citizens).</p>
<p>AIIS is pleased to announce that, thanks to the generosity of special friends, it is able to award the following named fellowships on an annual basis:</p>
<p>Asher Family Fellowship<br />
Ludo and Rosane Rocher Research Fellowship in Sanskrit Studies<br />
Daniel H..H. Ingalls Memorial Fellowship<br />
Metcalf Fellowship in Indian History<br />
Rachel F. and Scott McDermott Fellowship<br />
Thomas R. Trautmann Fellowship<br />
Thomas W. Simons Fellowship</p>
<p>Applications can be downloaded from the web site www.indiastudies.org. For more information please contact the American Institute of Indian Studies.<br />
Contact No.: (773) 702-8638<br />
Email: aiis@uchicago.edu<br />
Web site: www.indiastudies.org.<br />
<b>Application deadline is July 1, 2014.</b></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/american-institute-of-indian-studies-fellowship-competition/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/american-institute-of-indian-studies-fellowship-competition/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sai Vikas Gopal</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Maxwell Professor Yüksel Sezgin publishes new paper on &#8216;Regulation of “Religion” and the “Religious”: The Politics of Judicialization and Bureaucratization in India and Indonesia&#8217;]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/regulation-of-religion-and-the-religious-the-politics-of-judicialization-and-bureaucratization-in-india-and-indonesia/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=5826</id>
		<updated>2014-04-11T20:01:08Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-10T18:39:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Newsboard" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The article compares the strategies through which Hindu-majority India and Muslim-majority Indonesia have regulated religion and addressed questions of what constitutes “the religious” in the post-independence period.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/regulation-of-religion-and-the-religious-the-politics-of-judicialization-and-bureaucratization-in-india-and-indonesia/"><![CDATA[<p><center><img class="colorbox-5826"  src = "http://india.syr.edu/wp-content/uploads/Yuksel-Sezgin.jpg"></center><br />
<br/></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">The article compares the strategies through which Hindu-majority India and Muslim-majority Indonesia have regulated religion and addressed questions of what constitutes “the religious” in the post-independence period. We show that the dominant approach pursued by the Indian state has been one of judicialization, i.e. the delegation of religious questions to the high courts, while in Indonesia it has predominantly been one of bureaucratization, i.e. the regulation of religious affairs through the Ministry of Religious Affairs. Contrary to the expectation that judicialization devitalizes normative conflicts while bureaucratization, more frequently associated with authoritarian politics, just “locks” these conflicts “in,” we show that these expectations have not materialized; indeed, at times, the effects have been reverse. Engaging the literatures on judicialization and on bureaucratization, we argue that what determines the consequences of the policy toward religion is less the choice of the implementing institution (i.e. the judiciary or bureaucracy) than the mode of delegation (vertical vs. horizontal) which shapes the relationship between the policy-maker and the institution implementing it. Bureaucrats, judges and elected politicians in multicultural societies around the world encounter questions of religious nature very similar to those that authorities in India and Indonesia tackle. How they respond to questions of religion and address the challenge of religious heterogeneity has a profound impact on prospects of nation-building and democratization. It is therefore imperative that the consequences of the policy towards religion and even more so the consequences of political delegation be studied more systematically. This includes how outcomes are shaped by the relationship between policy-making and -implementing authority – a relationship that this article shows may be harder to steer for democratic governments than autocratic ones.</p>
<p>The paper can be  viewed and downloaded from this <a href="https://www.academia.edu/4204552/Regulation_of_Religion_and_the_Religious_The_Politics_of_Judicialization_and_Bureaucratization_in_India_and_Indonesia">link</a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/regulation-of-religion-and-the-religious-the-politics-of-judicialization-and-bureaucratization-in-india-and-indonesia/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/regulation-of-religion-and-the-religious-the-politics-of-judicialization-and-bureaucratization-in-india-and-indonesia/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tejas Chaphalkar</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Wadley edits new book titled ‘South Asia in the World: An Introduction’]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/title-wadley-edits-new-book-titled-south-asia-in-the-world-an-introduction/" />
		<id>http://india.syr.edu/?p=5348</id>
		<updated>2014-03-24T19:37:50Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-03T18:32:04Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://india.syr.edu" term="Newsboard" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Susan S. Wadley, professor of anthropology and Ford Maxwell Professor of South Asian Studies, has edited a new textbook South Asia in the World: An Introduction. This first book in the new Foundations in Global Studies series published by M. E. Sharp offers a fresh, comprehensive, multidisciplinary introduction to South Asia by exploring its social, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://india.syr.edu/title-wadley-edits-new-book-titled-south-asia-in-the-world-an-introduction/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: justify;">
<div style="width: 20%; list-style: none; float: left;"><img class="colorbox-5348"  alt="" src="http://india.syr.edu/wp-content/uploads/Wadley-Susan.jpg" /></div>
<div style="width: 80%; list-style: none; float: left;">Susan S. Wadley, professor of anthropology and Ford Maxwell Professor of South Asian Studies, has edited a new textbook <a href="http://www.mesharpe.com/mall/resultsa.asp?Title=South+Asia+in+the+World%3A+An+Introduction">South Asia in the World: An Introduction</a>. This first book in the new Foundations in Global Studies series published by M. E. Sharp offers a fresh, comprehensive, multidisciplinary introduction to South Asia by exploring its social, culture, economic, and political life. All but about 15 pages are authored by current faculty, alumni, or students of Syracuse University.</div></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://india.syr.edu/title-wadley-edits-new-book-titled-south-asia-in-the-world-an-introduction/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://india.syr.edu/title-wadley-edits-new-book-titled-south-asia-in-the-world-an-introduction/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
