<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us"><title>children</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/tags/children" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/atomfeeds/tags/children" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.wnyc.org/tags/children</id><updated>2014-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Deportation vs. Asylum: What's Your Take on the Border Crisis?
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/deportation-vs-asylum-whats-your-take-border-crisis/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/deportation-vs-asylum-whats-your-take-border-crisis/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Roughly 57,000 minors from Central America have crossed the border into the US since October. Some policy-makers say they should be deported as quickly as possible. Others say they should be welcomed as refugees. What do you think about the tone used by policy-makers and the status of these young immigrants?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl071714cpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="central_america"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="immigration"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="open_phones"></category></entry><entry><title>A Solution to the Child Migrant Crisis May Be on the Horizon
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/there-solution-child-migrant-crisis-horizon/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-15T13:31:22-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/there-solution-child-migrant-crisis-horizon/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the child migrants crisis, it seems that the narrative of political dysfunction continues in Washington D.C. Both parties are pointing fingers at each other and ramping up the political rhetoric.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a press conference last Thursday, House Speaker John Boehner laid the blame squarely on President Obama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Along our southern border we've got a true humanitarian crisis underway with children caught in the middle," he said. "Unfortunately, it's a crisis of the president's own making. His actions gave false hope to children and their families that if they entered the country illegally, they would be allowed to stay."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in fact, behind the theatrics, there are promising indications that a bipartisan deal is possible. Takeaway Washington Correspondent &lt;strong&gt;Todd Zwillich&lt;/strong&gt; explains why there may be some hope coming out of Capitol Hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"There is no question that, especially on cable television and across the airways, the word war around immigration and this border crisis is really hot," says Zwillich. "We know how fractured immigration debates are in this country—comprehensive immigration reform has failed, and the finger pointing is going on everywhere."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="twitter-follow-button" href="https://twitter.com/ToddZwillich" data-show-count="false" data-size="large"&gt;Follow @ToddZwillich&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script&gt;// &lt;![CDATA[
!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');
// ]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zwillich says that when it comes to an immigration strategy, Democrats think they have a big advantage going into the 2014 midterm elections because of the lack of consensus from the Republican Party. However, the tide may be shifting—Zwillich points out that former Alaska Governor and Republican vice presidential nominee Sarah Palin is calling for President Obama to be impeached over the child migrant crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The right is fired up," says Zwillich. "Behind closed doors here in the Capitol, the leaders—and I'm talking about (John) Boehner, (Nancy) Pelosi, (Harry) Reid, and the White House—are trying really, really hard to keep conditions steady so that all of this public recrimination doesn't upset the chances for a deal. It's not going to be easy, and it still could fail."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In early July, President Obama requested $3.7 billion in emergency aid to address the influx of child migrants crossing the border—a request that may actually be fulfilled, despite the tense bipartisan climate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What often happens with emergency supplemental (aid) in this environment—what do Republicans say right away? 'Fine, but find a way to pay for it. We're going to make cuts somewhere else in order to pay for this,'" says Zwillich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of late, getting approval for emergency funding can be a Herculean task, even in the face of things like natural disasters—Zwillich points out that it took about three months to get approval for this type of aid in the wake of Hurricane Sandy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"But you know what John Boehner didn't say when the White House sent this request out—he never said it has to be paid for," says Zwillich. "If you're listening, you take that as a signal that he really, really wants to keep Democrats in the fold and make a deal possible."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the Democratic leadership in the House of Representatives, Zwillich says that House Minority Leader Nancy Pelosi seems willing to compromise. According to Zwillich, Congressional Republicans are hoping to change asylum rules and rules surrounding the deportation of these child migrants. The current law makes it difficult to send children back to non-contiguous countries like Guatemala and El Salvador.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"A lot of liberal Democrats and Congressional Hispanics are really against that," says Zwillich. "(Pelosi) said, 'I don't like it, but it's not a deal breaker.' These are two signals coming from the big kids on Capitol Hill."&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway071514-immigration.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="central_america"></category><category term="child_migrants"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="congress"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="immigration"></category><category term="migration"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>Eating While Parenting
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/how-find-deliciousness-your-kids-table-scraps/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/how-find-deliciousness-your-kids-table-scraps/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Anyone who takes care of kids knows that eating off children's plates is part of the everyday dining experience. But which kid scraps make for the most delicious eats? How can an eater make these scraps even better? And which touched/dropped/pre-masticated foods are just too gross to consume?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hillary Frank of WNYC's parenting podcast &lt;a href="http://longestshortesttime.com/"&gt;The Longest Shortest Time&lt;/a&gt; is disgusted by Dan's answers, but Dan remains undeterred. He talks with Arun Venugopal of WNYC's &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/micropolis/"&gt;Micropolis&lt;/a&gt; about the role of eating with your hands in Indian culture and how it can help parents find prized morsels in the post-meal detritus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, former New York Congressman Anthony Weiner discusses the scraps he most enjoys eating from his toddler's high chair, and Dan's own daughters demonstrate how they eat and share food with the grown-ups in a special Sporkful video. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungry for more on eating while parenting? Join The Longest Shortest Time's &lt;a href="http://longestshortesttime.com/2014/07/16/hangout-make-mealtime-happier/"&gt;Google+ Hangout&lt;/a&gt; on July 16, 2014. Hillary Frank will be moderating. Dan and pediatric dietitian Heidi Kecskemethy will be fielding your questions. Submit your questions and find out more &lt;a href="http://longestshortesttime.com/2014/07/07/ask-a-pediatric-dietitian/comment-page-2/#comments"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="user-embedded-video"&gt;&lt;div id="videoplayer_idm4990434deb887-bebd-4e0f-ab0b-5b23952fb993"&gt;&lt;iframe width="620" height="349" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/msuvjpX5C3g?wmode=transparent&amp;amp;autohide=1&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;feature=oembed&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" id="a-1883597691729240735" class="youtube_video" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" data-original-url="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=msuvjpX5C3g"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/sporkful/sporkful071514pod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="anthony_weiner"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="evergreen"></category><category term="families"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="longest_shortest"></category><category term="parenting"></category></entry><entry><title>Extracurricular Summer Camp?
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/extra-curricular-summer-camp/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-10T09:22:03-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/extra-curricular-summer-camp/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=KJ+Dell%27Antonia"&gt;KJ Dell'Antonia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://parenting.blogs.nytimes.com/author/kj-dellantonia/"&gt;editor and lead writer of the Motherlode blog for &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, talks about the pressure on parents to design curricula for their children in coding and other subjects and to send kids to a summer camp for those extra skills.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl071014bpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="parenting"></category><category term="summer_camps"></category></entry><entry><title>Anthony Weiner Leaves No Child's Mac and Cheese Behind
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/anthony-weiner-leaves-no-childs-mac-and-cheese-behind/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-08T15:22:42-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/anthony-weiner-leaves-no-childs-mac-and-cheese-behind/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How do you find deliciousness among the detritus of your kids' table scraps? Do you ever sneak treats when your kids aren't looking, or try to get them to order the thing you want to eat at a restaurant, since you know they won't finish it anyway? If so, what's the best way to do it without them catching on?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week on The Sporkful we'll talk about all this and more when we cover Eating While Parenting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our guests will include Hillary Frank of WNYC's parenting podcast &lt;a href="http://longestshortesttime.com/"&gt;The Longest Shortest Time&lt;/a&gt; and Arun Venegopal of WNYC's &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/micropolis/"&gt;Micropolis&lt;/a&gt;, plus a special cameo from former New York Congressman Anthony Weiner. Listen to the above preview, in which I ask the congressman about his policy on whether to eat his two-and-a-half year old son's leftover scraps.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/sporkful_teaser/sporkful_teaser070814_weiner.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="parenting"></category><category term="twittercard"></category></entry><entry><title>How to Eat off Your Children's Plates
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/how-eat-your-childrens-plates/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-08T14:22:40-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/how-eat-your-childrens-plates/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Like burying beetles and blowflies, parents are natural scavengers. We have no time or energy to make our own decent meals so we scavenge for what we can, where we can, defying the laws of grossness to which non-parents adhere. (And sometimes we even find &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/parents-guide-eating-over-sink/"&gt;some tasty morsels&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've identified a hierarchy of small children's table scraps, to help parents decide where to draw the line between edible and trash-worthy. Here they are, from the ideal scenario to the bottom of the barrel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dan's Hierarchy of Kids' Table Scraps&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. On the plate, untouched. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. On the plate, mushed around with hands. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Picked up and dropped on the floor. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. Put in the mouth and returned to the plate. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Put in the mouth and dropped on the floor by accident. &lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;6. Put in the mouth and dropped on the floor on purpose.*&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;address&gt;*If the food was put on the floor intentionally, there was likely velocity involved. The food was probably hurled, which means it was hand-smooshed before being thrown. That's why this is the worst — the food has been degraded by the mouth, hands, and floor.&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be taking your questions on how to make mealtime happier in a &lt;a href="http://longestshortesttime.com/2014/07/16/hangout-make-mealtime-happier/"&gt;Google+ Hangout&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/longestshortesttime/"&gt;The Longest Shortest Time&lt;/a&gt;. You can submit questions ahead of time &lt;a href="http://wp.me/p4bvGZ-1jG"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="children"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="parenting"></category></entry><entry><title>Wherefore Teach Thy Children Shakespeare?
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/wherefore-teach-thy-children-shakespeare/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-08T13:24:14-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/wherefore-teach-thy-children-shakespeare/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Ken+Ludwig"&gt;Ken Ludwig&lt;/a&gt;, playwright ("Lend Me a Tenor," "Crazy for You") and the author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/0307951502"&gt;How to Teach Your Children Shakespeare&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(Broadway Books, 2014), offers tips for parents on some of the Shakespeare performances around town this summer.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Productions of Shakespeare plays in and around the city this summer include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;As You Like It&lt;/em&gt;, currently playing until July 27 (&lt;a href="http://www.newyorkclassical.org/"&gt;New York Classical Theatre&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Othello; The Two Gentlemen of Verona&lt;/em&gt;, currently playing until August 31 (&lt;a href="http://hvshakespeare.org/content/2014-season"&gt;Hudson Valley Shakespeare Festiva&lt;/a&gt;l)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Romeo n Juliet&lt;/em&gt;, July 5 - July 27 (&lt;a href="http://www.cthnyc.org/now-playing/productions/"&gt;CTHNYC&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twelfth Night&lt;/em&gt;, July 10 - 26 (&lt;a href="http://shakespeareintheparkinglot.com/"&gt;Shakespeare in the Parking Lot&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Taming of the Shrew&lt;/em&gt;, July 18 - 20 (&lt;a href="http://www.brooklynbridgepark.org/events/taming-of-the-shrew"&gt;Shakespeare at Sunset&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Midsummer Night’s Dream&lt;/em&gt;, July 18 - 20, 25- 27 (&lt;a href="http://www.quirkyproductions.net/a-midsummer-nights-dream.html"&gt;Quirky Productions&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;King Lear&lt;/em&gt;, July 22 - August 17 (&lt;a href="http://publictheater.org/Tickets/Calendar/PlayDetailsCollection/FSITP/King-Lear/"&gt;The Public Theater&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Two Gentlemen of Verona; Cymbeline&lt;/em&gt;, July 23 - August 17 (&lt;a href="http://www.hiptohip.org/"&gt;Hip to Hip Theatre Company&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Much Ado About&lt;/em&gt; Nothing, July 23 - August 10 (&lt;a href="http://www.smithstreetstage.org"&gt;Smith Street Stage&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Romeo and Juliet&lt;/em&gt;, July 24 - August 17 (&lt;a href="http://pulseensembletheatre.org/harlem-summer-shakespeare"&gt;Pulse Ensemble Theatre&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Winter’s Tale&lt;/em&gt;, July 31 - August 24 (&lt;a href="http://www.hudsonwarehouse.net/season.html"&gt;Hudson Warehouse&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl070814epod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="books"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="local_news"></category><category term="new_york"></category><category term="shakespeare"></category><category term="theater"></category></entry><entry><title>Is the Child Migrant Crisis a Refugee Crisis?
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/us-role-in-child-migrant-crisis/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-03T10:11:35-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/us-role-in-child-migrant-crisis/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since October of last year, some 50,000 Central American children have streamed across the U.S.-Mexico border unaccompanied by their parents. The children come fleeing extreme violence and poverty in their home countries of Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A report from the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees found that a full 58 percent are forcibly displaced from their homelands because they have suffered or face harms that require international protection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon arriving in the United States, they are detained and processed for a few of days before being handed off to relatives in the U.S. pending their immigration processing. But this process is not sitting well some of the residents of Murietta, California.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, a protest of more than 100 people waving American flags and signs protesting "illegals" blocked three Homeland Security buses carrying Central American women and children headed to a suburban processing facility. As a result, the buses were forced to reroute to a facility in San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could the U.S. government be handling this escalating humanitarian crisis better?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Norma Torres&lt;/strong&gt; is the State Senator representing California’s 32nd district and a candidate for Congress. She is the highest ranking American elected official born in Guatemala, and today she discusses the government's response to this new wave of immigrants and the lives these children are leaving behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway070314-central.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="immigration"></category><category term="immigration_reform"></category><category term="international"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>Extreme Violence &amp; Poverty Drives Honduran Children to the U.S.
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/migrant-children-honduras-flee-lives-extreme-violence-and-poverty/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-30T11:08:45-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/migrant-children-honduras-flee-lives-extreme-violence-and-poverty/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The White House is requesting $2 billion in emergency funding to stem the increasing flow of children crossing the U.S.-Mexico border. So far this year, more than 52,000 Central American children have been detained at the border after making the arduous trip unaccompanied by a parent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of these children are coming from Honduras, fleeing a life of poverty and extreme violence. A 2012 United Nations report named Honduras the murder capital of the world, with 90 homicides occurring per every 100,000 residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The White House has announced additional plans to create more economic opportunities for farmers in Central America, but that won't stem the intense gang violence overcoming urban centers, which is driving children to travel thousands of miles alone in search of safety and opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Martin Davies, &lt;/strong&gt;Texas Public Radio's news director, &lt;a href="http://tpr.org/post/streets-honduras-look-what-driving-thousands-children-us"&gt;traveled to Honduras&lt;/a&gt; to see where and how their journeys begin.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway063014-honduras.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="honduras"></category><category term="immigration"></category><category term="international_relations"></category><category term="migrants"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="poverty"></category><category term="violence"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>How Young Is Too Young To Read To Your Kids?
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/how-young-too-young-read-your-kids/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/how-young-too-young-read-your-kids/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you're the parent of a newborn, what do you think about reading to your baby? Does it make a difference, or is it one more parenting recommendation to follow at a stressful time? &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Jamie+Zibulsky"&gt;Jamie Zibulsky&lt;/a&gt;, author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0199843937/wnycorg-20/"&gt;Book Smart: How to Develop and Support Successful, Motivated Readers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; makes the case for reading to your infants and takes your calls.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl062714dpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="books"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="reading"></category></entry><entry><title>What Unaccompanied Minors Mean for Immigration Reform
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/what-unaccompanied-minors-mean-immigration-reform/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-26T15:50:54-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/what-unaccompanied-minors-mean-immigration-reform/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Children from Central America are crossing the US-Mexico border by themselves. &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Bob+Ortega"&gt;Bob Ortega&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://archive.azcentral.com/news/ask/reporter/ortega/"&gt;senior reporter&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;The Arizona Republic&lt;/em&gt;, talks about his reporting from both sides of the border on why the kids say they want to come to the US, and the message in their home countries about the dangerous journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl062614apod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="central_america"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="immigration"></category><category term="mexico"></category><category term="national_news"></category></entry><entry><title>Education Sec. Arne Duncan on The Future of Learning
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/education-sec-arne-duncan-discusses-future-learning/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-26T12:48:17-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/education-sec-arne-duncan-discusses-future-learning/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A coalition of mayors and brain scientists are trying to get the U.S. government to make early childhood education both a priority and a right in America. This is just one of the many initiatives rolled out at the 82nd Annual U.S. Conference of Mayors meeting this week in Dallas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This initiative, called Early Childhood Nation, would be the first to incorporate the latest brain science into actual pre-school programs. This program also aims to help public schools prepare kids to start kindergarten, and it addresses the need for day care. Early Childhood Nation is funded by the Bezos Family Foundation, which is already funding  actual programs for schools and home called &lt;a href="http://www.bezosfamilyfoundation.org/vroom"&gt;Vroom.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Education Secretary&lt;strong&gt; Arne Duncan&lt;/strong&gt; supports the program, which got a unanimous vote of approval from the U.S. Conference of Mayors this week. He sat down exclusively to talk about early childhood education with The Takeaway while we were in Dallas earlier this week.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway062614-duncan.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="school"></category></entry><entry><title>Arizona Lawmaker Reacts to Detention of Hundreds of Immigrant Children
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/lawmakers-react-detention-hundreds-immigrant-children/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-20T10:19:53-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/lawmakers-react-detention-hundreds-immigrant-children/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, the country got its first glimpse of the immigration detention centers in Arizona and Texas where hundreds of child migrants are being held in chain link holding cells topped with razor wire. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The images sparked renewed outrage from lawmakers, who demanded answers from the Department of Homeland Security on how the children were being handled and what plans had been made for their release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 1,000 migrant children have been shipped to the Nogales, Arizona holding center alone, and state officials are less than pleased with the scarlet "I" the center is casting on their border town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Senator Kelli Ward&lt;/strong&gt;, a Republican state senator representing Arizona's 5th district, reflects on the consequences of having these migrant children in the state’s custody, and what federal policy is necessary to address the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway062014-arizona.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="central_america"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="immigrant"></category><category term="immigration"></category><category term="migrants"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="undocumented"></category><category term="undocumented_immigrant"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>Undocumented Children &amp; The Pull of the Capital
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/influx-immigrants-central-american-strain-washington-dc/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-19T13:21:49-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/influx-immigrants-central-american-strain-washington-dc/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Driven away from their communities by poverty and violence, there has &lt;a href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/wave-immigration-tests-ill-equipped-system/"&gt;been an influx&lt;/a&gt; of undocumented children coming to the United States from Central America. And they’re crossing the U.S.–Mexico border in alarming numbers. In fact, 90,000 unaccompanied minors are expected to be apprehended this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of detaining them until their immigration processing, the federal government is placing the children with a relative or sponsor. According to &lt;strong&gt;Armando Trull&lt;/strong&gt;, a senior reporter from WAMU,&lt;a href="http://wamu.org/news/14/06/19/dc_area_struggles_with_surge_of_underage_immigrants"&gt; many are arriving in Washington, D.C.&lt;/a&gt;, which has one of the largest Central American populations in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children come fleeing desperate situations in their home countries. "These youths are boys who have been threatened by local drug cartels to join their gangs or their families will be killed," says Melissa Graves with Lutheran Social Services. "They're girls who have been forced into sex trafficking."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trull's reporting reveals that the minors flowing into the the country are often sent for by their parents who already reside here. He spoke to one such woman, Elena, who paid $12,000 to have her three young children smuggled to the United States from Guatemala.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You know you are placing your children at risk by bringing them by themselves on this trip," she says. "I placed them in God's hands and prayed on my knees every night."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Washington D.C. metro area is beginning to feel the strain of taking on a wave of high needs children. Montgomery County high school counselor Stefanny Aramayo has seen the number of Central American students in one class more than double from 12 to 26 since October.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I have a student who came from a tiny village in Guatemala," she says. "And the first time I put her in front of a computer she wanted to cry...She said, 'What do we do with this?'"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;See Also: &lt;a href="http://www.jrn.com/kgun9/galleries/Our-first-look-inside-the-CBP-holding-center-in-Nogales-housing-hundreds-of-children-263710951.html"&gt;Inside the Arizona Center Housing Undocumented Children&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway061914-immigration.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="dream_act"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="immigration"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="undocumented"></category><category term="undocumented_immigrant"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>What's Going on Inside the Toddler Brain
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/whats-goes-inside-toddler-brain/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-17T16:05:43-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/whats-goes-inside-toddler-brain/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Child psychologist and director of the Barnard Center for Toddler Development &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Dr.+Tovah+P.+Klein"&gt;Dr. Tovah P. Klein&lt;/a&gt; reveals what parents can do to help their toddler grow into a fulfilled child and adult, and she discusses new science that shows that resilience, self-reliance, self-regulation, and empathy are more critical to success than simple intelligence. She also explains what’s behind tantrums and fights over bedtime and why “toddlers are the opposite of civilized human beings.” &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On toddlers are so prone to tantrums&lt;/strong&gt;: “They have a lot of new emotions – so anger, frustration, disappointment, fear really come into play as they start to separate. But they don’t – literally – have the brain mechanisms to control those. So they get upset, they get upset in the moment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On why their newfound independence can be so confusing for toddlers&lt;/strong&gt;: "The struggle between being independent or wanting to rely on others is a lifelong struggle."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the importance of routines&lt;/strong&gt;: “Toddlers have no sense of time. Zero. And so what routines do is they help organize them. They walk them through the day. And we’re also, literally in those routines, setting up kind of a roadmap for them so we don’t have to keep micromanaging them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On not believing everything you read on the web&lt;/strong&gt;: “I think that parents need to step back, and sometimes ask them or maybe even often ask themselves, ‘What do, in my heart, I think is right for this child?’ And parents are usually right.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On why time outs don’t really work for toddlers&lt;/strong&gt;: “Time outs were started for older children…It was the nicer version of the dunce cap.” She says, “But young children don’t have that capacity to sit and to think, so removing a child in a supportive way because a situation’s not working, and saying, ‘Hey, we need to take a break,’ is one thing. But punishing them actually does backfire and makes them feel very, very badly rather than getting control of their behavior.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On why sticker charts rarely work&lt;/strong&gt;: “They’re short-term control mechanisms.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most important thing to keep in mind&lt;/strong&gt;, Klein says: “There’s not one set of rules.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Klein's book is &lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1476735131/wnycorg-20/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Toddlers Thrive: What Parents Can Do Today for Children Ages 2-5 to Plant the Seeds of Lifelong Success&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate061714apod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="books"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="parents_and_children"></category><category term="psychology"></category><category term="science"></category></entry><entry><title>Sowing Seeds: Raising Toddlers and Community Gardens
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/the-leonard-lopate-show-2014-06-17/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/the-leonard-lopate-show-2014-06-17/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On today’s show: Child psychologist &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Tovah P. Klein&lt;/strong&gt; explains why the toddler years are crucial for a child’s development and what parents can do to help their kids—and themselves—thrive. Then, find out about the 1922 double murder in New Jersey that loomed large in F. Scott Fitzgerald’s mind as he wrote &lt;em&gt;The Great Gatsby&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Tom Rachman&lt;/strong&gt; talks about his new novel, &lt;em&gt;The Rise and Fall of Great Powers&lt;/em&gt;. And we’ll take a look at the past, present, and future of community gardens in New York City.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="community_gardens"></category><category term="science"></category></entry><entry><title>U.S. Man Discovers his Beginnings at Deadly Irish Unwed Mothers Home
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/man-discovers-beginnings-at-deadly-irish-unwed-mothers-home/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/man-discovers-beginnings-at-deadly-irish-unwed-mothers-home/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The news last week that between 1925 and 1961 nearly &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2014/06/03/bodies-of-800-babies-long-dead-found-in-septic-tank-at-former-irish-home-for-unwed-mothers/"&gt;800 babies died&lt;/a&gt; at St. Mary's unwed mothers home in Ireland has thrust a shadowy period of the country's history onto the American consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located in Tuam, Ireland, St. Mary's was one of many unwed mothers homes run by the Catholic Church. They were designed to punish unwed mothers and house their children, but what actually occurred seems to be much darker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Young mothers were shamed for their sins and forced to work in indentured servitude, and if their children survived childbirth and infancy, they were often given up for adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;North Carolina resident &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2014/06/09/born-in-irelands-home-of-800-baby-bodies-north-carolina-man-recalls-the-evil/"&gt;Peter Ferris Cochran&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; was born at St. Mary’s and lived there for the first year and a half of his life before an American family adopted him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I couldn't walk, I couldn't talk, I had never been held by anybody when they received me at 18-months-old," says Cochran. "These are the things that gave me the driving force to want go to Ireland and see where I came from."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through Cochran's visits to the the location where the home once stood and his tireless research into his past, he learned that his birth mother was among those whom the Tuam Center shamed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It wasn't an orphanage, it was a place where women who had bastard children had to repent their sins," he says. "Like my mother, she got there in August and she had me in November and she left in December of the following year. So she had to work at the orphanage before she delivered, and once she delivered she had to stay there at the house and pay her debt to society."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A local &lt;a href="http://www.economist.com/news/europe/21604210-where-are-nearly-800-babies-buried-search-truth"&gt;Tuam historian&lt;/a&gt; speculates that the bodies of the babies who died at St. Mary's were disposed of in a mass grave on the old premises without a  proper burial or recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"How can the Catholic Church be such a horrible influence in my mother's life and into all of these orphans' lives?" wonders Cochran. “Now we’re discovering they didn’t even give these women a choice. It was either you delivered normally and paid your sins, or if there were complications with the child, the child was disposed of.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cochran was fortunate to discover his birth family. “My mother’s sister was working with a social worker in Ireland,” he tells The Takeaway. “And that social worker was working with my other mother, Cochran. The stories all matched.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Cochran is worried that there are more like him who have no means of discovering their family history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I'm sure there are a lot of mothers out there that wonder whether their child is alive or whether their child did pass away,” said Cochran. “Right now in Ireland, they just need to open up all their books, stop lying, and stop hiding stuff.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Archbishop of Dublin acknowledged that what happened in Tuam and St. Mary’s could have happened elsewhere across the country. He says there is a need for a full investigation into convent-run mother and baby homes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Cochran never met his birth mother, he said  “I wanted nothing but to look at her and say, ‘Look, you went through Hell. But the bottom line is the decision that you made was the right decision because I am here, I’m safe, and I’ve had a good life in the United States. It’s time for you to just close your eyes, rest, and know that what happened 50 years ago turned out to be a good story.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UPDATE 6/23/2014: The Associated Press has clarified new details of this story. &lt;a href="http://hosted.ap.org/dynamic/stories/E/EU_IRELAND_CHILDRENS_MASS_GRAVES?CTIME=2014-06-20-14-48-31&amp;amp;SECTION=HOME&amp;amp;SITE=AP&amp;amp;TEMPLATE=DEFAULT"&gt;Click here for more information.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway061614-ireland.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="catholic_church"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="history"></category><category term="ireland"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="pregnancy"></category><category term="religion"></category><category term="religion_faith"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>The Story of a Teen Dad's Struggle to Become a Better Father
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/teen-dads-struggle-become-better-father/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/teen-dads-struggle-become-better-father/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Growing up, &lt;strong&gt;Marvin Ramos&lt;/strong&gt; had few role models in terms of fatherhood. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I didn't see nobody doing what they need to do to their kids, like feed them," he tells The Takeaway's John Hockenberry. "I didn't see that from my father. I didn't have a model."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, at the age of 18, Ramos has a one year old daughter, Hailey. As he prepares to celebrate Father's Day with his daughter this weekend, Ramos reflects on his family, and his hopes for his daughter's future. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three of Marvin's brothers had children when they were young. About a year ago, their father left the family leaving Ramos without a fatherly figure to guide him as he became a dad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I'm going to try to give the best time to my daughter—something I didn't have," he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvin is part of &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/radio-rookies-trying-be-better-dad/" target="_blank"&gt;Radio Rookies&lt;/a&gt;, a project of Takeaway co-producer WNYC. He says he learned a lot about himself and his family through in reporting his first radio story. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His most important lesson? "Just be there," he says. "You don't want them running to anyone else but you."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marvin's hoping to complete his high school diploma this year. He admits that he wasn't much of a presence in his daughter's life until recently. This Father's Day is his second, but he's recommitted himself to Hailey and her mother, Ramos's girlfriend, Stephanie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ramos wants to strengthen his bond with his daughter, to "spend the greatest time with her while [she's] young, because when they get older, they want to do what they want to do. And then when they get older they'll remember, wow. I had a great dad."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to get involved in the conversation? Tell us about a person who has been a father figure to you—even if they're not your biological father. Leave a comment below or call 1-877-869-8253.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway061314-fatherrr.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="fatherhood"></category><category term="fathers_day"></category><category term="local_news"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="parenting"></category><category term="radio_rookies"></category><category term="teen_parenthood"></category><category term="teen_pregnancy"></category><category term="twittercard"></category></entry><entry><title>Wave of Immigration Tests Ill-Equipped System
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/wave-immigration-tests-ill-equipped-system/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-06-10T10:14:03-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/wave-immigration-tests-ill-equipped-system/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past week, the status quo of discussion surrounding immigration reform has been disrupted by new numbers that show an influx of tens of thousands of women and children traveling from Central America across the U.S.-Mexico border in recent months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Border agents and government officials are completely overwhelmed by the spike in single women and children arriving, as local and federal governments find they lack the resources or space to house the families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with an estimated 74,000 unaccompanied minors expected to make the journey in 2014, there seems to be little relief in sight as immigration reform remains stagnant in Congress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Julia Preston&lt;/strong&gt;, national immigration correspondent for our partner The New York Times, gives a look at the cause and scope of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of the 47,000 migrant children that have crossed the U.S.-Mexico border this year, about a thousand of them are now in Nogales, Arizona, after being transferred there by the federal Department of Homeland Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The children are being held in a makeshift detention center. Though it's equipped by the Department of Health and Human Services, local authorities are still scrambling to gather supplies from local donors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arturo Garino&lt;/strong&gt; is the mayor of Nogales. He provides the view from inside the makeshift detention facility.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway061014-immigration.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="detention_center"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="illegal_immigration"></category><category term="immigration"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="unaccompanied_minors"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>Are Kids Getting Enough Playtime? 
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/play-tk-tk/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-27T11:34:26-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/play-tk-tk/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the tranquil nation of Finland, kids get an average of 75 minutes for recess and it's almost exclusively outdoors. School administrators there say neither wind nor rain nor snow could mitigate the benefits of good old fashioned fresh air. But in the U.S., the average time for recess is right around 27 minutes and it's a number that's been declining in states like Washington.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KUOW education reporter &lt;strong&gt;Ann Dornfeld&lt;/strong&gt; has found a one minute drop in recess time for Seattle elementary students every year since 2010. Seattle students now have on average 32 minutes for recess. The numbers are even lower for schools in low income neighborhoods, where administrators chalk up disciplinary problems as a reason for cutting into play time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Notre Dame psychology professor &lt;strong&gt;Darcia Narvaez&lt;/strong&gt; says restricting and over-regulating play is a bad idea. We talk with Ann and Darcia about the state of play for American children.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway052714-play.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="recess"></category></entry><entry><title>Hot Ticket: Library Story Hour
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/hot-ticket-library-story-hour/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-23T09:56:32-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/hot-ticket-library-story-hour/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Heidi+Mitchell"&gt;Heidi Mitchell&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; contributor, talks about the &lt;a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702303468704579571911441257096?mg=reno64-wsj"&gt;increasing popularity of toddler story time at public libraries&lt;/a&gt; in the city. While libraries are expanding programming to meet the demand, some branches have had to resort to ticketing systems for crowd control for the free programs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;div style="clear:both;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Story Time at NYPL's Webster Branch&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/j3oMQsWQxlk" width="560"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;New York Magazine Video about Libraries as Community Centers and Their Petition for More Funding from the City&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="433" scrolling="no" src="http://videos.nymag.com/video/Libraries-Now-A-Day-In-the-Life/player?layout=&amp;amp;title_height=24" width="616"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl052314epod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="local_news"></category><category term="public_library"></category><category term="storytelling"></category></entry><entry><title>Beautiful and Disturbing 'Peter and the Wolf' Album Covers
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/peter-and-wolf-album-covers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-23T05:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/peter-and-wolf-album-covers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is Prokofiev's &lt;em&gt;Peter and the Wolf &lt;/em&gt;the most popular children's piece ever? This month marks the anniversary of its debut in Moscow to tepid reviews, but it seems every famous person has narrated the story —often coupled with high-octane musicians. Here is a compilation of some of the versions in our library. We think some of them are much scarier than the big, grey wolf in the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is your favorite version? And your favorite album cover? Let us know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW001ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW002ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW003ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW004ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW005ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW006ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW007ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW008ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW009ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW010ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW011ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW012ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW013ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW014ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW015ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW016ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW017ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW018ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW019ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW020ForWeb.jpg" alt="(Sorry about the monocle and 'stache, cap'n!)" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW021ForWeb_2.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW022ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW023ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW024ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW025ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW026ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW027ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/PeterAndTheWolfPATW028ForWeb.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="600"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="children"></category><category term="classical_music"></category><category term="peter_and_the_wolf"></category><category term="prokofiev"></category></entry><entry><title>Neil deGrasse Tyson's Mom Explains How to Raise a Brilliant Child
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/neil-degrasse-tysons-mom-explains-how-raise-brilliant-child/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-05-09T18:15:16-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/neil-degrasse-tysons-mom-explains-how-raise-brilliant-child/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Though it might be a bit outdated, the old saying goes: "Behind every successful man, there's a great woman." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of astrophysicist, author, radio and television host Neil deGrasse Tyson, that great woman would be his mother, &lt;strong&gt;Sunchita "Toni" Tyson&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In honor of Mother's Day, Toni Tyson discusses the unique challenges of raising a future astrophysicist in the Bronx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ms. Tyson encouraged her son's scientific aptitude and interests, even when some teachers and professors had low expectations for Neil due to a racist bias.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It was not easy—it was a full time 24-hour a day job," says Toni. "All three of my children are brown, and they stay brown all year round, and they even get darker in the summertime. We had to make it very, very clear at a very early age that some people are not going to be very nice to them, but it was not their problem but the other person's problem. When things did occur, we would get onto it immediately."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Neil was in junior high school, Toni says that she had read about a scholarship available through the Department of Education. Neil filled out the application, wrote an essay, and had to get three references. According to Toni, one teacher Neil asked for a reference came back with some harsh feedback. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"When he presented it to the teacher, he said, 'What makes you think you can get this scholarship?'" says Toni. "Of course, he came home devastated. As a result, he used another teacher. I had gotten vibes from this individual that I did not like during one of the Parent Teacher Association meetings."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is just one of many stories of struggles Toni discusses in this wide ranging interview Takeaway Host John Hockenberry. &lt;strong&gt;Neil deGrasse Tyson&lt;/strong&gt; himself also joins in the conversation—listen to the full discussion above to hear more.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway050914-tysonnn.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="creativity"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="kids"></category><category term="mothers_day"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="parenting"></category><category term="parents"></category><category term="science"></category><category term="technology"></category></entry><entry><title>Our Favorite Children's Stories
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/our-favorite-childrens-stories/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/our-favorite-childrens-stories/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For kids and their parents, bedtime often starts with a few books. &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Elizabeth+Bird"&gt;Elizabeth Bird&lt;/a&gt;, a Youth Materials Specialist from the New York Public Library, talks about some of our favorite classic story books and some of the popular newcomers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tell us: what was your favorite book as a child? What books were you excited to share with your own kids? Which books do your kids want to read over and over again?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A lot of books that are favorites today, like &lt;em&gt;Goodnight Moon&lt;/em&gt;, were not hits when they were first published. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Callers shared some of their favorites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dandelion&lt;/em&gt; by Don Freeman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thank You Bear&lt;/em&gt; by Greg Foley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Robot and the Bluebird&lt;/em&gt; by David Lucas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Helen called us to share that her son insisted every night that she read the Fire Department's diversity enrollment brochure, including the pages about the pension and health benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our librarian also shared three book recommendations of her own:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flora and the Flamingo&lt;/em&gt; by Molly Idle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Niño Wrestles the World&lt;/em&gt; by Yuyi Morales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mr. Tiger Goes Wild &lt;/em&gt;by Peter Brown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate042414cpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="books"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="families_and_children"></category><category term="reading"></category><category term="sleep"></category></entry><entry><title>The Risks Parents Take to Get Their Kids Medical Marijuana
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/why-parents-are-bringing-marijuana-nj-illegally-their-sick-children/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-18T04:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/why-parents-are-bringing-marijuana-nj-illegally-their-sick-children/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When Sabina Rose Joana was 6 months old she was diagnosed with Dravet Syndrome, a severe form of epilepsy that was causing her to have up to 90 seizures a day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her parents heard of other families having positive results with medicinal marijuana. The evidence was anecdotal, but parents said it was reducing the frequency and intensity of seizures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were in the process of getting Sabina a medical marijuana card in New Jersey, but faced months of delays. Sabina died in the process, after having a seizure that lasted 24 hours and left her brain dead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was 15 months old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her mom, Paula Joana, says there are unnecessary hurdles to get a marijuana card. She wants a meeting with Gov. Chris Christie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float: right; margin: 10px;" src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/SabinaRose.JPG" alt="" width="300" height="250"&gt;“I would show him a video of her dancing and blowing kisses, and I would show him what I don’t have anymore,” Joana said. “I would show him the video of her having a seizure, and I would make him watch that. And that’s all I would need to say. He knows what needs to be done.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under pressure from parents, Christie signed a law last September allowing edible forms of marijuana to be sold to minors with life-threatening illnesses who are too young or unable to learn how to smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the state has still not given the marijuana dispensaries permission to sell edibles. And Sabina’s death has convinced other families to get edible marijuana for their children whatever ways they can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementing the Marijuana Law&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former Gov. Jon Corzine signed a bill allowing the sale of medical marijuana in 2010 — the day before Christie’s inauguration. But Christie has been slow to implement it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently three dispensaries in New Jersey and 2,211 marijuana card holders, including both adults and minors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, Arizona, which passed medical marijuana the same year as New Jersey, has 78 dispensaries and 50,073 card holders, according to the Arizona Department of Health Services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State legislators introduced another bill that would allow parents to bring edible marijuana from other states until edibles are sold in New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a press conference in December, right after he was re-elected, Christie said he wouldn’t consider it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am done expanding the medical marijuana program. Under any circumstances,” Christie said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said the program works fine for people “who truly need it,” and says the legislature is using sick kids as an excuse to legalize recreational use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“They’re not getting legalization under this governor. They’ll have to elect somebody else, and you know what? They don’t get the chance for that for another four years,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paula Joana, Sabina’s mom, says Christie made the comment the very hour her daughter was taken off a ventilator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’m in Livingston completely broken and this bull headed governor has the gall to say that,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pressure from parents recently caused the governor to acknowledge there are flaws with the medical marijuana program. He blamed it on the dispensaries, saying the businesses are not offering edibles because there is no profit in it for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Yale Galanter, the attorney for Garden State Dispensary in Woodbridge, N.J., says the company is already selling edibles in Colorado.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If the state of New Jersey said to us, listen Garden State Dispensary, you’re allowed to sell edibles tomorrow morning, I could do that,” Galanter said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parents have complained that dispensaries are turning patients away, and taking too long to fill prescriptions.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donna Leusner with the New Jersey Department of Health says it’s up to the dispensaries to decide what they sell and who they sell it to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Alternative Treatment Centers are independent, nonprofit businesses regulated by the New Jersey Department of Health. The Department is not involved in their day to day business decisions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The health department says it’s working with the dispensaries on the process they will use to make edible products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bringing Edibles from Other States&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, some parents, like Jennie Stormes, are learning how to turn marijuana buds into butter and oils their children can consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At her home in Hope, N.J., Stormes takes a mason jar off the shelf in the refrigerator where most people keep their butter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style="float: left; margin: 10px;" src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/MarijuanaButter.JPG" alt="" width="350" height="250"&gt;“It smells like marijuana,” she says as she opens the jar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It looks just like a butter, has the consistency of butter, it is butter, it’s just green. It’s been infused with the medicinal marijuana.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She makes it for her 14-year-old son Jackson. He’s had life threatening seizures since he was 4-months-old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His mom says he cannot learn to smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He watches Barney and plays with picture books. He doesn’t talk but he does pace around the house shouting, “Good morning, Jax,” every few minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jax has had parts of his brain removed in an effort to stop the seizures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has failed 50 different combinations of psychoactive drugs with severe side effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergency drugs to stop a seizure could also stop his heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I was at a point where I was very desperate with my son and I had nothing to lose and everything to gain because my son was dying,” Stromes said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Jax went on marijuana a year-and-a-half ago, his seizures have gone from about 10 or 20 every day, to one every couple weeks. They now last a few minutes instead of hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jax is off all pharmaceuticals except for one, and for the first time in his life Stormes says her son is no longer “stoned.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She buys a bud that is low in THC — the element in marijuana that gives the high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But she can’t get enough of it. The state only allows her to purchase two ounces every month. That’s about 10 days worth of edible medicine for Jax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So she has marijuana oil brought in.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s not safe,” Stormes said. “I run the risk of being arrested every day because his medicine comes from California.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jax is a dual resident of California and New Jersey and is a medical marijuana card holder in both states.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stormes says the marijuana from California is better than any marijuana she can get in New Jersey. The THC level is less than 1 percent. It’s impossible to get high. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raman Sankar, a pediatric neurologist at Mattel Children’s Hospital at UCLA, treats children with the same syndrome as Jax. He says he’s hearing compelling results from families using medicinal marijuana. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He will be one of several investigators in the country to study its effectiveness among epilepsy patients. But he’s reluctant to prescribe marijuana himself until there’s more data on its safety and efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a little like early 19-20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century medicine,” Sankar said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When I was very, very young in my grandfather’s office in rural India they would make up medication. They'd buy raw ingredients and put together concoctions and colorful liquids and, ‘this is your cough mixture,’ they would say,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sankar says there’s no consistency in the marijuana products. Every dispensary makes their own. They don’t go through the FDA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But parents say the FDA-approved drugs aren’t stopping the seizures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when Sabina died, it convinced others that bringing marijuana across state lines is worth the risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sabina’s mom wishes she had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Getting probation for weed doesn’t scare me. Seizures scare me,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Losing my daughter, worst fear I ever had came true," she said. "I’d sit in prison my entire life if she was still here and on cannabis. I would sit in there gladly. But it was too late.” &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/news/news20140417_medical_marijuana_intro.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="chris_christie"></category><category term="christietracker"></category><category term="crime"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="legislature"></category><category term="local_news"></category><category term="marijuana"></category><category term="medical_marijuana"></category><category term="new_jersey"></category><category term="news"></category></entry><entry><title>Last Chance Foods: Flowers You Can Eat
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/last-chance-foods-flowers-you-can-eat/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-17T16:52:46-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/last-chance-foods-flowers-you-can-eat/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ignore the recent chilly blast of weather, spring is here and so are the blooms. Some of those cheerful flowers aren’t just a treat for the eye—they’re tasty, too. Violas are one edible variety. They’re part of the pansy family, and you can find them at farmers markets now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Fresh flowers are one of the few things that you’ll be hard pressed to find packaged in a store,” says &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Annie+Novak"&gt;Annie Novak&lt;/a&gt;, a rooftop farmer and co-founder of &lt;a href="http://rooftopfarms.org/"&gt;Eagle Street Rooftop Farm&lt;/a&gt;. “So really the pleasure of eating a flower garnish is you can almost guarantee it’s coming right out of a garden nearby.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novak is also the manager of the New York Botanical Garden’s &lt;a href="http://www.nybg.org/education/edible-academy/"&gt;Edible Academy&lt;/a&gt;, where she works to teach children about the connection between gardening and healthy eating. She points out that, as a children’s educator, edible flowers like violas are an easy way to get kids interested in food. Even simple tricks like floral ice cubes (directions below) can be an incentive for them to stay hydrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the adults, the appeal of eating violas is also simple. “They’re one of the easiest ways to make a very simple dish appear quite fancy,” says Novak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Naturally, not all flowers are edible, so do your research before chomping away. (The New York Botanical Garden has &lt;a href="http://www.nybg.org/gardens/home-gardening/tips/edible-flowers.php"&gt;this list for reference&lt;/a&gt;.) Novak advises the sensible step of planting only nontoxic flowers if you’re introducing your kids to edible blooms. She recommends avoiding things like angel's trumpet, which reportedly causes hallucinations. Sound advice, that. &lt;img style="float: right; margin: 10px;" src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/NYBG_Annie_Novak_by_Victor_Chu.jpg" alt="" width="280"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Photo: &lt;em&gt;Annie Novak with Julia and Janine Gayenelo at the New York Botanical Garden&lt;/em&gt;/&lt;strong&gt;Victor Chu&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the rest of us worried about ingesting unexpected chemicals or pesticides, Novak recommends starting the flowers from seed or asking your plant purveyor if they were treated in any way with chemicals. “And if it was, you can wash it or pick off the flowers before you start to eat them,” Novak adds. “Picking off the flowers will actually encourage more blooms and more growth so it will work out the best.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Violas should be a hit with kids and adults alike, since they’re sweet and have a mild floral taste. “The texture is a really important part of the taste of flowers because the petals themselves are very soft,” adds Novak. “It’s a weird combination but [they have] like a crystalline, velvety, melt-in-your-mouth kind of texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're looking to keep your little ones entertained this weekend, The New York Botanical Garden's &lt;a href="http://www.nybg.org/exhibitions/2014/festivals/food-festival/april-culinary-kids-food-festival.php"&gt;Culinary Kids Food Festival&lt;/a&gt; has a variety of food and plant focused activities going on through Monday, April 21. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Floral Ice Cubes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ice cube tray: larger sizes work better because the ice will melt less quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boiled, distilled water: This makes for the clearest-looking ice cubes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edible flowers (such as violas), enough for each ice cube&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fill the trays ⅓ of the way with the boiled, distilled water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Place the flowers face down in the water and freeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill ⅔ of the way with more of the water, freeze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fill to the top and freeze.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/news/news20140418_lcf_viola.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="annie_novak"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="kids"></category><category term="last_chance_foods"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="new_york_botanical_garden"></category><category term="recipe"></category><category term="violas"></category></entry><entry><title>Should We Teach Children Entrepreneurship?
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/should-we-teach-kids-entrepreneurship/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-17T15:23:48-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/should-we-teach-kids-entrepreneurship/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Can you teach entrepreneurship? It's an idea The Takeaway &lt;a href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/can-you-teach-entrepreneurship/"&gt;has explored before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We're very confident that this can be taught," Bill Aulet, managing director of the Martin Trust Center for MIT Entrepreneurship, said on this program. "I think the problem is that while demand is surging, the supply of high-quality entrepreneurship education is not meeting that demand. Entrepreneurship has not been taken seriously and there's not a huge body of work out there on it. It's been more of kind of a black art.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aulet teaches college students how to build their own businesses. But what if the process started with even younger students? High schoolers or middle schoolers, or even younger? What if instead of waiting to talk about entrepreneurship in college classrooms, students started out really young?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cristal Glangchai&lt;/strong&gt; is founder of VentureLab in San Antonio, which offers a weeklong course for 5- to 7-year-old girls called Girl Startup 101—a course that pushes little girls to unleash their inner start-up maven. Six year-old &lt;strong&gt;Isabel Mendler&lt;/strong&gt; has attended Girl Startup twice. &lt;strong&gt;Frederick Mendler&lt;/strong&gt;, her father, knows a thing or two about start-ups as the co-founder of a recruitment-technology business called TrueAbility. He hopes his little girl will develop an entrepreneurial streak also. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"When I was teaching at the university level, I found that it was really hard for me to get a lot of students, and girls in particular, into the entrepreneurship program," says Cristal, who is the mother of two 5-year-old daughters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cristal says she found that the college women she was teaching didn't have the confidence to pursue entrepreneurship and were intimidated by the male-dominated industry. After that experience, she says she wanted to instill the entrepreneurial spirit in girls much earlier on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I think that kids, even before they go to elementary school, need to learn that they can do anything," she says. "They can create, they can go into science, and they can go into technology. And just having that confidence to believe that they can turn their ideas into products, services or even start companies before they get into school."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Isabel, early-life entrepreneurship is about testing the waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You sort of can start your own business by like getting some friends and sort of practicing and then you can start your own business," the six-year-old says, who adds she would like to make a duct tape craft business, designing things like purses out of duct tape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Isabel's father Frederick, he sees programs like Girl Startup 101 as a way to teach his daughter independence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"As a co-founder of a start-up and being an entrepreneur myself, it's actually tough to influence her in the things I want to—I want to build independence and teach her the things that I've learned in maybe the only last 10 or 15 years of my life," he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Fredrick says that he was skeptical about teaching entrepreneurship to a six-year-old, he says the Girl Startup 101 program allowed his daughter to brainstorm ideas and make creative products that were relevant to their age group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I was really proud," he says. "And those are things that I want her to learn at a young age so that they just become second nature for her in life."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Cristal, this all about equipping young girls with the tools they need to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The main thing I want them to have is confidence so that they can go out and take an idea and turn it into a product by doing market research, talking with as many customers as possible, really validating their idea, creating a prototype, coming up with a business model and then actually being able to present themselves and pitch confidently in front of investors," she says. "The whole entrepreneurial skill set."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far Isabel has pitched to two great investors—her mom and dad—but says she wouldn't take no for an answer if she were turned by other investors, something that Fredrick says is the goal of the program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It's about her understanding that there's options and opportunities, and that she doesn't always have to rely on other people," he says. "The future is hers to define, and that resilience is there too—to try something and fail, and get back up and learn from that and continue on."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway041714-startups2.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="business"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="innovation"></category><category term="kids"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="technology"></category><category term="women"></category></entry><entry><title>Should We Teach Kids Entrepreneurship? | From Wall Street to the Trailer Park | Rosa Parks' Legacy is Trapped in a New York Warehouse
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/the-takeaway-2014-04-17/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/the-takeaway-2014-04-17/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lethal Clashes Mark Start of Ukraine Peace Talks | Hundreds Remain Lost After South Korea Ferry Crash | Deportations Dropped 43% in Last 5 Years | Rosa Parks' Legacy is Trapped in a New York Warehouse | From Wall Street to the Trailer Park | Should We Teach Children Entrepreneurship?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/ttp/ttp041714.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="business"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="civil_rights"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="entrepreneurship"></category><category term="entrepreneurship_and_innovation"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="finance"></category><category term="history"></category><category term="innovation"></category><category term="kids"></category><category term="local_news"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="rosa_parks"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>Parenting Strategies for the Digital Age
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/parenting-digital-age/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-04-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/parenting-digital-age/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Shhhh...don’t tell the kids, but grown-ups are mostly just making up the rules as they go along, especially when it comes to technology and child rearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week on New Tech City, we give you a chance to sit and consider where YOU stand on screen-time, video games, and social media for our next generation. Four experts with radically different points of view, ranging from banning all devices, to full digital immersion, present their arguments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus we hear parents’ deepest fears and what the kids themselves think is the right way to help them grow up healthy and confident in the digital age. There is a happy balance between technology adoption, addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us as we try to find it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this show we mention two past stories we've covered. Find more about &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/reasons-why-this-family-who-built-computer-just-play-minecraft/" target="_blank"&gt;how and why to build Minecraft computer with your kids&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/312524-smartphones-at-summer-camp-revisited/" target="_blank"&gt;that summer camp experiment with cell phones.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/newtechcity/newtechcity20140402pod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="parenting"></category><category term="science"></category><category term="technology"></category></entry><entry><title>Why Being Poor Is Bad for Your Health
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/why-being-poor-bad-your-health/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/why-being-poor-bad-your-health/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the second part of this week's installment of Strapped: A Look at Poverty in America, Dr. &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Benard+Dreyer"&gt;Benard Dreyer&lt;/a&gt;, Professor of Pediatrics at New York University School of Medicine, and Dr. &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Peter+Muennig"&gt;Peter Muennig&lt;/a&gt;, Associate Professor of Health Policy and Management at Columbia’s Mailman School of Public Health, discuss the impacts poverty has on cognitive development and overall health, especially in children, and what policies could improve health and mental health of children and families.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate033114dpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="poverty"></category><category term="public_health"></category><category term="science"></category></entry><entry><title>How Poverty Affects Mental Health
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/how-poverty-affects-mental-health/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/how-poverty-affects-mental-health/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the first part of this week’s installment of our series &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/shows/lopate/series/strapped-look-poverty-america" target="_blank"&gt;Strapped: A Look at Poverty in America&lt;/a&gt;, we’re finding out how poverty affects mental health. Epidemiologist Dr. &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Jane+Costello"&gt;Jane Costello&lt;/a&gt; examines the impact poverty has on mental health, especially among children. She tells us about her &lt;a href="https://devepi.duhs.duke.edu/gsms.html" target="_blank"&gt;Great Smoky Mountains Study&lt;/a&gt;—a longitudinal study of more than 1,400 children in North Carolina—looking at who gets mental illness, who gets treatment, and how rising out of poverty improves the mental health of children and families. Dr. Costello is Associate Director for Research, Center for Child &amp;amp; Family Policy  and Professor of Medical Psychology in the Department of Psychiatry and  Behavioral Sciences at Duke University.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate033114cpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="mental_health"></category><category term="poverty"></category><category term="science"></category></entry><entry><title>Scientific Parenting
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/scientific-parenting/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-19T10:48:07-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/scientific-parenting/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Dalton+Conley"&gt;Dalton Conley&lt;/a&gt;, University Professor of the social sciences at NYU, chair of the Children and Youth Section of the American Sociological Association and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1476712654/wnycorg-20/"&gt;Parentology: Everything You Wanted to Know about the Science of Raising Children but Were Too Exhausted to Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, turned to the latest scientific papers for advice on parenting.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl031914cpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="books"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="parenting"></category><category term="science"></category></entry><entry><title>Pushpa Basnet, CNN Hero of the Year 
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/pushpa-basnet-cnn-hero-year/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/pushpa-basnet-cnn-hero-year/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The 2012 CNN Hero of the Year &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Pushpa+Basnet"&gt;Pushpa Basnet&lt;/a&gt; is an internationally lauded social worker and founder of the groundbreaking development center for children in her native Nepal who would otherwise grow up behind bars with their incarcerated parents. She’s also the subject of the award-winning documentary "&lt;a href="http://www.waitingformamu.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Waiting For Mamu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;" She discusses her work, along with the documentary’s director, &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Thomas+Morgan"&gt;Thomas Morgan&lt;/a&gt;, and producer &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Angela+Bernard+Thomas"&gt;Angela Bernard Thomas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate031214dpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="documentary"></category><category term="film"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="nepal"></category><category term="social_workers"></category></entry><entry><title>Childhood Amnesia: Why Do Some Memories Fade and Others Don't?
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/new-findings-why-childhood-memories-fade/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-23T13:15:21-05:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/new-findings-why-childhood-memories-fade/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Why is it that you can recall some memories like your second grade little league tournament, but not others like your sixth birthday party?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New research out of Emory University has identified a crucial turning point in memory development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists have found that by age seven, childhood amnesia begins to take effect, in which early memories are forgotten at a faster rate, and sometimes lost entirely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining The Takeaway to explain the science behind our childhood memories is &lt;strong&gt;Patricia Bauer&lt;/strong&gt;, professor of psychology at Emory University and lead author on this study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think back—what is your very first memory from childhood? How old were you and what can you remember? Tell us in the comments. Check out the video of our Host John Hockenberry asking his own young son to remember back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/B_3WRtoTWn0" width="560"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway012314-memories.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="brain"></category><category term="childhood"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="memory"></category><category term="parenting"></category><category term="science"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>Margie Stern on Helping Underprivileged Children
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/margie-stern-unsung-hero/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-01-10T11:23:10-05:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/margie-stern-unsung-hero/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Margie+Stern"&gt;Margie Stern&lt;/a&gt; owner of the Manhattan store A Time for Children, which donates 100% of the profits to the Children's Aid Society of New York, discusses her work helping underprivileged children get a leg up in life through education. She's joined by &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Catherine+Aponte"&gt;Catherine Aponte&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Blanca+More+Recinos"&gt;Blanca More Recinos&lt;/a&gt;, both part of A Time for Children's training program who have gone on to get college degrees.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate011014bpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="business"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="poverty"></category></entry><entry><title>The Children's Village
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/childrens-village/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-12-06T11:36:35-05:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/childrens-village/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Dr.+Jeremy+Kohomban"&gt;Dr. Jeremy Kohomban&lt;/a&gt;, director of &lt;a href="http://childrensvillage.org/"&gt;The Children's Village&lt;/a&gt;, talks about the organization's transformation and their role keeping at-risk kids at home instead of in residential programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl120613epod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="non_profit"></category></entry><entry><title>Where Is Your Mother? A Child Custody Case in California
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/where-your-mother-child-custody-case-california/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-12-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/where-your-mother-child-custody-case-california/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Rachel+Aviv"&gt;Rachel Aviv&lt;/a&gt;, staff writer for &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;, recounts the story of Niveen Ismail, a mother whose young son was put up for adoption by the state of California despite her multi-year fight to prove she was fit to remain his parent. She writes about the case in her article “&lt;a href="http://www.newyorker.com/reporting/2013/12/02/131202fa_fact_aviv" target="_blank"&gt;Where Is Your Mother&lt;/a&gt;” is in the December 2 issue of &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate120513apod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="child_custody"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="foster_care"></category><category term="life"></category></entry><entry><title>Caryl Stern, President and CEO of the U.S. Fund for UNICEF
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/caryl-stern-president-and-ceo-us-fund-unicef/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/caryl-stern-president-and-ceo-us-fund-unicef/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Caryl+Stern"&gt;Caryl Stern&lt;/a&gt;, President and CEO of the U.S. Fund for UNICEF, talks about her travels around the world and the powerful and sometimes counter-intuitive lessons she’s learned about life. &lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1250026245/wnycorg-20/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;I Believe in Zero: Learning from the World’s Children&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;reflects her—and UNICEF's—mission to reduce the number of preventable deaths of children under the age of five from 19,000 each day to zero. From Bangladesh, Mozambique, earthquake-ravaged Haiti, the Brazilian Amazon, she weaves together history, an account of the humanitarian crises at issue, and depictions of the people she meets on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate111813dpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="poverty"></category><category term="unicef"></category></entry><entry><title>Israel; Capturing Tribal Cultures on Film; Daniel Menaker's Life at The New Yorker; UNICEF
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/the-leonard-lopate-show-2013-11-18/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/the-leonard-lopate-show-2013-11-18/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Haaretz &lt;/em&gt;columnist &lt;strong&gt;Ari Shavit&lt;/strong&gt; looks at Israel's past and present dilemmas. Globe-trotting photographer &lt;strong&gt;Jimmy Nelson&lt;/strong&gt; talks about capturing the ways of life, art, and traditions of tribal cultures around the world. And &lt;strong&gt;Daniel Menaker&lt;/strong&gt; talks about his career at &lt;em&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/em&gt;, where he began as a fact-checker and later became an editor at the beloved magazine.&lt;strong&gt; Caryl Stern&lt;/strong&gt;, the president and CEO of the US Fund for UNICEF talks about what she’s learned from children around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="memoir"></category></entry><entry><title>Selected Shorts:  Child's Play
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/selected-shorts-childs-play/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-11-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/selected-shorts-childs-play/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The stories on this program, hosted by Wyatt Cenac, feature two exceptional children and a nervous parent.   &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;“Solomon’s Big Day,” by performance artist Toure, follows a child prodigy as he tries to paint a masterpiece and escape pretentious adults.   Toure is the host of “Hiphop Shop” and “On the Record” (on the Fuse TV channel) and co-host of “The Cycle” on MSNBC. He teaches at New York University’s Tisch School of the Arts.  His published works include &lt;em&gt;The Portable Promised Land: Stories&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Soul City: A Novel&lt;/em&gt;, and the essay collection &lt;em&gt;Never Drank the Kool-Aid&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reader Daniel Alexander Jones is also a performance artist, and playwright.  He is the head of the playwriting program at Fordham  University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our second story, “Lars Farf, Excessively Fearful Father and Husband,” George Saunders imagines a father who goes to extremes to protect his family—from absolutely everything, including life itself.  Among Saunders many honors are a MacArthur “Genius Grant” and inclusion in &lt;em&gt;Time Magazine’&lt;/em&gt;s “100 Most Influential People” list.   His most recent collection is &lt;em&gt;Tenth of December&lt;/em&gt;.  “Lars Farf, Excessively Fearful Father and Husband,” is read by Tony Award-winner James Naughton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our final story, “Charles,” is an uncharacteristically light-hearted tale by horror maven Shirley Jackson (“The Lottery,” &lt;em&gt;The Haunting of Hill House&lt;/em&gt;).  In it, a precocious kindergartener horrifies his parents all right, but it’s with tales of the class delinquent.  “Charles,” is read by Lois Smith, whose many film, television and theatre credits include performances in “Twister,” “True Blood,” and “The Trip to Bountiful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“&lt;/strong&gt;Solomon’s Big Day,” by Toure, performed by Daniel Alexander Jones&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Lars Farf, Excessively Fearful Father and Husband,” by George Saunders, performed by James Naughton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Charles,” by Shirley Jackson, performed by Lois Smith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SELECTED SHORTS theme is David Peterson's “That's the Deal,” performed by the Deardorf/Peterson Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For additional works featured on SELECTED SHORTS, please visit &lt;a href="http://www.symphonyspace.org/genres/seriesPage.php?seriesId=71&amp;amp;genreId=4"&gt;http://www.symphonyspace.org/genres/seriesPage.php?seriesId=71&amp;amp;genreId=4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re interested in your response to these programs.  Please comment on this site or visit &lt;a href="http://www.selectedshorts.org/"&gt;www.selectedshorts.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And for more thoughts on the stories in SHORTS, check out literary commentator Hannah Tinti’s site at &lt;a href="http://hannahtinti.com/"&gt;http://hannahtinti.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="books"></category><category term="childhood"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="daniel_alexander_jones"></category><category term="george_saunders"></category><category term="james_naughton"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="shirley_jackson"></category><category term="short_stories"></category><category term="symphony_space"></category><category term="toure"></category><category term="wnyc"></category><category term="wyatt_cenac"></category></entry><entry><title>John Lithgow's Plays Children's Music 'Right Next To The Zoo'
</title><link href="http://soundcheck.wnyc.org/story/john-lithgow-zoo/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-25T15:23:49-04:00</updated><id>http://soundcheck.wnyc.org/story/john-lithgow-zoo/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=John+Lithgow"&gt;John Lithgow&lt;/a&gt;’s acting career has included award-winning roles in the television show &lt;em&gt;3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; Rock from The Sun&lt;/em&gt;, the Broadway musical &lt;em&gt;Sweet Smell Of Success&lt;/em&gt;, and even as a serial killer for a season in the Showtime series &lt;em&gt;Dexter&lt;/em&gt;. But John Lithgow has another career: children’s author. His latest book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Never-Play-Music-Right-Next/dp/1442467436"&gt;Never Play Music Right Next To The Zoo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;tells the story of a boy who goes to see an orchestra performance — and is joined by some unexpected musical guests. The book includes a recording of Lithgow singing the tale, backed by the virtuosic animals of his young protagonist’s imagination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Lithgow discusses his new book and his long career in the &lt;em&gt;Soundcheck&lt;/em&gt; studio.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h3&gt;Interview Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;John Lithgow, on&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;whether he used his own children as a focus group for his books:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I certainly began entertaining kids when I had my own kids — my oldest is 41 years old, so I’ve been doing it a long time. But it started becoming a big deal when I became famous through &lt;em&gt;3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; Rock From The Sun&lt;/em&gt; and I got an opportunity to make albums and do Carnegie Hall concerts. By that time I was a terrible embarrassment to my kids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On using his role as a serial killer on Dexter to play against what’s expected of him:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any time you get the chance to upend people’s expectations, you can manipulate them in all sorts of ways. I had the same experience when I first did &lt;em&gt;3&lt;sup&gt;rd&lt;/sup&gt; Rock&lt;/em&gt;, and nobody had seen me clown around like that. Nobody had seen me be funny. And just when they’re completely accustomed to me being funny and domesticated, I play a hideous, terrifying serial killer, whose cover is being a very normal, almost inconspicuous man.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On playing against type as a &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=I6_C4fK94-c&amp;amp;list=PL5E38FC017CFD16E4"&gt;preacher rallying against rock and roll in &lt;em&gt;Footloose&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a matter of fact, when we shot that film, it was me and &lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001848/"&gt;Dianne Wiest&lt;/a&gt; and a whole bunch of young, early 20-year-olds, if not teenagers, in Provo, Utah, a fairly straight-laced town. And Diane and I were the wild ones! We almost got in some serious trouble there. I do remember there was a memo posted the morning after we all swam nude in the motel pool. They’re still talking about it in Provo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/soundcheck/soundcheck102513apod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="books"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="television"></category></entry><entry><title>John Lithgow's Bestial Orchestra; John Paul Keith Plays Live; 'Losers Take All'
</title><link href="http://soundcheck.wnyc.org/story/john-lithgow-john-paul-keith-losers-take-all/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://soundcheck.wnyc.org/story/john-lithgow-john-paul-keith-losers-take-all/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this episode: &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=John+Lithgow"&gt;John Lithgow&lt;/a&gt; portrayed a goofy alien on &lt;em&gt;3rd Rock From The Sun&lt;/em&gt;," provided the haughty voice for Shrek’s Lord Farquaad and played a serial killer on the Showtime series &lt;em&gt;Dexter&lt;/em&gt;. He also won a Tony Award for his role in in the musical adaptation of &lt;em&gt;Sweet Smell Of Success&lt;/em&gt;. Lithgow talks about his latest project, a children's book and album called&lt;em&gt; Never Play Music Right Next To The Zoo&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus: Roots rocker &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=John+Paul+Keith"&gt;John Paul Keith&lt;/a&gt; casts the city of Memphis in a starring role for his new album, &lt;em&gt;Memphis Circa 3 AM.&lt;/em&gt; He plays live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And: The new comedy film &lt;em&gt;Losers Take All &lt;/em&gt;explores the world of '80s punk through the eyes of a fictional band. Director &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Alex+Steyermark"&gt;Alex Steyermark&lt;/a&gt; joins John Paul Keith, who contributed music to the film, to talk about the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/soundcheck/soundcheck102513pod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="books"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="film"></category><category term="music"></category><category term="punk"></category><category term="rock"></category><category term="roots"></category><category term="television"></category></entry><entry><title>“American Promise,” a Documentary
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/american-promise-documentary/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-17T10:52:01-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/american-promise-documentary/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Directors &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Joe+Brewster"&gt;Joe Brewster&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Michele+Stephenson"&gt;Michele Stephenson&lt;/a&gt; discuss their documentary, “&lt;a href="http://www.americanpromise.org/" target="_blank"&gt;American Promise&lt;/a&gt;,” which spans 13 formative years in the lives of two young black boys, their son Idris and his best friend Seun, as they navigate an elite New York City prep school. The environment is still largely segregated by race, class and culture. It follows both boys as they face challenges at school and the pressures of growing up. “American Promise” opens at the &lt;a href="http://www.ifccenter.com/" target="_blank"&gt;IFC Center&lt;/a&gt; and at the &lt;a href="http://www.filmlinc.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Film Society of Lincoln Center&lt;/a&gt; on October 18.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Brewster and/or Michele Stephenson will be appearing in person and answering questions at the following screenings at IFC:&lt;br&gt;Friday, 10/18, at 7:00&lt;br&gt;Saturday, 10/19, at 1:10, 4:05, 7:00&lt;br&gt;Sunday, 10/20, at 1:10, 4:05, 7:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Brewster and/or Michele Stephenson will be appearing in person and answering questions at the following screenings at Film Society of Lincoln Center:&lt;br&gt;Friday, 10/18, at 8:00&lt;br&gt;Saturday, 10/19, at 2:00, 5:00, 8:00&lt;br&gt;Sunday, 10/20, at 2:00, 5:00, 8:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate101713bpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="documentary"></category><category term="film"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="new_york_city"></category></entry><entry><title>Liz Neumark on Farm to Table Seasonal Recipes
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/liz-neumark-farm-totable-seasonal-recipes/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-10-04T12:18:29-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/liz-neumark-farm-totable-seasonal-recipes/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Liz+Neumark"&gt;Liz Neumark&lt;/a&gt; discusses founding &lt;a href="http://katchkiefarm.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Katchkie Farm&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://sylviacenter.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Sylvia Center&lt;/a&gt;, where children learn firsthand where fresh food comes from—how to grow it, how to harvest it, and how to cook with it. Her new book &lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0307595137/wnycorg-20/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sylvia’s Table: Fresh, Seasonal Recipes from Our Farm to Your Table &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;brings these lessons and recipes from the farm to home kitchens. It’s a cookbook for families, featuring recipes from friends like chefs like Michael Romano of Union Square Cafe and Jonathan Waxman of Barbuto; culinary experts including &lt;em&gt;Food &amp;amp; Wine&lt;/em&gt;’s Dana Cowin; cookbook authors Giuliano Bugialli, Rozanne Gold, Deborah Madison, and Sara Moulton.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate100413apod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="cooking"></category><category term="farming"></category><category term="food"></category><category term="food_fridays"></category><category term="recipes"></category></entry><entry><title>Human Made From Paper Eats Pepperoni Pizza — And Lives! 
</title><link href="http://www.radiolab.org/story/314072-human-made-paper-eats-pepperoni-pizza-and-lives/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-22T10:36:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.radiolab.org/blogs/radiolab-blogland/2013/aug/22/human-made-paper-eats-pepperoni-pizza-and-lives/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.npr.org/assets/img/2013/08/21/human-body.gif" alt="" width="620"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember those frog transparencies from biology class? The ones in the  textbook where you could lay the circulatory system on top of the  digestive system on top of the skeleton system? Here's that same idea,  updated and gently presented for kids, from a company called &lt;a href="http://www.tinybop.com/"&gt;Tinybop&lt;/a&gt;. This  time, the layers are cut from colored paper, exquisitely designed by  Kelli Anderson. And this time (unlike that sadly frozen frog) it moves!  Watch it eat a pizza slice ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="465" src="http://player.vimeo.com/video/72393668?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff" width="620"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Anything that a real body does, this body does," Kelli &lt;a href="http://kellianderson.com/blog/2013/08/illustrating-tinybops-1st-app/"&gt;writes on her blog&lt;/a&gt;. "It eats, digests, pumps blood, gets sick, burps, runs in place, you name it, all at multiple zoom levels."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So  if the user (presumed to be a 5-year-old, I'm guessing, but who's  checking?) wants to look at a heart up close, she can zoom in and see  details ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/2heart_custom.jpg" alt="" width="620"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Courtesy of Kelli Anderson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;... or should she be wondering how an arm or leg manage to swing, there are balls and sockets ready for inspection ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.npr.org/assets/img/2013/08/21/ball-socket.gif" alt="" width="620"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tinybop's &lt;a href="http://tinybop.com/products"&gt;Human Body App&lt;/a&gt; just presents you with a body (there's a body menu: boy,  girl, choose your race). That's it. There are no goals, no "levels," no  rewards. It's just there to be looked at, explored. I like that. I also  like how Kelli cuts paper. When she puts down her scissors, our wet,  mucky, smelly bodies seem suddenly fit for angels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://www.wnyc.org/i/raw/1/31-cut_custom.jpg" alt="" width="620"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Courtesy of Kelli Anderson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="app"></category><category term="biology"></category><category term="body"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="health"></category><category term="human body"></category><category term="kids"></category></entry><entry><title>FTC Complaint: Children's Apps Not Really Educational
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/311756-complaint-ftc-about-apps-claiming-be-educational/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-12T13:46:26-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/2013/aug/12/complaint-ftc-about-apps-claiming-be-educational/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="http://www.commercialfreechildhood.org/advocates-urge-ftc-stop-deceptive-marketing-educational-baby-apps"&gt;complaint&lt;/a&gt; filed with the &lt;a href="http://www.ftc.gov/"&gt;Federal Trade Commission&lt;/a&gt; last week claims that many mobile apps &lt;a href="http://bits.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/08/07/childrens-advocacy-group-faults-learning-apps-for-babies/"&gt;claiming to be educational&lt;/a&gt; are not. The &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/commercialfree"&gt;Campaign for a Commercial-Free Childhood&lt;/a&gt; filed the complaint against Fisher-Price "Laugh and Learn" apps and Open Solutions, a software developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advocacy group argues that screen-play can even be harmful if it comes at the expense of human interaction with family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is this actually a new debate?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many of us were planted down in front of the TV on a Saturday morning, so that mom and dad could get some quiet time without having us nag them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to the history of children's media, what is the line between education and distraction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.iqjournals.com/sample-page/about-melissa/"&gt;Dr. Melissa Morgenlander&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is an educational consultant and curriculum developer. She founded the blog &lt;a href="http://www.iqjournals.com/"&gt;IQ Journals&lt;/a&gt;, where she shares her experiences using technology with her own children. She joins us to discuss the evolution of children's media and what actually constitutes an educational app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stay up to date with &lt;/em&gt;The Takeaway&lt;em&gt;—&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thetakeaway"&gt;become a Facebook fan&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheTakeaway"&gt; follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway081213-apps.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="apps"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="technology"></category><category term="television"></category></entry><entry><title>In Harm's Way: Remembering the Life of Kamau Chandler
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/310210-in-harms-way-remembering-the-life-of-kamau-chandler/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-08-02T04:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/articles/wnyc-news/2013/aug/02/in-harms-way-remembering-the-life-of-kamau-chandler/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Seventeen-year-old Kamau Chandler was known for his grace with physical pursuits like rowing, skiing and martial arts. His family credits him with popularizing skateboarding in the section of Coney  Island where he lived. The soon- to-be high school senior was shot early on July 27 on Fulton Street after leaving a party with friends.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;His father, 40-year-old Cheo Chandler, slouched on his couch in their apartment thinking back to when Kamau was born.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The first time I saw him he just looked at me and cried,” recalled the grieving dad. “He looked almost sad for me because he knew my heart was feeling so strong about him…the look on his face was almost like he was giving me comfort.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name Kamau in Swahili means quiet warrior. Although most of the time the teen was called by his nickname, Mau Mau. Kamau lived with Chandler for most of his life, since he was a toddler. The two looked alike - the same warm brown skin and long limbs. They also had a similar look in their eyes: kind and curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kamau grew up mostly a daddy's boy, and as he got older, Chandler said his son became paternal towards his younger siblings, especially his three younger half sisters who live across town in Bedford Stuyvesant with his mom. He said the last time Kamau asked for money, it was to buy shoes for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chandler teared up remembering his son’s generosity. “He said pop…I was able to get the oldest two [girls] sneakers….but I’m short.” So he asked his dad to help him cover the cost of the last pair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kamau’s great aunt, Jewel Chandler, said she was also overwhelmed by Kamau’s generosity when he escorted her to a street festival in Fort Greene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"He said very shyly, in sort of a meek way…if I buy you a piece of artwork, would you like it, would you keep it?” said Chandler, fondly recalling the print of African dancers that hangs on her wall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I always told him his heart was too big for his body,” said his father, thinking about his son’s last night. He said apart from a few skirmishes, Kamau was a good kid who did his best to stay out of trouble. He believes his protective nature may have contributed to his death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He'd always be willing to go out and take care of people, even when they weren't willing to take care of themselves, which of course could put him in harms way."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chandler said detectives told him that when Kamau was shot, he was defending his friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His funeral service will be held on Saturday afternoon, August 3, at the Frank R.  Bell Funeral home in Brooklyn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;WNYC is profiling the life of every child in the city killed by gunfire in our series &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border: 0px none; outline: none 0px; font-size: 13px; vertical-align: baseline; background-color: transparent; color: #000000; text-decoration: none; word-wrap: break-word; background-position: initial initial; background-repeat: initial initial;" href="http://www.wnyc.org/tags/in_harms_way/"&gt;In Harm’s Way&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ONE YEAR LATER, KAMAU'S GREAT AUNT REFLECTS: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Kamau was killed, my family has not been and will never be the same. Although I live in another state and don't have daily contact with Kamau's father and other family members, I can still hear and feel the sense of devastation when I call or when I visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their pain and grief is palpable. There will always be a big void that his absence will create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I think people will remember most about Kamau is his honesty, generosity of spirit and loyalty. He was an amazing person who, although he didn't get a chance to realize his full potential, did in fact touch many lives in a very positive way. Over 300 people attended his funeral. Many took the podium to say how much they loved him and will miss him. This outpouring from the community spoke volumes about how Kamau spent the short amount of time he had among us. He had a very successful life that was cut short way too soon.     &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thought that always comes back to me was how dear he was when his grandfather charged him with being my escort around the 2012 African Art Festival in Brooklyn.  Most teenagers would want to be with their friends, they wouldn't take the time to enjoy walking around a festival with an older relative. Kamau truly embraced the opportunity to spend some quality time with me.  He sheepishly asked me if I would like a present he had in mind to give me. It was a piece of artwork that I cherished from the moment he gave it to me and even more now. I'm so grateful we had that time together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the year ahead, my family and I are working on a tribute to Kamau. We are finding some sense of peace in the idea of creating an initiative to help someone else make a better choice than the choice that was made to shoot Kamau.  If it changes one mind, we will be grateful. There's nothing we can do to ever bring Kamau back. He will always be missed.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-Jewel Chandler&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/news/news20130802_ihw_chandler_horan_me.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="brooklyn"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="in_harms_way"></category><category term="kamau_chandler"></category><category term="local_news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="obituaries"></category><category term="shootings"></category></entry><entry><title>What Went Wrong With School Meals in India?
</title><link href="http://www.thetakeaway.org/story/307452-look-what-went-wrong-school-meals-india/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-07-18T13:52:52-04:00</updated><id>http://www.thetakeaway.org/2013/jul/18/look-what-went-wrong-school-meals-india/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's a story that has scandalized India—a free school lunch program for poor children may have &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/07/18/india-school-lunch-deaths_n_3615274.html"&gt;resulted in the death&lt;/a&gt; of more than 20 young students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were contaminated ingredients mixed into the food that produced these fatal results?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, thousands of students are &lt;a href="http://www.rawstory.com/rs/2013/07/18/fearful-indian-schoolchildren-refuse-free-meals/"&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; refusing to touch any of the free meals offered out of understandable fear. But the possibility of deliberate contamination, or at best reckless disregard of the safety of children, is also being &lt;a href="http://parenting.blogs.nytimes.com/2013/07/17/despite-poisoning-deaths-indias-school-lunch-program-must-go-on/"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joining us to discuss this is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://shobanarayan.com/"&gt;Shoba Narayan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; a freelance journalist based in India and author of the memoir "Return to India."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stay up to date with &lt;/em&gt;The Takeaway&lt;em&gt;—&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/thetakeaway"&gt;become a Facebook fan&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/TheTakeaway"&gt; follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/takeaway/takeaway071813-india.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="family"></category><category term="international"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="school"></category></entry><entry><title>The Voices Inside You
</title><link href="http://www.radiolab.org/story/301424-voices-inside-you/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.radiolab.org/2013/jun/27/voices-inside-you/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Where would we be without the voices in our heads? To get at this question, &lt;strong&gt;Charles Fernyhough&lt;/strong&gt; raises another: can children think before they have words? According to Fernyhough, a Russian psychologist named Lev Vygotsky developed a theory about how the words and voices we hear as kids turn from speech outside our heads, to speech inside our heads... and help steer our reasoning and decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, of course, not all the voices echoing inside our skulls are friendly helpers. &lt;strong&gt;Claude Steele&lt;/strong&gt; describes how big an impact negative inner voices can have when we're stressed, and just how powerful words and stereotypes can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Fernyhough, &lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1583333975/radiolabbooks-20/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Thousand Days of Wonder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio4.wnyc.org/radiolab/radiolab062713a.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="charles_fernyhough"></category><category term="children"></category><category term="claude_steele"></category><category term="education"></category><category term="iq"></category><category term="language"></category><category term="test_scores"></category><category term="voices"></category></entry><entry><title>The Joy of Only Children
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/298302-joy-only-children/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-06-12T13:59:17-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/shows/lopate/2013/jun/12/joy-only-children/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Lauren+Sandler"&gt;Lauren Sandler&lt;/a&gt;, an only child and the mother of one, makes a humorous and honest case for being and having an only child. In &lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1451626959/wnycorg-20/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;One and Only: The Freedom of Having an Only Child and the Joy of Being One&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Sandler looks at the larger societal costs of having more than one child and examines what the rise of the single-child family means for our economy, environment, and families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who do you think is better off—only children or children with siblings?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate061213bpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="children"></category><category term="families_and_children"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="society_and_culture"></category></entry></feed>