<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Columbia Journalism Review</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/atom.xml" />
   <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14</id>
    <link rel="service.post" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14" title="Columbia Journalism Review" />
    <updated>2014-07-21T16:54:33Z</updated>
    <subtitle>Columbia Journalism Review: The future of media is here</subtitle>
    
 

<entry>
    <title>Minus proper archives, news outlets risk losing years of backstories forever</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/minus_proper_archives_many_new.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40961" title="Minus proper archives, news outlets risk losing years of backstories forever" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40961</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-21T16:41:40Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-21T16:54:33Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Print stories can be lost, but digital stories last forever, captured for eternity in some nebulous internet ether or on a hard drive in a desk drawer. At least, that&apos;s the vague theory assumed by many producers and consumers of digital news. Once something is posted or backed up, it never really disappears--and if that&apos;s true, archiving digital work seems...</summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Lene Sillesen Print stories can be lost, but digital stories last forever, captured for eternity in some nebulous internet ether or on a hard drive in a desk drawer. At least, that&apos;s the vague theory assumed by many producers and consumers of digital news. Once something is posted or backed up, it never really disappears--and if that&apos;s true, archiving digital work seems...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Twitter and factchecking don&apos;t mix during debates</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/twitter_and_fact-checking_dont.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40960" title="Twitter and factchecking don't mix during debates" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40960</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-21T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-20T23:39:49Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Mitt Romney&rsquo;s assertion in the first 2012 presidential debate - that Obamacare was a government takeover of the healthcare industry - was right in PolitiFact&rsquo;s wheelhouse. And the factchecking organization didn&rsquo;t whiff. With about 10 reporters and editors on duty that night, eyes peeled for both new and oft-repeated factual claims, PolitiFact quickly tweeted a link to its 2010 piece...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By David Uberti <![CDATA[Mitt Romney&rsquo;s assertion in the first 2012 presidential debate - that Obamacare was a government takeover of the healthcare industry - was right in PolitiFact&rsquo;s wheelhouse. And the factchecking organization didn&rsquo;t whiff. With about 10 reporters and editors on duty that night, eyes peeled for both new and oft-repeated factual claims, PolitiFact quickly tweeted a link to its 2010...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Must-reads of the week</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/the_kicker/must-reads_of_the_week_68.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40957" title="Must-reads of the week" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40957</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-18T18:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-19T11:59:25Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Culled from CJR&rsquo;s own stories, plus the frequently updated &ldquo;Must-reads from around the Web,&rdquo; our staff recommendations for the best pieces of journalism (and other miscellany) on the internet, here are your can&rsquo;t-miss must-reads of the past week: Who gets shot in America: What I learned compiling records of carnage for <em>The New York Times </em>(Raw Story) - "A year...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="The Kicker" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By The Editors <![CDATA[Culled from CJR&rsquo;s own stories, plus the frequently updated &ldquo;Must-reads from around the Web,&rdquo; our staff recommendations for the best pieces of journalism (and other miscellany) on the internet, here are your can&rsquo;t-miss must-reads of the past week: Who gets shot in America: What I learned compiling records of carnage for The New York Times (Raw Story) -...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Jose Antonio Vargas&apos; detention shows what &apos;border security&apos; actually entails</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/jose_antonio_vargas_detention.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40958" title="Jose Antonio Vargas' detention shows what 'border security' actually entails" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40958</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-18T18:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-19T12:00:54Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[AUSTIN, TX -- The blurry photograph appears to capture the moment on July 15 when a Border Patrol agent handcuffed Jose Antonio Vargas, a Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist and perhaps the nation's most well-known undocumented immigrant, at a South Texas airport near the border. A video captured by a reporter with the McAllen newspaper, <i>The Monitor</i>, who was evidently positioned a...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Michelle Garcia AUSTIN, TX -- The blurry photograph appears to capture the moment on July 15 when a Border Patrol agent handcuffed Jose Antonio Vargas, a Pulitzer Prize-winning journalist and perhaps the nation&apos;s most well-known undocumented immigrant, at a South Texas airport near the border. A video captured by a reporter with the McAllen newspaper, The Monitor, who was...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Free Press takes its transparency dispute with the University of Michigan to court</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/detroit_free_press_sues_university_michigan_open_meetings_act.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40956" title="&lt;i&gt;Free Press&lt;/i&gt; takes its transparency dispute with the University of Michigan to court" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40956</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-18T15:02:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-18T15:12:32Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Investment commitments and funding of more than $120 million, a property purchase for $12.8 million, construction of a new biological sciences building&mdash;all unanimously approved by the University of Michigan Board of Regents without public deliberation or discussion. Those allegations, among others, are at the heart of a lawsuit filed last week by the <em>Detroit Free Press</em> and the <em>Lansing State...</em>]]></summary>
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Jonathan Peters <![CDATA[Investment commitments and funding of more than $120 million, a property purchase for $12.8 million, construction of a new biological sciences building&mdash;all unanimously approved by the University of Michigan Board of Regents without public deliberation or discussion. Those allegations, among others, are at the heart of a lawsuit filed last week by the Detroit Free Press and the Lansing...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The best and worst of this week&apos;s data journalism</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/data_points/data_darts_and_laurels_nyc_tax.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40951" title="The best and worst of this week's data journalism" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40951</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-18T15:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-18T15:00:23Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Chris Whong--a self-proclaimed urbanist, mapmaker, and data junkie--filed a Freedom of Information request that resulted in acquiring information about all 170 million taxi rides that occurred in New York City in 2013. He created a beautiful map visualization out of it that went live early Monday morning, tracking how many passengers cab drivers picked up for 30 randomly chosen days,...</summary>
    
        <category term="Darts and Laurels" />
    
        <category term="Data Points" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Tanveer Ali Chris Whong--a self-proclaimed urbanist, mapmaker, and data junkie--filed a Freedom of Information request that resulted in acquiring information about all 170 million taxi rides that occurred in New York City in 2013. He created a beautiful map visualization out of it that went live early Monday morning, tracking how many passengers cab drivers picked up for 30 randomly chosen...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>How to check if that viral video is true</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/news_literacy/verifying_ugc.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40953" title="How to check if that viral video is true" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40953</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-18T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-18T14:48:37Z</updated>
    
    <summary> When big news breaks, like the Malaysian airline plane crash in eastern Ukraine on Thursday afternoon, news organizations can&apos;t say much that&apos;s not confirmed. So they, along with hungry news consumers, turn to user-generated content for answers, such as these first two crash-related posts on verified UGC feed FB Newswire: a photo of extra security at Schiphol Airport in...</summary>
    
        <category term="News Literacy" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Jihii Jolly  When big news breaks, like the Malaysian airline plane crash in eastern Ukraine on Thursday afternoon, news organizations can&apos;t say much that&apos;s not confirmed. So they, along with hungry news consumers, turn to user-generated content for answers, such as these first two crash-related posts on verified UGC feed FB Newswire: a photo of extra security at...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Murdoch moves on Time Warner</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/the_audit/murdoch_and_time_warner.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40955" title="Murdoch moves on Time Warner" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40955</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-17T20:04:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-17T20:12:07Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Seven years ago, when Rupert Murdoch stunned the media world by bidding for <i>The Wall Street Journal</i>, its parent company turned him down flat. Investors didn't buy the rejection, and Dow Jones stocks jumped immediately to just under Murdoch's unsolicited $60-a-share bid. Three months later, the Bancroft family signed over the company, and the rest is history. Now Murdoch is...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="The Audit" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Ryan Chittum Seven years ago, when Rupert Murdoch stunned the media world by bidding for The Wall Street Journal, its parent company turned him down flat. Investors didn&apos;t buy the rejection, and Dow Jones stocks jumped immediately to just under Murdoch&apos;s unsolicited $60-a-share bid. Three months later, the Bancroft family signed over the company, and the rest is...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Dangerous drug side effects will no longer be secret in Canada</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/the_second_opinion/dangerous_drug_side_effects_no_longer_secret_in_canada.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40954" title="Dangerous drug side effects will no longer be secret in Canada" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40954</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-17T19:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-17T19:05:50Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ Last fall on a visit to Canada, I spotted a first-rate piece in the <i>Toronto Star</i> by Diana Zlomislic, which chronicled the death of 18-year-old Marit McKenzie who had suffered a catastrophic blood clot blocking blood flow to her lungs. McKenzie had been taking the controversial acne medication Diane-35 for about a year to treat mild acne even though...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Darts and Laurels" />
    
        <category term="The Second Opinion" />
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Trudy Lieberman  Last fall on a visit to Canada, I spotted a first-rate piece in the Toronto Star by Diana Zlomislic, which chronicled the death of 18-year-old Marit McKenzie who had suffered a catastrophic blood clot blocking blood flow to her lungs. McKenzie had been taking the controversial acne medication Diane-35 for about a year to treat...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>How Katrina and BP spill coverage defined NOLA as the two events, in turn, shaped local press</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/critical_eye/oil_and_water_book_review.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40947" title="How Katrina and BP spill coverage defined NOLA as the two events, in turn, shaped local press" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40947</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-17T14:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-17T14:28:26Z</updated>
    
    <summary>When Hurricane Katrina charged through New Orleans, the devastation left in its wake had an unintended side effect: It became a destination for the media, whose coverage defined the city in the eyes of the nation. Before 2005, New Orleans was scintillating, if unknown, place--a historic African American city and a wonderful vacation destination. After, it was a place where...</summary>
    
        <category term="Critical Eye" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Alexis Sobel Fitts When Hurricane Katrina charged through New Orleans, the devastation left in its wake had an unintended side effect: It became a destination for the media, whose coverage defined the city in the eyes of the nation. Before 2005, New Orleans was scintillating, if unknown, place--a historic African American city and a wonderful vacation destination. After, it was a place where...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>A long-time science reporter wrote a questionable book on genetics. Can we trust his other work?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/the_observatory/the_race_and_genes_story.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40949" title="A long-time science reporter wrote a questionable book on genetics. Can we trust his other work?" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40949</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-17T10:53:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-17T13:57:05Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[In the 10 weeks since veteran science journalist Nicholas Wade penned a book claiming that genetic difference between the races account for social behavior like work ethic and obedience to authority, the clamor over his assertions has steadily climbed. Critics have pointed out that <em>A Troublesome Inheritance: Genes, Race and Human History</em> mixes correlation and causality, makes generalized assumptions about...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="The Observatory" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Chris Ip <![CDATA[In the 10 weeks since veteran science journalist Nicholas Wade penned a book claiming that genetic difference between the races account for social behavior like work ethic and obedience to authority, the clamor over his assertions has steadily climbed. Critics have pointed out that A Troublesome Inheritance: Genes, Race and Human History mixes correlation and causality, makes&lt;a...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>For Detroit&apos;s alt-weekly, rising ambition and a few questionable decisions</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/metro_times_rising_ambition_sponsored_content.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40950" title="For Detroit's alt-weekly, rising ambition and a few questionable decisions" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40950</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-17T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-17T03:46:00Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[DETROIT, MI &mdash; <em>The Boston Phoenix</em> closed up shop. <em>The Village Voice</em> is diminished by heavy layoffs and staff disquiet. And last winter, the outlook for <em>Metro Times</em>, the 34-year-old alt-weekly in Detroit, didn&rsquo;t look too good either. After years of declining circulation and staff cuts, the paper was put up for sale. But in an unexpected turnaround, a newly-formed...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Anna Clark <![CDATA[DETROIT, MI &mdash; The Boston Phoenix closed up shop. The Village Voice is diminished by heavy layoffs and staff disquiet. And last winter, the outlook for Metro Times, the 34-year-old alt-weekly in Detroit, didn&rsquo;t look too good either. After years of declining circulation and staff cuts, the paper was put up for sale. But in an...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Journalist on criticism of &apos;neglected child&apos; broadcast: &apos;I reported the facts I was given by the police&apos;</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/wjbf_report_mom_arrested_kid_at_park.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40948" title="Journalist on criticism of 'neglected child' broadcast: 'I reported the facts I was given by the police'" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40948</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-16T18:58:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-16T20:57:18Z</updated>
    
    <summary>CHARLESTON, SC -- &quot;I reported the facts I was given by the police.&quot; That&apos;s what broadcast reporter Deon Guillory told me last night over email. I had asked Guillory if he&apos;d been following the pointed criticism of a two-week-old story of his that had suddenly gone viral--becoming the most popular item on the website of WJBF, the ABC affiliate that...</summary>
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Corey Hutchins CHARLESTON, SC -- &quot;I reported the facts I was given by the police.&quot; That&apos;s what broadcast reporter Deon Guillory told me last night over email. I had asked Guillory if he&apos;d been following the pointed criticism of a two-week-old story of his that had suddenly gone viral--becoming the most popular item on the website of WJBF, the ABC affiliate that...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title> After 29 years, Freep is indefinitely halting its high school journalism program (UPDATED)</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/freep_ending_apprentice_progra.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40946" title=" After 29 years, Freep is indefinitely halting its high school journalism program (UPDATED)" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40946</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-16T15:15:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-19T23:36:33Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[The <i>Detroit Free Press</i> is abruptly ending a 29-year-old high school journalism program within weeks, where high school students were brought into the newsroom to work alongside seasoned professionals. The Gannett-owned newspaper no longer has a financial interest in funding the program, according to multiple <i>Free Press</i> employees, who learned that the program would be discontinued on Monday but declined...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
        <category term="Minority Reports" />
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Aaron Foley The Detroit Free Press is abruptly ending a 29-year-old high school journalism program within weeks, where high school students were brought into the newsroom to work alongside seasoned professionals. The Gannett-owned newspaper no longer has a financial interest in funding the program, according to multiple Free Press employees, who learned that the program would be discontinued on Monday but...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Somaly Mam, Nick Kristof, and journalism&apos;s hero problem</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/somaly_mam_nick_kristof_and_jo.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40933" title="Somaly Mam, Nick Kristof, and journalism's hero problem" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40933</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-16T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-15T16:45:04Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Heroes are complicated and victims aren&apos;t always who we think they are. As journalists, we are storytellers lured by the power of a great narrative. But we are also investigators, and that&apos;s the part of our job we must honor first--especially when heroes fall and readers become victims, misled by the stories we write. In recent weeks, the Somaly Mam...</summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Karen Coates Heroes are complicated and victims aren&apos;t always who we think they are. As journalists, we are storytellers lured by the power of a great narrative. But we are also investigators, and that&apos;s the part of our job we must honor first--especially when heroes fall and readers become victims, misled by the stories we write. In recent weeks, the Somaly Mam...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The Grand Dame of Florida reporting has retired twice, but she&apos;s still causing trouble</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/lucy_morgan_inducted_florida_newspaper_hall_of_fame.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40944" title="The Grand Dame of Florida reporting has retired twice, but she's still causing trouble" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40944</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-16T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-16T14:33:11Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ MIAMI &mdash; The&nbsp;<em>Tampa Bay Times&rsquo;</em>&nbsp;Lucy Morgan is the Grand Dame of statehouse reporters in Florida. Morgan was recently inducted into the Florida Newspaper Hall of Fame to honor her nearly half century in the business. But her fame is not just for her longevity. She&rsquo;s a&nbsp;Pulitzer Prize-winner&nbsp;renowned for &ldquo;causing trouble&rdquo; for corrupt lawmen, petty politicians, and generations of governors....]]></summary>
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Susannah Nesmith <![CDATA[Lucy Morgan with videocamera and phone, before her retirement. (Photo via State Archives of Florida, Florida Memory, http://floridamemory.com/items/show/103503, Donn Dughi.) MIAMI &mdash; The&nbsp;Tampa Bay Times&rsquo;&nbsp;Lucy Morgan is the Grand Dame of statehouse reporters in Florida. Morgan was recently inducted into the Florida Newspaper Hall of Fame to...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>A silver lining in Pew&apos;s statehouse press report?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/a_silver_lining_in_pews_statehouse_press_report.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40938" title="A silver lining in Pew's statehouse press report?" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40938</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-15T20:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-15T20:15:05Z</updated>
    
    <summary>It was 4pm, nearing the end of a workday for North Carolina&apos;s state legislators, political experts, and public relations flacks, and I was a college freshman sitting in class waiting for a call back before 5pm came and all hope was lost. Finally, a source from Raleigh called. I ran out of my introductory journalism class, phone and computer in...</summary>
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Amanda Albright It was 4pm, nearing the end of a workday for North Carolina&apos;s state legislators, political experts, and public relations flacks, and I was a college freshman sitting in class waiting for a call back before 5pm came and all hope was lost. Finally, a source from Raleigh called. I ran out of my introductory journalism class, phone and computer in...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>6 Wikipedia edits made from Capitol Hill</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/6_wikipedia_edits_made_from_ca.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40941" title="6 Wikipedia edits made from Capitol Hill" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40941</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-15T19:07:22Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-16T17:31:59Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Congressional approval ratings are near all-time lows. Policy issues have taken a back seat on the campaign trail, special interests exert disproportionate influence in Washington, and gridlock between parties appears insurmountable. Someone in the halls of power, however, is still doing the people&rsquo;s work: anonymously editing the Wikipedia entry of the popular sitcom <em>It&rsquo;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia</em>. As originally...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By David Uberti <![CDATA[Congressional approval ratings are near all-time lows. Policy issues have taken a back seat on the campaign trail, special interests exert disproportionate influence in Washington, and gridlock between parties appears insurmountable. Someone in the halls of power, however, is still doing the people&rsquo;s work: anonymously editing the Wikipedia entry of the popular sitcom It&rsquo;s Always Sunny in Philadelphia....]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>A quest to ban the &apos;R-word&apos; from a high-school newspaper nets national attention</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/redskins_high_school_newspaper.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40940" title="A quest to ban the 'R-word' from a high-school newspaper nets national attention" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40940</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-15T18:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-15T19:47:57Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[ One woman ignited a controversy that has embroiled a suburban Philadelphia high school newspaper staff, student body, administration, and the community. All the tumult is over a single word: Redskins. Donna Fann-Boyle, part Cherokee and part Choctaw, appeared before the Neshaminy school board in 2013 and implored the school directors to cease using the name &ldquo;Redskins&rdquo; for the high...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Dave Warner Jackson Haines and Gillian McGoldrick say their high-school paper will no longer print the word &quot;Redskin.&quot; (Photo credit: Dave Warner) One woman ignited a controversy that has embroiled a suburban Philadelphia high school newspaper staff, student body, administration, and the community. All the tumult is over a single word: Redskins. Donna Fann-Boyle, part...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Stories I&apos;d like to see</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/googles_lost_links_us_border_c.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40934" title="Stories I'd like to see" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40934</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-15T16:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-15T15:59:16Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[<i>This column, a regular feature, was originally published on Reuters.com.</i> <b>1. Google's dilemma:</b> Writing in the <i>Guardian</i> last week, Google general counsel David Drummond described the trouble the European unit of his company is having trying to implement a European Union court's decision that the search giant must eliminate links to certain Web articles or postings about people that these...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Steven Brill This column, a regular feature, was originally published on Reuters.com. 1. Google&apos;s dilemma: Writing in the Guardian last week, Google general counsel David Drummond described the trouble the European unit of his company is having trying to implement a European Union court&apos;s decision that the search giant must eliminate links to certain Web articles or postings about people...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>In the rise of race beats, echoes of history</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/minority_reports/race_beats.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40932" title="In the rise of race beats, echoes of history" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40932</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-15T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-15T15:35:21Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Mississippi Senator Thad Cochran may owe the Congressional Black Caucus for helping him beat back a tea party challenger in his state&apos;s primary last month, but journalists have the Associated Press&apos; Jesse Holland to thank for breaking the news last month in the first place. As a race and ethnicity reporter at the AP, the tale of mostly Democratic black...</summary>
    
        <category term="Minority Reports" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Tracie Powell Mississippi Senator Thad Cochran may owe the Congressional Black Caucus for helping him beat back a tea party challenger in his state&apos;s primary last month, but journalists have the Associated Press&apos; Jesse Holland to thank for breaking the news last month in the first place. As a race and ethnicity reporter at the AP, the tale of mostly...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Wanton behavior</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/language_corner/language_corner_071414.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40929" title="Wanton behavior" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40929</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-14T18:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-14T15:24:05Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[In the 1700s, <i>Garner's Modern American Usage</i> says, Samuel Johnson declared an end to "wont." But, <i>Garner's</i> continues, "it hangs on today as a slightly whimsical way of expressing customary behavior." It also hangs on as a misuse of "want." "Wont" has to do with habit or custom; "want" has to do with desire. But when something is a habit,...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Language Corner" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Merrill Perlman In the 1700s, Garner&apos;s Modern American Usage says, Samuel Johnson declared an end to &quot;wont.&quot; But, Garner&apos;s continues, &quot;it hangs on today as a slightly whimsical way of expressing customary behavior.&quot; It also hangs on as a misuse of &quot;want.&quot; &quot;Wont&quot; has to do with habit or custom; &quot;want&quot; has to do with desire. But when something is a habit,...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>LeBron&apos;s SI announcement was the anti-&apos;Decision&apos;</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/full_court_press/lebron_announcement.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40930" title="LeBron's SI announcement was the anti-'Decision'" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40930</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-14T18:25:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-14T18:24:24Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Last Friday the sports world was astonished by two stories. First, the NBA&apos;s best player, LeBron James, was reversing his decision from four years ago to leave Cleveland for the Miami Heat. In a surprising but understandable move, James decided to return to the team he played for during his first seven seasons in the league, close to his boyhood...</summary>
    
        <category term="Full-Court Press" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Robert Weintraub Last Friday the sports world was astonished by two stories. First, the NBA&apos;s best player, LeBron James, was reversing his decision from four years ago to leave Cleveland for the Miami Heat. In a surprising but understandable move, James decided to return to the team he played for during his first seven seasons in the league, close to his...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>On the NSA, a White House credibility problem</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/a_white_house_credibility_prob.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40928" title="On the NSA, a White House credibility problem" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40928</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-14T15:20:51Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-14T15:52:49Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[On Friday, The Associated Press reported that the Obama administration had advance knowledge last year that the British government would force <em>The</em> <em>Guardian</em>&nbsp;to destroy hard drives containing documents leaked by Edward Snowden. Indeed, as declassified emails obtained through a Freedom of Information request show, National Security Agency officials even applauded the move. And <em>Guardian</em>&nbsp;editors, under government supervision, used power tools...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By David Uberti <![CDATA[On Friday, The Associated Press reported that the Obama administration had advance knowledge last year that the British government would force The Guardian&nbsp;to destroy hard drives containing documents leaked by Edward Snowden. Indeed, as declassified emails obtained through a Freedom of Information request show, National Security Agency officials even applauded the move. And Guardian&nbsp;editors, under government supervision, used...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>A new course in video games journalism</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/a_new_course_in_video_games_jo.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40927" title="A new course in video games journalism" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40927</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-14T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-14T14:46:41Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[It has been eight years since Chuck Klosterman lamented in <em>Esquire</em> that there was no &ldquo;Lester Bangs of video games,&rdquo; no true arts critic to give voice to one of this generation's unique cultural artifacts. Today, while video games writing has a broad readership on sites like Kill Screen and the Vox Media-owned Polygon&mdash;as well as in general publications like...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Chris Ip <![CDATA[It has been eight years since Chuck Klosterman lamented in Esquire that there was no &ldquo;Lester Bangs of video games,&rdquo; no true arts critic to give voice to one of this generation's unique cultural artifacts. Today, while video games writing has a broad readership on sites like Kill Screen and the Vox Media-owned &lt;a...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Must-reads of the week</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/the_kicker/must_reads_0710.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40924" title="Must-reads of the week" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40924</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-11T18:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-11T19:26:05Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Culled from CJR&rsquo;s own stories, plus the frequently updated &ldquo;Must-reads from around the Web,&rdquo; our staff recommendations for the best pieces of journalism (and other miscellany) on the internet, here are your can&rsquo;t-miss must-reads of the past week: After the fall: An amazing profile of Lance Armstrong (<em>Esquire</em>) -&nbsp;"Here in purgatory, the mansion is smaller, but the wine cellar, paneled...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="The Kicker" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By The Editors <![CDATA[Culled from CJR&rsquo;s own stories, plus the frequently updated &ldquo;Must-reads from around the Web,&rdquo; our staff recommendations for the best pieces of journalism (and other miscellany) on the internet, here are your can&rsquo;t-miss must-reads of the past week: After the fall: An amazing profile of Lance Armstrong (Esquire) -&nbsp;"Here in purgatory, the mansion is smaller, but the wine cellar,...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Newspaper revenue experiment throwdown: crowdfunding vs underwriting</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/revenue_experiment_throwdown_crowdfunding_vs_underwriting.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40925" title="Newspaper revenue experiment throwdown: crowdfunding vs underwriting" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40925</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-11T16:05:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-11T16:08:53Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[CHARLESTON, SC &mdash; Last week, we&nbsp;wrote about a deal&nbsp;between the <em>News &amp; Record</em> in Greensboro, NC, and a local arts group in which the group will give the paper $15,000 to underwrite expanded arts coverage. We raised some concerns about the arrangement&mdash;as did several other critics. One of those critics was the <em>News &amp; Record&rsquo;s</em> former editor, John Robinson, and...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Corey Hutchins <![CDATA[CHARLESTON, SC &mdash; Last week, we&nbsp;wrote about a deal&nbsp;between the News &amp; Record in Greensboro, NC, and a local arts group in which the group will give the paper $15,000 to underwrite expanded arts coverage. We raised some concerns about the arrangement&mdash;as did several other critics. One of those critics was the News &amp; Record&rsquo;s former editor, John...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>How reporters used data covering the World Cup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/data_points/how_reporters_used_data_in_cov.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40920" title="How reporters used data covering the World Cup" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40920</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-11T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-14T18:26:11Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[With the 2014 World Cup set to end on Sunday, this week's edition of Data Darts and Laurels will focus on how journalists used data to explain everything from what's going on in the games to fan behavior. To start, we're going to pay special attention to FiveThirtyEight, given their position as quantitative storytellers within the ESPN family. A <b>LAUREL</b>...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Darts and Laurels" />
    
        <category term="Data Points" />
    
        <category term="Full-Court Press" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Tanveer Ali With the 2014 World Cup set to end on Sunday, this week&apos;s edition of Data Darts and Laurels will focus on how journalists used data to explain everything from what&apos;s going on in the games to fan behavior. To start, we&apos;re going to pay special attention to FiveThirtyEight, given their position as quantitative storytellers within the ESPN family. A LAUREL...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The Associated Press factchecks a couple &apos;Mediscare&apos; ads in Kentucky</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/the_second_opinion/associated_press_factchecks_medicare_ads_kentucky_senate.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40923" title="The Associated Press factchecks a couple 'Mediscare' ads in Kentucky" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40923</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-10T18:50:56Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T18:39:22Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Bravo to The Associated Press! As soon as dueling ads for Kentucky Senator Mitch McConnell and his challenger in the November election, Alison Lundergan Grimes, went up this week, AP reporters Adam Beam and Calvin Woodward were out of the gate, too. Their coverage quickly and clearly noted the shaky claims on which the &ldquo;Mediscare&rdquo; ads rested&mdash;and showed that campaign...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="The Second Opinion" />
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Trudy Lieberman <![CDATA[Bravo to The Associated Press! As soon as dueling ads for Kentucky Senator Mitch McConnell and his challenger in the November election, Alison Lundergan Grimes, went up this week, AP reporters Adam Beam and Calvin Woodward were out of the gate, too. Their coverage quickly and clearly noted the shaky claims on which the &ldquo;Mediscare&rdquo; ads rested&mdash;and showed that...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Long all-volunteer, Guernica Mag looks toward paying its contributors</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/guernica_going_forward.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40918" title="Long all-volunteer, Guernica Mag looks toward paying its contributors" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40918</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-10T16:30:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T17:36:14Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Ten years after a professor told Guernica Magazine founder and editor in chief Michael Archer to open a free magazine and let it fail as an experience, the publication is still up and running. In the past decade, even as online writing outlets have proliferated, Guernica has continued to attract writers and editors to its pages, all working without the...</summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Julie Lasson Fromowitz Ten years after a professor told Guernica Magazine founder and editor in chief Michael Archer to open a free magazine and let it fail as an experience, the publication is still up and running. In the past decade, even as online writing outlets have proliferated, Guernica has continued to attract writers and editors to its pages, all working without...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The Portland Press Herald&apos;s longform look at ethnic inequality in Maine</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/portland_press_herald_longform.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40917" title="The &lt;i&gt;Portland Press Herald&lt;/i&gt;'s longform look at ethnic inequality in Maine" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40917</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-10T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T14:49:27Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[Since late June, <i>The Portland Press Herald</i> has been running daily installments of "Unsettled," a 29-piece series that chronicles the local Passamaquoddy tribe's fight for equal rights in the face of institutionalized racism. It's a startling story of injustice and defiance, and a masterclass in serialization--each chapter ends with a hook that has readers coming back for more. "Unsettled" has...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Edirin Oputu Since late June, The Portland Press Herald has been running daily installments of &quot;Unsettled,&quot; a 29-piece series that chronicles the local Passamaquoddy tribe&apos;s fight for equal rights in the face of institutionalized racism. It&apos;s a startling story of injustice and defiance, and a masterclass in serialization--each chapter ends with a hook that has readers coming back for more. &quot;Unsettled&quot;...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Gawker&apos;s so-far successful experiment in making office chats public</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/realtalk/disputations_gawker_etc.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40912" title="Gawker's so-far successful experiment in making office chats public" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40912</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-09T18:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-09T19:01:36Z</updated>
    
    <summary>Last Monday, Gawker editor Max Read announced that the bloggers and editors on his team were spending too much time chatting on Campfire, one of several group-chat apps that have become popular in newsrooms. Smart ideas aired on Campfire should, in fact, be appearing on the site, he wrote, and there was now a space on Gawker, called Disputations, for...</summary>
    
        <category term="#Realtalk" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Ann Friedman <![CDATA[Last Monday, Gawker editor Max Read announced that the bloggers and editors on his team were spending too much time chatting on Campfire, one of several group-chat apps that have become popular in newsrooms. Smart ideas aired on Campfire should, in fact, be appearing on the site, he wrote, and there was now a space on Gawker, called &lt;a...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Daily Caller editor doubles down on Menendez &apos;scoop&apos;</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/behind_the_news/daily_caller_menendez.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40915" title="Daily Caller editor doubles down on Menendez 'scoop'" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40915</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-09T16:19:24Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T17:29:00Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[When Tucker Carlson launched The Daily Caller in 2010, he told CJR that the site would produce serious journalism without fear or partisan favor&mdash;and that if it got something wrong, it would correct the mistake. &ldquo;Our view is that people want reliable information they&rsquo;re not getting other places,&rdquo; he said at the time. &ldquo;If that&rsquo;s right-wing, the world has turned...]]></summary>
    
        <category term="Behind the News" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By David Uberti <![CDATA[When Tucker Carlson launched The Daily Caller in 2010, he told CJR that the site would produce serious journalism without fear or partisan favor&mdash;and that if it got something wrong, it would correct the mistake. &ldquo;Our view is that people want reliable information they&rsquo;re not getting other places,&rdquo; he said at the time. &ldquo;If that&rsquo;s right-wing, the world has...]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Medicare isn&apos;t doing its own &apos;truth checking.&apos; Why?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/the_second_opinion/why_isnt_medicare_doing_its_own_truth-checking.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40913" title="Medicare isn't doing its own 'truth checking.' Why?" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40913</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-09T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-09T15:29:34Z</updated>
    
    <summary>In April, the Department of Health and Human Services released its great Medicare data dump unlocking a treasure chest of reporting opportunities. The government revealed details about the $77 billion in payments Medicare made to 800,000 doctors who treat patients for Part B services, which include doctor visits, outpatient treatments, and lab services. News organizations and others had long pushed...</summary>
    
        <category term="The Second Opinion" />
    
        <category term="United States Project" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Trudy Lieberman In April, the Department of Health and Human Services released its great Medicare data dump unlocking a treasure chest of reporting opportunities. The government revealed details about the $77 billion in payments Medicare made to 800,000 doctors who treat patients for Part B services, which include doctor visits, outpatient treatments, and lab services. News organizations and others had long...
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>A $52 million loss, but a good year for The Guardian</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.cjr.org/the_audit/the_guardians_very_good_52_mil.php" />
    <link rel="service.edit" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.cjr.org/cgi-bin/cgiwrap/posting/managed-mt/mt-atom.cgi/weblog/blog_id=14/entry_id=40914" title="A $52 million loss, but a good year for &lt;I&gt;The Guardian&lt;/i&gt;" />
    <id>tag:www.cjr.org,2014://14.40914</id>
    
    <published>2014-07-09T10:50:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-09T09:30:45Z</updated>
    
    <summary><![CDATA[It's quite something to note that a company that lost $52 million last year had a very good year. But so it is with <i>The Guardian</i>, which is unique among major news organizations because it's effectively a trust-fund paper&mdash;owned by a company whose sole objective is not to make shareholders happy but to make sure <i>The Guardian</i> operates in perpetuity....]]></summary>
    
        <category term="The Audit" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.cjr.org/">
        By Ryan Chittum <![CDATA[It's quite something to note that a company that lost $52 million last year had a very good year. But so it is with The Guardian, which is unique among major news organizations because it's effectively a trust-fund paper&mdash;owned by a company whose sole objective is not to make shareholders happy but to make sure The Guardian operates in perpetuity....]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>


<script src="http://www.google-analytics.com/urchin.js" type="text/javascript"></script>
<script type="text/javascript">
	_uacct = "UA-417896-1";
	urchinTracker();
</script>
</feed> 