<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en-us"><title>The latest stories from www.wnyc.org</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/atomfeeds/all/" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.wnyc.org/</id><updated>2014-07-21T13:47:14-04:00</updated><subtitle>The latest stories from www.wnyc.org</subtitle><entry><title>The Leonard Lopate Show-2014-07-29
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/the-leonard-lopate-show-2014-07-29/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/the-leonard-lopate-show-2014-07-29/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>Seán Hemingway on The Sun Also Rises
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/sean-hemingway-sun-also-rises/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/sean-hemingway-sun-also-rises/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Ernest Hemingway's first novel, &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1476739951/wnycorg-20/"&gt;The Sun Also Rises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is the quintessential story of the Lost Generation. The story follows Lady Brett Ashley and Jake Barnes and their carousing friends from the nightclubs of 1920s Paris to the bull fights in Spain. It looks at the disillusionment of the post-World War I generation,  but, at its heart, the novel is about unrequited love. Ernest Hemingway’s grandson, &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Se%C3%A1n+Hemingway"&gt;Seán Hemingway&lt;/a&gt;, will be here to discuss a new edition of the novel—and the early drafts and notes that show the author’s process. &lt;strong&gt;Leave your questions for him by leaving a comment, below!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="book_club"></category><category term="books"></category><category term="ernest_hemingway"></category><category term="fiction"></category><category term="novels"></category></entry><entry><title>From Mandela’s Enemy to His Right Hand
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/mandelas-secretary/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T13:47:14-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/mandelas-secretary/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Zelda+la+Grange"&gt;Zelda la Grange&lt;/a&gt; grew up white in segregated South Africa, supporting the regime and the rules of apartheid. Her conservative family referred to the imprisoned Nelson Mandela as “a terrorist.” Yet just a few years after his release and the end of apartheid, she had become one of the president’s most loyal and devoted associates. La Grange’s memoir, &lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0525428283/wnycorg-20/"&gt;Good Morning, Mr. Mandela&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, looks back at her time as one of Mandela’s private secretaries during his presidency and as an aid and spokesperson in his retirement. Working and traveling by his Mandela’s for almost two decades, La Grange found herself negotiating with celebrities and world leaders, supporting Mr. Mandela in his many roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate072114apod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="books"></category><category term="memoir"></category><category term="nelson_mandela"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="south_africa"></category></entry><entry><title>Jonathan Demme, André Gregory, and Wallace Shawn on Making "A Master Builder"
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/jonathan-demme-andre-gregory-and-wallace-shawn-making-master-builder/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T13:33:28-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/jonathan-demme-andre-gregory-and-wallace-shawn-making-master-builder/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Jonathan+Demme"&gt;Jonathan Demme&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Andr%C3%A9+Gregory"&gt;André Gregory&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Wallace+Shawn"&gt;Wallace Shawn&lt;/a&gt; discuss bringing their interpretation of Henrik Ibsen’s “The Master Builder” to the screen. This Ibsen classic tells the tale of a successful, egomaniacal architect who has spent a lifetime bullying his wife, employees, and mistresses, and who wants to make peace with himself as his life approaches its final act. Wallace Shawn, who wrote the screenplay, plays the cruel, guilt-ridden architect. Director Jonathan Demme based his direction on the stage production by André Gregory. The film “A Master Builder” premiers at July 23 at &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/filmforum.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Film Forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;div class="user-embedded-video"&gt;&lt;div id="videoplayer_idm57461762a37b9ad-16c3-4f43-af3f-2f7e5b21e26b"&gt;&lt;iframe class="youtube_video" src="//cdn.embedly.com/widgets/media.html?src=http%3A%2F%2Fplayer.vimeo.com%2Fvideo%2F93153422&amp;amp;wmode=transparent&amp;amp;src_secure=1&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fvimeo.com%2F93153422&amp;amp;image=http%3A%2F%2Fi.vimeocdn.com%2Fvideo%2F473589586_1280.jpg&amp;amp;enablejsapi=1&amp;amp;showinfo=0&amp;amp;autohide=1&amp;amp;rel=0&amp;amp;type=text%2Fhtml&amp;amp;schema=vimeo" width="620" height="349" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" id="a-8319722084950893481" mozallowfullscreen="mozallowfullscreen" webkitallowfullscreen="webkitallowfullscreen" data-original-url="http://vimeo.com/93153422"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/lopate/lopate072114bpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="andre_gregory"></category><category term="art"></category><category term="arts"></category><category term="arts_and_culture"></category><category term="film"></category><category term="jonathan_demme"></category><category term="wallace_shawn"></category></entry><entry><title>Metropolis: 7/19/14
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/metropolis-71914/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T13:02:35-04:00</updated><id>/story/metropolis-71914/</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Zero 7, "Take Me Away (feat. Only Girl)" (Make)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zero 7, "U Know" (Make)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Duke Dumont, "Won't Look Back" (Blase Boys Club)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dusky, "Love Taking Over" (Ajunadeep)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude Von Stroke, "Califuture feat. Barry Drift" (Dirty Bird)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shiba San, "Okay" (Dirty Bird)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basement Jaxx, "Never Say Never (Mark Knight Remix)" ([PIAS] America)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grimes, "Go" (4AD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classixx, "A Stranger Love (Salva Remix)" (Innovative Leisure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Young Punx, "Supersonic" (Mofohifi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;N55, "Eclipse" (Bullet Train)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bassnectar, "You &amp;amp; Me (feat. W. Darling)" (Amorphous)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Porter Robinson, "Sad Machine" (Astralwerks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ten Walls, "Walking With Elephants" (Life And Death)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oliver $ And Jimi Jules, "Pushing On" (Ultra)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spada feat. Hosie Neal, "Feels Like Home (Bakermat Remix)"&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watermat, "Bullit (Original Mix)" (Spinnin' Deep)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Para One, "You Too (2014 Club Mix)" (Marble/Because)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Presets, "No Fun (Lancelot Remix)" (Modular)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rufus Du Sol, "Sundream (Claptone Remix)" (Sweat It Out!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;James Curd &amp;amp; Luke Million, "Say The Words To You (feat. Nah Man!)" (Mr. Kim)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zhu, "Faded" (Mind Of A Genius/TH3rd Brain)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Massive Attack, "Paradise Circus (Gui Borrato Remix)" (EMI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 KCRW-FM. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.kcrw.com"&gt;http://www.kcrw.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Metropolis%3A+7%2F19%2F14&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The History Of Tunnel Warfare
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/the-history-of-tunnel-warfare/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:50:37-04:00</updated><id>/story/the-history-of-tunnel-warfare/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This past week, much of the of the Israeli mission in Gaza has focused on targeting the tunnels used by Hamas to transport weapons and supplies, as well as launching attacks and moving troops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tunnel warfare is not a new phenomenon. Since as early as the 9th century BC, when Assyrian forces would attempt to dig under enemy fortifications and destroy their walls, tunnel warfare has been a constant strategy in siege warfare worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://hereandnow.wbur.org/"&gt;Here &amp;amp; Now’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;s Jeremy Hobson talks with &lt;strong&gt;Wayne Lee&lt;/strong&gt;, a professor at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill and author of the book “&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Barbarians-Brothers-Anglo-American-Warfare-1500-1865/dp/0199737916/?tag=wburorg-20" target="_blank"&gt;Barbarians and Brothers&lt;/a&gt;,” about the history of tunneling, from ancient Rome to Vietnam to today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Guest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.unc.edu/~welee/" target="_blank"&gt;Wayne Lee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, professor of history at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill and author of “Barbarians and Brothers: Anglo-American Warfare, 1500-1865.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 WBUR-FM. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wbur.org"&gt;http://www.wbur.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=The+History+Of+Tunnel+Warfare&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/wbur/media/2014/07/20140721_hereandnow_history-tunnel-warfare.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link></entry><entry><title>Battle Survivor Receives Medal Of Honor
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/battle-survivor-receives-medal-of-honor/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:47:21-04:00</updated><id>/story/battle-survivor-receives-medal-of-honor/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nine American soldiers died in the Battle of Wanat in 2008. But according to his commanding officers, more men would have been killed if not for the actions of Staff Sgt. Ryan Pitts on that day in Afghanistan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitts fought back while badly wounded when hundreds of Taliban fighters attacked Operation Topside, which the soldiers were building in Waygal Valley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitts’ actions, they say, turned the tide of the battle and today at the White House, President Obama will drape the Medal of Honor around his neck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitts, who was born in Lowell, Massachusetts, now lives in Nashua, New Hampshire. He is the ninth living recipient of the nation’s highest military honor. Seven men have been honored posthumously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://hereandnow.wbur.org/2014/07/09/medal-honor-ryan-pitts" target="_blank"&gt;See our conversation with Ryan Pitts earlier this month&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.army.mil/medalofhonor/pitts/profile/index.html" target="_blank"&gt;Watch the ceremony live at 3pm ET&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Guest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.army.mil/article/128651/Former_Soldier_to_receive_Medal_of_Honor_for_fierce_battle_in_Afghanistan/" target="_blank"&gt;Ryan Pitts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, retired Army sergeant who will receive the Medal of Honor for his bravery in the War in Afghanistan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 WBUR-FM. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wbur.org"&gt;http://www.wbur.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Battle+Survivor+Receives+Medal+Of+Honor&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/wbur/media/2014/07/20140721_hereandnow_ryan-pitts-medal-honor.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link></entry><entry><title>Changes To D.C.'s Blue Line Schedule Leaves Some Commuters Seeing Red 
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/changes-dcs-blue-line-schedule-leaves-some-commuters-seeing-red/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:46:06-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/changes-dcs-blue-line-schedule-leaves-some-commuters-seeing-red/</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="article"&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Metro rail commuters began their work week on a grumpy note, and it had nothing to do with the mere fact that it was Monday morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reductions in Blue Line service to one train every 12 minutes went into effect, lengthening the commute for some workers heading into D.C. from Virginia at rail stations from Pentagon south to Franconia-Springfield. The new rail schedule is necessary to accommodate the opening of the Silver Line this Saturday, July 26.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the bottleneck at the Rosslyn tunnel, which will now handle Blue, Orange, and Silver Line trains, two Blue Line trains per hour were switched to the Yellow Line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While riders grumbled about enduring longer wait times for the Blue Line or having to hop a Yellow Line train instead to L’Enfant Plaza to transfer to the crowded Orange Line to complete their trip into downtown Washington, Metro downplayed the inconvenience, saying only five percent of all Metro rail riders are being negatively affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“During rush hour you are still waiting at L’Enfant… you never know, really. It really doesn’t make that much of a difference,” said frustrated commuter Lakesh Nigam as he waited on the platform at the Crystal City station. He said he did not believe the Yellow Line would help him get to work faster, and when his lease is up in June he plans on moving away from the Blue Line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metro disagrees. For instance, a trip from Pentagon to McPherson Square takes 11 minutes on a Blue Line train with no wait time on the platform. Taking the Yellow Line to L’Enfant Plaza and switching to the Blue, Orange, or Silver Lines takes just three minutes longer. So if the next Blue Line train is more than three minutes away, taking the Yellow Line would be faster under normal operating conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least that is how Metro is explaining commuters’ options in its official literature. But whether commuters who are creatures of habit make the effort to compute the time savings remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Taking the Yellow Line takes just as long as waiting for a Blue Line train,” said commuter Marie Murphy at Crystal City station. “In theory I understand why they have to make the changes, but in practice it seems like they could have made it a little better.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metro says Blue Line trains ran every 8.5 minutes during rush hour before the Silver Line-related changes were instituted. So the average additional wait time will be about four minutes, which can be avoided by using the Yellow Line instead, depending on your departure and destination points. Blue Line riders from Virginia who must go to Rosslyn or Foggy Bottom, to name two stations west of downtown, are stuck with longer waits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Everybody is probably a little dissatisfied...and this just adds to it for anybody riding the Blue Line,” said Karen Brigham as she rode into Washington Monday morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s kind of ridiculous but I guess they have no other choice given the lack of capacity in the Rosslyn tunnel,” said commuter Matt Hourihan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metro says the Rosslyn tunnel can handle a maximum of 26 trains per hour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Any more frequent than that and there would be congestion delays, i.e. trains holding in tunnels with nowhere to move until the parade advances. That is more frequent than headways on the NYC subway,” said Metro spokesman Dan Stessel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The transit authority said most of the changes coming with the arrival of the Silver Line will be positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 37 percent of existing Metrorail riders, accounting for 260,000 Metrorail trips, will benefit from shorter wait times, Metro said in a statement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These include rush-hour riders traveling to or from stations north of L'Enfant Plaza on the Green/Yellow lines, those traveling to or from stations east of Stadium-Armory on the Blue Line, and those along the Orange Line in Arlington County.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ninety percent of all riders will have either a shorter or the same wait times once the Silver Line starts running, according to Metro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="d.c."></category><category term="metro"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="transit"></category><category term="transportation"></category><category term="wmata"></category></entry><entry><title>Why Hot Cars Are So Deadly
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/why-hot-cars-are-so-deadly/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:40:33-04:00</updated><id>/story/why-hot-cars-are-so-deadly/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p style="padding-left: 30px"&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s an annual summer tragedy. So far this year, 17 children in the U.S. have died of heat stroke inside a parked car. Some of those cases have been getting extra attention this summer, but that number is not unusual. Georgia Public Broadcasting’s &lt;strong&gt;Adam Ragusea&lt;/strong&gt; looked into the science that explains how a parked car can get so hot, so fast.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a sunny, summer day in Macon, Georgia. I’m standing with Matt Marone outside his truck, and the A.C. is on full blast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Right now it’s 97 degrees outside, and the interior temperature is, what, 79 and a half,” Marone says. “So then we can shut it off, and then we’ll just keep track of the temperature and how it changes over time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marone is a physics professor at Mercer University. I ask him about leaving kids in the car — even for bit. You think, “At worst, it’ll just get as hot inside the car as it is outside.” But Marone explains how it can get a lot hotter — fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There’s a lot of energy penetrating the windshield, some of it’s reflecting off and bouncing back, some of it’s going inside the car, heating up the interior of the car,” Marone says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After three minutes, it has already hit 90 degrees inside the car — and the temperature is still climbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the windows closed, the inside of the car is just like a greenhouse. Light from the sun comes in through the glass and is absorbed as heat on the seats, the dash. Glass doesn’t transmit that heat nearly as well as it transmits light, so energy pours into the car, and gets trapped. It accumulates. Marone says the only quick way for all that energy to escape is through the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But if the car is all sealed up, is there gonna be a way for convection currents to let cool air flow in and displace the warm air and blow it out? How’s that gonna happen?” Marone asks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We try cracking the windows a few inches, the way you would before leaving a car. But it doesn’t allow enough air flow to make a real difference. Before long, it’s 116 degrees in Marone’s truck, almost 20 degrees hotter than it is outside. Now, you might be thinking, “That’s hot, but deadly?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="pullquote" style=""&gt;“Please, never leave your child alone in a car, not even for a second.”&lt;div class="pullquoteauth"&gt;– Jenny Stanley&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Young children have poorer tolerance to heat when compared with adults,” says pediatrician Mark Zonfrillo, who leads the Child Road Traffic Safety Research Group at Children’s Hospital of Philadelphia. “They sweat less, and they also have a larger body surface area to mass ratio than adults. But the main reason that children cannot tolerate heat in the vehicle is because they’re literally trapped in these instances, and developmentally, they can’t escape from the car.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenny Stanley of Evans, Georgia, lost her 6-year-old daughter Sydney this way four years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Please, never leave your child alone in a car, not even for a second. Because I can tell you, a hundred percent, it is not worth it,” Stanley says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now she gives talks, sharing her story. Stanley didn’t even leave her daughter in the car. Little Sydney climbed in by herself, right there in the driveway. No one could find her until it was too late.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I don’t want any other family to go through this pain. I want you to leave here knowing you should always lock your car. You have to check and make sure all the children are out, but make sure the car is locked so they cannot get back in.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An average of 38 kids die in a hot car every year in the U.S. That number hasn’t budged, in spite of a big public awareness campaign the National Highway Transportation Safety Administration launched in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now, safety advocates are getting creative. Brett Garrett, a firefighter and paramedic in Tuscaloosa, Alabama, pulled a stunt recently to illustrate the danger. He actually baked cookies inside a car warmed only by the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“According to the oven thermometer, it’s 174 degrees on the dash. These have been in there just over 40 minutes, but these are done,” he says, taking a bite. “It’s hot.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the lesson to remember: It’s not just the heat of a really hot day that heats up a parked car, it’s the sunshine. One study from San Francisco State University found that on a sunny day, a car can get deadly hot for a child even when temperatures outside are in the low 70s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;San Francisco State University:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://ggweather.com/heat/" target="_blank"&gt;Statistics and information on hot car deaths&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Guest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gpb.org/author/adam-ragusea" target="_blank"&gt;Adam Ragusea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Macon bureau chief and Morning Edition host for &lt;a href="http://www.gpb.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Georgia Public Broadcasting&lt;/a&gt;. He tweets &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aragusea" target="_blank"&gt;@aragusea&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 WBUR-FM. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wbur.org"&gt;http://www.wbur.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Why+Hot+Cars+Are+So+Deadly&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/wbur/media/2014/07/20140721_hereandnow_hot-car-danger-children.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link></entry><entry><title>More Than 20 Major Wildfires Burning In Oregon And Washington
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/more-than-20-major-wildfires-burning-in-oregon-and-washington/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:35:47-04:00</updated><id>/story/more-than-20-major-wildfires-burning-in-oregon-and-washington/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nearly a million acres are burning across Oregon and Washington, in more than 20 major wildfires. Thousands of firefighters are working to contain them and the military is now sending in air tankers to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, at least 150 structures have burned in Washington, and one man has died trying to protect his home. Sheriff Frank Rogers in Okanogan County in north-central Washington says he’s never seen anything like this in 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Courtney Flatt&lt;/strong&gt;, a reporter with Northwest Public Radio, is in Okanogan and she joins &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://hereandnow.wbur.org/"&gt;Here &amp;amp; Now’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;s Meghna Chakrabarti with details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Guest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://nwpr.org/people/courtney-flatt" target="_blank"&gt;Courtney Flatt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, multimedia journalist for Northwest Public Radio, based in Richland, Wash. She tweets &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/courtneyflatt" target="_blank"&gt;@courtneyflatt&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 WBUR-FM. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wbur.org"&gt;http://www.wbur.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=More+Than+20+Major+Wildfires+Burning+In+Oregon+And+Washington&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/wbur/media/2014/07/20140721_hereandnow_wildfires-oregon-washington.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link></entry><entry><title>Another Facet Of The Jobs Debate: Baby Boomers
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/another-facet-of-the-jobs-debate-baby-boomers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:25:19-04:00</updated><id>/story/another-facet-of-the-jobs-debate-baby-boomers/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A strong economy naturally depends on a large portion of the population earning money and sending it back into the economy. But the U.S. labor force has been shrinking since 2007, and according to a report by the White House Council of Economic Advisers, this is because baby boomers are reaching retirement age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But critics disagree, saying that the weak economy has forced baby boomers to work longer to support their families. NPR’s &lt;strong&gt;Marilyn Geewax&lt;/strong&gt; discusses the report and what it means for the economy with &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://hereandnow.wbur.org/"&gt;Here &amp;amp; Now’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;s Meghna Chakrabarti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/2014/07/17/332363116/latest-wrinkle-in-the-jobs-debate-blame-the-boomers" target="_blank"&gt;Read Geewax’s piece, “Latest Wrinkle In The Jobs Debate: Blame The Boomers”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Guest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/people/98525078/marilyn-geewax" target="_blank"&gt;Marilyn Geewax&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, senior business editor for NPR. She tweets &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/geewaxnpr" target="_blank"&gt;@geewaxnpr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 WBUR-FM. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wbur.org"&gt;http://www.wbur.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Another+Facet+Of+The+Jobs+Debate%3A+Baby+Boomers&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/wbur/media/2014/07/20140721_hereandnow_baby-boomers-economy.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link></entry><entry><title>Gay Florida Couple In Limbo After Winning Right To Marry
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/gay-florida-couple-in-limbo-after-winning-right-to-marry/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:20:39-04:00</updated><id>/story/gay-florida-couple-in-limbo-after-winning-right-to-marry/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A county in Florida could join 17 states and the District of Columbia in allowing same sex marriage. &lt;strong&gt;Aaron Huntsman&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;William “Lee” Jones&lt;/strong&gt; will be among the first in line for a marriage license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two bartenders from Key West have been together for 11 years, and in April they sued, arguing that the 2008 amendment in the Florida Constitution banning gay marriage violated their rights under the U.S. Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Monroe County last Thursday, state court Judge Luis Garcia agreed with them, requiring that county to approve same-sex marriage licenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within hours, the state’s Attorney General Pam Bondi filed a &lt;a href="http://www.myfloridalegal.com/newsrel.nsf/newsreleases/EA33384D2F071BB485257D180068B246" target="_blank"&gt;notice of appeal&lt;/a&gt;, staying the ruling – effectively putting it on hold. The judge could make a decision on that today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid the flurry of legal activity and uncertainty, Huntsman and Jones join &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://hereandnow.wbur.org/"&gt;Here &amp;amp; Now’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;s Jeremy Hobson to discuss the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Guests&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aaron Huntsman&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;William “Lee” Jones&lt;/strong&gt;, bartenders in Key West and plaintiffs in Huntsman v. Heavilin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 WBUR-FM. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wbur.org"&gt;http://www.wbur.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Gay+Florida+Couple+In+Limbo+After+Winning+Right+To+Marry&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/wbur/media/2014/07/20140721_hereandnow_florida-gay-marriage.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link></entry><entry><title>A Fatal Arrest, and Questions About Chokeholds
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/fatal-arrest/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:15:21-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/fatal-arrest/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;WNYC criminal justice reporter &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Kathleen+Horan"&gt;Kathleen Horan&lt;/a&gt; talks about the death of Eric Garner &lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/anger-and-tears-staten-island-eric-garner/?utm_source=/story/fatal-arrest/&amp;amp;utm_medium=treatment&amp;amp;utm_campaign=morelikethis"&gt;during an arrest on Staten Island&lt;/a&gt; during which the NYPD used the banned "chokehold."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl072114dpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="crime_and_law_enforcement"></category><category term="local_news"></category><category term="nypd"></category></entry><entry><title>The Russian View Of What Happened To Flight MH17
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/the-russian-view-of-what-happened-to-flight-mh17/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:12:15-04:00</updated><id>/story/the-russian-view-of-what-happened-to-flight-mh17/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While the West says pro-Russian separatists in Eastern Ukraine fired a missile that brought down MH17, the point of view in Russia is different. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://hereandnow.wbur.org/"&gt;Here &amp;amp; Now’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;s Meghna Chakrabarti speaks to &lt;strong&gt;Dmitri Trenin&lt;/strong&gt;, director of the Carnegie Moscow Center. Trenin retired from the Russian Army in 1993.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Guest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://carnegieendowment.org/experts/?fa=287" target="_blank"&gt;Dmitri Trenin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, director of the &lt;a href="http://www.carnegie.ru/en/#/slide_3573_malaysia-and-ukraine" target="_blank"&gt;Carnegie Moscow Center&lt;/a&gt;, which was established as a subdivision of the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace. He retired from the Russian Army in 1993. He tweets &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/DmitriTrenin" target="_blank"&gt;@DmitriTrenin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 WBUR-FM. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wbur.org"&gt;http://www.wbur.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=The+Russian+View+Of+What+Happened+To+Flight+MH17&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://pd.npr.org/anon.npr-mp3/wbur/media/2014/07/20140721_hereandnow_russian-view-mh17-crash.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link></entry><entry><title>Chaotic Investigation Into Plane Crash Continues
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/chaotic-investigation-into-plane-crash-continues/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:06:05-04:00</updated><id>/story/chaotic-investigation-into-plane-crash-continues/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are international investigators on the scene in Eastern Ukraine, where Malaysia Airlines Flight MH17 crashed last week. But there are also pro-Russian separatists in the fields where the jet went down, as well as volunteers — some of them walking up to reporters with wallets belonging to victims of the crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The BBC’s &lt;strong&gt;Olga Ivshina&lt;/strong&gt; discusses the latest on the cleanup and investigation effort at the crash site with &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://hereandnow.wbur.org/"&gt;Here &amp;amp; Now’&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;s Jeremy Hobson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Please download the Here &amp;amp; Now &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/rss/podcast/podcast_detail.php?siteId=5183243" target="_blank"&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt; or use the &lt;a href="http://www.wbur.org/listen/smartphone-apps" target="_blank"&gt;WBUR app&lt;/a&gt; to hear this interview.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Guest&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Olga Ivshina&lt;/strong&gt;, correspondent for the BBC in Ukraine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 WBUR-FM. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.wbur.org"&gt;http://www.wbur.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Chaotic+Investigation+Into+Plane+Crash+Continues&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Afghan Vet, Who Held Off Taliban Attack On His Own, Will Receive Medal Of Honor
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/afghan-vet-will-become-9th-living-recipient-of-medal-of-honor/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T12:06:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/afghan-vet-will-become-9th-living-recipient-of-medal-of-honor/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Army Sgt. Ryan Pitts will be the ninth living veteran to receive the nation's highest award for valor for actions in Iraq or Afghanistan, when President Obama presents him with the Medal of Honor later today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As NPR's Tom Bowman reports, Pitts is credited with holding off a brutal Taliban attack back in 2008. Tom filed this report for our Newscast unit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Soldiers from Chosen Company were setting up an outpost in the rugged hills near the Pakistan border. Suddenly they came under attack by more than a hundred Taliban fighters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Mike Denton and the other soldiers saw much of the fire was focused on Chosen Company's separate observation post or OP, set a hundred yards away on a hillside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Ryan Pitts was in that OP and the only one left alive. He tossed grenades, helped call in airstrikes, and comforted the dying. Denton and others eventually were able to come to Pitts' aid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"'Him staying up there and holding that position definitely kept the day from getting a lot worse,' Denton said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Still the attack was one of the worst of the Afghan war: Nine Americans killed, 27 wounded."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.army.mil/article/128651/Former_Soldier_to_receive_Medal_of_Honor_for_fierce_battle_in_Afghanistan/?from=moh_pitts_news_image"&gt;According to the Army&lt;/a&gt;, after Pitts realized he was all alone, that all the soldiers around him were gone, he radioed the command post, but was told they had no one who could help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pitts said he wasn't angry about that. Instead, he kept fighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I basically reconciled that I was going to die, and made my peace with it," he told the Army. "My personal goal was to just to try and take as many of them with me, before they got me."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://hereandnow.wbur.org/2014/07/21/ryan-pitts-medal-honor"&gt;Public radio's &lt;em&gt;Here and Now&lt;/em&gt; spoke to Pitts&lt;/a&gt; earlier this month. He told the news magazine that when he was first told about the honor, he wasn't happy, because he didn't think he deserved it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"But time has allowed me to process it," Pitts said. "And this was a team effort. It belongs to every man there that day and I'll accept it on behalf of the team. It's not mine."  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Afghan+Vet%2C+Who+Held+Off+Taliban+Attack+On+His+Own%2C+Will+Receive+Medal+Of+Honor&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Our Delusional Brains
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/world-around-us-shapes-delusions-inside-us/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T11:34:21-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/world-around-us-shapes-delusions-inside-us/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Joel+Gold"&gt;Joel Gold&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Ian+Gold"&gt;Ian Gold&lt;/a&gt; take us on a journey through the delusional brain to explore the intersection of neuroscience, biology, and culture. The current view of delusions is that they are the result of biology gone awry, of neurons in the brain misfiring, but the Golds argue that delusions are in fact the result of the interaction between the brain and the social world. Their new book, &lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1439181551/wnycorg-20/"&gt;Suspicious Minds: How Culture Shapes Madness &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;uses case studies and the latest research in schizophrenia, and looks at the role of culture and the social world in the development of psychosis. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="delusions"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="mental_health"></category><category term="mental_illness"></category><category term="psychiatry"></category></entry><entry><title>Benjamin Booker, 'Have You Seen My Son?'
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/benjamin-booker-have-you-seen-my-son/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T11:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/benjamin-booker-have-you-seen-my-son/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you've not heard of Benjamin Booker yet, get ready. He's a fiery 22-year-old guitar player from New Orleans about to hit the road with Jack White. This tune, "Have You Seen My Son," is about evangelical father praying for his son's soul. The video, directed by Rick Alverson, was shot at the James River Correctional Facility in Virginia. Benjamin Booker's self-titled debut album comes out August 19.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Saturday, July 26, Booker will be playing at the Newport Folk Festival. You can download an mp3 of "Have You Seen My Son" alongside songs by four of the festival's most promising up-and-coming acts &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/2014/07/18/330424429/at-2014s-newport-folk-festival-5-discoveries-to-stretch-folks-limits" target="_blank"&gt;right here&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Benjamin+Booker%2C+%27Have+You+Seen+My+Son%3F%27&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Do You Have to Be Crazy to Be a Genius?
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/secrets-creative-brain/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T10:33:32-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/secrets-creative-brain/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Neuroscientist and literary scholar &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Nancy+C.+Andreasen"&gt;Nancy C. Andreasen&lt;/a&gt; tries to answer the question: If high IQ does not indicate creative genius, then where does the trait come from, and why is it so often accompanied by mental illness? Andreasen has studied the neuroscience of mental illness and has worked with many gifted subjects, including Kurt Vonnegut, John Irving, and John Cheever, from the Iowa Writers' Workshop to investigate the science of genius. She’s currently working with artists and scientists including George Lucas, the mathematician William Thurston, the novelist Jane Smiley, and six Nobel laureates. Her article &lt;a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/features/archive/2014/06/secrets-of-the-creative-brain/372299/" target="_blank"&gt;“Secrets of the Creative Brain” &lt;/a&gt;is the cover story of the July/August issue of &lt;em&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="artist"></category><category term="creativity"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="mental_illness"></category><category term="writers"></category></entry><entry><title>International Politics: Russia, Gaza, and Iran
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/international-politics-russia-gaza-and-iran/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T10:28:47-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/international-politics-russia-gaza-and-iran/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=David+Sanger"&gt;David Sanger&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://topics.nytimes.com/top/reference/timestopics/people/s/david_e_sanger/index.html"&gt;national security correspondent&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0307718034/wnycorg-20/"&gt;Confront and Conceal: Obama's Secret Wars and Surprising Use of American Power &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (Broadway, 2013), talks about developments in Russia and Ukraine, violence in Gaza, and nuclear talks on Iran. Plus &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Max+Seddon"&gt;Max Seddon&lt;/a&gt;, Buzzfeed&lt;a href="http://www.buzzfeed.com/maxseddon"&gt; foreign affairs reporter&lt;/a&gt; based in Russia, joins from Ukraine with the latest on the downed airliner and the geopolitical implications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl072114apod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="gaza"></category><category term="iran"></category><category term="israel"></category><category term="middle_east"></category><category term="politics"></category><category term="russia"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>An Insider's View to the Failed Iran-U.S. Relationship
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/insiders-view-failed-iran-us-relationship/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T10:06:34-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/insiders-view-failed-iran-us-relationship/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Seyed+Hossein+Mousavian"&gt;Seyed Hossein Mousavian&lt;/a&gt;, scholar at the Wilson School at Princeton, former Iranian diplomat, and author of the new book &lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1628920076/wnycorg-20/"&gt;Iran and The United States: An Insider's View on the Failed Past and the Road to Peace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span&gt;Bloomsbury Academic 2014)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="book"&gt;&lt;a title="buy this book at Amazon" target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN//wnycorg-20/"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, offers a first-hand account of the U.S. and Iran's rocky past, continual failures to negotiate peace, and what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl072114epod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="international_politics"></category><category term="iran"></category><category term="world_news"></category></entry><entry><title>Reports: Texas Gov. Perry To Deploy 1,000 National Guardsmen To Border
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/reports-texas-gov-perry-to-deploy-1000-national-guardsmen-to-border/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T09:55:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/reports-texas-gov-perry-to-deploy-1000-national-guardsmen-to-border/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Texas Gov. Rick Perry is expected to announce on Monday that he is ordering 1,000 National Guard troops to the U.S. border with Mexico, according to reports from &lt;em&gt;The Monitor&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.chron.com/news/houston-texas/houston/article/Perry-expected-to-call-up-National-Guard-to-Rio-5634620.php"&gt;The Houston Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.themonitor.com/news/local/gov-rick-perry-to-deploy-national-guard-troops-to-rgv/article_a016fb52-1073-11e4-975b-0017a43b2370.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Monitor&lt;/em&gt;, a south Texas newspaper, reports &lt;/a&gt;that it received a memo that outlined the plan. The paper says the 1,000 troops would cost about $12 million per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Monitor&lt;/em&gt; adds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The memo was provided to &lt;em&gt;The Monitor&lt;/em&gt; on the condition of anonymity because the information is not yet public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Troops are expected to enter the area gradually, building up to 1,000 after about a month, the memo said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The troops will join the Texas Department of Public Safety in its recent surge to combat human smuggling and drug trafficking amid the influx of mostly Central Americans illegally crossing the Rio Grande. Perry, Lt. Gov. David Dewhurst, and Texas House Speaker Joe Straus announced the $1.3 million per week effort last month."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/06/24/325192601/on-capitol-hill-a-debate-over-whats-driving-central-american-exodus"&gt;As we've been reporting&lt;/a&gt;, the U.S. border with Mexico has been flooded with unaccompanied minors. Over the past year, the number of minors crossing the border illegally more than doubled. &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/07/08/329851404/obama-seeks-3-7b-to-handle-immigration-crisis"&gt;President Obama has asked Congress for $3.7 billion&lt;/a&gt; in emergency funds to deal with the crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Chronicle&lt;/em&gt; quotes state Sen. Juan "Chuy" Hinojosa as saying that Perry briefed legislators representing the border region, before he made a formal announcement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper also rounded up some of the reaction from across the state:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"'The children fleeing violence in Central America are seeking out Border Patrol agents. They are not trying to evade them. Why would Rick Perry send soldiers to confront these kids?' U.S. Rep. Joaquin Castro, D-San Antonio, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Rep. Jeff Leach, R-Plano, took to social media with his reaction, tweeting: 'Glad to hear @GovernorPerry is calling up the National Guard to help secure the border and protect our state. Pray for our troops.'"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/morning-mix/wp/2014/07/21/gov-rick-perry-to-mobilize-texas-national-guard-troops-to-secure-u-s-mexico-border/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Perry telegraphed his intention during a stop in Iowa on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If the federal government does not do its constitutional duty to secure the Southern border of the United States, the state of Texas will do it," Perry said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper adds that sending the National Guard to the border has precedent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Following the murder of Arizona rancher Robert Krentz in 2010, New Mexico Gov. Bill Richardson (D) ordered the National Guard to patrol the border to protect New Mexico residents. ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Obama sent the guard to the border in 2010 to support the Border Patrol. In 2006, Bush, in response to requests for support enforcing federal immigration laws from the governors of Arizona, California, New Mexico and Texas, sent some 6,000 National Guard troops to the Southern border for the same reason."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile in Washington, President Obama will meet with the presidents of Guatemala, Honduras and El Salvador at the White House on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The four leaders and Vice President Biden will discuss how to reinforce our ongoing collaboration to stem the flow of undocumented migrants from Central America to Mexico and the United States," &lt;a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2014/07/18/statement-press-secretary-visit-presidents-guatemala-honduras-and-el-sal"&gt;the White House said in a statement.&lt;/a&gt; "This will include discussion of how the United States and Central American governments are cooperating to promote safe, legal, and orderly migration between our countries in a spirit of shared responsibility, including with respect to the return of family units, which began this week for all three countries."  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Reports%3A+Texas+Gov.+Perry+To+Deploy+1%2C000+National+Guardsmen+To+Border&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Dozens Killed As Libyan Militias Battle For Tripoli's Airport
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/47-killed-as-libyan-militias-battle-for-tripolis-airport/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T09:44:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/47-killed-as-libyan-militias-battle-for-tripolis-airport/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At least 47 people have been killed in fighting over the past 24 hours between rival Libyan militias battling for control of Tripoli's international airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The country's health ministry said late Sunday that the fighting also wounded 120 people. The Associated Press reports:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The weeklong battle over the airport is being waged by a powerful militia from the western city of Zintan, which controls the facility, and Islamist-led militias, including fighters from Misrata, east of Tripoli. The clashes resumed Sunday after cease-fire efforts failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Television footage broadcast Sunday showed a mortar shell striking a Libyan Arab Airlines plane and a column of black smoke billowing from inside the airport, which has been closed since last Monday."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fighting in the North African country is some of the worst since the ouster of Moammar Gadhafi in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/07/17/332384873/libya-asks-u-n-for-assistance-in-protecting-oil-and-airports"&gt;As we told you last week&lt;/a&gt;, Libya's foreign minister asked the U.N. Security Council for help to protect the country's airports, oil installations and ports "before it is too late."  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Dozens+Killed+As+Libyan+Militias+Battle+For+Tripoli%27s+Airport&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Straightening Sisay's Spine: A Twist Of Fate Saves A Boy's Life 
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/straightening-sisays-spine-a-twist-of-fate-saves-a-boys-life/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T09:38:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/straightening-sisays-spine-a-twist-of-fate-saves-a-boys-life/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One dewy morning back in May 2013, a dozen children gathered in an elementary school courtyard to play soccer in Addis Ababa. Seven-year-old Sisay Gudeta stood alone on the balcony above them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sisay poked his head through the arms of a rusty, blue guard rail, staring down at his classmates as they kicked&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;an empty plastic bottle across the pavement. The kids rarely ask him to play, Sisay says. They are afraid to touch him, afraid of the bump on his back that stretches out his neatly pressed school sweater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"He is such a beautiful child," Sisay's grandmother says. "I ask God what I did to do this to him."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For reasons unknown, thousands of children in Ethiopia suffer from congenital spine conditions so severe that humps grow from their backs. Their spines resemble flattened pancakes and roller-coaster tracks, says &lt;a href="http://rickhodes.org/about/"&gt;Dr. Rick Hodes&lt;/a&gt;, an American who runs the only&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;spine clinic in Addis Ababa, a city of 3 million people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such extreme scoliosis cases are found in many poor countries. But Hodes thinks that lack of screening and access to basic medical care leaves Ethiopia with some of the worst spines in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If not effectively treated, &lt;a href="http://www.nlm.nih.gov/medlineplus/scoliosis.html"&gt;scoliosis&lt;/a&gt; can lead to permanent deformity, disc injuries and neurological damage. Here in the U.S., the National Institutes of Health &lt;a href="http://www.niams.nih.gov/Health_Info/Scoliosis/scoliosis_ff.asp"&gt;recommends&lt;/a&gt; doctors use a brace to help straighten a child's back when the spine curves more than 25 to 30 degrees. When the curve reaches more than 45 degrees, surgery is often needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet thousands of Ethiopian children receive no medical treatment for their scoliosis. In villages, a traditional healer may try to flatten the child's back by pressing hot rocks to the skin. Others with twisted spines and humpbacks are ostracized or abandoned and left to die.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Addis+Ababa,+Ethiopia/@6.9285691,38.9758987,5z/data=!4m7!1m4!3m3!1s0x164b85cef5ab402d:0x8467b6b037a24d49!2sAddis+Ababa,+Ethiopia!3b1!3m1!1s0x164b85cef5ab402d:0x8467b6b037a24d49"&gt;Addis Ababa&lt;/a&gt;, Hodes examines more than 200 spine patients each year. The majority have curved protrusions on their backs greater than 100 degrees. Hodes says he once saw a patient with a 240-degree curve, "like a saxophone."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We're sort of setting world records [for spine curvatures]," says Hodes, who leads the Ethiopian medical branch for the nonprofit American Jewish Joint Distribution Committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without continued treatment to correct the 120-degree curve in Sisay's spine, doctors say he will have only the lung capacity of an 8-year-old. His limited breathing will be unable to support his growing body, and he will likely die, perhaps as early as age 14.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But despite his condition, Sisay sounds like a typically 7-year-old boy at his home when we visited him. His biggest worry, on that day, was keeping the TV antennae working. Otherwise how would he watch &lt;em&gt;Tom And Jerry&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I don't touch it," Sisay says of the TV. "If I touch it, it will break. And if it breaks, I will not be happy."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surgeons in Ethiopia are ill-equipped to perform procedures as complicated as the one Sisay needs. But a doctor nearly 4,000 miles away in Ghana can do the $20,000 corrective surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twice a week, Hodes evaluates patients from Ethiopia to see if they're candidates for the surgery. Every three months, he sends about a dozen of them to Accra, Ghana, where &lt;a href="http://vivo.med.cornell.edu/display/cwid-ohb2001"&gt;Dr. Oheneba Boachie-Adjei&lt;/a&gt; examines and sometimes fixes their backs. Adjel, an orthopedic surgeon at Weill Cornell Medical College in New York City, leads the nonprofit &lt;a href="http://www.orthofocos.org/"&gt;Foundation of Orthopedics and Complex Spine&lt;/a&gt;, offering complex medical procedures to poor people across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If you leave these kids alone, you won't see them as teenagers," Boachie-Adjei says of his patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sisay is one of the lucky few.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late 2013, Boachie-Adjei drilled four holes into Sisay's skull and affixed a metal halo to his head. The halo contraption stretches out Sisay's back so there's enough space for his spine once it's&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;straightened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the month of December, Sisay grew about 2.5 inches to 3-foot-5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then in March, Boachie-Adjei sliced opened&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Sisay's back and inserted screws into many of Sisay's vertebrae. The surgeon also attached &lt;a href="http://www.srs.org/professionals/conditions_and_treatment/juvenile_scoliosis/growing_rods.htm"&gt;growing rods&lt;/a&gt; to Sisay's spine to help straighten and lengthen it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the time Sisay hits puberty, he will likely undergo a final procedure to finish correcting the curvature. But for now, Sisay is healing at home in Ethiopia — and still worried that he'll catch the next episode of &lt;em&gt;Tom And Jerry.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://muckrack.com/faiz-siddiqui/portfolio"&gt;Faiz Siddiqui&lt;/a&gt; is a senior at the College of Journalism and Mass Communications at University of Nebraska-Lincoln. He and photographer, senior &lt;a href="http://www.andrewdickinsonphoto.com/"&gt;Andrew Dickinson&lt;/a&gt;, traveled with nine other students and three teachers to Ethiopia as part of an ongoing multimedia project on poverty. &lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Straightening+Sisay%27s+Spine%3A+A+Twist+Of+Fate+Saves+A+Boy%27s+Life+&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Chris Christie Goes to Iowa
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/chris-christie-goes-iowa/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T08:56:39-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/chris-christie-goes-iowa/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Governor Chris Christie recently visited Iowa - ostensibly to raise money for the National Governor's Association - stirring speculation that he's setting up a presidential run and trying to put "Bridgegate" behind him. &lt;a class="guestlink" href="/people/r/?n=Karen+Tumulty"&gt;Karen Tumulty&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/pb/karen-tumulty"&gt;national political correspondent&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt;, discusses the trip's political implications. &lt;/p&gt;
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/bl/bl072114bpod.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="chris_christie"></category><category term="iowa"></category><category term="national_news"></category><category term="politics"></category></entry><entry><title>Top Stories: Kerry Travels To Mideast; Putin On Ukraine Crash
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/top-stories-kerry-travels-to-mideast-putin-on-ukraine-crash/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T08:45:34-04:00</updated><id>/story/top-stories-kerry-travels-to-mideast-putin-on-ukraine-crash/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Good morning, here are our early stories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/07/21/333552933/putin-tragedies-like-mh17-should-bring-people-together"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;-- Putin: Tragedies Like MH17 Should 'Bring People Together'.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/07/21/333546582/in-effort-to-forge-cease-fire-kerry-heads-to-egypt"&gt;-- In Effort To Forge Cease-Fire, Kerry Heads To Egypt.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/07/21/333211643/rubio-small-government-can-help-fix-economic-inequality"&gt;-- Rubio: Small Government Can Help Fix Economic Inequality.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are more early headlines:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wisconsin Train Derailment Forces Evacuations.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.jsonline.com/news/ozwash/slinger-train-derailment-leads-to-evacuations-b99314884z1-267883351.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wisconsin Journal Sentinel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Western Wildfires Scorch 1 Million Acres.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-northwest-wildfires-20140720-story.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Los Angeles Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jamaica Warns Of Worsening Drought.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.jamaicaobserver.com/news/Worst-of-the-drought-is-yet-to-come--Pickersgill-warns-_17211082"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Jamaica Observer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vic Atiyeh, Former Oregon And First Arab American Governor, Dies.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.oregonlive.com/politics/index.ssf/2014/07/republican_vic_atiyeh_who_guid.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oregonian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hundreds Escape Deadly Fighting At Tripoli Airport.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jul/20/libyan-militas-battle-tripoli-hundreds-families-flee-fight"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trial Resumes Today Over Fate Of NBA's Los Angeles Clippers.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.ocregister.com/articles/sterling-629386-shelly-donald.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;OC Register&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chinese Supplier Of McDonalds, KFC Asia Outlets Accused Of Mislabeling Meat.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.smh.com.au/world/fast-food-chains-mcdonalds-kfc-in-food-safety-scandal-in-china-20140721-zvb88.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sydney Morning Herald&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;59-Foot Yellow Rubber Duck Is Missing In China After Flood.&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/blogs-news-from-elsewhere-28364613"&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;)  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Top+Stories%3A+Kerry+Travels+To+Mideast%3B+Putin+On+Ukraine+Crash&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Putin: Tragedies Like MH17 Should 'Bring People Together'
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/putin-tragedies-like-mh17-should-bring-people-together/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T08:18:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/putin-tragedies-like-mh17-should-bring-people-together/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h6&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(This post was updated at 12:51 p.m. ET.)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin says tragedies such as the downing of Malaysia Airlines Flight MH17 last week should "bring people together" rather than "dividing us."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://eng.kremlin.ru/news/22701"&gt;Putin issued the written statement&lt;/a&gt; a day after the United States outlined its case against Russia. &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/07/20/333061052/pressure-grows-on-putin-to-secure-access-to-ukraine-crash-site"&gt;As we reported&lt;/a&gt;, U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry said "it's pretty clear" the missile that downed the commercial jetliner came from "a system that was transferred from Russia."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putin did not directly address those allegations, but instead pointed the finger at the pro-Western government in Kiev.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I believe that if military operations had not resumed in eastern Ukraine on June 28, this tragedy probably could have been avoided," Putin said, &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/06/30/327097563/ukraines-president-ends-ceasefire-vows-to-free-our-lands"&gt;referring to the end of a 10-day-old cease-fire&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putin also called for authorities in Ukraine to do everything possible to "ensure that international experts can work in safety at the crash site."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/the-press-office/2014/07/21/statement-president-situation-ukraine-and-gaza"&gt;In a statement from the South Lawn of the White House late Monday morning&lt;/a&gt;, Obama said he appreciates those words, "but they have to be supported by actions."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obama said Russia has a "direct responsibility" to compel rebels to cooperate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Our friends and allies need to be able to recover those who were lost," Obama said. "Families deserve to be able to lay down their loved ones with dignity."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Russia continues to destabilize Ukraine, Obama said, it will further isolate itself from the international community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/world/2014/07/21/malaysia-russia-ukraine-putin-united-nations/12930557/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;USA Today&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that Dutch investigators arrived at the scene of the crash on Monday to begin their inspection of scores of bodies stored in a refrigerated rail car. All of the 298 passengers and crew onboard the Boeing 777 were killed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newspaper adds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The arrival of the Dutch forensics experts came as the United Nations Security Council was preparing to vote on a resolution demanding international access to the site where Flight MH17 went down Thursday after being hit by a surface-to-air missile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Armed rebels, who control the area, had kept international inspectors at bay for days, prompting outrage from political leaders in the Netherlands and Australia, whose citizens were aboard the ill-fated jetliner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"During the weekend, separatist groups began removing bodies and other evidence from the huge debris field."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2014/jul/21/mh17-un-vote-condemning-downing-plane-monday"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Guardian&lt;/em&gt; reports&lt;/a&gt; that the 15-member security council is set to vote on the Australian-drafted resolution on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking on the condition of anonymity, diplomats told the paper they were unsure if the final resolution would be supported by Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update at 12:51 p.m. ET. Reported Deal With Militants: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/najibrazak/posts/10152172545680952"&gt;In a statement posted on his Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;, Malaysian Prime Minister Najib Razak says his government has established "the basis of an agreement" with Ukrainian separatists to secure evidence, launch an independent investigation and recover the remains of those who died on Flight MH17.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Razak says the remains of 282 people will be moved by train from Torez to Kharkiv in Ukraine, "where they will be handed over to representatives from the Netherlands." Later this evening, the prime minister said, two black boxes will handed over to a Malaysian team in Donetsk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Razak said that Alexander Borodai, the self-proclaimed prime minister of the Donetsk People's Republic, also guaranteed the safe passage of independent investigators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"In recent days, there were times I wanted to give greater voice to the anger and grief that the Malaysian people feel. And that I feel. But sometimes, we must work quietly in the service of a better outcome," Razak concluded. "My heart reaches out to those whose loved ones were lost on MH17. We hope and pray that the agreement reached tonight helps bring them a clear step towards closure."  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Putin%3A+Tragedies+Like+MH17+Should+%27Bring+People+Together%27&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>TN MOVING STORIES: Transpo News Links from Around the Web
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/tn-moving-stories-07212014/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T08:11:57-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/tn-moving-stories-07212014/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOP STORIES ON TN:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LIRR strike has been averted. Repeat: the LIRR strike has been averted. (&lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/lirr-union-reach-tentative-deal/" target="_blank"&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Virginia, highways are getting wider -- and they're getting tolled. (&lt;a href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/virginia-highways-grow-wider-and-come-tolls/" target="_blank"&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MONDAY LINKS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Orleans has a $3.5 billion plan to replace and expand its bus fleet, install 187 bus shelters and lay 33.5 more miles of streetcar track by 2030. That's &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; it can find the money. (&lt;a href="http://www.nola.com/politics/index.ssf/2014/07/new_orleans_rta_unveils_35_bil.html" target="_blank"&gt;Times-Picayune&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to talk to the mayor of Fort Worth? Get on a bike. (&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/07/21/us/politics/fort-worth-mayor-betsy-price-bikes-to-connect-with-residents.html" target="_blank"&gt;NYT&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York City wrongly accused hundreds of people of operating illegal cabs, including &lt;em&gt;"a retired MTA worker dropping off his girlfriend at her job at the Queens racino, an Astoria dad taking his teenage daughter and her friend to school and a Brooklyn retiree who volunteers at a convent giving nuns a lift to JFK Airport in his minivan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;strong&gt;" &lt;/strong&gt;(&lt;a href="http://www.dnainfo.com/new-york/20140721/long-island-city/tlc-wrongly-accused-hundreds-of-being-illegal-cabbies-past-year" target="_blank"&gt;DNA Info&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How the Long Island Rail Road negotiations went down. (&lt;a href="http://www.newsday.com/long-island/lirr-negotiations-were-on-slow-track-for-4-years-1.8848381" target="_blank"&gt;Newsday&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A rock slide suspended Metro-North service on Saturday. (&lt;a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2014/07/19/rock-slide-suspends-metro-north-rail-service/12901655/" target="_blank"&gt;USA Today&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A future of driverless cars might not make the roads less crowded. "'&lt;em&gt;U.S. history shows that anytime you make driving easier, there seems to be this inexhaustible desire to live further from things...The pattern we’ve seen for a century is people turn more speed into more travel, rather than maybe saying, ‘I’m going to use my reduced travel time by spending more time with my family&lt;/em&gt;.’" (&lt;a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2014-07-21/self-driving-cars-will-mean-more-traffic" target="_blank"&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Long Island pilot landed his plane on the Sunrise Highway...twice in eight days. He "&lt;em&gt;seems to have a post-runway approach to flying,&lt;/em&gt;" wrote &lt;a href="http://gothamist.com/2014/07/19/long_island_pilot_lands_his_plane_o.php" target="_blank"&gt;Gothamist&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tappan Zee Bridge now has its own floating concrete production factory. (&lt;a href="http://www.lohud.com/story/news/local/tappan-zee-bridge/2014/07/18/progress-tappan-zee-site-gets-concrete-plant/12858679/" target="_blank"&gt;Journal News&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bus crash in China killed 38 people. (&lt;a href="http://www.bbc.com/news/world-asia-china-28382737" target="_blank"&gt;BBC&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are thousands of suspicious ticketing spikes in red light cameras across Chicago. (&lt;a href="http://www.chicagotribune.com/news/local/ct-red-light-camera-ticket-spikes-met-20140717,0,704793.story" target="_blank"&gt;Tribune; sub&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you can get out of that ticket if you were escorting Elton John to the airport. (&lt;a href="http://www.chicagotribune.com/news/local/ct-red-light-camera-excuses-met-20140718,0,3335530.story" target="_blank"&gt;Tribune&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out you &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; teach a new trick to old dogs. Behold: dogs behind the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe frameborder="0" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/BWAK0J8Uhzk?list=PLr8Ol3z5fRqoCemaCS2-sFm6c87mAAV05" width="640"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="daily_email"></category><category term="links"></category><category term="moving_stories"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="transportation"></category></entry><entry><title>To Save These Pigs, Ky. Farmer Says We Have To Eat Them
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/to-save-these-pigs-ky-farmer-says-we-have-to-eat-them/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T07:47:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/to-save-these-pigs-ky-farmer-says-we-have-to-eat-them/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Robertson County has the smallest population of any county in the state of Kentucky, and it's the only one, word has it, without a stoplight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it's an unlikely place to find a campaign to keep the food system more genetically diverse. But that is exactly what's happening on a small farm owned by Travis Hood, called &lt;a href="http://www.hoodsheritagehogs.com/"&gt;Hood's Heritage Hogs.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hood raises Red Wattle pigs, a heritage breed that the Livestock Conservancy, a nonprofit working to protect breeds and poultry from extinction, &lt;a href="http://www.livestockconservancy.org/index.php/heritage/internal/redwattle"&gt;says&lt;/a&gt; is threatened. In 1999, there were fewer than 50 of these pigs left in the U.S. Today, that number is back up to about 6,000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"As counterproductive as it may seem, to save these pigs we have to eat them," says Hood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hood is part of a small but growing movement across the country of small producers and Slow Food advocates working to hold on to biodiversity by building demand for heritage breed meats. It doesn't hurt that Red Wattle meat is known to be exceptionally juicy with a rich texture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The origins of this tasty breed are fuzzy; some believe the pig came from the Iberian Peninsula, but first appeared in the U.S. in eastern Texas when a farmer found two in the woods and began breeding them. The Red Wattle Hog Association says there's another, unverified story that's been passed down: Decades ago, a pig thief infiltrated a Swiss veterinary school, stole three Red Wattle piglets and snuck them into the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pigs are known to be good-natured and can be as friendly as golden retrievers. They grow on average to about 600 to 800 pounds and range from a strawberry blonde to a deep cherry color. Wattles, pieces of cartilage 1 to 5 inches long, hang from either side of their necks like fleshy dreadlocks. (The wattles don't have a function, as far as anyone can tell.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.kyagr.com/apps/staff.aspx"&gt;Warren Beeler&lt;/a&gt; of Kentucky's Department of Agriculture says what Hood is doing is critical for pig production everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You don't want to lose any genetics, because when you do, you lose them forever," he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Beeler, the Red Wattle is used to raising its babies outside and braving the elements. That makes it genetically tougher than an industrially raised pig that lives its life in a pen. That toughness is important, says Beeler, if farmers want to cross-breed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &lt;a href="http://afs.ca.uky.edu/Rentfrow"&gt;Gregg Rentfrow&lt;/a&gt;, a meat scientist at the University of Kentucky, says raising the Red Wattle doesn't generate much meat to feed people because heritage breeds take longer to get to market than conventional pigs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We're faced with in the next 25 to 50 years of how we're going to feed 9 billion people, and the ability to get an animal to market faster not only helps us feed those 9 billion people, but it helps us do it more cheaply than before," says Rentfrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hood started raising Red Wattles five years ago. At that time he was a golf-course superintendent, a career he'd had for 16 years. Then came job cuts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It went from a salaried position with benefits to an hourly position with no benefits," he says. "Well, I thought, the least we can do is feed ourselves. So I got a couple of hogs and then it started to snowball."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, he lives on 78 acres with a four-generation blended version of &lt;em&gt;Modern Family&lt;/em&gt;, all committed to making the farm work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not an easy life. Over the winter of the polar vortex, Hood hauled 20-gallon buckets of water for the pigs to drink three times a day at 20 below zero degrees Fahrenheit. One windy night, the roof folded up like a gum wrapper. Hood's mother-in-law has been keeping everything afloat through her full-time job as a nurse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hood has been lucky. So far, he's escaped the &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thesalt/2014/06/27/325529915/as-pig-virus-spreads-the-price-of-pork-continues-to-rise"&gt;porcine epidemic diarrhea virus&lt;/a&gt; that has killed nearly 8 million pigs since May 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He sells his meat at the Lexington Farmers Market and straight off the farm, and he turned a profit of $100 for the first time in February. In June, that profit was up to $1,600. Hood is hopeful he can continue to make a go of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"If we weren't doing this," Hood says of the Red Wattle, "they wouldn't exist."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://leslieguttman.com/"&gt;Leslie Guttman&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;is a freelance journalist based in Lexington, Ky.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=To+Save+These+Pigs%2C+Ky.+Farmer+Says+We+Have+To+Eat+Them&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Book News: 'Big 5' Publishers Absent From Amazon's New E-Book Service
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/book-news-big-5-publishers-absent-from-amazons-new-e-book-service/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T07:42:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/book-news-big-5-publishers-absent-from-amazons-new-e-book-service/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The daily lowdown on books, publishing, and the occasional author behaving badly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The so-called Big Five publishers — Penguin Random House, Macmillan, HarperCollins, Hachette and Simon &amp;amp; Schuster — don't appear to be participating in &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/07/18/332575051/amazon-launches-subscription-service-for-books"&gt;Kindle Unlimited&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon's new e-book subscription service. Following the model of services such as Oyster and Scribd, Kindle Unlimited offers unlimited e-books for a fixed monthly fee. Searches through Kindle Unlimited's library of 600,000-plus titles turn up bestsellers from Houghton Mifflin Harcourt, W.W. Norton, Scholastic and other publishers, but no titles from the five major houses. Amazon's recent dispute with Hachette has highlighted tensions between online retailer and traditional publishers. HarperCollins declined to comment, while Amazon and the other four publishers did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Hillmann, the author of a guide to not getting gored by bulls &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/thetwo-way/2014/07/10/330390001/book-news-co-author-of-book-on-how-not-to-be-gored-by-a-bull-gets-gored"&gt;who recently got gored&lt;/a&gt; by a bull, &lt;a href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/i-got-gored-in-pamplona-but-i-will-run-with-the-bulls-again/2014/07/18/e683be6a-0b94-11e4-b8e5-d0de80767fc2_story.html?hpid=z4"&gt;writes an op-ed&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post &lt;/em&gt;explaining why he plans to run with the bulls again: "I will keep running for another chance to lead a Spanish fighting bull up the street. When that happens, I become one with the fiercest, most majestic animal on Earth. And in those moments, I am at peace." (Listen to his interview with NPR's Kelly McEvers &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/2014/07/12/330683866/wounded-bull-runner-if-you-run-long-enough-you-get-gored"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Orr &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/07/20/books/review/james-franco-poet.html?_r=0"&gt;is circumspect&lt;/a&gt; in reviewing James Franco's new poetry collection: "[T]he annoyance this collection will inspire is rooted in a deeper anxiety: The attention commanded by James Franco's poetry has everything to do with "James Franco" and almost nothing to do with poetry. And that cultural wealth is not transferable. Attention withheld from Franco's poems will not instantly devolve upon some worthy but obscure poet; it will go to another actor, or singer, or commercial nonfiction writer, or memoirist — or even to James Franco in his novel-writing incarnation. Poetry is the weak sister of its sibling arts, alternately ignored and swaddled like a 19th-century invalid, and that will change only by means of a long, tedious and possibly futile effort at persuasion. Perhaps it's a blessing to have James Franco on one's side in that struggle."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Valerie Macon — whose appointment as the Poet Laureate of North Carolina enraged even more poets than James Franco's book deal — &lt;a href="http://artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com/2014/07/18/north-carolinas-new-poet-laureate-bows-out/?_php=true&amp;amp;_type=blogs&amp;amp;_r=0"&gt;resigned&lt;/a&gt; from the position late last week. Macon, a self-published poet and disability claims processor, was criticized for her relative lack of literary accolades. In her resignation letter, she wrote that she didn't want "negative attention" to distract from the laureateship, adding, "I would like to encourage everyone to read and write poetry. They do not need prestigious publishing credits or a collection of accolades from impressive organizations — just the joy of words and appreciation of self-expression."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Book+News%3A+%27Big+5%27+Publishers+Absent+From+Amazon%27s+New+E-Book+Service&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>In Effort To Forge Cease-Fire, Kerry Heads To Egypt
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/in-effort-to-forge-cease-fire-kerry-heads-to-egypt/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T07:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/in-effort-to-forge-cease-fire-kerry-heads-to-egypt/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;U.S. Secretary of State John Kerry is headed to Egypt today in an effort to broker a cease-fire between Israel and Hamas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.state.gov/r/pa/prs/ps/2014/07/229510.htm"&gt;In a statement&lt;/a&gt;, State Department Spokesperson Jen Psaki said Kerry would meet with Egyptian and other senior officials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The United States — and our international partners– are deeply concerned about the risk of further escalation, and the loss of more innocent life," Psaki said. "We believe there should be a ceasefire as soon as possible — one that restores the cease-fire reached in November of 2012."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2014/07/15/world/middleeast/toll-israel-gaza-conflict.html"&gt;According to a &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; count&lt;/a&gt;, Sunday's fighting was the deadliest in the 14-day conflict. Ninety-five Palestinians and 15 Israelis were killed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPR's Soraya Sarhaddi Nelson reports that 13 of those Israelis were soldiers, two of whom were American citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soraya adds that the Israeli military on Sunday said it had foiled an attempt by Hamas militants to infiltrate into southern Israel. According to Israeli Army Radio, the militants entered Israel using two tunnels from northern Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, on the diplomatic front, the United Nations Security Council had an &lt;a href="http://www.un.org/apps/news/story.asp?NewsID=48310#.U8zwwo1dV8s"&gt;emergency meeting on Sunday night&lt;/a&gt; and emerged calling for an immediate cease-fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Qatar, Secretary-General Ban Ki-moon echoed those calls, saying Israel must end its military incursion and Hamas must end its rocket fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.un.org/sg/offthecuff/index.asp?nid=3483"&gt;Ban added&lt;/a&gt;: "While I was en route to Doha, dozens more civilians, including children, have been killed in Israeli military strikes in the Shejaiyah neighborhood in Gaza. I condemn this atrocious action. Israel must exercise maximum restraint and do far more to protect civilians."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the conflict started, 25 Israelis and more than 500 Palestinians have been killed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update at 1:42 p.m. ET. 7 IDF Soldiers Killed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Israel Defense Forces says &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IDFSpokesperson/status/491263758908395521"&gt;seven of its soldiers have been killed during this conflict in the past 24 hours&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.haaretz.com/news/diplomacy-defense/1.606315"&gt;According to Haaretz&lt;/a&gt;, that brings the total number of Israelis killed to 25. The paper puts the total number of Palestinians killed at 508 with 3,130 wounded.   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=In+Effort+To+Forge+Cease-Fire%2C+Kerry+Heads+To+Egypt&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Company Says It Can Cure Your Hangover – For Up To $300 A Visit
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/company-says-it-can-cure-your-hangover-for-up-to-300-a-visit/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T06:35:58-04:00</updated><id>/story/company-says-it-can-cure-your-hangover-for-up-to-300-a-visit/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>Arkansas Razorbacks Trademark Famous Hog Call 
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/arkansas-razorbacks-trademark-famous-hog-call/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T06:06:11-04:00</updated><id>/story/arkansas-razorbacks-trademark-famous-hog-call/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Flexner Incident: Not One of Our Finer Moments
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/flexner-incident-not-one-our-finer-moments/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T06:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/flexner-incident-not-one-our-finer-moments/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;James Thomas Flexner (1908-2003) was a distinguished man of letters writing about American history and art. As a historian and biographer he is best known for a four-volume biography of George Washington that earned him a National Book Award in biography and a special Pulitzer Prize. In 1931, he was the Executive Secretary for the New York City Board of Health's Noise Abatement Commission. Like many civil servants at the time, he was asked to deliver remarks over WNYC on the work of his agency. Though memorable, it unfortunately was not a pleasant experience. He wrote about it in his 1996 autobiography, &lt;em&gt;Maverick's Progress&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;My experience with radio broadcasting began when, as a twenty-three-year-old, I was scheduled to speak on noise abatement over New York City's radio station, WNYC. The studios were under the roof of the huge municipal building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was with a great deal of uneasiness that I set out with my much-worked-over speech grasped convulsively in my hand. The occasion was so important to me that I expected to be received when I arrived with much attention. But the one elevator that went so high disgorged me into a tremendous empty space, lugubriously lit, with a few dirty sofas, against soiled walls and no humans in sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empty, murky corridors went off in several directions. Dreading to be late, I feverishly sampled one corridor after another, banging on locked doors, forlornly rattling doorknobs. Finally, I sat down on one of the sofas, raising a cloud of dust. I was marooned in an atmosphere so depressing that even during subsequent years when I had become inured to radio, it never failed to lower my spirits. Now, terrified or disgracing myself on my first appearance before a huge audience, the more ominous because it would be unseen, I felt as if I had fallen into a morbid pit in my own psyche.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, an oblong of light sprang onto the floor of one of the corridors. From the door that had been opened stepped a tall, willowy, immaculately dressed young man. Having approached me formally, he greeted me with all the ceremony I could have desired. I was led into a room furnished with a few rickety chairs and an oblong table bearing several microphones. My companion showed me how close I should put my mouth to the microphone, and asked me to say a few words so that sound could be adjusted. Then he spoke into his own microphone a few words of gracious introduction, and pointed to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My manuscript before me, I was reading smoothly, without any of the confusions or hesitations I had feared, when I felt a strange sensation on the top of my head. Something was happening to my hair. I felt that I should not interrupt my speech by turning from the microphone to investigate, but finally, as the sensation went on, I dared a quick backward glance. The announcer was running his hands through my curly red hair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I could not shout into the air waves, 'Take your god-damned hands out of my hair!' all I could do, as I read doggedly on, was to shake my fist backward over my shoulder. This had no effect. The hand continued to move through my hair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instant I had got through my speech, I sprang up to face the announcer. He was talking into his microphone, gracefully closing the show. Having finished, he rose languorously, delivered in my direction a deep courtier's bow, and then dashed for the door, slamming it behind him. By the time I got the door open, the murky corridors had returned to their suicidal emptiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;________________________________________________&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: James Thomas Flexner in his autobiography,&lt;em&gt; Maverick's Progress&lt;/em&gt;, Fordham University Press, 1996, pgs. 467-468. Reprinted with permission and courtesy of &lt;a href="http://fordhampress.com/"&gt;Fordham University Press.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="hair"></category><category term="james_thomas_flexner"></category><category term="life"></category><category term="n.y.) [lc]"></category><category term="wnyc (radio station : new york"></category><category term="wnyc_history"></category></entry><entry><title>Report Of Expired Meat Sparks Food Safety Scare In China
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/report-of-expired-meat-sparks-food-safety-scare-in-china/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:57:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/report-of-expired-meat-sparks-food-safety-scare-in-china/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>How Many Frequent Flyer Miles Can You Get With A $36M Charge?
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/how-many-frequent-flyer-miles-can-you-get-with-a-36m-charge/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:55:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/how-many-frequent-flyer-miles-can-you-get-with-a-36m-charge/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>Latest Newscast From the WNYC Newsroom
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/latest-newscast/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:44:14-04:00</updated><id>http://www.wnyc.org/story/latest-newscast/</id><summary type="html">
</summary><link length="0" href="http://www.podtrac.com/pts/redirect.mp3/audio.wnyc.org/newscast/news_latest_newscast.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" rel="enclosure"></link><category term="local news"></category><category term="news"></category><category term="newscast"></category></entry><entry><title>Israelis Shaken Over Deaths Of Soldiers
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/israelis-shaken-over-deaths-of-soldiers/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:40-04:00</updated><id>/story/israelis-shaken-over-deaths-of-soldiers/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>Tobacco Company Told To Pay $23.6B In Lawsuit
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/tobacco-company-told-to-pay-236b-in-lawsuit/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/tobacco-company-told-to-pay-236b-in-lawsuit/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>White House Faces Foreign Crises On Multiple Fronts
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/white-house-faces-foreign-crises-on-multiple-fronts/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/white-house-faces-foreign-crises-on-multiple-fronts/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>Next To Silicon Valley, Nonprofits Draw Youth Of Color Into Tech
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/next-to-silicon-valley-nonprofits-draw-youth-of-color-into-tech/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/next-to-silicon-valley-nonprofits-draw-youth-of-color-into-tech/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Twenty-year-old Taneka Armstrong wants to land a high-tech job, but her day starts at Taco Bell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armstrong stands behind a steel counter, making Burrito Supremes and ringing up customers. She counts pennies and quarters. She also gets orders from her bosses, who she says can be pretty condescending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"They're just like, 'Oh, did you know that already?' Or, 'Can you do this?' " she says. "Yes, I've been doing it, for almost a year now."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armstrong is a native of Oakland, Calif., next door to Silicon Valley, and she lives two lives. This first one, which starts as early as 5 a.m., doesn't challenge her or pay well. And that's why she set off in search of life No. 2: learning tech skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's not an easy path, though. Technology companies have a problem when it comes to employee diversity. The workforce at places like &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/05/29/317024113/googles-white-male-heavy-staff-underlines-techs-diversity-problem"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/alltechconsidered/2014/06/26/325798198/facebooks-diversity-numbers-are-out-and-theyre-what-you-expect"&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; is overwhelmingly white and male.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To counter that, a growing number of nonprofits are popping up in Oakland to help young blacks and Latinos break into the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Goal Is Exposure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every afternoon this summer, Armstrong is in the offices of a small nonprofit called Hack the Hood. Her job is to fix websites for clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I'm trying to do an outline," she says, staring at a page on her laptop that has a lot of links. "You click on it, it takes you everywhere in the world. I like short and simple."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summer, the teens will meet top talent from the companies that make the popular apps they download. Armstrong says there's some chance she'll get deep into coding. Or she might prefer a nontechnical job, like sales and marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That exploration is part of the process, says instructor Zakiya Harris.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Nobody ever asks young people that come from affluent neighborhoods why they're doing programs, because the notion is it's exposure," she says. "The more you expose young people to opportunities, the better they're going to become as adults."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She wants to find ways to empower young people with "low-hanging fruit" — skills in the tech industry. That way, she says, "they can start earning some money in their pocket that's going to actually lead to a career, and not just a dead-end opportunity in a service job."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Search Of Funding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These big ideas come with a small budget line. That's where people like Freada Kapor Klein come in. She's an investor in Silicon Valley and a leading philanthropist for coding nonprofits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her Kapor Center for Social Impact is tracking &lt;a href="http://kaporcenter.org/coding-nation/"&gt;new and growing programs&lt;/a&gt;. Klein says the sheer number is increasing rapidly, but "it's unclear how to measure their effectiveness."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her foundation gives a few million dollars a year. That scale of contribution is rare. She estimates that "foundations are giving tens of thousands of dollars, and in the aggregate you might be getting hundreds of thousands of dollars."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google recently awarded Hack the Hood a half-million dollars for being a winner in its Bay Area nonprofit &lt;a href="https://impactchallenge.withgoogle.com/bayarea2014"&gt;competition&lt;/a&gt;. The tech company has been &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/a/aartishahani.com/file/d/0B-E2rcvhnlQ_a1Q4VUxWQ2dtTHM/edit?pli=1"&gt;studying&lt;/a&gt; why women don't enter computer science, and has pledged to give $50 million overall to programs in the U.S. and abroad that try to recruit women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klein is talking to Twitter and others about the factors that make tech a "&lt;a href="http://www.lpfi.org/sites/default/files/tilted_playing_field_lpfi_9_29_11.pdf"&gt;tilted playing field&lt;/a&gt;." She's asking them to step up their game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What's going to distinguish tech companies going forward is who takes this seriously and who doesn't," she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For her part, Armstrong is taking the work seriously. With Hack the Hood last summer, she experienced the challenge of pitching services. Her team would go door-to-door offering to build websites for local business owners. "What's the catch?" they'd ask. She'd explain over and over, "No, it's free. We're a nonprofit."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armstrong says that process can feel weird, but it's better than making burritos.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Next+To+Silicon+Valley%2C+Nonprofits+Draw+Youth+Of+Color+Into+Tech&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Youth Unemployment Crisis Hits African-Americans Hardest
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/the-youth-unemployment-crisis-hits-african-americans-hardest/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/the-youth-unemployment-crisis-hits-african-americans-hardest/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Young people are being chased out of the labor market. Though the national unemployment rate has fallen steadily in recent months, youth unemployment remains stubbornly high, and the jobless rate is even higher among young minorities. For young people between the ages of 16 and 24, unemployment is more than twice the national rate, at 14.2 percent. For African-Americans, that rate jumps to 21.4 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, discrimination could be a factor. But according to William Spriggs, an economist at Howard University, the trend is also being driven by a sluggish economy. As he told &lt;em&gt;Morning Edition's&lt;/em&gt; Renee Montagne, there is still a backlog of Americans who are unemployed or underemployed as a result of the Great Recession, creating more competition for even minimum wage jobs. In a job market where many people with a college education are settling for jobs outside of their fields, a teenager looking for a summer job will find the market crowded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another big problem, says Spriggs, is the absence of adequate job information. In most states, companies are not required to publicly list all of their job openings. As a result, there are huge disparities in labor market information, based as much on who you know as what you know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Interview Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On job-specific segregation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you walk — in Washington, D.C., as an example — and go to the McDonald's, which is near Howard University on Georgia Avenue, you will see a crew that's almost all black. If you go to a McDonald's that's downtown, you're probably going to see them be mostly Latino. Now, it's the same skills, the same type of job, the same employer. Why do the workforces look that different? It's really job networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the importance of a summer job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's very important, and again it's that network. It's getting to know other people who work. It's getting an employer who can vouch for you when you go to get another job. It's having on your resume that you have that experience. And it's understanding an industry and understanding what the opportunities are within that industry. So, maybe you do take a job in retail, but you're exposed to buyers as an occupation. You're exposed to who supplies the store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the implications of the youth unemployment crisis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a society, we have a deeper challenge. We have set up our entire system assuming that as a young person you started with a work history — including the way that we think about social security. We haven't designed our unemployment system to handle this type of labor market. Our unemployment system, unlike in Europe, says you have to have worked first. We're giving you insurance against an existing work record. But young people now are having a very hard time establishing that work record and therefore don't even have access to unemployment insurance.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=The+Youth+Unemployment+Crisis+Hits+African-Americans+Hardest&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>International Observers Work To Keep Tabs On Site Of Malaysia Jet Crash
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/international-observers-work-to-keep-tabs-on-site-of-malaysia-jet-crash/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/international-observers-work-to-keep-tabs-on-site-of-malaysia-jet-crash/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>In Asheville, N.C., Summer Vacation Lasts Just A Few Weeks
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/in-asheville-nc-summer-vacation-lasts-just-a-few-weeks/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/in-asheville-nc-summer-vacation-lasts-just-a-few-weeks/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's the first day of school at Hall Fletcher Elementary in Asheville, N.C. Principal Gordon Grant stands outside in a white suit and bow tie, greeting students. The kids arrive sporting fresh haircuts and new shoes. One even wears a tutu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the biggest change on this first day of school may be the least obvious. It's July, and students are returning after just five weeks of break. This public school is beginning a three-year experiment, running on a year-round schedule for the first time. The students will get the same number of school days as others in the district, just distributed differently: five weeks in the summer, three-week breaks in September and March, plus a winter holiday vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A primary motivation for the change is to make sure kids don't fall behind academically over the long summer break — a phenomenon &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/blogs/ed/2014/05/30/317360969/free-ways-to-beat-the-summer-slide"&gt;known as the "summer slide."&lt;/a&gt; About 80 percent of the students at this school are eligible for free and reduced lunch, and Grant says, "children who don't have really good enriching opportunities provided for them in the summer move back academically."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tamera Owen is the grandmother of two students at Hall Fletcher, a kindergartner and a second-grader, and she says she can see them "retaining things that they learned."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Karl Alexander is a sociology professor at Johns Hopkins University. He studies learning gaps between students at different income levels. He says a gap widens during the summer break, when "school is out of the picture" and students are dependent on the resources of their families and communities. Asheville City Schools has seen this pattern first-hand, after giving students tests before and after summer vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a recent report from the &lt;a href="http://fas.org/sgp/crs/misc/R43588.pdf"&gt;Congressional Research Service,&lt;/a&gt; 3,700 public schools in the United States operate year-round. That's about 4 percent of the nation's schools. They are most common in the South. While research on student achievement in year-round schools is spotty and inconclusive, some studies have shown a small, positive effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul von Hippel studies educational inequality at the University of Texas at Austin, and he says the benefits of year-round school seem to even out over time: "Students learn more in the summer," but, on the other hand, "they're learning less in the school year."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't the first time Hall Fletcher has tried to shift to a year-round schedule, also known as a "balanced schedule." They experimented with the idea back in the '90s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"After three years they dropped it because of the mismatch of the balanced school year calendar with the regular school year calendar," says Principal Grant. "I think we've done a better job of matching those calendars this year."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This story comes to us from &lt;a href="http://wcqs.org/"&gt;member station WCQS &lt;/a&gt;in Asheville, N.C.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=In+Asheville%2C+N.C.%2C+Summer+Vacation+Lasts+Just+A+Few+Weeks&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Rubio: Small Government Can Help Fix Economic Inequality
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/rubio-small-government-can-help-fix-economic-inequality/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/rubio-small-government-can-help-fix-economic-inequality/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.rubio.senate.gov/public/"&gt;Sen. Marco Rubio&lt;/a&gt;, a potential 2016 GOP presidential contender, is concerned about issues of access to affordable education, availability of job training and prospects for economic mobility. While shunning the "income inequality" language of the left, he insists that those problems need to be viewed through the lens of limited government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"At its core, conservatism is not an anti-government movement, and it's not a no-government movement," Rubio tells &lt;em&gt;Morning Edition&lt;/em&gt; host Steve Inskeep in the first of a two-part interview today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The conservative movement is about government playing its important yet limited role, and about not falling into the trap of believing that every problem has an exclusive government answer for it," the Florida Republican says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just last week, Rubio, 43, &lt;a href="http://www.columbusceo.com/content/stories/apexchange/2014/07/16/rubio-delves-into-student-debt-debate-dominated-by-democrats.html"&gt;co-sponsored a bill&lt;/a&gt; with Virginia Democratic Sen. Mark Warner to set up a system for federal student loan repayment based on a borrower's income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While many conservatives argue that federal aid perpetuates dependency, others, such as Rubio, want to help struggling families without disowning their core ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In May, for example, former Florida Gov. Jeb Bush, another possible 2016 candidate, warned against an economy where some people are permanently on top and others stuck at the bottom. While he offered no rhetoric about "the 1 percent," Bush was referencing some of the same underlying concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rubio steers away from criticizing unequal incomes, preferring instead to focus on unequal opportunity. "If you're the cashier at Burger King, of course you make less than the manager or even the CEO," Rubio tells NPR. "The issue is whether you're stuck being a cashier for the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"So, what we need to do is figure out, what is it that's holding people back? And try to do what we can to address it within the confines of what limited government should be doing," he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a single mother with two children who's struggling to support her family on $10 an hour: "[There] are things that government can do to incentivize the creation of innovations in education that are accessible to people like [her], because if you have to work full time and raise a family, you can't just drop everything and go into a traditional four-year college program," he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"There are things that government can do through our tax code to allow you to keep more of the money that you make, particularly when you look at the cost of child care," he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asked why he specifically mentions single mothers, Rubio responds, "Because I know a bunch of them."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"There are millions of women who are trapped in lower-paying jobs and don't have the skills for a higher-paying job, and don't have the money or the time to access the higher education that they need for a better job," he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"So, for the rest of their lives, they're stuck making $10 an hour, and their kids, as a result, don't have opportunities either," Rubio says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many conservatives see government support as only reinforcing a dependency and incentivizing the father's absence. Rubio, however, insists that often it's not the mother's fault. "The man has abandoned her, or he was abusive."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The success sequence in America says you get an education, you get a good job, you get married, you have children," Rubio says. "People who do those four things have an incredible level of economic stability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"But there are millions of people who aren't going to have one or any of those things," he says. "They are not going to have an equal opportunity to succeed unless something happens to equalize the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The question for those of us in public policy is: What can a limited government do to become a part of that solution — not the exclusive solution — but a part of that solution?" Rubio contends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"People should be allowed to package learning no matter how they acquired it," he says. "Their life experience, their work experience, free online courses, one course at a community college, another at another community college — you should be able to package all that cumulative learning into the equivalent of a degree that allows you to be employed."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second part of our conversation with Rubio, on Tuesday's &lt;em&gt;Morning Edition&lt;/em&gt;, we'll hear from him about immigration and his presidential ambitions.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Rubio%3A+Small+Government+Can+Help+Fix+Economic+Inequality&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Big Data Peeps At Your Medical Records To Find Drug Problems
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/big-data-peeps-at-your-medical-records-to-find-drug-problems/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/big-data-peeps-at-your-medical-records-to-find-drug-problems/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;No one likes it when a new drug in people's medicine cabinets turns out to have problems — just remember the Vioxx debacle a decade ago, when the painkiller was removed from the market over concerns that it increased the risk of heart attack and stroke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do a better job of spotting unforeseen risks and side effects, the Food and Drug Administration is trying something new — and there's a decent chance that it involves your medical records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's called &lt;a href="http://www.mini-sentinel.org/"&gt;Mini-Sentinel&lt;/a&gt;, and it's a $116 million government project to actively go out and look for adverse events linked to marketed drugs. This pilot program is able to mine huge databases of medical records for signs that drugs may be linked to problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The usual system for monitoring the safety of marketed drugs has &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=10318764"&gt;real shortcomings&lt;/a&gt;. It largely relies on voluntary &lt;a href="http://www.fda.gov/Drugs/GuidanceComplianceRegulatoryInformation/Surveillance/AdverseDrugEffects/default.htm"&gt;reports&lt;/a&gt; from doctors, pharmacists, and just plain folks who took a drug and got a bad outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We get about a million reports a year that way," says &lt;a href="http://www.fda.gov/AboutFDA/CentersOffices/ucm193984.htm"&gt;Janet Woodcock&lt;/a&gt;, the director of the FDA's Center for Drug Evaluation and Research. "But those are random. They are whatever people choose to send us."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figuring out from those reports if a drug is really to blame for the symptom isn't easy. And if the side effect is something common, such as a rash or a stroke, there might not even be any reports because doctors might not connect a patient's symptoms to the drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We need a rapid way to find out what's happening with drugs, especially safety of drugs, after they're approved and on the market," says Woodcock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why the FDA is turning to workers at the operations center of Mini-Sentinel, which is located in a brick office building near Fenway Park in Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, people in cubicles can send out queries to 18 data partners that include health plans and insurance companies. Their health records include nearly 180 million Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have insurance through a private health plan, the chances are "pretty good" that your data may have been used in one of these studies, says &lt;a href="http://www.populationmedicine.org/node/205"&gt;Dr. Richard Platt&lt;/a&gt;, the principal investigator for Mini-Sentinel and a professor at Harvard Medical School's Department of Population Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost all of that data comes from billing records — not what your doctor has scribbled in your chart, but rather the codes for any diagnostic tests and procedures you undergo. (These codes are on your medical bill.) Platt says the data partnership has been carefully set up to preserve patient privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His own records have probably been part of a study, says Platt, but he has no way of knowing that. "We've built the system so the analyst here would have no way to say, 'Let's see if Dr. Platt's data is in there,' " he says. "The system is built so that that is an impossible question to ask."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's taken five years for Platt's team to build Mini-Sentinel from scratch and make it a routine part of FDA's work. "We're now doing hundreds of queries a year," he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, they ran a search when the FDA got some troubling reports tentatively linking intestinal problems to a blood pressure drug called olmesartan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"They had noticed that patients who had received this drug were having these complications that they thought might be related to the drug," recalls Platt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, Mini-Sentinel found no connection. Then the FDA asked for a second search, this time focusing on people who took the drug for long periods. They found a link, Platt says. As a result, the FDA added a &lt;a href="http://www.fda.gov/drugs/drugsafety/ucm359477.htm"&gt;warning&lt;/a&gt; to the drug's label.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It was possible to provide an answer that otherwise would frankly just be unavailable to them," says Platt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini-Sentinel has been an experiment to see what's possible, but its contract ends in September and the FDA will be deciding what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone agrees that the ability to sift through huge amounts of patient data is the way of the future — but not everyone believes that we really know how to best do that sifting yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I think it's a good and important step that the FDA is moving in this direction," says Thomas Moore, a senior scientist at the nonprofit &lt;a href="https://www.ismp.org/default.asp"&gt;Institute for Safe Medication Practices&lt;/a&gt;. "The problem is, I think, they have underestimated how far they have to go."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billing data were never meant to be used this way, says Moore, who questions how well they can reveal side effects from drugs. He thinks "the biggest danger is that people will get a false reassurance about safety."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He points to a controversy over a new blood-thinning medicine called dabigatran. Reports had come in about serious bleeding episodes, says Moore, but "the FDA published an &lt;a href="http://www.nejm.org/doi/full/10.1056/NEJMp1302834"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in a leading medical journal, basically discounting all that — saying that, using Mini-Sentinel, they had seen no unusual risk for this drug."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency is now taking another, more nuanced look at dabigatran, after critics &lt;a href="http://circ.ahajournals.org/content/128/7/745.full"&gt;questioned&lt;/a&gt; how well the FDA had designed the original Mini-Sentinel study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People at the FDA are aware that when doing this type of research with big data, the way you set up the question can affect the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Things may change depending on what claims data set you use, or how you run your definitions, how you set up your parameters and so forth," says Woodcock. "And there's no doubt these studies are vulnerable to all these changes."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She says that's why the FDA is also involved in another effort to explore all these potential effects. This effort is led by &lt;a href="http://www.reaganudall.org/"&gt;The Reagan-Udall Foundation for the FDA&lt;/a&gt;, a foundation set up by Congress. Right now its major project is research on how to use large databases to study the safety of medicines on the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is a new science, and much work needs to be done to develop and continue to improve the methods behind this," says Troy McCall, who is managing the &lt;a href="http://imeds.reaganudall.org/"&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; for the Reagan-Udall Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foundation does get some money from the FDA, but supports its research with other funds. And so far, all the money for this particular project has come from pharmaceutical companies like Merck, Pfizer, Novartis, Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson, GlaxoSmithKline, AstraZeneca and Eli Lilly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCall says he doesn't think it's seen as an "'industry project," because the work is so important. "Clearly at the end of the day this is all to benefit patients and ensure that drugs that are on the market are safe," he says, adding that patients also benefit when safe drugs are not unnecessarily removed from the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drug companies do have a big interest in what stays on or off the market. But Woodcock sees no problem with industry funding the development of the scientific methods that will then be used to help make regulatory decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It would be very difficult to develop a method that was going to favor your drug when you're developing a general method, I think," Woodcock says. "But what I would say is, OK, who is going to develop these methods? We need them developed."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officials at the Reagan-Udall Foundation say it operates transparently and has different stakeholders represented on its governing boards. But one board member who represents consumers says she finds the lack of independent funding troubling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I think that creates an appearance of a conflict of interest and potentially a real conflict of interest," says &lt;a href="http://center4research.org/about-us/key-staff/"&gt;Diana Zuckerman&lt;/a&gt;, president of the nonprofit National Center for Health Research. "If all the money is coming from the pharmaceutical companies whose livelihoods are going to be affected by what the project finds, I just think that's an untenable situation."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zuckerman says she worries that industry funding might influence the methods that eventually get used for finding signals in big data that drugs are unsafe — and that could potentially limit what this new approach will reveal about the medicines Americans take every day.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Big+Data+Peeps+At+Your+Medical+Records+To+Find+Drug+Problems&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Writer Plumbs 'Nature Of Evil' In Hometown's Violent Civil Rights Past
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/writer-plumbs-nature-of-evil-in-hometowns-violent-civil-rights-past/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/writer-plumbs-nature-of-evil-in-hometowns-violent-civil-rights-past/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mississippi's past looms large in Greg Iles' best-selling thrillers. His latest book, &lt;em&gt;Natchez Burning,&lt;/em&gt; is the first in a trilogy that&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;takes readers back 50 years to chilling civil rights-era murders and conspiracies all set in Iles' hometown — the antebellum river city of Natchez, Miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iles' hero, Penn Cage, is a former prosecutor and widowed single father who has returned to his childhood home. Once there, he finds himself confronting killers, corruption and dark secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Penn Cage I think of as annoyingly righteous sometimes," Iles says. "He's almost too good."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author says he wanted to create a character who reflected the Southern men he knew growing up in Natchez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"He is not, in any way, a traditional hero," Iles explains. "He's not always the actor who's committing all the things to make the story happen. In some ways, he's almost an observer sometimes. He is trying to figure out the 'why' of things."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Lasting 'Sense Of Place'&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Penn Cage series began with 1999's &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Quiet Game&lt;/em&gt;, a book Iles considers a valentine to his hometown. There are still elaborate, antebellum mansions in Natchez because — unlike the city of Vicksburg, to the north — Natchez surrendered to Union troops during the Civil War without a shot fired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iles says Natchez has a more European feel than other Southern towns. "It's not like Atlanta, where they just put up a town because that's where the railroads crossed and it grew into a city. It really grew organically out of the land, the climate, the topography. And it just gives you a sense of place that you just never get out of you."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sense of place permeates the Penn Cage novels. Iles even takes the titles of his books from famous Natchez landmarks: He named &lt;em&gt;Turning Angel&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(2005) after a statue in the city cemetery that appears to turn around and follow you with her gaze, and &lt;em&gt;The Devil's Punchbowl&lt;/em&gt; (2009) was named after a jungle-like ravine below the cemetery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;'Shaking Hands With Death'&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Natchez Burning&lt;/em&gt;, Iles plumbs both place and history. The book's first pages set the scene:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us begin in 1964, with three murders. Three stones cast into a pond no one had cared about since the siege of Vicksburg, but which was soon to become the center of the world's attention. A place most people in the United States like to think was somehow different from the rest of the country, but which was in fact the very incarnation of America's tortured soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mississippi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book pulls from the true stories of unspeakable racial violence that gripped Mississippi 50 years ago, and their legacy today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I hope it throws a little bit of light on how complicated relations are between black and white," Iles says. "In Mississippi, black and white live cheek by jowl, day in and day out. It's not some remote problem and it never has been."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the book&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Penn Cage discovers long-buried family secrets when he's forced to defend his idolized father — Tom Cage, the city's favorite doctor — when he's accused of killing his African-American nurse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom Cage is based on Iles' own father, a Natchez doctor he describes as Atticus Finch with a stethoscope. Iles' father died several years ago. Then, in 2011, fate dealt Iles another blow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I pull out on the highway, and a truck hit my driver's door going 70 miles an hour," Iles says. "Took off my right leg from the knee down; broke 20 something bones. But [the] worst thing was it tore my aorta — which, you're shaking hands with death then."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He awoke from a coma eight days later with a different outlook on life — and his work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You go along in sort of a blur. You know, we're all 42, 43 years old. You're doing the same thing every day. You blink your eyes and you're 53, 54 years old. You don't even see the passage of time," he says. "But when fate reaches down and just about kills you, you realize: You know what? I don't have an infinite number of books left to write."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Lens To View One Southern Town, And Race In America&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Natchez Burning&lt;/em&gt; debuted at No. 2 on the &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; best-seller list when it came out in the spring, and it's getting a warm reception in Natchez.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iles recently spent hours signing books at the white-columned Dunleith mansion, where locals remember the author's younger days playing in a rock band. Iles' friend Rod Givens&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;says when the author first started setting his thrillers in Natchez, there was some consternation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"One of the classic examples is ... &lt;em&gt;Turning Angel,&lt;/em&gt;" Givens explains. "And you want to talk about controversial in the town — there you go."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Turning Angel&lt;/em&gt; is about the murder of a popular high school senior and her affair with a married, middle-aged doctor. Givens says Iles' plots certainly get folks talking: " 'Did that really happen?' 'Well, who is it?' ... 'Is he really writing about so and so?' You know, classic Southern gossip."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in &lt;em&gt;Natzchez Burning&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; a key character &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; based on a real person — Stanley Nelson, editor of the &lt;em&gt;Concordia Sentinel&lt;/em&gt;. In Iles' novel, the &lt;em&gt;Concordia&lt;/em&gt;'s editor is fixated on solving the civil rights-era murder of a black music shop owner. In real life, Stanley Nelson &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/2011/02/15/133659641/grand-jury-convenes-to-investigate-1964-cold-case"&gt;tackled the unsolved murder&lt;/a&gt; of Frank Morris, who was killed when his shoe shop was set ablaze in 1964.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Frank Morris was the kind of person in the community that we should embrace, that we should care about," Nelson says. "If we don't fight for justice for those kinds of people, who do we fight for?" He says he hopes that &lt;em&gt;Natchez Burning&lt;/em&gt; can spark candid conversations about the Klan violence that went unpunished 50 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for Iles, he's still focused on figuring out the "why" of things: "All my books are an inquiry into the nature of evil. Why do good people do bad things? Are any human beings completely evil? Do we all have good within us? That's what I'm interested in."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he says Mississippi is a fitting lens through which to view how race shapes the American identity.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Writer+Plumbs+%27Nature+Of+Evil%27+In+Hometown%27s+Violent+Civil+Rights+Past&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>After An Ultimatum, Christians Flee Iraqi City 
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/after-ultimatum-christians-flee-iraqi-city-en-masse/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/after-ultimatum-christians-flee-iraqi-city-en-masse/</id><summary type="html">
</summary></entry><entry><title>In Crowded Gaza, Civilians Have Few Places To Flee 
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/in-gaza-ambulances-race-to-recover-dead-and-wounded/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/in-gaza-ambulances-race-to-recover-dead-and-wounded/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As the Israeli military offensive grew unbearable in her Gaza City neighborhood, Um Rajab Helles fled to the city's main hospital Sunday with her husband and their 12 children even though no one was hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We didn't sleep all Saturday night," she said. "The kids were screaming and we were screaming. They kept running to the front door trying to leave and we pulled them back. Around dawn a relative called and said what are you still doing there? We left at 6 am." &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;They hurried, some barefoot, about a mile to the family that had called them. Later they made their way to Shifa Hospital, thinking it is the only truly safe place to stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday afternoon, Helles sat holding her 7-month-old son on a stretch of grass outside the hospital, crowding under a tree with other women and children, trying to escape the merciless sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the days before it launched its offensive, Israel dropped leaflets and called people in the Shejaiya neighborhood, telling them to leave. Many did. But others were reluctant to abandon their homes and stayed behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This scenario has played out many times in Gaza over the past decade or so and the issue is always the same. Gaza is an extremely crowded place with 1.8 million Palestinians squeezed into a territory that is 25 miles long and about seven miles across at its widest point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Palestinians can not leave Gaza because Israel and Egypt have blocked the crossing points, and there are relatively few places for residents to take refuge. Some have gone to the homes of relatives in areas they think are safer. Others have packed United Nations shelters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One woman, Um Ata Sa'ad, said her family of 15 left home almost two weeks ago, when this round of fighting began, seizing the only shelter they could find at the time. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"On the first day of the war we left our house because of bombing," she said. "We've been staying in a shop storeroom. There's no light or window. Yesterday the shelling reached there. So we came here (to the hospital)."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The kids are a dirty and disheveled bunch. Still, some are irrepressible. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"I love you, I love you," says Mahbouba Helles, 13, practicing her limited English. Her name means to be loved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The families outside Shifa Hospital are among thousands of Palestinians who fled the Shejaiya neighborhood after Israel sent ground troops in on Saturday night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Israeli forces met tough resistance, with 13 Israeli soldiers were killed in that neighborhood. Seven died together when their armored vehicle was hit by an explosive, and three more got trapped inside a burning building, according to the Israeli military. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Gaza health officials say Israeli forces killed scores of Palestinians in Shejaiya. Arabic TV channels called it a massacre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Many people were killed while in their houses or on their way trying to find safe refuge," said Issam Younis, the director of Gaza's Al-Mezan Center for Human Rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambulances raced in to recover dead and wounded during a short ceasefire Sunday. The hospital is only about two miles from the far eastern edge of Shejaiya. That's the side closest to the border with Israel, where the Israeli ground troops entered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the ceasefire, several reporters spotted armed militant fighters on the ground in the neighborhood. Younis said fighters during battle are the only legitimate targets. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;"A militant should hold his weapon, his Kalashnikov. Anyone who is not a combatant, not engaged in a battlefield, he is not a target. Period. Even a militant who is not engaged in a battlefield. He is not a target," said Younis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Israel does target people it believes are militants, wherever they may be. The military stresses it does not intend to harm civilians, although the Gaza Health Ministry says scores of children, as well as women and elderly men, are among the more than 500 Palestinians killed by the Israeli military in the past two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the many civilians delivered to the Shifa Hospital morgue Sunday was a little girl. She was held high as she was carried from the ambulance. Her short black ponytail dangled down.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Inside, Gazans searched for bodies of loved one or space to add another corpse. The morgue door jammed up, as people tried to carry bodies in and out at the same time. After the ambulance unloaded, the driver went out again. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;With more fighting taking place Monday, the ambulances were back out on the streets again.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=In+Crowded+Gaza%2C+Civilians+Have+Few+Places+To+Flee+&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Legal Battle Looms Over Florida Congressional Districts
</title><link href="http://www.wnyc.org/story/legal-battle-looms-over-florida-congressional-districts/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-07-21T05:15:00-04:00</updated><id>/story/legal-battle-looms-over-florida-congressional-districts/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With the midterm election a little more than three months away, a legal battle in Florida has cast uncertainty over the state's upcoming congressional races.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A state judge ruled this month that maps for two of Florida's 27 congressional districts violated the state constitution. He ordered the Legislature to redraw the maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question now is when.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like most states, Florida redrew the maps for its congressional districts after the 2010 census. Some states appoint special commissions to do the job, but in Florida, redistricting is done by the state Legislature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deirdre Macnab, president of Florida's League of Women Voters, says that for decades the Legislature drew congressional district maps with two goals: to protect incumbents and the party in power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"They were able to ensure that their party and their candidates won many, many times without any competition whatsoever," she says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rules for drawing Florida's congressional maps changed, however, in 2010, when voters approved constitutional amendments that required the Legislature to draw maps without regard to incumbents or political parties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sounds simple. But in a state with an entrenched system of lobbyists and consultants expert in manipulating the levers of government, taking politics out of the process was easier said than done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The League of Women Voters and other groups went to court to block the congressional maps, charging that they violated the new rules, and state Judge Terry Lewis agreed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florida's Republican-controlled Legislature promised an open and transparent redistricting process, but Macnab says Lewis found it was anything but. She said there was clear evidence that maps for two Florida congressional districts were drawn to benefit the Republican Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The judge said that the Legislature in fact made a mockery of that statement and had a shadow process going on, which was completely inappropriate," Macnab explains. "He used the word conspire."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The head of Florida's Senate, Republican Don Gaetz, says he doesn't see the judge's ruling as a rebuke. He says the Republican leaders who controlled the process knew they faced a difficult challenge — crafting districts that complied both with federal law and the new state mandates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He's not disappointed with the ruling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Its effect is to hold intact as the Legislature drew them 25 of the 27 congressional districts," he says. "That's pretty good when you consider the fact that we were operating in a process that was unprecedented in this country."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Republican leaders in Florida's Legislature declined to appeal the ruling, telling the court they'll draw new maps for the two contested districts and any others affected by the change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a hearing last week in Tallahassee, one of the attorneys representing the Legislature, George Meros, told Judge Lewis that new maps can't possibly be drawn up in time for the upcoming election for a simple reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is not an impending election," he said. "This election has begun."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florida's primary is just over a month away and absentee ballots have already been sent out to military and overseas voters. County elections supervisors say some have already been returned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron Labasky, who represents Florida's elections supervisors, says it's not just absentee ballots. If there are new districts, there will also have to be a new qualifying period for prospective candidates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"There just doesn't seem to be a window of time sufficient between now and November to re-craft these districts, have new qualifying in the revised districts, have a primary and a subsequent general election on Nov. 4," he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judge Lewis will take the matter up in a hearing Thursday. But along with the difficult deadline, Macnab says there's an even more important issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We believe that the judge stated very clearly that the current map is invalid and unconstitutional," she says. "We do believe that the people of Florida have the right to cast their vote on races and maps that are valid."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, voters cast ballots in the two congressional districts where the maps have now been declared invalid. A Florida judge now has to decide whether to allow it to happen again  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;div class="fullattribution"&gt;Copyright 2014 NPR. To see more, visit &lt;a href="http://www.npr.org/"&gt;http://www.npr.org/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;img src="http://www.google-analytics.com/__utm.gif?utmac=UA-5828686-4&amp;amp;utmdt=Legal+Battle+Looms+Over+Florida+Congressional+Districts&amp;amp;utme=8(APIKey)9(MDEwODYxNTQyMDEzNjAxODk2Nzc2NzNmYQ001)"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>