<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">AugieBlog</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A window inside life at Augustana College</subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-09T15:21:55Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" />
	<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.9">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Natalie Sherman</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Where are they today?]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8355" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8355</id>
		<updated>2014-07-09T15:21:55Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-08T19:44:04Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Natalie Sherman" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="adulthood" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="dog" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="fiance" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Graduation" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="interview" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="jobs" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="personal life" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hi everyone! It&#8217;s been over a month since I graduated, does that mean I am no longer fit to write this blog? I hope not!! My life is still in transition since graduation, I moved back home for the time being, and trust me, fitting 4-years of stuff back into one storage room was exhausting! [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8355"><![CDATA[<p>Hi everyone! It&#8217;s been over a month since I graduated, does that mean I am no longer fit to write this blog? I hope not!!</p>
<p>My life is still in transition since graduation, I moved back home for the time being, and trust me, fitting 4-years of stuff back into one storage room was exhausting! Not to mention that my parents had already begun to take over my bedroom, so rearranging furniture and moving my parents possessions out was a task in itself</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve been working at <a href="http://santasvillagedundee.com/">Santa&#8217;s Village</a> for about a month now, and I must say I really enjoy it. It doesn&#8217;t feel like a job, but that I just get to hang out with cool animals and people all day while my bank account magically grows. It&#8217;s not the end stop of my journey by any means, but I&#8217;m enjoying the ride and learning a lot.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/image.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-8358" src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/image-169x300.jpg" alt="image" width="169" height="300" /></a><a href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/image1-e1404847875713.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-8359" src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/image1-e1404847875713-225x300.jpg" alt="image" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>And I get to take some awesome selfies in my downtime. For all my past experiences, I have worked behind-the-scenes, and now I get to see how it feels working one-on-one with the guests- a totally new perspective.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m still shopping around for careers for the future/at the end of  the amusement park season, as are most of the people I&#8217;m working with. It&#8217;s awesome to work with people my age who have just finished or are finishing their education. We swap stories of what we&#8217;ve done in the past, and where we want to work in the future. In fact, I have an interview tomorrow for what seems like a dream job, so I&#8217;m hoping I won&#8217;t have to frantically find another job once the park is closed for the season. Here goes nothing!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/image2.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-8362" src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/image2-300x300.jpg" alt="image" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>On a more personal note: Kevin and I are doing great (no surprise there) and so is our new dog, Chula- whom we adopted from our wonderful OZO neighbor! <img src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_wink.gif" alt=";)" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
<p>Wherever the road may take us, we&#8217;re a family now, and we stick by each other through  it all. Adult life may be a bit scary, but it has definitely been one fun adventure so far!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8355#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8355" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Victoria Cartland</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Beauty in the Darkness]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8351" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8351</id>
		<updated>2014-05-18T05:05:01Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-18T05:05:01Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Victoria Cartland" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Beauty in the Darkness This week I have been reminded what life is really about. I’ve also been thinking a lot about what I want to get for my next tattoo, a lotus flower, which is far down the road, but it’s always nice to dream! Anyways this post connects those two things; what life [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8351"><![CDATA[<p>Beauty in the Darkness</p>
<p>This week I have been reminded what life is really about. I’ve also been thinking a lot about what I want to get for my next tattoo, a lotus flower, which is far down the road, but it’s always nice to dream! Anyways this post connects those two things; what life is about and lotus flowers.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/lotus-wallpaper-83651366x7688365.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-8352" src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/lotus-wallpaper-83651366x7688365-300x168.jpg" alt="Lotus" width="300" height="168" /></a></p>
<p>As we near the end of both the term and the school year at Augustana, you would be hard pressed to find someone who isn’t at least a little bit stressed out. Everyone has their mind on final papers, final exams, packing to go home for the summer, figuring out summer employment, and a whole slew of other things that arise at the end of the school year and term. Honestly, the end of the school year is usually pretty ugly; there are not a lot of smiles and there are tears (okay, maybe a lot of tears on my part). However, there are also good things. People are happy to go home for the summer and see their “home” friends. People are happy to have jobs for the summer. People are happy to finally be done with classes, especially when some of us have friends who have been done for weeks.</p>
<p>For me, this term has been rough. I’ve been continuing work on both my Political Science and my Sociology Senior Inquiries. I’ve been homesick, missing my little niece and nephews who seem to grow inches in the few short months that I’m gone. I’ve been sick and injured for most of the last 3 weeks. Despite all of this “bad” stuff, I was able to find beauty in it and rise above the circumstances. I have received an “A” on my sociology SI. I’ve successfully finished my junior year of college and made the Dean’s List two terms in a row.</p>
<p>As I mentioned in <a title="Relay for Life 2014" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8280">this </a>post , my Uncle Phil was diagnosed with terminal leukemia in January. I dedicated my Relay walk of 15 miles and a fundraising goal of $500 to Phil. I am so happy that he was able to know that I reached my goal. However, I am saddened to say that my Uncle Phil passed away this past week. While he was in Florida, visiting his parents, he became sick and his body was overcome with sickness that he was able to fight against. But, as this post goes, there is beauty in the darkness and while mourning the loss of Phil I am able to celebrate the birth of a new cousin this week. Well actually a first cousin once removed, as my cousin Justin and his wife had another baby this week! She is absolutely beautiful, and I can’t wait to meet her once I go home in a couple of weeks.</p>
<p>Overall, this year, but especially this term, has taught me to look past the bad that is happening now to see the good that will happen soon.</p>
<p>PS &#8211; Some of you may recognize the content of this post as it was based on a Facebook status that I posted earlier in the week.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8351#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8351" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jessica Leifheit</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[A reflection on my Augustana internship experience]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8341" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8341</id>
		<updated>2014-05-14T06:07:00Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-14T06:07:00Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Jessica Leifheit" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="assignments" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="game notes" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Graduation" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="internship" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="SID" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="sports information" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Sports information office" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Women&#039;s lacrosse" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[If you have been on the Campusnet webpage at all this term chances are that you&#8217;ve seen the link for a few of my blogs. While I wish I could say that I blog this frequently for pure enjoyment, that would be a complete lie. For the academic portion of my six-credit internship in the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8341"><![CDATA[<p>If you have been on the Campusnet webpage at all this term chances are that you&#8217;ve seen the link for a few of my blogs. While I wish I could say that I blog this frequently for pure enjoyment, that would be a complete lie. For the academic portion of my six-credit internship in the sports information office one of my assignments was to complete 30 blogs during the experience. This happens to be blog number 30, but probably not the last.</p>
<p>Another assignment was to conduct phone interviews with three different sports information directors to build my network and gain some different perspectives to the field. Originally I shied away from this requirement, however after those three interviews I wish I would have had a chance to conduct even more! Learning about how SIDs got into their careers is extremely fascinating because very few actually planned to be an SID from the beginning.</p>
<p>A really useful assignment that I completed without reference in my blog was my job packet. I had to prepare all of the materials that I would send to apply for an internship and turn them in to ensure that I was ready for the process.</p>
<p>I think in order to improve an internship similar to mine for the next student a couple alterations could be made. Like I mentioned earlier, the SID interviews were really fun and helpful and I would suggest making an interview due every other week to both encourage the student to keep up with the work and gain a larger network. I would also encourage the addition of an assignment along the lines of creating game notes for a few events, a task that I completed for the first time in preparation for the women&#8217;s lacrosse game against Salisbury this weekend (<a title="Game Notes" href="http://www.suseagulls.com/sports/wlax/2013-14/releases/copy_of_201405108hjqdo" target="_blank">http://www.suseagulls.com/sports/wlax/2013-14/releases/copy_of_201405108hjqdo</a>).</p>
<p>In the end, I received academic credit towards graduation for interning in the sports information office at Augustana. This experience was absolutely amazing and my only regret is that I did not start working in the office until my sophomore year.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8341#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8341" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jessica Leifheit</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[That looks cool!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8332" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8332</id>
		<updated>2014-05-13T03:36:25Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-13T03:36:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Jessica Leifheit" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="augustana" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="bad uniforms" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="hard to read jerseys" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="internship" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="SID nightmare" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="sports information" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="things that annoy SIDs" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[&#160; Everyone loves new uniforms, especially really cool ones! But sometimes those &#8220;cool uniforms&#8221; are impossible to read from further than 10 feet away&#8230;let alone in a press box.  Here are a few examples of jerseys that sports information departments hate! The worst part is, Augustana is guilty of having hard to read jerseys as [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8332"><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Everyone loves new uniforms, especially really cool ones! But sometimes those &#8220;cool uniforms&#8221; are impossible to read from further than 10 feet away&#8230;let alone in a press box.  Here are a few examples of jerseys that sports information departments hate! The worst part is, Augustana is guilty of having hard to read jerseys as well. Our men&#8217;s soccer team has white jerseys with yellow numbers and dark horizontal stripes. Using a darker version of the same color is a nightmare for any stat keepers. Thank goodness for binoculars, otherwise the stats for these teams would be all jumbled due to not being able to read the jerseys!  If you ever have the chance to design an athletic uniform, keep the people doing stats for the team in mind!</p>
<p>For the record, the Augustana basketball jersey that is hard to read belongs to the South Dakota Augustana.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-3.jpg"><img class="alignright size-large wp-image-8333" src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-3-1024x682.jpg" alt="bad jersey 3" width="1024" height="682" /></a> <a href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-4.jpg"><img class="alignright size-large wp-image-8334" src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-4.jpg" alt="bad jersey 4" width="450" height="300" /></a> <a href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-large wp-image-8335" src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-1.jpg" alt="bad jersey 1" width="407" height="400" /></a> <a href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-2.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-8336" src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-2.jpg" alt="bad jersey 2" width="594" height="396" /></a> <a href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-5.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-8337" src="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/bad-jersey-5.jpg" alt="bad jersey 5" width="620" height="366" /></a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8332#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8332" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jessica Leifheit</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[An interview with Dave Hilbert of the University of St. Francis]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8328" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8328</id>
		<updated>2014-05-13T02:42:20Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-13T02:37:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Jessica Leifheit" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Dave Hilbert" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="internship" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="SID" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="sports information" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="University of St. Francis" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="USF" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The third interview that I conducted for my internship at Augustana was with Dave Hilbert of the University of St. Francis located in Joliet, Illinois. With USF being an NAIA competitor, Mr. Hilbert offered a different perspective of sports information, especially considering his background at each different level during his career. &#160; Dave Hilbert – [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8328"><![CDATA[<p>The third interview that I conducted for my internship at Augustana was with Dave Hilbert of the University of St. Francis located in Joliet, Illinois. With USF being an NAIA competitor, Mr. Hilbert offered a different perspective of sports information, especially considering his background at each different level during his career.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Dave Hilbert – University of St. Francis (Joliet) – NAIA</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: How did you get into sports information?</p>
<p>“I went to Michigan Tech. I was starting my senior year and we needed to do some sort of an internship to complete my degree. Since it was a pretty small town most of the internships were done through the campus departments. I had no idea what to do so I went to my advisor and he said that they had just hired a new sports information director and he had passed along that he was looking for someone to work with him. As a freshman I had worked doing statistics in the SID office so I went over there and started working for him. He was almost brand new and he needed someone to come over there who was able to do some real work right away so he turned over a lot of assignments to me. I did a lot of feature writing and game summaries and by halfway through that internship I decided that I want to do this for a living.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: What did you do after your undergrad?</p>
<p>“I went to graduate school at Saint Thomas University in Miami. It was a pretty small school but they had a sports administration program and there wasn’t a whole lot of those programs around. One of the best parts of that program there was just being in Miami there was so much around and so many opportunities to work. I was lucky enough to get an internship at Florida Atlantic University. They hired a new SID whose main job was marketing and sales so they wanted someone to come in to do day-to-day SID work. At the end of that internship the guy that was the SID left so I ended up being the replacement.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: In your office at St. Francis, do you employ a lot of student workers?</p>
<p>“Yeah, we have really just two that work primarily in statistics and game management.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: How many hours do the student workers average each week?</p>
<p>“On average, probably 8-10. Then again some weeks we don’t have games and some weeks we have 5 so on average probably somewhere in that range.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: How many hours would you say that you work a week?</p>
<p>“Somewhere in the 60-70 range. During the summer it’s more like 40 but you make up for it. I think that’s pretty comparable for just about anybody in this business.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: What do you like most about sports information and doing what you do?</p>
<p>“There are a couple of things. One, from a professional standpoint, you almost never have two days that are the same. And definitely no two years are the same. With the changing in technology from one year to the next you never know. Neither of us know what new technology is out there that we are going to have to learn, which in a way is a challenge but it is also a lot of fun. It makes the job a lot more interesting. And more from a personal standpoint, it is fun to be on a college campus everyday. It helps to keep you young. It’s fun to be in the campus setting and get to know and be around the kids.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8328#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8328" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jessica Leifheit</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[An interview with Jim McGrath of Butler]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8325" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8325</id>
		<updated>2014-05-13T02:31:18Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-13T02:31:18Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Jessica Leifheit" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Butler University" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Division I" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="internship" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Jim McGrath" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="SID" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="sports information" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The second interview I conducted was with Jim McGrath of Butler University, formerly our own Augustana College. Mr. McGrath offered a unique perspective having started at Augustana, a Division III institution, and then moving to Butler, a Division I school. &#160; Jim McGrath – Butler University – Division I &#160; Q: How did you get into [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8325"><![CDATA[<p>The second interview I conducted was with Jim McGrath of Butler University, formerly our own Augustana College. Mr. McGrath offered a unique perspective having started at Augustana, a Division III institution, and then moving to Butler, a Division I school.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Jim McGrath – Butler University – Division I</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: How did you get into sports information?</p>
<p>“It was really kind of a round about way. I was actually planning on going onto law school when I was at Augustana. I worked in the sports information office during my last two years as a student and Augie didn’t have a full-time SID at the time, so as students we really did the sports information work. During my senior year I unfortunately got a low draft number and was drafted which meant any career plans I had hoped for, I had to put on hold. Fortunate for me, during the summer right after I got my draft notice and went through my physical and got my orders to report President Nixon halted the call-up and I was put into a holding group and if things would have escalated I would have been in the first group called but I was kind of back on a career track. I hadn’t made any plans to go to law school so I was trying to refigure what I was going to do.  Just about that time the Augustana athletic director called me and said they wanted to make a full-time sports information position and would I be interested. And so I became Augie’s first full-time SID and I did that for 10 years before I turned the reins over to Dave Wrath and came to Butler University.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: What do you see as the biggest differences between Augustana and Butler?</p>
<p>“That would be the level on competition and the notoriety and recognition that goes along with it. Certainly the athletes at Augie worked every bit as hard and had every bit as much success and were terrific people to be around. But being in Division III that Augie was when I left, they were NAIA when I started there, there just isn’t as much national media demand. When I came to Butler, moving up to Division I and then as we progressed from the Horizon League to the Atlantic 10 and now to the Big East the amount of media attention just grew exponentially. “</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: In your office do you employ many student workers?</p>
<p>“We do, we actually use student interns that we get from our journalism school and college of business. They’ll work a semester as an intern. This past year we had four working for us. Some of them have gone on to work into sports information which has been nice. And in fact, some of them I have even hired as assistants here. “</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: How many hours do the student interns work each week?</p>
<p>“We ask that they can commit 10 hours a week. It usually ends up being twice that much with the covering of events. They’ll be in the office maybe 10 hours a week and then they’ll put in another 10 hours working various athletic events that we host.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: How many hours do you put in on average per week?</p>
<p>“Probably close to 70. “</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: What do you like most about sports information?</p>
<p>“I like the variety of the job. How it changes day to day. One of the things I’ve told people is that you can come into the office with a to-do list of things that you plan on getting done on that particular day and one phone call can change all of that. You’ve got to be prepared to change on the fly and turn your attention to another task and still be able to get that first one done. I think the constant activity and variety day to day keeps you young and motivated.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="color: #000000">This interview was part of the academic portion of my internship in the Augustana sports information office. A third interview will soon follow.</span></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8325#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8325" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jessica Leifheit</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[An interview with Dave Blanchard of Luther College]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8322" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8322</id>
		<updated>2014-05-13T02:43:20Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-13T02:19:42Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Jessica Leifheit" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Dave Blanchard" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Division III" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="internship" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Luther College" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="SID" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="sports information" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I had the chance to talk to the sports information director, Dave Blanchard, of Luther College. It was a great chance to see how the Augustana office compares to another Division III institution. &#160; Dave Blanchard – Luther – Division III &#160; Q: Why did you want to be an SID and how did you [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8322"><![CDATA[<p>I had the chance to talk to the sports information director, Dave Blanchard, of Luther College. It was a great chance to see how the Augustana office compares to another Division III institution.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Dave Blanchard – Luther – Division III</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: Why did you want to be an SID and how did you get into it?</p>
<p>“That was strictly accidental. I started coaching men’s basketball at Bethel University (Minn.) where I graduated from college. As I got into the coaching more and as Division III schools do they started piece-mealing things together to get on at a decent full-time so first I was an equipment room manager then head golf coach, then they tossed the sports information thing at me because no one else really wanted to do it. So I just ended up learning it from the ground up.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: Do you have any regrets?</p>
<p>“No, it’s been a good way to make a living. You get to watch athletics. Things have really changed…10 years ago before the internet and websites broke loose the time commitment was drastically different than it is today in the instantaneous world that we live in. To be honest with you, if it would have been like it is today, it would have been harder to sell your soul, especially when you are raising a family. It was a lot easier raising a family in this position than it was coaching because you were always on the road. That’s one thing that I do not regret because I was able to be home and help with the family and get to my kids’ events.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: How many hours would you say that you put in a week?</p>
<p>“It depends on the time of year. In the fall it is a heavy load in the one man shop, plus the transition into winter. On an average I’m guessing that I have to be working somewhere between 60-80 hours a week. It’s seven days a week right now, it never used to be that way but it is now.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: Do you use student workers quite a bit?</p>
<p>“Yes. The school does an excellent job with providing student work opportunities and I use quite a few student workers. That staff has grown drastically, especially now with the video streaming that takes place in our world. So right now I have a student work staff of around 14.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: Do any of your students work office hours with you?</p>
<p>“Yes. There are two things that go on. First, I hire a few athletes that help during their off-season. I do usually have two or three (workers) that keep regular office hours. The most they can work is 10 hours a week and most of our kids are at 6-8 hours. They’ll do stuff like get programs ready and writing releases along with sizing photos for websites. Some of them that want to get into this kind of business, I turn loose and let them go and they are doing things like updating the website, working on bios, and writing game recaps, we use it as a learning experience. “</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: Do any of your students that work the 6-8 hours a week usually help at events?</p>
<p>“Usually not. I have a group set up to help at events. I have three or four kids trained and I try to do it from when they’re freshman on so I have them for a few years.  If we get in a pinch sometimes the people that work in the office will help at events, but not usually.“</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Q: Do you think that you’ve kept up with social media?</p>
<p>“For the most part. We’ve kept up with Facebook and twitter. Those are probably the two that we use the most along with our website. We’ve tried some instagram as well.&#8221;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>This interview was part of the academic portion of my internship in the Augustana sports information office. A couple more will follow.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8322#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8322" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Marie Brzezinski</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Once EDUC340, Always EDUC340]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8320" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8320</id>
		<updated>2014-05-09T19:54:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-09T19:54:14Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Marie Brzezinski" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Clinical" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="education" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="reflection" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="teaching" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This was a line in my EDUC340 professor&#8217;s final &#8220;Random Memorandum&#8221; for the term. Deborah Bracke teaches EDUC340: Methods of Inclusion, a class required by all Education majors, and the Random Memorandum is her weekly email containing any stray thoughts about our week&#8217;s progress. As we come to the end of the term (and the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8320"><![CDATA[<p>This was a line in my EDUC340 professor&#8217;s final &#8220;Random Memorandum&#8221; for the term. Deborah Bracke teaches EDUC340: Methods of Inclusion, a class required by all Education majors, and the Random Memorandum is her weekly email containing any stray thoughts about our week&#8217;s progress.</p>
<p>As we come to the end of the term (and the year!), I&#8217;ve done some serious reflecting on my career as a teacher candidate as well as the amount of growing I&#8217;ve done in just the past year.</p>
<p>At the beginning of the year, I was a scared little baby walking into my first day of EDUC300. I had been told that EDUC300 was the &#8220;weed out&#8221; class of the Education major, and that was proven to me as I progressed through the course material. Randy truly challenged all of us to step outside of our box of assumptions and discover what it really means to be a teacher.</p>
<p>EDUC330 came next, where I learned about the power of assessment. Assessment is far more than just multiple-choice questions, short answer items, and a book report here and there. Assessment is a constant process that teachers go through every day, and I&#8217;ve learned how to craft meaningful assessments for many different kinds of students. Dr. Scarlett&#8217;s first term at Augustana proved to be a great success, and I&#8217;m so thankful to have had him for a professor.</p>
<p>Now, I&#8217;m approaching the end of my sophomore year and the end of EDUC340. Dr. Bracke (or Deb, as I call her) was my first year advisor. The first time I actually met with her was when my mom and I were exchanging tearful hugs at the opening convocation during Fall Connection! Little did I know, I would come to the end of this year having developed a fantastic relationship with Deb. She has helped me through my first clinical experience, deciphering IEPs, and even submit my first paper to a national education conference. I never thought in my wildest dreams that I would have the guts to submit a paper to a national conference full of veteran teachers, but she helped me find the courage to do so. Now we&#8217;re crossing our fingers, waiting until September to find out if we get to travel to San Diego for the 2015 annual conference of the Council for Exceptional Children!</p>
<p>The amount of growing that I&#8217;ve done in the past year is just astounding to me. I came to Augustana to become a teacher, knowing how spectacular the Education department was. However, I didn&#8217;t know just how brilliant every member of the department truly was. So many of them have helped me in just these two first years, and I can&#8217;t wait to see what the second half of my undergrad career has in store for me.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8320#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8320" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jessica Leifheit</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Interviews with SIDs]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8317" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8317</id>
		<updated>2014-05-09T17:17:07Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-09T17:17:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Jessica Leifheit" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Butler" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Dave Blanchard" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Dave Hilbert" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="internship" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="interviews" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Jim McGrath" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Luther" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="sports information" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="University of Saint Francis" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As part of my internship in the sports information office at Augustana this term there has been an academic component that I manage to find time to complete occasionally. One of my assignments was to conduct brief 5-10 minute long phone interviews with three sports information directors that I have never interacted with before. &#160; [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8317"><![CDATA[<p>As part of my internship in the sports information office at Augustana this term there has been an academic component that I manage to find time to complete occasionally. One of my assignments was to conduct brief 5-10 minute long phone interviews with three sports information directors that I have never interacted with before.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The three victims of my interviews were Dave Blanchard from Luther, Jim McGrath of Butler (formerly Augustana), and Dave Hilbert from the University of St. Francis in Joliet, Illinois.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Luther is a Division III school while Butler is Division I and St. Francis is an NAIA institution. Having the opportunity to speak with individuals from three different levels of competition was really interesting. It was cool to learn how different schools, at different levels, operate so similarly.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>In the next couple of days I will get the questions and answers up from those interviews in my blog.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8317#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8317" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jessica Leifheit</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[My Augustana internship experience hosting an NCAA women’s lacrosse game]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8314" />
		<id>http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8314</id>
		<updated>2014-05-09T04:37:45Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-09T04:37:45Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Jessica Leifheit" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="augustana" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="internship" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="NCAA" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="sports information" /><category scheme="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog" term="Women&#039;s lacrosse" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For most people week nine consists of countless tests, quizzes, exams, and presentations. However, my final week nine has been a little different. On top of presenting my senior inquiry research in aquatic biology from this past fall, I have also been planning and preparing for an NCAA second-round women’s lacrosse game along with a [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8314"><![CDATA[<p>For most people week nine consists of countless tests, quizzes, exams, and presentations. However, my final week nine has been a little different. On top of presenting my senior inquiry research in aquatic biology from this past fall, I have also been planning and preparing for an NCAA second-round women’s lacrosse game along with a speech and my internship assignments.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>My experience planning the lacrosse game that takes place on Saturday has been such an awesome opportunity. I have taken part in conference calls along with meetings that give me a first-hand taste of the business. Being a part of everything that goes on behind the scenes of an NCAA event has caused to me gain a great deal of appreciation for the people that make these events run smoothly.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>During the week, I have been busy assigning workers and making sure that they have picked up their game management passes for the contest. I also created a statsheet insert for the programs provided by the NCAA.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It hasn’t taken long for me to realize that planning an event of this caliber requires a lot of small tasks not just a few big things.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>At this point, I would have to say that my favorite part of this experience is how much I have gotten to interact with coaches and officials of the event and being consulted about things regarding the event.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?p=8314#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.augustana.edu/blogs/augieblog/?feed=atom&#038;p=8314" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
