<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:asia.nd.edu,2005:/news-and-events/news</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://asia.nd.edu"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://asia.nd.edu/news-and-events/news.atom"/>
  <title>Liu Institute for Asia and Asian Studies // Liu Institute for Asia and Asian Studies</title>
  <updated>2013-11-05T08:00:00-05:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:asia.nd.edu,2005:News/44688</id>
    <published>2013-11-05T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-12-02T08:52:57-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://asia.nd.edu/news-and-events/news/44688-former-ambassador-to-india-timothy-roemer-to-give-liu-institute-lecture/"/>
    <title>Timothy Roemer, former ambassador to India, to give Liu Institute lecture</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Timothy J. Roemer" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/117027/tim_roemer_300.jpg" title="Timothy J. Roemer" /&gt; Timothy J. Roemer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href="http://newdelhi.usembassy.gov/ambroemertjbio.html"&gt;Timothy J. Roemer&lt;/a&gt;, former U.S. ambassador to India, will give a lecture titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://asia.nd.edu/news-and-events/2013-11-13-roemer/"&gt;Twitter, Buffett, and Darwin: India and the United States Relationship&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; at 4 p.m. Nov. 13 (Wednesday) in the Jordan Auditorium of the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu"&gt;Mendoza College of Business&lt;/a&gt;. The event is free and open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The lecture, which is co-sponsored by the &lt;a href="http://asia.nd.edu/"&gt;Liu Institute for Asia and Asian Studies&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt;, is part of the Liu Institute&amp;rsquo;s Distinguished Speaker Series and Notre Dame International&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/43810-notre-dame-to-celebrate-international-education-week-nov-8-17/"&gt;International Education Week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Roemer, who earned master&amp;rsquo;s and doctoral degrees in political science from Notre Dame in 1981 and 1985, respectively, was elected to Congress in 1990 to represent Indiana&amp;rsquo;s 3rd District. He served six terms, and later was a member of the 9/11 Commission. He was president of the Center for National Policy, a Washington, D.C.-based national security think tank, before being appointed ambassador to the Republic of India by President Barack Obama. He served as ambassador from 2009 to 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;: Liu Institute, &lt;a href="mailto:asia@nd.edu"&gt;asia@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/44002-former-ambassador-to-india-timothy-roemer-to-give-liu-institute-lecture/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;November 05, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:asia.nd.edu,2005:News/44648</id>
    <published>2013-10-22T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-27T11:23:48-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://asia.nd.edu/news-and-events/news/44648-william-kirby-harvards-chang-professor-of-chinese-studies-inaugurates-liu-institute-lecture-series/"/>
    <title>William Kirby, Harvard’s Chang Professor of Chinese  Studies, inaugurates Liu Institute lecture series </title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	On Oct. 18, at the invitation of &lt;a href="http://mcgreevy.nd.edu/"&gt;John T. McGreevy&lt;/a&gt;, dean of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s College of Arts and Letters, &lt;a href="http://history.fas.harvard.edu/people/faculty/kirby.php"&gt;William C. Kirby&lt;/a&gt;, T.M. Chang Professor of China Studies and Spangler Family Professor of Business Administration at Harvard University, gave a lecture titled &amp;ldquo;Can China lead?&amp;nbsp; The world of universities in the 21st century.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="10" src="http://international.nd.edu/assets/116031/192x/10.18.13_william_kirby_lecture_2.jpg" title="10" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Kirby&amp;rsquo;s lecture, derived from an eponymous book forthcoming from Harvard Business Review Press and subtitled &amp;ldquo;Reaching the limits of power and growth,&amp;rdquo; was given in the Officers Meeting Room of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s Main Building to inaugurate the &lt;a href="http://asia.nd.edu/"&gt;Liu Institute for Asia and Asian Studies&lt;/a&gt; Distinguished Speaker Series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Illustrating his presentation with nearly 100 slides illustrating modern Chinese history from the mid-19th century to the present day, Kirby discoursed on the conditions, controversies and promises of higher education in China and around the world since the 19th century, as the most consequential centers and systems of higher education have spread from Europe to the United States and, increasingly, to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Among those listening to Kirby&amp;rsquo;s lecture was 2000 Notre Dame alumnus Justin Liu, president of the RM Liu Foundation and chief operating officer of Tireco Inc. A member of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s College of Arts and Letters Advisory Council, he also serves on the University&amp;rsquo;s Asian Studies Advisory Board. It was a &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/17250-rm-liu-foundation-gift-supports-creation-of-institute-for-asia-and-asian-studies-at-notre-dame/"&gt;gift&lt;/a&gt; of the Liu Foundation, which established the Institute for Asia and Asian Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	At the conclusion of the lecture, &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/about/leadership/council/nicholas-entrikin/"&gt;J. Nicholas Entrikin&lt;/a&gt;, Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s vice president and associate provost for internationalization, thanked both Kirby and Liu for their &amp;ldquo;leadership during a positive movement as we expand our scholarly and cultural engagement with China&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; and presented each of them with a commemorative plaque and framed photograph of Liu, Kirby, Entrikin, College of Arts and Letters Dean John McGreevy, and Liu Institute director &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/mark.shtml"&gt;Nelson Mark&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu/news/43782-william-kirby-harvards-chang-professor-of-chinese-studies-inaugurates-liu-institute-lecture-series/"&gt;international.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;October 22, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:asia.nd.edu,2005:News/44649</id>
    <published>2013-10-18T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-27T11:24:23-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://asia.nd.edu/news-and-events/news/44649-keoughs-make-30-million-gift-to-notre-dame/"/>
    <title>Keoughs make $30 million gift to Notre Dame</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Donald Keough" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/115535/donald_keough_300.jpg" title="Donald Keough" /&gt; Donald Keough&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Donald and Marilyn Keough have made a $30 million gift to the University of Notre Dame to underwrite the construction of a new building for its international institutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	To be named in honor of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s president, &lt;a href="http://president.nd.edu"&gt;Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, the structure will be conjoined to &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/42837-nanovics-make-leadership-gift-for-social-sciences-building-at-notre-dame/"&gt;Nanovic Hall&lt;/a&gt;, a recently announced facility to be built on Notre Dame Avenue south of the Hesburgh Center for International Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;This wonderful gift is the most recent instance of Don and Mickie Keough&amp;rsquo;s tremendous generosity to Notre Dame,&amp;rdquo; Father Jenkins said. &amp;ldquo;I am truly humbled by their request to name this magnificent addition to our campus in my honor, and grateful beyond words for their gift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Don and Mickie&amp;rsquo;s generosity to Notre Dame over the years is unsurpassed, and Don&amp;rsquo;s visionary counsel to me and others at the University has been invaluable. This extraordinary gift will inspire us to become a more global university, bringing the world to Notre Dame and Notre Dame to the world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Jenkins Hall will house Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/"&gt;Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://asia.nd.edu/"&gt;Liu Institute for Asia and Asian Studies&lt;/a&gt;, and provide additional space for the &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://kroc.nd.edu/"&gt;Kroc Institute for International Peace Studies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The adjoining Nanovic Hall will be the new home for the Departments of Economics, Political Science and Sociology, as well as the &lt;a href="http://nanovic.nd.edu/"&gt;Nanovic Institute for European Studies&lt;/a&gt;. The combined complex will total approximately 170,000 square feet. Construction is expected to begin in spring 2015 and be completed by the start of the 2017-18 academic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Don and Mickie have often said that any great university in the 21st century must be a global university,&amp;rdquo; said &lt;a href="http://provost.nd.edu"&gt;Thomas G. Burish&lt;/a&gt;, the University&amp;rsquo;s provost. &amp;ldquo;This gift will enable Notre Dame, in multiple ways, to become even more global than it currently is, including bringing together the key international institutes and related programs in a state-of-the-art facility that will promote collaboration and allow growth. Once again, the Keoughs will help transform Notre Dame.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Donald Keough is chairman of the board of Allen &amp;amp; Company Inc., a New York investment banking firm. He retired as president and chief operating officer of The Coca-Cola Company in 1993. A longtime director of the company, he currently serves as an adviser to the board of directors. He has been a member of the University&amp;rsquo;s Board of Trustees since 1978, serving as chair from 1986 to 1991.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Our family has been blessed in many ways, and that certainly includes the blessing of our longtime association with this great University,&amp;rdquo; Donald Keough said. &amp;ldquo;We believe in the power of Notre Dame to be a force for good in the world, and we know that the research and teaching that will be accomplished in this new facility will contribute to that end. We&amp;rsquo;re especially pleased that the building will bear the name of Father Jenkins, who has made the continued internationalization of the University a top priority.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The Keoughs have made several other significant contributions to Notre Dame for a variety of educational and residential initiatives, including the Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies; two endowed chairs in Irish studies; a summer internship program for Notre Dame students in Ireland; Malloy Hall, which houses the Departments of Theology and Philosophy; three library collections; the restoration of &lt;a href="http://oconnellhouse.nd.edu/"&gt;O&amp;rsquo;Connell House&lt;/a&gt; in Dublin; the Keough-Hesburgh Professorships for leading scholars who demonstrate a commitment to Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s Catholic mission; and a men&amp;rsquo;s residence hall named in Marilyn Keough&amp;rsquo;s honor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Donald Keough received an honorary degree from Notre Dame in 1985 and was the recipient of the University&amp;rsquo;s highest honor, the &lt;a href="http://commencement.nd.edu/archives/laetare-medal/"&gt;Laetare Medal&lt;/a&gt;, in 1993. Marilyn Keough received a Notre Dame honorary degree in 1998.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Their children &amp;mdash; Shayla Keough Rumely, Michael, Patrick and Clarke Keough, and Eileen Keough Millard &amp;mdash; are Notre Dame graduates. Shayla is a member of the University&amp;rsquo;s Board of Trustees, and Michael, Patrick, Clarke and Eileen serve on Notre Dame advisory councils.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Dennis Brown&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/43620-keoughs-make-30-million-gift-to-notre-dame/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;October 18, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Dennis Brown</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:asia.nd.edu,2005:News/44650</id>
    <published>2013-01-21T11:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-27T11:24:58-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://asia.nd.edu/news-and-events/news/44650-nelson-mark-named-acting-director-of-institute-for-asia-and-asian-studies/"/>
    <title>Nelson Mark Named Acting Director of Institute for Asia and Asian Studies</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Nelson Mark" src="http://al.nd.edu/assets/90607/nelson_mark_web_resized.jpg" title="Nelson Mark" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Notre Dame economist Nelson Mark has been appointed acting director of the University&amp;rsquo;s Institute for Asia and Asian Studies. The appointment is effective immediately and runs through July 1, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;As acting director, I am eager to help develop research and academic programming that drive collaborative scholarship on the many interdisciplinary issues that confront Asia,&amp;rdquo; says Mark, the Alfred C. DeCrane Jr. Professor of International Economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The Institute for Asia and Asian Studies is a key piece of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s commitment to international studies, notes Nick Entrikin, vice president and associate provost for internationalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Jonathan Noble" src="http://al.nd.edu/assets/90609/jonathan_noble_web_resized.jpg" title="Jonathan Noble" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;The institute provides the University a great opportunity to make important contributions toward improved understanding of this culturally rich and geopolitically significant region, both by making investments in faculty and by promoting student engagement in Asia-focused scholarship,&amp;rdquo; he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The University has also appointed Jonathan Noble, assistant provost for internationalization, Asia, to serve as acting executive director of the institute under the leadership of Mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;
	Core Pursuits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Endowed by a gift from the RM Liu Foundation, the Institute for Asia and Asian Studies creates a centralized infrastructure to enhance the University&amp;rsquo;s portfolio of ongoing scholarship and programming in Asian studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The institute will focus on four core pursuits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		supporting the University goal of offering an unsurpassed education in Asian studies and for preparing students for leadership roles in a changing global landscape;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		contributing to a better understanding of the particular economic, political, social, cultural, ethical, and religious issues facing Asia through collaborative and multidisciplinary scholarship;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		developing Asia-focused initiatives that build on Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s signature research strengths and contribute to a more positive flow of information, commerce, and understanding between Asia and the rest of the world; and&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		solidifying Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s reputation as the world&amp;rsquo;s premier Catholic research university by developing a strong and visible institutional presence in Asia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;The role and impact Asia has on all of us, both directly and indirectly, is enormous and will continue to remain relevant at least through our lifetimes,&amp;rdquo; says RM Liu Foundation President Justin Liu &amp;rsquo;00. &amp;ldquo;Our goal is to establish a world class, renowned, and multi-disciplinary institute that leverages Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s strengths and that is consistent with the University&amp;rsquo;s overarching mission.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;
	International Reputation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	As a noted scholar of international macroeconomics and the macroeconomics of China, Mark is well suited to play this important role in establishing the institute, says John T. McGreevy, I.A. O&amp;rsquo;Shaughnessy Dean of the College of Arts and Letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Mark is a research associate of the National Bureau of Economic Research and an international research fellow of the Kiel Institute for the World Economy. He has been a visiting scholar at the International Monetary Fund, the Federal Reserve Board, and the Hong Kong Institute for Monetary Research; he has also served as a visiting professor at the University of Chicago, the City University of Hong Kong, and Central University of Finance and Economics in Beijing, among others. Mark is currently the North American editor of the &lt;em&gt;Pacific Economic Review&lt;/em&gt;, which is the official publication of the Hong Kong Economic Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The author of a textbook titled &lt;em&gt;International Macroeconomics and Finance: Theory and Empirical Methods&lt;/em&gt;, Mark currently teaches an advanced undergraduate course called the Economics of China. His recent research focuses on understanding that nation&amp;rsquo;s high saving rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;China&amp;rsquo;s remarkable record of investment-led economic growth has been financed by an astonishingly high national saving rate exceeding 50 percent of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;GDP&lt;/span&gt;,&amp;rdquo; Mark says, &amp;ldquo;but the high saving rate also contributes to trade and current account imbalances which have become a source of international tension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;As China continues its transition towards a market-based economy, policy makers seek to rebalance the engine of growth away from investment towards consumption, which would require less saving by the Chinese and more saving by Americans. Hence,&amp;rdquo; Mark says, &amp;ldquo;a necessary precondition to have a productive conversation about growth re-balancing would be to have a good understanding of why the Chinese save so much.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Marks&amp;rsquo; research has been published in the &lt;em&gt;American Economic Review&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Review of Economic Studies&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Monetary Economics&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Journal of International Economics&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In addition to serving as an assistant provost, Noble is director of Notre Dame International&amp;rsquo;s Asia office in Beijing, China. His research focuses on contemporary Chinese culture and society, and he has published numerous articles, essays, and translations, including translations of film scripts for &lt;em&gt;Blind Shaft&lt;/em&gt;, which won the Silver Bear in the 2003 Berlin International Film Festival, and the Chinese blockbusters &lt;em&gt;The Assembly&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Aftershock&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Noble received a Ph.D. in East Asian languages and literatures from The Ohio State University in 2003. He was also one of just 20 young China scholars in the United States selected to participate in the Public Intellectuals Program (2005-2008) sponsored by the National Committee on U.S.&amp;ndash;China Relations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;
	Learn More &amp;gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://economics.nd.edu/the-faculty/nelson-mark/"&gt;Nelson Mark webpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://www.notredameasia.org/leadership_and_board/director/"&gt;Jonathan S. Noble webpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/17250-rm-liu-foundation-gift-supports-creation-of-institute-for-asia-and-asian-studies-at-notre-dame/"&gt;Related story: Liu Gift Endows New Institute for Asia and Asian Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame International&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://www.notredameasia.org/"&gt;Notre Dame in Asia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://eastasian.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of East Asian Languages and Cultures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://economics.nd.edu"&gt;Department of Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published at &lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu"&gt;international.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Kate Cohorst&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/37039-nelson-mark-named-acting-director-of-institute-for-asia-and-asian-studies/"&gt;al.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;January 21, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Kate Cohorst</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:asia.nd.edu,2005:News/44651</id>
    <published>2012-06-11T11:25:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-27T11:25:52-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://asia.nd.edu/news-and-events/news/44651-college-of-arts-and-letters-launches-international-economics-major/"/>
    <title>College of Arts and Letters Launches International Economics Major</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="College of Arts and Letters graduates" src="http://al.nd.edu/assets/70374/int_l_econ_resized.jpg" title="College of Arts and Letters graduates" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Linguistic and cultural fluency is an increasingly important asset in business. And to address the growing demand for professionals who can both understand and help shape the world market, Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s College of Arts and Letters has created a new major in international economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The program&amp;mdash;the College&amp;rsquo;s first new major in almost a decade&amp;mdash;combines substantial coursework in the Department of Economics with advanced training in language and culture, starting with French, Italian, or Spanish. It will also provide students with the potential for overseas internships and specialized research projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;This program will be an attractive option for ambitious, sophisticated, and savvy Notre Dame undergraduates seeking to prepare themselves for successful international careers,&amp;rdquo; says Richard Jensen, Gilbert F. Schaefer Professor of Economics and chair of the Department of Economics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	These careers, he says, span the government and nonprofits as well as multinational corporations and more local entities that do business overseas or have international interests in areas such as research, law, or even the arts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;
	Global Citizens&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;The new major&amp;rsquo;s blend of economics with foreign language and culture exemplifies the College&amp;rsquo;s liberal arts approach to nurturing the development of future global citizens,&amp;rdquo; says Theodore Cachey, professor and chair in the Department of Romance Languages and Literatures, who, together with Jensen, spearheaded the initiative for the new course of study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Students in this major will take an introductory class called Exploring International Economics, plus a minimum of eight economics courses and seven to 10 intermediate and advanced courses in French, Italian, or Spanish, including at least four that have a cultural, economic, and/or historical emphasis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Under the guidance of faculty mentors, all international economics majors will also complete a capstone research project that integrates the analytical aspects of economics with the linguistic and cultural aspects of a Romance language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The course offerings and program initiatives in the new major, Cachey says, are designed to help students understand how aesthetic and cultural categories and value judgments are shaped by&amp;mdash;and, in turn, influence&amp;mdash;economic trends and political conditions, whether they go on to graduate school or immediately enter the business world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;We will produce graduates,&amp;rdquo; he says, &amp;ldquo;who will become leaders and global citizens in a world that is increasingly interconnected from an economic point of view and requires individuals with a specialized knowledge of local languages and cultures to navigate the uneven terrain of the world&amp;rsquo;s environmental, cultural, social, economic, and political geographies.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;
	World Leaders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Both Cachey and Jensen say they intend to expand the international economics major beyond their two departments, and anticipate collaborating with other foreign language and culture programs in the College, including Arabic, Chinese, Japanese, and Korean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;The new international economics major has tremendous potential for our majors in the Department of East Asian Languages and Cultures,&amp;rdquo; says that department&amp;rsquo;s chair, Dayle Seidenspinner-N&amp;uacute;&amp;ntilde;ez, who notes that many East Asian languages students already choose to double major in either economics or business. &amp;ldquo;We hope to offer this new option to them soon.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The new major&amp;rsquo;s distinctive approach will not only serve students well, Jensen says, it can also make a difference in the marketplace as the College&amp;rsquo;s international economics majors move into leadership positions in their careers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Quoting from the University&amp;rsquo;s mission statement, he says, &amp;ldquo;This new major has a direct correlation to Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s commitment to &amp;lsquo;constructive and critical engagement with the whole of human culture.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;
	Learn More &amp;gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://economics.nd.edu"&gt;Department of Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://romancelanguages.nd.edu"&gt;Department of Romance Languages and Literatures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://eastasian.nd.edu"&gt;Department of East Asian Languages and Cultures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/27271-college-of-arts-and-letters-introduces-new-business-economics-minor/"&gt;Related story: College of Arts and Letters Introduces New Business Economics Minor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Joanna Basile&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/31334-college-of-arts-and-letters-launches-international-economics-major/"&gt;al.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 11, 2012&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joanna Basile</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
