<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en"
  xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Jonathan McCombs, MSCJ, PhD (ABD)</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-10T17:26:17Z</updated>
	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="2.9.1">WordPress</generator>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" />
	<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/feed/atom/" />

			<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Legal Marijuana creates some other legal issues]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/10/legal-marijuana-creates-some-other-legal-issues/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=107</id>
		<updated>2014-07-10T17:26:17Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-10T17:25:09Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="My CRJ Blog" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Spokane, Washington began selling marijuana legally this week.  One of the first people to buy marijuana in the State of Washington was pictured in media outlets.  However, the next day he was fired from his job for failing a drug test.  The legalization of marijuana in some states can and will cause [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/10/legal-marijuana-creates-some-other-legal-issues/"><![CDATA[<p>Spokane, Washington began selling marijuana legally this week.  One of the first people to buy marijuana in the State of Washington was pictured in media outlets.  However, the next day he was fired from his job for failing a drug test.  The legalization of marijuana in some states can and will cause some additional legal issues that people need to consider. <a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/wash-man-buy-legal-weed-spokane-fired-spotted-news-article-1.1861214"> NYTimes article.</a></p>
<p>What happens when a tourists visit Colorado or Washington and buys marijuana legally but then returns to their home state to fail a pre-employment drug test.  They obtained the substance legally but policies in companies still persist as making this practice a violation of policy.  Do you think this will change as time goes by?</p>
<p>Legal in one sense does not necessarily mean that there are not additional consequences to partaking in this sort of activity.  Tourists and even residents of Colorado and Washington state need to consider that their employer may not be inclined to condone marijuana use even if it is legal.  The next question, are there employment law or case law precedents for companies regulating conduct outside of work hours.  Certainly, drug testing has been legally validated with respect to a public safety interest and especially when employees are driving on the job.  A new litany of case law may need to be litigated to decide the issue of legal marijuana use.  In the meantime, marijuana users should be careful to consult their own employer&#8217;s policy before engaging in this behavior.  </p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/10/legal-marijuana-creates-some-other-legal-issues/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/10/legal-marijuana-creates-some-other-legal-issues/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[CJAD Call for Members- Students?]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/09/cjad-call-for-members-students/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=104</id>
		<updated>2014-07-09T17:36:25Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-09T17:36:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="CJAD Honor Society" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[July 9, 2014
CJAD Students, 
Call for Membership and Induction Ceremony
In October we will be holding an additional honor society class induction ceremony.  The requirements of membership are below.  Please consider this excellent resume/cv builder as you think about things to accomplish while in school at Franklin University.  
Officers
In addition to the induction [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/09/cjad-call-for-members-students/"><![CDATA[<p>July 9, 2014<br />
CJAD Students, </p>
<p><strong>Call for Membership and Induction Ceremony</strong><br />
In October we will be holding an additional honor society class induction ceremony.  The requirements of membership are below.  Please consider this excellent resume/cv builder as you think about things to accomplish while in school at Franklin University.  </p>
<p><strong>Officers</strong><br />
In addition to the induction ceremony, we will be electing new officers for the coming year and planning events/meetings.  Please consider this additional responsibility/opportunity to showcase yourself and your talents.  We will need a President, Vice President, and Secretary.  These officers will work closely with me to plan and administer the organization throughout the year.  It is not really a lot of work and is a tremendous amount of fun!</p>
<p><strong>Honor Society Membership Requirements</strong><br />
Baccalaureate students shall be enrolled in the institution represented by the chapter, have declared a major, minor or equivalent in the criminal justice or related field, have completed three full time semesters or its equivalent, have a minimum GPA of 3.2 on a 4.0 scale, with a minimum GPA of 3.2 in courses in criminal justice related fields and rank in the top 35% of their class. A minimum of four courses of the above course work shall be in the criminal justice field.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.alphaphisigma.org/">http://www.alphaphisigma.org/</a></p>
<p><strong>Benefits of Membership</strong><br />
•	Addition to resume/cv with regard to academic honors and extracurricular activities.<br />
•	Interact with other CJAD students and faculty outside of class.<br />
•	Organize and participate in meetings with specialized guest speakers.<br />
•	Networking with faculty, employers, and advisory committee members</p>
<p>If you are interested in one or both of these opportunities, please email me today – <strong>jonathan.mccombs@franklin.edu</strong><em></p>
<p>Thank you!</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/09/cjad-call-for-members-students/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/09/cjad-call-for-members-students/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Crime is Resilient- Cybercrime is harder]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/09/crime-is-resilient-cybercrime-is-harder/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=97</id>
		<updated>2014-07-09T17:34:13Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-09T17:33:21Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="My CRJ Blog" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In this technology age, we see more and more criminals going digital.  They can steal money or credit cards from a distance and in many cases beyond the arm of the law.  In many instances they remain undetected and are able to steal many more thousands or millions of dollars than they might [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/09/crime-is-resilient-cybercrime-is-harder/"><![CDATA[<p>In this technology age, we see more and more criminals going digital.  They can steal money or credit cards from a distance and in many cases beyond the arm of the law.  In many instances they remain undetected and are able to steal many more thousands or millions of dollars than they might have otherwise been able to steel with a conventional robbery.  Greed still lives in this age and legal prosecution tools still work.  The Wall Street Journal published an <a href="http://online.wsj.com/articles/cybercrime-is-likened-to-organized-crime-1404841253?KEYWORDS=crime">article</a> in today’s edition about the use of the RICO (Racketeering Influenced and Corrupt Organizations) statute to combat international cyber criminals.  Crime is about opportunity and it evolves to combat being caught.  </p>
<p>Criminals seem to persist through time.  They evolve and they are able to elude capture with very innovative means.  They are very motivated.  They are motivated much more than prosecutors who are just seeking another notch in their belts.  In this digital age where everyone is connected, crime seems to flourish.<br />
The RICO statute was created to combat mafia crime families who would infiltrate neighborhoods and would create a culture of their own.  They would demand money of businesses and serve the black market for whatever the economy demanded be provided.  In the 1920’s, during the era of prohibition, this was often illegal alcohol and gambling.  In fact, much of the case law and statutory law revolves around an organized crime history.  Fast forward to present day and it is now common place for organized criminals to be involved in whatever criminal enterprise they might be good at.  Supplying illegal drugs has been a long standing criminal enterprise.  Now obtaining and selling stolen credit card numbers seems to be the digital criminal enterprise of choice.  Which one comes first, the criminal enterprise or the crime? </p>
<p>Throughout history we see that organized crime has been created to efficiently support the evolution, production, and continuation of crimes that make money.  The enterprises are created in partnerships much like in legitimate businesses where a market is found and an enterprise is created of people that can make this thing happen.  Law enforcement is tasked with combating these organizations through identifying the criminals in the organization and then providing evidence of their criminal activity for prosecution.  I used to do this sort of evidentiary building as a narcotics investigator and gun trafficking investigator.  It was truly a rewarding experience.  However, I am coming to realize that combating crime in this way is counter-intuitive.  There will always be people in plentiful numbers that move to conduct illegal activities for their own profit and many times at great risk to their own survival. </p>
<p>We see very little difference with digital crime other than the fact that defendants are more difficult to prosecute.  The arm of courts seems too short to combat the problem effectively when criminals are in Russian or other unfriendly extradition countries.  The time is now to seek a multijurisdictional arena for the combat of cyber criminals to go beyond international borders and to get cyber criminals wherever they are located.  The other side of the coin is that we have to allow other countries to extradite American citizens that do this sort of thing abroad.  Is it worth the benefit?</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/09/crime-is-resilient-cybercrime-is-harder/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/07/09/crime-is-resilient-cybercrime-is-harder/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching Undergraduate CRJ after retirement seminar&#8230;]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/17/teaching-undergraduate-crj-after-retirement-seminar/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=90</id>
		<updated>2014-06-17T17:12:08Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-17T17:12:08Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="Presentations" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Columbus PD Teaching in HE Seminar Flyer aug 22 2014
Teaching Criminal Justice at the Undergraduate Level:  You will need a Master’s Degree!
As a law enforcement officer you have spent a career learning, teaching, and gaining valuable experience in the Criminal Justice field.  You may be looking at retirement as an opportunity to teach [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/17/teaching-undergraduate-crj-after-retirement-seminar/"><![CDATA[<p><a href='http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/files/2014/06/Columbus-PD-Teaching-in-HE-Seminar-Flyer-aug-22-2014.pdf'>Columbus PD Teaching in HE Seminar Flyer aug 22 2014</a></p>
<p>Teaching Criminal Justice at the Undergraduate Level:  You will need a Master’s Degree!<br />
As a law enforcement officer you have spent a career learning, teaching, and gaining valuable experience in the Criminal Justice field.  You may be looking at retirement as an opportunity to teach at colleges or universities and to help give back to a new generation of criminal justice practitioners.   This presentation will help to answer questions many have asked.<br />
•	How should you prepare to teach at the undergraduate level?<br />
•	Credentials, what are they and why do they matter?<br />
•	What is the difference between a cv and a resume?<br />
•	How is teaching in a higher education institution different from training in public safety?</p>
<p>Where:	                Columbus Division of Police Academy (Hague Avenue)<br />
When: 			August 22, 2014	10:00 AM-11:30 AM<br />
RSVP:			jonathan.mccombs@franklin.edu</p>
<p>NO COST SEMINAR</p>

<a href='http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/17/teaching-undergraduate-crj-after-retirement-seminar/cohpa-seal/' title='COHPA seal'><img width="150" height="150" src="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/files/2014/06/COHPA-seal-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="" title="COHPA seal" /></a>

]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/17/teaching-undergraduate-crj-after-retirement-seminar/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/17/teaching-undergraduate-crj-after-retirement-seminar/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Cell Phone Tracking Opinion and the Mosaic Theory]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/12/cell-phone-tracking-opinion-and-the-mosaic-theory/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=86</id>
		<updated>2014-06-12T14:32:17Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-12T14:30:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="My CRJ Blog" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The ruling by Judge David Sentelle and his panel of Appeals Court Judges in the 11th U.S. Circuit was published yesterday and articles in the Wall Street Journal and other media sites have stated that tracking cell site hits of a cell phone is a 4th Ammendment siezure.  This is true if reading the [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/12/cell-phone-tracking-opinion-and-the-mosaic-theory/"><![CDATA[<p>The ruling by Judge David Sentelle and his panel of Appeals Court Judges in the 11th U.S. Circuit was published yesterday and articles in the Wall Street Journal and other media sites have stated that tracking cell site hits of a cell phone is a 4th Ammendment siezure.  This is true if reading the opinion but there is more at stake for law enforcement and intelligence agencies.  </p>
<p>Cell site location data is transmitted by a phone when a call is made and the opinion of the 11th Circuit Court of Appeals is clear that law enforcement needs a warrant to obtain this information.  The easy answer for law enforcement is to obtain warrants when in the process of investigating such crimes where, in this case, cell site information is pivotal to establishing the location of the defendant as related to various violent crimes.  However, if you read the opinion carefully one might be more disturbed.  </p>
<p>Judge Sentelle provides an excellent legal lineage of case law related to the right to privacy and its application to electronic data.  In fact, my cybercrime course could use this opinion to sum up much of the law around cyber privacy.  However, the Judge and his panel rely on United States v. Jones, 451 F. Supp. 2d 71, GPS monitoring case where the court said that electronic transmissions of electronic data were not a privacy issue but that the aggregation of the location information would be private.  This is contrary to the Mosaic Theory commonly espoused by government and intelligence agencies when supporting analytic aggregation of information and that is briefly mentioned by Judge Sentelle with citations for CIA v. Simms, 471 U.S. 159.  </p>
<p>Think about what this says.  If agencies obtain information by whatever means (electronic, surveillance, etc.) and they utilize their expert analysis capabilities to produce more valuable intelligence information, the product could amount to private information for which a defendant would have a right to privacy protected under the Fourth Amendment.  </p>
<p>Intelligence agencies have collected and aggregated information for decades that makes for more useful information in both criminal investigations and anti-terror investigations.  Electronic evidence is just one piece of this &#8220;mosaic&#8221; puzzle.  The true &#8216;Smart Policing&#8217; that many have espoused will be a force multiplier of police and make for more analytical policing could be in jeopardy.<br />
<a href="https://www.aclu.org/sites/default/files/assets/q_davis_opinion_0.pdf"></p>
<p>https://www.aclu.org/sites/default/files/assets/q_davis_opinion_0.pdf</a></p>
<p>Also published on LinkedIn.  </p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/12/cell-phone-tracking-opinion-and-the-mosaic-theory/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/12/cell-phone-tracking-opinion-and-the-mosaic-theory/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Predictive Policing]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/06/predictive-policing/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=81</id>
		<updated>2014-06-06T14:46:33Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-06T14:46:33Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="My CRJ Blog" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Predicting crime like in the movie, &#8220;The Minority Report&#8221; is farfetched and unrealistic.  However, law enforcement intelligence analysts have been putting together crime data to get a much better understanding of how crime will be committed in the future.  Good analysis is not palm reading or absolute, but it does help to multiply [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/06/predictive-policing/"><![CDATA[<p>Predicting crime like in the movie, &#8220;The Minority Report&#8221; is farfetched and unrealistic.  However, law enforcement intelligence analysts have been putting together crime data to get a much better understanding of how crime will be committed in the future.  Good analysis is not palm reading or absolute, but it does help to multiply a police force under-staffed by years of budget cuts and other cost saving measures.  </p>
<p><a href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/files/2014/06/predictive.jpg"><img src="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/files/2014/06/predictive.jpg" alt="" title="predictive" width="222" height="245" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-82" /></a></p>
<p>The <a href="http://http://www.nij.gov/journals/266/pages/predictive.aspx?ref=nf">National Institute of Justice</a> provided an excellent article by Beth Pearsall that outlines what predictive policing is and what it is not.  Predictive policing is one of those police practices that is an excellent example of how research can translate well into practice.  As Pearsall references, it takes a community effort with full police officer support to really make predictive policing work.  </p>
<p>As we think about how grocery stores and big box stores across the country are calculating our every purchase with big data analytics for everything from product placement to product ideas we must think how this sort of technology will help policing and criminal justice.  The privacy advocates will likely be concerned but their concerns are not warranted when research and data is analyzed in the aggregate instead of at the individual level.  If individuals happen to get caught then it should be chalked up to good police work not an invasion of privacy.  </p>
<p>The police officers of the next generation will be less reliant on intuition and &#8220;gut&#8221; feelings and more in tune with data analytics.  This sort of analysis will require a higher level of education and more critical thinking.  Privacy advocates should embrace this sort of shift toward &#8216;Smart&#8217; policing as a way to target true criminals.  </p>
<p>An example of the work being done in academia and its translation to practice is in the body of research conducted by Dr. Jerry Ratcliffe.  Many of his books and publications can be found at his <a href="http://www.jratcliffe.net/">website</a>.  I had the opportunity to see him present at the <a href="http://www.ialeia.org/">International Association of Law Enforcement Intelligence Analysts </a>conference in Boston, MA in 2008.  It was truly a fascinating presentation and indicative of some of his cutting edge work.  </p>
<p>Franklin University, Criminal Justice Administration program, will be offering CJAD 415-Contemporary Policing Strategies and ISS in the Fall term.  This course has the textbook written by Dr. Ratcliffe and is focused on intelligence-led policing.  If you are interested in pursuing a Bachelor&#8217;s degree in Criminal Justice Administration then consider Franklin University and its quality online courses to begin your journey.  <a href="http://www.franklin.edu/getting-started/undergraduate-admissions-process">Apply today!</a></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/06/predictive-policing/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/06/06/predictive-policing/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[More Mayberry and Less Falujah: The Militarization of the Police]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/05/29/more-mayberry-and-less-falujah-the-militarization-of-the-police/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=72</id>
		<updated>2014-05-29T14:22:36Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-29T13:58:50Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="Interesting Articles" /><category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="My CRJ Blog" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A recent article in the Wall Street Journal, “Towns Say ‘No Tanks’ to Militarized Police” by Jennifer Levitz (2014) seems to outline a symptom of a growing debate in communities across the country.  One need only look back to the last three major war events in U.S. history to see a buildup of para-military [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/05/29/more-mayberry-and-less-falujah-the-militarization-of-the-police/"><![CDATA[<p>A recent article in the Wall Street Journal, “<a href="http://online.wsj.com/news/articles/SB10001424052702304450904579366963588434656?mod=WSJ_WSJ_US_News_5&amp;cb=logged0.33533590547102804">Towns Say ‘No Tanks’ to Militarized Police</a>” by Jennifer Levitz (2014) seems to outline a symptom of a growing debate in communities across the country.  One need only look back to the last three major war events in U.S. history to see a buildup of para-military ideology within law enforcement.  It is logical to connect the end of the War in Afghanistan and Iraq and its closure to a growing group of post-military professionals within law enforcement ranks and a growing need for the U.S. military to get rid of excess equipment.  In light of public opinion and the research, one might be hard pressed to find a good reason to continue to militarize the police.</p>
<p><img src="http://si.wsj.net/public/resources/images/NA-BZ963_TANKS1_G_20140206222428.jpg" alt="" width="553" height="369" /></p>
<p>The goal of domestic law enforcement is to maintain the peace which is starkly different than a military mission.  At specific times, public support for militarization could be attributed to a growing number of school and mall shootings along with such major events as the 9/11/2001 terror attacks in New York and Washington, D.C.  In fact, Regan’s ‘War on Drugs’ has been provided a reason for much of the militarization of the police over the last several decades.</p>
<p>The American Civil Liberties Union has launched a nationwide investigation into the police use of military technology and tactics.  They highlight the SWAT team killing of seven year old Aiyana Jones in Michigan who was shot when a SWAT team entered a house where she was sleeping on the couch after throwing a flash bang onto her blanket which caught on fire.  These sorts of tactics take place all over the country and give credence to the notion that the police are not as approachable as they used to be in the past.</p>
<p><a id="irc_mil" href="http://www.google.com/url?sa=i&amp;rct=j&amp;q=&amp;esrc=s&amp;frm=1&amp;source=images&amp;cd=&amp;cad=rja&amp;uact=8&amp;docid=uvPm_NCDvegwZM&amp;tbnid=Ibr2POK333XrRM:&amp;ved=0CAUQjRw&amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2012%2F07%2F04%2Farts%2Ftelevision%2Fandy-griffith-actor-dies-at-86.html&amp;ei=_DyHU9O8LI2MyAS2loKABg&amp;bvm=bv.68114441,d.aWw&amp;psig=AFQjCNEK2uKbBYzetueiDneU5E7ylDSpBQ&amp;ust=1401458298563742"><img src="http://graphics8.nytimes.com/images/2012/07/03/arts/GRIFFITH_337/GRIFFITH_337-articleLarge-v2.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="370" /></a></p>
<p>What can be done to provide more Mayberry style police officers and agencies?  Many people grew up watching Andy Griffith and learned how small-town law enforcement in the deep South was more about relationships than it was about the law.  Certainly, in a more litigious society, this might not always be absolutely true.  However, more should be done to eliminate and mitigate barriers between the police and the society they protect.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/05/29/more-mayberry-and-less-falujah-the-militarization-of-the-police/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/05/29/more-mayberry-and-less-falujah-the-militarization-of-the-police/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Honor Society Meeting and Webinar on&#8230;Criminal Justice in &#8220;The Walking Dead&#8221;]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/05/07/honor-society-meeting-and-webinar-on-criminal-justice-in-the-walking-dead/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=58</id>
		<updated>2014-05-07T13:38:18Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-07T13:04:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="CJAD Honor Society" /><category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="Presentations" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Criminal Justice concepts in the popular television show, “The Walking Dead.”  
The Walking Dead is a very popular television show and it has some interesting components to the show that highlight criminal justice issues and topics.  Join us as we have a brief Honor Society meeting followed by an hour long Webinar showing [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/05/07/honor-society-meeting-and-webinar-on-criminal-justice-in-the-walking-dead/"><![CDATA[<p>Criminal Justice concepts in the popular television show, “The Walking Dead.”  </p>
<p>The Walking Dead is a very popular television show and it has some interesting components to the show that highlight criminal justice issues and topics.  Join us as we have a brief Honor Society meeting followed by an hour long Webinar showing you how to look for examples of criminal justice concepts in the show.  </p>
<p><strong>Where:	FranklinLive (Web Conferencing)<br />
Who:	        Open to anyone<br />
When: 	June 4, 2014  8:00 PM<br />
RSVP:	<a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/honor-society-meeting-and-criminal-justice-in-the-walking-dead-webinar-tickets-11554885975">Registration</a></p>
<p>The FranklinLive link will only be available to those that RSVP to the above email address<br />
by June 2, 2014.  </p>
<p>Please inquire about the Criminal Justice Administration Program at Franklin University or the CJAD Honor Society.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/05/07/honor-society-meeting-and-webinar-on-criminal-justice-in-the-walking-dead/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/05/07/honor-society-meeting-and-webinar-on-criminal-justice-in-the-walking-dead/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Criminal Justice Administration Honor Society Meeting]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/03/26/criminal-justice-administration-honor-society-meeting/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=43</id>
		<updated>2014-03-26T15:13:37Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-26T15:13:18Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="CJAD Honor Society" /><category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="Research" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Franklin University is holding an Honor Society meeting on Monday March 31 at 6pm in Frasch Hall Room 221.  Make plans to attend as we discover and plan for the coming year.  Our officers are excited to get everyone involved in this planning event.  
The meeting will also be available on FranklinLive, [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/03/26/criminal-justice-administration-honor-society-meeting/"><![CDATA[<p>Franklin University is holding an Honor Society meeting on Monday March 31 at 6pm in Frasch Hall Room 221.  Make plans to attend as we discover and plan for the coming year.  Our officers are excited to get everyone involved in this planning event.  </p>
<p>The meeting will also be available on FranklinLive, if you cannot attend on campus.  Please email jonathan.mccombs@franklin.edu if you will need to attend via FranklinLive!  </p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/03/26/criminal-justice-administration-honor-society-meeting/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/03/26/criminal-justice-administration-honor-society-meeting/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>jonathan-mccombs</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Criminal Justice Related Internships Project]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/03/26/criminal-justice-related-internships-project/" />
		<id>http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/?p=40</id>
		<updated>2014-03-28T12:24:20Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-26T14:59:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="Internships" /><category scheme="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs" term="Research" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In an effort to provide students robust learning opportunities in the Criminal Justice field, the Criminal Justice Administration program is currently seeking internship contacts and other information from Criminal Justice related agencies in Ohio and throughout the Midwest.  If your agency is willing to host a student for 6 weeks or longer then please [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/03/26/criminal-justice-related-internships-project/"><![CDATA[<p>In an effort to provide students robust learning opportunities in the Criminal Justice field, the Criminal Justice Administration program is currently seeking internship contacts and other information from Criminal Justice related agencies in Ohio and throughout the Midwest.  If your agency is willing to host a student for 6 weeks or longer then please contact us immediately so that we can get you on the list- jonathan.mccombs@franklin.edu.</p>
<p>Students should be aware that internships are an important component of their education and an opportunity for them to learn how the content they have been learning in courses is applied in the field.  We have already been in contact with the following agencies who are interested in interns.  If you are interested in an internship please contact Jonathan McCombs at jonthan.mccombs@franklin.edu, Lead Faculty in Criminal Justice Administration at Franklin University.</p>
<p>Ohio Bureau of Workers Compensation- Office of Special Investigations	</p>
<p>Ohio State University Police Department	</p>
<p>Grove City Police Department	</p>
<p>Whitehall Police Department	</p>
<p>Minerva Park Police Department	</p>
<p>Dublin Police Department	</p>
<p>Ohio Attorney General&#8217;s Office	</p>
<p>United States Pretrial Services- Southern District of Ohio	</p>
<p>Ohio Department of Rehabilitation and Corrections (All Institutions)	</p>
<p>US Attorney&#8217;s Office Southern District of Ohio	</p>
<p>United States Supreme Court	</p>
<p>Union County Sheriff&#8217;s Office	</p>
<p>Columbus Airport Authority Police Department	</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/03/26/criminal-justice-related-internships-project/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://faculty.franklin.edu/jonathan-mccombs/2014/03/26/criminal-justice-related-internships-project/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
