<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en"
  xml:base="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Science &#38; the CSU</title>
	<subtitle type="text">Science and the CSU</subtitle>

	<updated>2014-04-07T19:08:49Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" />
	<id>http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?feed=atom</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?feed=atom" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.0.5">WordPress</generator>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>sthara</name>
						<uri>http://www.calstate.edu/pa/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Student Researchers Connect with CSU President, Trustees]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2392" />
		<id>http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2392</id>
		<updated>2014-04-07T19:08:49Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-02T21:12:54Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="News &amp; Notes" /><category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="COAST" /><category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="WRPI" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[CSU Bakersfield student Kelsey Padilla discussing her research on the relationship between sea surface temperatures and precipitation levels with CSUB President Horace Mitchell and Governor Jerry Brown Student researchers and their faculty mentors spend years working on projects that help solve complex water and coastal zone challenges. For 25 student-faculty teams, their experiments culminated with [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2392"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/COAT_WRPI.jpg" alt="CSU Bakersfield student Kelsey Padilla discussing her research on the relationship between sea surface temperatures and precipitation levels with CSUB President Horace Mitchell and Governor Jerry Brown" title="COAST_WRPI" width="370" height="247" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2393" /></a><br />
<em>CSU Bakersfield student Kelsey Padilla discussing her research on the relationship between sea surface temperatures and precipitation levels with CSUB President Horace Mitchell and Governor Jerry Brown</em></p>
<p>Student researchers and their faculty mentors spend years working on projects that help solve complex water and coastal zone challenges. For 25 student-faculty teams, their experiments culminated with presentations of their findings to Governor Jerry Brown, CSU campus presidents, Trustees and other CSU officials after the Board of Trustees meeting on March 25.</p>
<p>“It’s so nice that the Trustees and Presidents get to speak to students one-on-one , see what they are working on and hear what they have learned at the CSU,” said Dr. Krista Kamer, director of CSU’s Council on Ocean Affairs, Science &amp; Technology (<a href="http://www.calstate.edu/coast/">COAST</a>). “These students are the end product of what our Trustees and Presidents are fighting for and why they do what they do.”<br />
<span id="more-2392"></span><br />
With support from COAST and the Water Resources and Policy Initiatives (<a href="http://www.calstate.edu/water/">WRPI</a>) team, student-faculty research teams acquired grants and other funding needed to complete research experiments. COAST and WRPI were also fundamental in helping teams connect with environmental organizations that played a vital role in furthering their research. Students had the opportunity to make lifelong professional connections with top scientists from agencies such as Point Blue Conservation Science, the Santa Monica Bay Restoration Commission and Coastal Resources Management.</p>
<p>Students and faculty from each of the 23 CSU campuses, as well as two CSU marine institutes (Moss Landing Marine Laboratories and the Ocean Studies Institute), informed the crowd on topics ranging from coastal erosion and soil fertility to elephant seal breeding and incubation behavior in seabirds.</p>
<p>To learn more about the student-faculty research projects, visit <a href="http://www.calstate.edu/coast/funding/past_student_research_awards.shtml">COAST Research Awards</a> . </p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2392#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?feed=atom&amp;p=2392" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>sthara</name>
						<uri>http://www.calstate.edu/pa/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Keeping the Water Flowing]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2375" />
		<id>http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2375</id>
		<updated>2014-03-21T19:09:06Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-21T18:59:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="A Closer Look" /><category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="drought" /><category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="water conservation" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been a dry year for the Golden State so far, and the drought is only projected to get worse. The rain received in February was not enough to be a drought-breaker, and California’s rainfall deficit is still rapidly reaching record highs. With the significant reduction in the number of crops being grown and [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2375"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/3501-300x225.jpg" alt="Image courtesy of NPR.org" title="Image courtesy of NPR.org" width="300" height="225" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-2383" /></p>
<p>It has been a dry year for the Golden State so far, and the drought is only projected to get worse. The rain received in February was not enough to be a drought-breaker, and California’s rainfall deficit is still rapidly reaching record highs. With the significant reduction in the number of crops being grown and devastatingly low river and reservoir ebb and flow tides, Governor Brown declared a drought State of Emergency. Managing the state’s water resources is crucial in helping maintain the health of California, and the CSU is taking necessary actions to produce proficient leaders in the water industry.<br />
<span id="more-2375"></span><br />
CSU San Marcos recently launched a <a href="http://www.csusm.edu/el/courses/waterprograms1.html">new course</a> for water managers to boost the number of individuals with the knowledge and experience needed to manage shrinking water resources. The program kicked off on March 18 with a preliminary course that will introduce students to the water management industry in California. Current professionals in the water industry looking to become top-level managers, as well as students aspiring to break into the water management industry, will learn about efficient uses of water, consequences of water shortages, water infrastructure, sources of water and issues facing the water industry.</p>
<p>“Academics and industry professionals are working together to create an education hub for water management,” said Alan K. Styles, director of the Certificate in Water Management &amp; Leadership Program. “With a majority of the water management executives retiring within the next ten years, we are trying to transfer that industry knowledge to the younger generation.”</p>
<p>In addition to lectures by local water experts, students will take tours of local state-of-the-art water facilities and will work with water organizations to address a current problem or issue. This course is a precursor to a Water Resources Management Certificate that will be offered beginning next fall.</p>
<p>CSU Monterey Bay is also helping tackle the ongoing drought by partnering with NASA, the U.S. Department of Agriculture, the U.S. Geological Survey and the California Department of Water Resources to develop monitoring tools that better manage the state’s water resources. The <a href="http://www.jpl.nasa.gov/news/news.php?release=2014-059">collaboration</a> is working to establish an operational monitoring service for fallowed land (cultivated land intentionally left unattended) as part of a drought early warning information system.</p>
<p>The pilot project will examine the feasibility of using satellite imagery to track fallowed land in California’s Central Valley. Being unable to fully irrigate crops due to the drought, farmers must choose which crops will get water and which crop will be left to wither. CSUMB researchers are key players in using satellites to detect reductions in the number of crops being planted early in the year. By examining the extent of fallowing, state officials will gain vital insight into the severity of the drought and will be able to develop a foundation for responding to droughts.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2375#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?feed=atom&amp;p=2375" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>echapin</name>
						<uri>http://www.calstate.edu/pa/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Research Takes Spotlight at CSU Symposium]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2362" />
		<id>http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2362</id>
		<updated>2014-01-28T22:43:43Z</updated>
		<published>2014-01-28T22:41:50Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="A Closer Look" /><category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="Biotechnology" /><category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="CSU Fullerton" /><category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="CSUPERB" /><category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="research" /><category scheme="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science" term="student research" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nearly 700 students, faculty, alumni, administrators and partners gathered at the 26th annual CSU Biotechnology Symposium in Santa Clara Jan. 9-11 to share research and advance innovation in the life sciences. The symposium, organized by the CSU’s Program for Education and Research in Biotechnology (CSUPERB), showcases the research of hundreds of students working toward high-demand science, technology, [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2362"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-2364" title="Collages2" src="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Collages2.jpg" alt="" width="324" height="216" /></p>
<p>Nearly 700 students, faculty, alumni, administrators and partners gathered at the 26th annual <a href="http://www.calstate.edu/csuperb/symposium/2014/">CSU Biotechnology Symposium</a> in Santa Clara Jan. 9-11 to share research and advance innovation in the life sciences.</p>
<p>The symposium, organized by the CSU’s <a href="http://www.calstate.edu/csuperb/">Program for Education and Research in Biotechnology</a> (CSUPERB), showcases the research of hundreds of students working toward high-demand science, technology, engineering and math degrees. <a href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/pa/news/?p=3408">More &gt;&gt;</a></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?p=2362#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/science/?feed=atom&amp;p=2362" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
