<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
   <title>CADVC News / Events</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/" />
   <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/atom.xml" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2014:/blogs/cadvc//49</id>
   <updated>2014-05-30T17:21:00Z</updated>
   
   <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type 3.34</generator>

<entry>
   <title>Foreign Ad Agency “Pops-Up” in Highlandtown</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2014/05/foreign_ad_agency_popsup_in_hi.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2014:/blogs/cadvc//49.17598</id>
   
   <published>2014-05-30T16:55:27Z</published>
   <updated>2014-05-30T17:21:00Z</updated>
   
   <summary>Ever wonder what it is like to suddenly experience a new culture and not understand the language, customs, products, or food? Artist and CADVC graduate research assistant, Victor Torres, invites you to his mock design agency, where products are developed...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Sandra Abbott</name>
      <uri>http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/</uri>
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC Events" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
         <category term="CADVC News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[Ever wonder what it is like to suddenly experience a new culture and not understand the language, customs, products, or food? Artist and CADVC graduate research assistant, Victor Torres, invites you to his mock design agency, where products are developed and marketed, but for a fictitious civilization created by the artist through his research around culture and the origins of language. Get ready for some fun as you explore a world that seems almost familiar...but not quite.

<img alt="10305978_789837461036108_1166826831795494304_n.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/10305978_789837461036108_1166826831795494304_n.jpg" width="288" height="384" />]]>
      <![CDATA[On May 31st, 2014 Torres will curate local performance artists Hoesy Corona, Sarah Tooley, Kata Frederick, and others to transform the temporarily unoccupied space at 3320 Eastern Avenue into an all-immersive art installation. Guests are invited to explore this fictitious design agency as both passersby and as interactive participants inside the world of this newly created culture.
 
“Highlandtown has historically been the point of entry for many immigrants who arrived in Baltimore for its proximity to the port. For this reason, Highlandtown has a reputation for being one of the most diverse neighborhoods in Baltimore City. There really isn’t a better place to talk about displacement, and the parameters of what makes something foreign.” -- Victor Torres
 
This event was made possible in partnership between Highlandtown Main Street, a program of the Southeast CDC, Highlandtown Arts District and UMBC’s Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture (CADVC) to promote arts and performance to showcase the potential of unoccupied storefronts along Eastern Avenue in Highlandtown’s Main Street district.

<strong>Hours and Location:</strong>
Saturday, May 31st
3-5pm
3320 Eastern Ave., Baltimore, MD 21224
(Located on the northwest corner of Highland and Eastern Avenues in the former Horton’s House of Tuxedos location.)

<img alt="1_in_height.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/1_in_height.jpg" width="360" height="127" />
 
<strong>Victor F. de M. Torres</strong>
Victor F. de M. Torres is an interdisciplinary, multimedia, performance artist born in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. He is currently a research assistant and MFA candidate at the University of Maryland Baltimore County. Victor Torres has a bachelor’s of arts in Socio-cultural Anthropology. His work is concerned with the construction of ‘common sense’ and parameters of the ‘foreign,’ focusing primarily on the derivation, creation, and dissemination of meaning prior to social agreement. He is an organizer of Glitter Thighs among other projects such as Rooms Fall Apart and Transmodern. 

<strong>UMBC’s Center for Arts Design and Visual Culture (CADVC)</strong> 
CADVC is a non-profit organization dedicated to organizing comprehensive exhibitions, the publication of catalogs, CDs, DVDs, and books on the arts, and educational and community outreach projects. The Center's programs serve as a forum for exploring the social and aesthetic issues of the day. The Center is committed to rethinking the relationship between art institutions and the public, offering extensive educational outreach initiatives and public programs, often in partnership with a variety of educational and cultural institutions.

<strong>HIGHLANDTOWN A&E DISTRICT</strong> (ha!):
ha! is the largest Arts & Entertainment District in the state, ha! encompasses Highlandtown, Patterson Park, and portions of Canton and Greektown. ha! offers artists the opportunity to live and work in one of the most culturally diverse neighborhoods in the city. ha! boasts Southeast’s largest collection of retail and industrial spaces, along with affordable housing and a convenient location, easily accessible from I-95, I- 895, Fells Point and Downtown. ha! is home of the Creative Alliance at The Patterson, the Southeast Anchor Library, several galleries, artist studios, and retail shops with a variety of activities happening year round including the Halloween Lantern Parade, the Highlandtown Farmer's Market, Annual Artist Studio Tours, Sculpture in the Park, the Highlandtown Wine Festival, and the Highlandtown Basement Bar Tour.

<strong>Southeast Community Development Corporation (SECDC): </strong>
SECDC is the oldest community development corporation in Baltimore City operating a premier housing counseling program and a unique combination of private and public programs that focus on the revitalization of Southeast Baltimore. SECDC stimulates investment, improves public spaces, promotes homeownership and improves quality of life in select neighborhoods. Southeast CDC is the coordinator of Highlandtown Main Street and Highlandtown Arts & Entertainment District.

]]>
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>SENIOR EXIT EXHIBITION</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2014/05/senior_exit_exhibition.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2014:/blogs/cadvc//49.17586</id>
   
   <published>2014-05-15T19:38:12Z</published>
   <updated>2014-05-15T19:49:51Z</updated>
   
   <summary>May 20 — June 14, 2014 The Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture presents the 2014 Senior Exit Exhibition. This exhibition reflects the interdisciplinary orientation and the technological focus of the Department of Visual Arts and provides the opportunity...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Alexandra Macchi</name>
      
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC Events" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[May 20 — June 14, 2014

<img alt="SEE_Postcard_Page_1.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/SEE_Postcard_Page_1.jpg" width="450" height="299" />

The Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture presents the 2014 Senior Exit Exhibition. This exhibition reflects the interdisciplinary orientation and the technological focus of the Department of Visual Arts and provides the opportunity for undergraduate seniors to exhibit within a professional setting prior to exiting the university.

Opening Reception: Tuesday, May 20, 2014, 5 p.m. - 7 p.m.

Commencement Breakfast Reception: Thursday, May 22, 2014, 9:00 a.m. - 11 a.m

Admission to the exhibition is free. The Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture is open Tuesday through Saturday from 10 am to 5 pm and is located in the Fine Arts Building. For more information call 410-455-3188. ]]>
      Admission to the exhibition is free. The Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture is open Tuesday through Saturday from 10 am to 5 pm and is located in the Fine Arts Building. For more information call 410-455-3188. 
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>MFA THESIS EXHIBITION 2014 </title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2014/03/mfa_thesis_exhibition_2014.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2014:/blogs/cadvc//49.17556</id>
   
   <published>2014-03-29T20:21:49Z</published>
   <updated>2014-03-29T21:10:05Z</updated>
   
   <summary> Imaging and Digital Arts at University of Maryland, Baltimore County MFA THESIS EXHIBITION 2014 Michael FARLEY Charlotte KENISTON Lexie MOUNTAIN Shana PALMER Carrie RENNOLDS Dominique ZELTZMAN Opening Reception Thursday April 3, 2014. 5 - 7pm. 5:15pm &quot;Fred Worden Cuts...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Alexandra Macchi</name>
      
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC Events" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[<img alt="IMDA_THESISSHOW_2014.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/IMDA_THESISSHOW_2014.jpg" width="432" height="324" />

Imaging and Digital Arts at University of Maryland, Baltimore County 
MFA THESIS EXHIBITION 2014

Michael FARLEY
Charlotte KENISTON
Lexie MOUNTAIN
Shana PALMER
Carrie RENNOLDS
Dominique ZELTZMAN

Opening Reception Thursday April 3, 2014. 5 - 7pm. 
5:15pm "Fred Worden Cuts A Couch In Half With A Chainsaw" (Performance by Lexie Mountain)

The Center for Arts, Design, and Visual Culture is proud to host the annual MFA Thesis Exhibition for Imaging and Digital Arts at UMBC from April 3 - 25, 2014.

Gallery Hours: Tuesday - Saturday 10am - 5pm
]]>
      <![CDATA[ABOUT THE ARTISTS

Artist and critic <a href="https://www.facebook.com/ellendegenerate666">Michael Anthony Farley</a>'s GOTH BRUNCH, a site-specific series of events and in-progress, changing installation elements, re-conceived Gallery CA as a hybrid studio, performance venue, and site for the production of documentation. Informed by (but not necessarily about) the logic of social media, GOTH BRUNCH is a semi-autobiographical exploration of constructed identity as represented through design objects, curation, and performance. 

<a href="http://charlottekeniston.com/">Charlotte Keniston</a>'s A Full Plate is the culmination of 18 workshops throughout Baltimore City in which participants painted ceramic dinner plates and discussed their food histories and their roles in the food system. The 300+ plates will be installed in the CADVC and all of the workshop participants will be invited back to view the project and share a meal together.

With Death or Higher Resolution, <a href="http://www.lexiemountain.com/">Lexie Mountain</a> uses markers of performance such as prints, mass-produced custom canvases, anonymous digital paintings and video documentation to explore art history's objectification of the female form and the ways in which meaning is replicated through ideas of "realism" and digital technology. 

2014 MFA Candidate <a href="http://shanapalmer.com/">Shana Palmer</a> presents an interactive environment that summons the essence of the uncanny.  A door that seems to open on it's own plays videos within it's frame, a convex lens displays her Moving Mountains animation and viewers watch  another video projected into a sink basin.  Her installation and videos blur the boundaries of dichotomies like natural/artificial while she weaves together autobiographical and fictional narratives into a tapestry of performance, photography, video, and installation. 

<a href="http://art.umbc.edu/graduate/students/rennolds.php">Carrie Ann Rennolds</a> is a visual artist who focuses primarily on problems and failures in modern society. SOMETIMES I WANT TO SHAKE THE BRANCHES OF MY FAMILY TREE AND SEE WHAT FALLS OUT (2014) is an installation piece focusing on the personal archive and its mercurial capacity.

<a href="http://dominiquezeltzman.com/">Dominique Zeltzman</a> is a performance and video installation artist. After a fifteen year dance and performance career in San Francisco, she is now finishing her MFA in Imaging and Digital Arts at the University of Maryland, Baltimore County. Radical Home (2014) is her study of the container as a societal construct. In the four-walled installation, life size female figures creep, crawl, and drag themselves across backdrops of banal domestic scenes and abstractions of New York Times photographs.]]>
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>Film Program in association with Visibility Machines: Harun Farocki and Trevor Paglen presented by the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture at UMBC and the Center for Advanced Media at Johns Hopkins University</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2014/01/film_program_in_association_wi.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2014:/blogs/cadvc//49.17505</id>
   
   <published>2014-01-29T17:32:04Z</published>
   <updated>2014-01-29T18:04:56Z</updated>
   
   <summary> February 5, 2014, 6pm Harun Farocki selects: Overlord (Stuart Cooper, 1975, United Kingdom, b&amp;w, 95 minutes, 35mm) Inextuinguishable Fire (Harun Farocki, 1969, b&amp;w, 21 mins, digital transfer of 16mm) Shriver Hall, Johns Hopkins University 3400 N. Charles Street Baltimore,...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Alexandra Macchi</name>
      
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC Events" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[<img alt="OVERLORD_FLIER_SIMPLE_100.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/OVERLORD_FLIER_SIMPLE_100.jpg" width="816" height="1067" />

<strong>February 5, 2014, 6pm
Harun Farocki selects:</strong>

<em>Overlord</em> (Stuart Cooper, 1975, United Kingdom, b&w, 95 minutes, 35mm)
<em>Inextuinguishable Fire</em> (Harun Farocki, 1969, b&w, 21 mins, digital transfer of 16mm)

Shriver Hall, Johns Hopkins University 
3400 N. Charles Street
Baltimore, MD 21218

<img alt="TENSKIES_FLIER_SIMPLE_100.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/TENSKIES_FLIER_SIMPLE_100.jpg" width="850" height="1100" />

<strong>February 11, 2014, 6pm
Trevor Paglen selects:</strong>

<em>Ten Skies</em> (James Benning, 2004, United States, color, 109 minutes, 16mm)
<em>Drone Vision</em> (Trevor Paglen, 2010, United States, b&w, 5 minutes, video)

AV Center, Milton S Eisenhower Library 
JHU Homewood Campus
3400 N. Charles Street
Baltimore, MD 21218

For more information, please contact:
Center for Art Design and Visual Culture
T 410.455.3188
http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/


The Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture (CADVC) at the University of Maryland Baltimore County presents a two-night film program curated by Sonja Simonyi in conjunction with the exhibition Visibility Machines: Harun Farocki and Trevor Paglen.

]]>
      <![CDATA[
Organized in collaboration with the Center for Advanced Media Studies at Johns Hopkins University, the program focuses on diverging cinematic representations of the military industrial complex. Harun Farocki and Trevor Paglen were invited to each select a film that deeply influenced their thinking about war-making and image-making, a selection which will be paired with the artist’s own works on film and video.

Feb 5
Harun Farocki selects:

Overlord (Stuart Cooper, 1975, United Kingdom, b&w, 95 minutes, 35mm)
Inextuinguishable Fire (Harun Farocki, 1969, b&w, 21 mins, digital transfer of 16mm)

The 1975 film Overlord, chosen by Farocki, places warfare in a fictional framework, evoking questions on the different ways in which archival footage can be incorporated into new filmic material to provide a thoughtful reconstruction of war. While Farocki does not approach the theme of war in a narrative context, issues relating to the visual representation of military strikes, and the formal strategies employed to construct such images, provide useful links to Farocki’s filmmaking as well. Meticulously researched, and using carefully selected footage from the film archives of the Imperial War Museum in Great Britain, Overlord follows a young soldier’s experiences of the Allied Forces’ D-Day invasion of Normandy during the Second World War. The striking aesthetic quality of the film was achieved by matching the archival material with live-action scenes shot with period lenses and stock footage from the 1930s. Overlord will be preceded by Farocki’s seminal essay-film Inextinguishable Fire, which powerfully dissects the connections between napalm bombings during the Vietnam War and diverging corporate and industrial interests that lie at the basis of the chemical’s destructive use by the US Army. As Farocki suggests, links between production, labor, and the ultimate implementation of a given product in warfare have been successfully separated and obfuscated in contemporary capitalist society.

Feb 11
Trevor Paglen selects:

Ten Skies (James Benning, 2004, United States, color, 109 minutes, 16mm)
Drone Vision (Trevor Paglen, 2010, United States, b&w, 5 minutes, video)

Trevor Paglen’s selection, James Benning’s Ten Skies, shows the skies and the continuous shifts in cloud formations above and around Val Verde, a small town in California. A formally rigorous work, it documents the effects of the physical transformation of the landscape below, brought about by natural processes as well as marks of human intrusion into the setting, such as wildfires and industrial pollution. This poetic experimental film, displaying a series of static shots, provides evocative links with Paglen’s work, for whom the sky frequently becomes an abstracted sphere in which one can probe, and potentially detect traces of military activity. Importantly, despite the seemingly unassuming subject matter of Ten Skies, Benning has repeatedly highlighted its political significance as an “anti-war artwork ... about the antithesis of war, the kind of beauty we’re destroying.” The screening will follow Paglen’s video Drone Vision, which shows images as recorded by a momentarily aimless drone, as the machine eerily mimics the wandering motions of human vision.    

<a href="http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/exhibitions/VisibilityMachines.php">Visibility Machines: Harun Farocki and Trevor Paglen</a>

The exhibition explores the unique roles Harun Farocki and Trevor Paglen play as meticulous observers of the global military industrial complex. Investigating forms of military surveillance, espionage, war-making, and weaponry, the artists each examine the deceptive and clandestine ways in which military projects have deeply transformed, and politicized, our relationship to images and the realities they seem to represent. 

On view at the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture from October 24, 2013 until February 22, 2014. For more information visit http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/exhibitions/VisibilityMachines.php.

Admission to the film program and exhibition is free. Supported by the Andy Warhol Foundation for the Visual Arts, the Elizabeth Firestone Graham Foundation, the Institut für Auslandsbeziehungen, the Goethe-Institut Washington, DC, the Baltimore County Commission on Art and Sciences, and the Maryland State Arts Council.

]]>
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>CADVC January Hours </title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2014/01/cadvc_january_hours.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2014:/blogs/cadvc//49.17496</id>
   
   <published>2014-01-05T20:54:00Z</published>
   <updated>2014-01-05T20:55:39Z</updated>
   
   <summary>Starting January 7th through January 25th, 2014, the Center for Art Design and Visual Culture will be open the following days: Tuesdays through Thursdays: Open by appointment (visitors can call on a phone outside the gallery and be let in)...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Alexandra Macchi</name>
      
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      Starting January 7th through January 25th, 2014, the Center for Art Design and Visual Culture will be open the following days:

Tuesdays through Thursdays: Open by appointment (visitors can call on a phone outside the gallery and be let in)

Fridays and Saturdays: Open to the public


      
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>Curator Niels Van Tomme at DC Art Science Evening Rendezvous (DASER)</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2013/12/curator_niels_van_tomme_at_dc.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2013:/blogs/cadvc//49.17495</id>
   
   <published>2013-12-24T20:50:53Z</published>
   <updated>2013-12-24T21:02:28Z</updated>
   
   <summary> On Thursday, November 14, 2013, The Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture (CADVC) at the University of Maryland Baltimore County and Cultural Programs of the National Academy of Sciences co-presented a DC Art Science Evening Rendezvous (DASER) exploring...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Alexandra Macchi</name>
      
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC Events" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[<iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/JgpsUoMtTVQ" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

On Thursday, November 14, 2013, The Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture (CADVC) at the University of Maryland Baltimore County and Cultural Programs of the National Academy of Sciences co-presented a DC Art Science Evening Rendezvous (DASER) exploring the topic of drones. This special event is organized in conjunction with the exhibition "Visibility Machines: Harun Farocki and Trevor Paglen," on view at the CADVC Oct. 24, 2013 through Feb. 22, 2014. 

Video courtesy <a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/CPNAS">Cultural Programs of the National Academy of Sciences</a>.
This event took place Thursday, November 14, 2013 at Keck Center, 500 Fifth St., N.W., Room 100, Washington, DC.

]]>
      DASER is co-sponsored by Cultural Programs of the National Academy of Sciences (CPNAS) and Leonardo, the International Society for the Arts, Sciences, and Technology. DASER foster community and discussion around the intersection of art and science. The thoughts and opinions expressed in the DASER events are those of the panelists and speakers and do not necessarily reflect the positions of the National Academy of Sciences nor of Leonardo. 

DASER was moderated by JD Talasek, Director, Cultural Programs of the National Academy of Sciences, with: 

- Missy Cummings, Visiting Professor of Aeronautics and Astronautics at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MA, Associate Professor, Department of Mechanical Engineering and Materials Science, the Duke Institute of Brain Sciences, and Director, Humans and Autonomy Laboratory, Duke University, Durham, NC 
- Marko Peljhan, Artist, Professor, Interdisciplinary Studies, Director Systemics lab, MAT/ART, University of California, Santa Barbara 
- Peter W. Singer, Director, Center for 21st Century Security and Intelligence, The Brookings Institution, Washington, DC

Opening remarks by Niels Van Tomme, visiting curator, Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture, Baltimore. 
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>Franklin Furnace: The Art of Performance Documentation with Martha Wilson in Person</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2013/11/franklin_furnace_the_art_of_pe_2.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2013:/blogs/cadvc//49.17471</id>
   
   <published>2013-11-13T17:17:56Z</published>
   <updated>2013-11-13T17:24:01Z</updated>
   
   <summary> Franklin Furnace: The Art of Performance Documentation Martha Wilson in person Thursday, December 12 at 7:00 p.m., Albin O. Kuhn Library Gallery, UMBC Martha Wilson is an artist and the founding director of Franklin Furnace. Wilson’s own work in...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Alexandra Macchi</name>
      
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC Events" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[<img alt="Martha%20Wilson%20colorful.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/Martha%20Wilson%20colorful.jpg" width="475" height="475" />

<u><strong><a href="http://https://www.facebook.com/events/616330645095384">Franklin Furnace: The Art of Performance Documentation</u>
Martha Wilson</strong> in person
<em>Thursday, December 12 at 7:00 p.m., Albin O. Kuhn Library Gallery, UMBC</em></a>

Martha Wilson is an artist and the founding director of Franklin Furnace. Wilson’s own work in photography, performance, and video art explores female subjectivity through role-playing, costume transformations, and “invasions” of other people’s personas. She was also a member of DISBAND, an all-female performance group; it is in this context that she developed the character of Alexander M. Plague, Jr., one of several personas (both fictional and real; including that of Barbara Bush) that she has adopted over the years. 
]]>
      
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>Project Director, Dr. Maurice Berger and Revolution of the Eye Receive Planning Grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2013/09/project_director_dr_maurice_be.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2013:/blogs/cadvc//49.17381</id>
   
   <published>2013-09-04T20:05:31Z</published>
   <updated>2013-09-04T20:14:50Z</updated>
   
   <summary>Revolution of the Eye: Modern Art and the Birth of American Television, a forthcoming project from the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture, UMBC and its Project Director, Dr. Maurice Berger are the recipient of a 2013 Planning Grant...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Alexandra Macchi</name>
      
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      Revolution of the Eye: Modern Art and the Birth of American Television, a forthcoming project from the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture, UMBC and its Project Director, Dr. Maurice Berger are the recipient of a 2013 Planning Grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities. The $40,000 grant, awarded under the Endowment&apos;s America&apos;s Historical &amp; Cultural Organizations Grant program, will assist in the planning of an exhibition, book, and website. Revolution of the Eye represents the first collaborative institutional effort between the CADVC and the Jewish Museum in New York, where Dr. Berger holds the title of Consulting Curator. He is Research Professor and Chief Curator at CADVC. The grant will be administered through the Jewish Museum. 

This is the third NEH grant awarded to Dr. Berger since 2008 in his capacity as project director at CADVC. An earlier project, For All the World to See: Visual Culture and the Struggle for Civil Rights received planning ($40,000) and Implementation ($400,000) grants from the NEH in 2008 and 2009. Additionally, For All the World to See was selected by the Endowment as the eleventh exhibition of the NEH on the Road initiative. NEH on the Road is designed to create wider national access to the ideas, themes, and stories explored in major grant-funded NEH exhibitions. Under Dr. Berger&apos;s direction, the initiative adapted the exhibition in a smaller, lower security version and will travel it to 25 additional venues, mostly smaller and mid-size institutions across the country over a five year period from 2012 to 2017.

      About Revolution of the Eye:
&quot;Revolution of the Eye is the first exhibition to comprehensively examine the influence of modern art on television in its formative years, from the late-1940s to the early-1970s. The project looks at the dynamic new visual medium, and the ways its risk-taking and aesthetic experimentation paralleled the cutting-edge nature of modern art. Revolution of the Eye also examines the incisive and sophisticated commentary about television delivered in turn by avant-garde artists who explored and interrogated the new medium and its increasingly powerful role in American culture and society. More than just a compelling and entertaining story, the exhibition, catalog, and website will captivate the mind, eye and ear through a dynamic and bold installation and book and web design inspired by the visual revolution ushered in by American television and modernist art and design of the 1950s and 1960s.&quot; 
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>CADVC Welcomes Guest Curator Joanna Raczynska</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2013/07/cadvc_welcomes_guest_curator_j.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2013:/blogs/cadvc//49.17354</id>
   
   <published>2013-08-01T00:43:41Z</published>
   <updated>2013-11-13T17:12:19Z</updated>
   
   <summary>CADVC welcomes guest curator Joanna Raczynska for her 2013 / 2014 film series, Jump Over Time: Using Documentation Video. Jump Over Time: Using Documentation Video presents a series of films and videos that utilize the subjective as well as mediated...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Alexandra Macchi</name>
      
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[CADVC welcomes guest curator <strong>Joanna Raczynska</strong> for her 2013 / 2014 film series, <em>Jump Over Time: Using Documentation Video</em>. 

<em>Jump Over Time: Using Documentation Video</em> presents a series of films and videos that utilize the subjective as well as mediated experiences of performance, exploring some of the many uses of video, film and audio documentation by artists, organizations, and collectives since the late 60s. The film and video presentations will contextualize questions regarding the concept of live performances and subjective experience; actions by Activist-Artists; histories of artist-run experimental media spaces and happenings; “professional” and “amateur” documentation and their purposes; copyright, archives, access and video format migration; and the experiences of projectionists, media arts curators and artists performing multiple roles in the making of meaning and history, among other concepts.  The series will also work towards provoking a more active participation in the documentation of current artistic practices, organizations, and events.

<em>Jump Over Time </em>looks at some creative uses of video documentation as an idiom and form used by media artists. When does the video documentation of an event shift from witness to evidence? If a performance is designed for the camera is the urgency, the live-ness, of the performance obliterated?  When the video maker’s intent is to re-present a specific historic period, action, or happening, can reenactments be considered documentation? Selected works as well as visiting artists and archivists will speak to the many ways archives—brimming with mediated experiences—are critical to cultural determination, memory, and practice.]]>
      <![CDATA[____________________________________________________________________________________
<u><strong>Playing Un-Documented Utopias</strong></u>
<em>Wednesday, November 6 at 4:00 p.m., CADVC, UMBC</em>

The first program presents an overview of the series with excerpts of recent videos as well as the presentation of two recent works:: <u><em>People to be Resembling</em></u> (Otolith Group, UK/India, 2012, 22 minutes), “a five sided portrait of the methodologies of the postfree jazz, pre-world music trio Codona. <em><u>People to be Resembling</u></em> returns to 1978 in order to redream the recording process at Tonstudio Bauer as a meditation upon the relations between visual anthropology, anti-colonial choreography, nuclear annihilation and Weltmusik;” and <u><em>Walk Through</em></u> (Redmond Entwistle, USA/UK, 2013, 17 minutes), “an exploration of the site, design and philosophy of the California Institute of the Arts in Los Angeles, as a starting point for posing wider questions about contemporary pedagogical models and their relationship to new forms of social, political and economic exchange that have emerged since the 1970s.” 

____________________________________________________________________________________
<img alt="Martha_Wilson.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/Martha_Wilson.jpg" width="548" height="392" />
<u><strong>Franklin Furnace: The Art of Performance Documentation</u>
Martha Wilson</strong> in person
<em>Thursday, December 12 at 7:00 p.m., Albin O. Kuhn Library Gallery, UMBC</em>

Martha Wilson is an artist and the founding director of Franklin Furnace. Wilson’s own work in photography, performance, and video art explores female subjectivity through role-playing, costume transformations, and “invasions” of other people’s personas. She was also a member of DISBAND, an all-female performance group; it is in this context that she developed the character of Alexander M. Plague, Jr., one of several personas (both fictional and real; including that of Barbara Bush) that she has adopted over the years. 

____________________________________________________________________________________
<u><strong>
Hallwalls Archive: Golden Years</strong></u>
<strong>Carolyn Tenant</strong>, media arts director, Hallwalls; <strong>Tony Conrad</strong>, artist, professor, University of Buffalo Center for Advanced Media Studies, Johns Hopkins University
<em>Thursday, February 20, 2014 at 1:30 p.m., Center for Advanced Media Studies, JHU</em>

Hallwalls was founded on Buffalo's West Side in late 1974 by a group of young visual artists, some of them still students at the time. Since its founding, numerous national and international artists have visited Hallwalls for performances, screenings, readings, panel discussions, and exhibitions. As early as 1977, Hallwalls received support from the New York State Council on the Arts to document its multidisciplinary activities using video. Early performances by Karen Finley, Ann Magnuson, Rachel Rosenthal, and Mike Kelley (among many others) are accessible now thanks to Hallwalls’ conservation efforts. 
____________________________________________________________________________________
<u><strong>We’re All VideoFreex!</strong></u>
<strong>Skip Blumberg</strong>, artist and Videofreex member; <strong>Tom Colley</strong>, collections manager, Video Data Bank 
<em>Sunday, March 9, 2014 at 4:00 p.m., National Gallery of Art</em>
Skip Blumberg, Videofreex member and artist
Parry Teasdale, Videofreex co-founder and editor, <u>The Columbia Paper</u> 
Tom Colley, collections manager, Video Data Bank

In the late 60s, the recording of image and sound with instantaneous playback signaled the dawn of a new media—video—that was more accessible and more discreet than film had ever been. With video cameras known as portapaks in hand, the co-founders of the Videofreex collective (1969-1978) were pioneers in the development of community television, founders of the country’s first pirate TV station, as well as mentors and instructors to countless individuals interested in making and sharing an open system of production. A selection of videos produced by the Freex and archived at Video Data Bank in Chicago features an interview with Fred Hampton of the Black Panthers, a discussion with organizer Abbey Hoffman, and excerpts from other early video recordings.

____________________________________________________________________________________

<img alt="occupy-wall-street_592x299.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/occupy-wall-street_592x299.jpg" width="592" height="299" /><em><strong>

Gravity Hill Newsreels: Occupy Wall Street</strong></em>
<strong>Jem Cohen</strong> in person 
April 2014 TBD, UMBC
<em>12 short observations about Occupy Wall Street (2011/2012), New York City.</em>

“In regards to Occupy Wall Street, when friends asked me where the newsreels were, I decided to plunge in and make some myself. We knew there’d eventually be many documentaries made about the phenomenon and that there were already short advocacy pieces in support of the movement (as well as YouTube slams against it). My own interest lay elsewhere: in a kind of reporting based on direct observation that expresses solidarity without propaganda, while leaving room for experimentation and lyricism.” – J.C. 

____________________________________________________________________________________
<u><strong>The Just Past</strong></u>
<em>May 2014 TBD, UMBC</em>

Final event in the series is a program of short videos including work by Redmond Entwistle, Gordon Matta-Clark, Elisabeth Subrin, Wendelien van Oldenborgh and others. Presented by Joanna Raczynska.
____________________________________________________________________________________

<img alt="DSCN1272.JPG" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/DSCN1272.JPG" width="96" height="128"  /Hspace="30" Vspace="10"align="left"/> <strong>Joanna Raczynska</strong> is the Assistant Head of Film Programs in the Department of Film Programs at the National Gallery of Art in Washington, DC. She earned her master’s degree in documentary by practice from Royal Holloway College, University of London in 2001. She first started making non-fiction films ands videos in 1996, while a student at the University of Maryland Baltimore County. Her works have screened internationally and across the United States, most recently at ZKM in Karlsruhe, Germany. She has previously worked for a variety of non-profit organizations including Hallwalls Contemporary Arts Center in Buffalo, NY (where she served as Media Arts Director from 2002 – 2006), the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, the Mid Atlantic Arts Foundation and the Baltimore Museum of Art. ]]>
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>Sandra Abbott, CADVC, Appointed to Baltimore City Public Art Commission</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2013/06/baltimore_community_arts_activ.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2013:/blogs/cadvc//49.17338</id>
   
   <published>2013-06-27T23:16:48Z</published>
   <updated>2013-08-20T21:28:46Z</updated>
   
   <summary>Baltimore community arts activist and UMBC’s curator of collections and outreach for the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture, Sandra Abbott, was sworn in to the board of the Baltimore City Public Art Commission on Monday, June 10, 2013...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Sandra Abbott</name>
      <uri>http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/</uri>
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[<img alt="abbott_rawlings-blake.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/abbott_rawlings-blake.jpg" width="172" height="255"  /Hspace="30" Vspace="10"align="left">Baltimore community arts activist and UMBC’s curator of collections and outreach for the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture, Sandra Abbott, was sworn in to the board of the Baltimore City Public Art Commission on Monday, June 10, 2013 by Mayor Stephanie Rawlings-Blake.

As a member of the board of the Public Art Commission, Abbott juries public art projects along with eight other members under the City’s 1% for Art Program. The program enhances the cityscape, quality of life, and artistic and creative climate in Baltimore.  The 1%-for-Art Ordinance requires at least one percent of the City's capital construction project's eligible funds be used for the selection, acquisition, commissioning, fabrication, placement, installation, display, and maintenance of public fine artwork. The program is administered through the Baltimore Office of Promotion & The Arts (BOPA).]]>
      <![CDATA[With her experience on the steering committee of the <a href="http://www.highlandtownarts.com/">Highlandtown Arts and Entertainment District</a> since 2008, Abbott will be well-positioned to work with BOPA and the other city arts districts on the recent $200K ArtPlace America grant for the City’s three arts districts in partnership with the European Union. The Grant will fund Transit, a project that brings together European and Baltimore artists, arts organizations, city planners, and transportation officials to strategically transform transit environments within the city’s A&E districts. The project was chosen from more than 1,200 applications as an exceptional example of creative placemaking.

Abbott is co-author of the chapter on museum internships in <em>A Life in Museums</em> (American Alliance of Museums, 2012), and serves as the Maryland representative to the Association of Academic Museums and Galleries. She often speaks at national conferences and most recently won the Collegetown Network’s Staff Award for outstanding service at the 6th annual Service-Learning and & Civic Engagement Conference.]]>
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>UMBC’s Department of Education and Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture Partner on Exhibit Highlighting Outreach to Area Schools</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2013/04/umbcs_department_of_education.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2013:/blogs/cadvc//49.17225</id>
   
   <published>2013-04-05T20:27:03Z</published>
   <updated>2013-04-06T04:12:31Z</updated>
   
   <summary> UMBC’s Department of Education joins the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture (CADVC) to celebrate their year long K-12 educational outreach collaboration with an art exhibition by students from their partnership schools. The exhibition is featured at the...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Sandra Abbott</name>
      <uri>http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/</uri>
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC Events" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[<img alt="FATWTS%20Outreach%20Card%20front%20blog%20edit.jpg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/FATWTS%20Outreach%20Card%20front%20blog%20edit.jpg" width="456" height="313" />

UMBC’s Department of Education joins the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture (CADVC) to celebrate their year long K-12 educational outreach collaboration with an art exhibition by students from their partnership schools.

The exhibition is featured at the UMBC Commons Mezzanine Gallery beginning with an artist’s reception Thursday, April 11, 6 – 8 pm. 

The installation features original artwork by three Baltimore City schools (Augusta Fells Savage Institute of Visual Arts High School, Baltimore City College High School, and Digital Harbor High School), Mt. Hebron High School in Howard County, and Hugh M. Cummings High School in North Carolina. Baltimore City College High School, Digital Harbor High School, and Mt. Hebron High School are Professional Development School partners with UMBC’s Department of Education. After experiencing the CADVC gallery and/or virtual exhibition, <em>For All the World to See: Visual Culture and the Struggle for Civil Rights</em>, the students were invited to create visual artwork, poetry, or prose for display at UMBC as well. Their work, a creative interpretation of the interaction between visual culture and social justice, will be on display to the public through May 23, 2013.]]>
      The Galleries at the Commons, UMBC are free and open to the public. For parking directions or maps, visit about.umbc.edu/visitors-guide. 

Project supporters include USM Redesign of Teacher Education Grant Program, UMBC’s commonvision, and Maryland State Arts Council.

The exhibition has been touring the US since 2010 when it opened in NY. Both the exhibition and the book, by the same title, have won many accolades, including a tour through the &lt;ahref=
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>Berger Featured in New York Time&apos;s Lens Blog</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2013/01/berger_featured_in_new_york_ti.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2013:/blogs/cadvc//49.17095</id>
   
   <published>2013-01-03T20:27:55Z</published>
   <updated>2013-01-03T20:43:29Z</updated>
   
   <summary>Maurice Berger, Chief Curator of the CADVC, has written his third essay for “Race Stories,” an ongoing series for the New York Times Lens Blog. The essay focuses on Ken Gonzales-Day’s important &quot;Lynchings in the West Project.&quot; Read the full...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Sandra Abbott</name>
      <uri>http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/</uri>
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[Maurice Berger, Chief Curator of the CADVC, has written his third essay for “Race Stories,” an ongoing series for the <em>New York Times</em> Lens Blog. The essay focuses on Ken Gonzales-Day’s important "Lynchings in the West Project."

Read the full article here: 
<a href="http://lens.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/12/06/lynchings-in-the-west-erased-from-history-and-photos/">"Lynchings in the West, Erased From History and Photos"</a>

The previous two entries in the “Race Stories” series are also available on the Lens Blog: 
<a href="http://lens.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/07/16/a-different-approach-to-civil-rights-images/">"A Radically Prosaic Approach to Civil Rights Images"</a>
<a href="http://lens.blogs.nytimes.com/2012/09/19/malcolm-x-as-visual-strategist/">"Malcolm X as a Visual Strategist"</a>
]]>
      
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>Command Z Featured as Top Ten Art Show of 2012 by City Paper</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2013/01/command_z_featured_as_top_ten.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2013:/blogs/cadvc//49.17094</id>
   
   <published>2013-01-03T20:07:01Z</published>
   <updated>2013-01-03T20:27:09Z</updated>
   
   <summary>Command Z: Artists Working with Phenomena and Technology curated by Lisa Moren, presented by the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture last spring was featured today as one of the top ten art exhibitions of 2012 by City Paper....</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Sandra Abbott</name>
      <uri>http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/</uri>
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[<em>Command Z: Artists Working with Phenomena and Technology</em> curated by Lisa Moren, presented by the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture last spring was featured today as one of the top ten art exhibitions of 2012 by <em>City Paper</em>.

The show, described as one that “reawakened our sense of wonder and possibility,” was alongside exhibitions presented by the Contemporary Museum, Open Space, Nudashank and others. Command Z also made the top ten list of Baker award-winning artist, Gary Kachadourian.

See the list here: <a href="http://citypaper.com/news/2012-top-ten-art-shows-1.1414976">“2012 Top Ten Art Shows.”</a>

<img alt="984900813.jpeg" src="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/984900813.jpeg" width="335" height="251" />]]>
      
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>Berger Awarded $50K from Warhol Foundation for Exhibit &amp; Publication</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2012/12/berger_awarded_50k_from_warhol.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2012:/blogs/cadvc//49.17074</id>
   
   <published>2012-12-14T15:17:59Z</published>
   <updated>2012-12-14T15:21:34Z</updated>
   
   <summary>The Andy Warhol Foundation for the Visual Arts has awarded CADVC Research Professor and Chief Curator Maurice Berger a $50,000 curatorial research fellowship award for his forthcoming curatorial project Revolution of the Eye: Modern Art and the Birth of American...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Sandra Abbott</name>
      <uri>http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/</uri>
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[The Andy Warhol Foundation for the Visual Arts has awarded CADVC Research Professor and Chief Curator Maurice Berger a $50,000 curatorial research fellowship award for his forthcoming curatorial project <em>Revolution of the Eye: Modern Art and the Birth of American Television</em>. This exhibition and publication project represents the first collaborative institutional effort between the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture and the Jewish Museum in New York, where Dr. Berger holds the title of Consulting Curator. The grant will be administered through the Jewish Museum.

From the early-1940s through the mid-1960s, a dynamic new visual medium emerged in the United States that, in its risk-taking and aesthetic experimentation, paralleled the cutting-edge nature of modern art: television. The revolutionary and uncharted medium attracted younger television executives, writers, producers, and directors. Scores of socially and culturally progressive and predominantly Jewish network executives, producers, directors, art directors, and writers—figures such as Paddy Chayefsky, William Golden, Leonard Goldenson, Robert Kintner, Ernie Kovacs, Dan Melnick, William S. Paley, David Sarnoff, Frank Stanton, David Susskind, and Rod Serling—mined the aesthetic, stylistic, and conceptual possibilities of a new and powerful technology. These innovators worked in a cultural milieu far less constricted by the competition for box office revenue and the censorious production codes then preoccupying the motion picture industry.
 
As the geographic focus of the networks shifted from the Hollywood movie studios to a television industry initially centered in New York, the proximity of these innovators to the city's dynamic artistic and cultural community—particularly the avant-garde art and philosophies of the New York School, an artistic milieu also with a significant Jewish presence—would result in a powerful conceptual and stylistic synergy between modern art and early television. American television and avant-garde art capitalized on the “modernist visual revolution,”

<em>Revolution of the Eye: Modern Art and the Birth of American Television</em> is currently scheduled to be presented at the Jewish Museum during the spring of 2016 and follows up at the CADVC / UMBC in 2017.]]>
      
   </content>
</entry>
<entry>
   <title>Warhol Foundation Awards CADVC $50K for Exhibit &amp; Publication</title>
   <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/2012/12/warhol_foundation_award_cadvc.html" />
   <id>tag:www.umbc.edu,2012:/blogs/cadvc//49.17073</id>
   
   <published>2012-12-14T15:12:23Z</published>
   <updated>2012-12-14T15:17:33Z</updated>
   
   <summary>The Andy Warhol Foundation for The Visual Arts has awarded the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture $50,000 for the upcoming project, Visibility Machines: Harun Farocki &amp; Trevor Paglen. The project, headed by Visiting Curator to the CADVC, Niels...</summary>
   <author>
      <name>Sandra Abbott</name>
      <uri>http://www.umbc.edu/cadvc/</uri>
   </author>
         <category term="CADVC News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
   
   
   <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.umbc.edu/blogs/cadvc/">
      <![CDATA[The Andy Warhol Foundation for The Visual Arts has awarded the Center for Art, Design and Visual Culture $50,000 for the upcoming project, <em>Visibility Machines: Harun Farocki & Trevor Paglen</em>.

The project, headed by Visiting Curator to the CADVC, Niels Van Tomme, is a traveling exhibition and publication project which explores the unique roles Harun Farocki and Trevor Paglen play as meticulous observers of the global military industrial complex. Investigating forms of military surveillance, espionage, war-making, and weaponry, Farocki and Paglen each examine the deceptive and clandestine ways in which military projects have deeply transformed, and politicized, our relationship to images and the realities they seem to represent. The exhibition initiates critical questions about the crucial part images play in revealing essential but largely concealed governmental information, and places the oeuvres of Harun Farocki and Trevor Paglen within the broader cultural and historical developments of the media they are creatively working with, namely photography, film, and new media.

<em>Visibility Machines</em> is scheduled to be presented next fall, mid-October through December, 2013.]]>
      
   </content>
</entry>

</feed>
