<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Geology Department</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2014-06-02T15:07:35Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology" />
	<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.7.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Nicholas Weidhaas ’15]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/25/591/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=591</id>
		<updated>2014-04-25T20:43:25Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-25T20:42:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Featured" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nicholas Weidhaas ’15 was awarded the Northeastern Sect [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/25/591/"><![CDATA[<p>Nicholas Weidhaas ’15 was awarded the Northeastern Section of the Geological Society of America Stephen Pollock Undergraduate Research Program grant. His research involves Holocene climatic change in the Peruvian Andes where he will study the impacts of climate change on glaciers and lakes. The award includes $800 to fund analyses in Union’s new Stable Isotope Laboratory, and he will travel to the Peruvian Andes this summer to collect samples. </p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/25/591/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/25/591/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Action at the Arc: A departmental trip to the Lesser Antilles]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/action-at-the-arc-a-departmental-trip-to-the-lesser-antilles/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=576</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T14:28:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-09T18:43:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Fall 2013" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Newsletters" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[During Union’s winter term break, fifteen geology major [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/action-at-the-arc-a-departmental-trip-to-the-lesser-antilles/"><![CDATA[<p>During Union’s winter term break, fifteen geology majors traveled the to the Caribbean for a 10 day field trip to Barbados and Dominica, accompanied by Profs. Holli Frey, John Garver, and Matt Manon.  The trip afforded the students an opportunity to study different aspects of a subduction zone, from the forearc sediments in the accretionary wedge in Barbados to the explosive volcanic deposits blanketing Dominica. Barbados is dominated by a Pleistocene coral reef limestone cap, but Tertiary sedimentary rocks of marine origin are exposed in the northeastern part of the island. Known as the Scotland District, the sediments are grouped into two fault-bounded deformed units: The Scotland Formation (sandstones and clays of early to late Eocene) as well as the Oceanic Formation (turbidites and deep water biogenics of mid Eocene to Miocene).  Dominica is one of the most volcanically active islands in the Caribbean, with nine relatively young volcanic centers (10 m) of pyroclastic flow deposits. We also did several hikes in the interior of the island, including an excursion to see welded ignimbrites at Trafalgar Falls and another to smell fumeroles at Sulfur Springs. The last day was an arduous 15 mile trek through the rainforest and geothermal fields in the Valley of Desolation to Boiling Lake, site of a small phreatic eruption in 1997.<br />
Student participants included Eileen Alejos ’15, Michelle Berube ’15, Sarah Brehm ’15, Emily Crampe ’15, Mike Deluca ’13, Ali Flake ’14, Holly Havel ’14, Kate Kaminski ’14, Lauren Main ’14, Tara Metzger ’15, Dane O’Neil ’14, Mike Sachs ’13, Kirk Seaman ’14, Kaitlyn Suarez ’15, and Jordan Thomson ‘14.  The trip was made possible by student contributions and the Geology Field Fund of the department.<br />
In addition to being a departmental field trip, the Caribbean excursion was also a reconnaissance sample collecting trip for Holli.  Despite the plethora of lava domes and associated deposits on Dominica, very little published research exists for the region.  We targeted three ignimbrite deposits from different parts of the island (Grand Savanne, Roseau, and Grand Bay) and collected multiple pumice and lithic clasts from each for petrographic and geochemical analysis.  Initial characterization of the samples was done by Sarah Brehm, Tara Metzger, and Kaitlyn Suarez, as Sophomore Scholars Projects, and their results were presented at the Steinmetz Symposium.  Sarah continued working on the project over the summer and into the fall as an independent study project.  Building on the initial results, Ali Flake and Lauren Main are doing senior theses, further characterizing the textures and phase assemblages with the SEM and LA ICP-MS. Holli will be presenting some of this research at the GSA meeting in Denver at the end of October.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/action-at-the-arc-a-departmental-trip-to-the-lesser-antilles/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/action-at-the-arc-a-departmental-trip-to-the-lesser-antilles/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Anouk Verheyden-Gillikin]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/anouk-verheyden-gillikin-2/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=573</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T14:28:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-09T18:13:43Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Fall 2013" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Newsletters" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This year has been an exciting and very stimulating yea [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/anouk-verheyden-gillikin-2/"><![CDATA[<p>This year has been an exciting and very stimulating year for me at Union College. Last winter the isotope ratio mass spectrometer funded by Gillikin and Rodbell’s NSF grant was delivered and installed. As a lab manager I oversaw the installation and went through a steep learning curve on how to use the instrumentation. The mass spec analyzes gasses such as CO2, CO, H2, N2 for their isotopic composition. In order to transform solid samples into a gas, we have several peripherals. The elemental analyzer (EA) combusts organic samples and separates the resulting gases using gas chromatography. This allows us to measure C and N isotopes of organic material such as hair, soils, tissue samples, wood, etc. The GasBench allows us to measure O and C isotopes of carbonates by adding phosphoric acid to the carbonate and analyzing the resulting CO2 gas. The GasBench can also measure O and H isotopes of water as well as C isotopes of dissolved inorganic carbon. The high temperature conversion elemental analyzer (TC/EA) uses pyrolysis to decompose organic samples and since there is no addition/contamination of atmospheric oxygen, it allows us to measure O and H isotopes in organic materials.<br />
After, the installation, which itself took more than a month, we proceeded with testing out the equipment by running lots of standards. This allowed us to get a feel for the mass spec and get an idea of the level of reproducibility.  It took another couple of months before we were ready to measure our first samples. This is because the mass spec is far from being a plug and play machine. There is a lot of daily monitoring involved and regular tuning to focus the ion beam. With the many connections and hair-like capillaries, leaks appear once in a while, which need to be fixed. The mass spectrometer has been running great and students have been running their own samples, gaining valuable lab experience.<br />
While, the mass spectrometer has kept me very busy last winter and this fall, I also taught Paleontology last spring and am guiding three research students this year. Jordan Thomson (‘14) investigates whether hurricane years are recorded in the isotopic composition of tree rings at sub-annual resolution. This summer, Jordan and I went to coastal North Carolina to collect her samples of Loblolly Pine.  Isabel McRae (’14) is doing a one term thesis with John Garver and I as thesis advisers. She studies slope instability in the Wolf Hollow using tree rings of Hemlock. Zack Wahl (’14) pursues his passion for paleontology and, in collaboration with Penny Higgins from the University of Rochester, he studies the potential to use carbon isotopes in fossil reptile teeth as proxies for climate/environmental change during the early stages of the Cenozoic.<br />
<strong>Recent  Publications from Anouk:</strong><br />
Trouet V, Mukelabai M, Verheyden A, Beeckman H (2012) Cambial growth season of brevi-deciduous Brachystegia spiciformis trees from south central Africa restricted to less than four months. PLoS ONE 7(10): e47364. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0047364<br />
Verheyden A. and H. Beeckman, 2012. Inter-annual and long-term growth trends of Rhizophora mucronata observed from tree ring time-series: Implication for mangrove restoration. Association of American Geographers, Annual meeting, New York City, February 24-28, 2012.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/anouk-verheyden-gillikin-2/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/anouk-verheyden-gillikin-2/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Don Rodbell]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/don-rodbell/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=570</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T14:28:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-09T17:37:56Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Fall 2013" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Newsletters" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[My research activities this year involved our continuin [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/don-rodbell/"><![CDATA[<p>My research activities this year involved our continuing project to document Holocene climatic change as recorded in glacial deposits and lake sediments in the Andes of Peru.  This project is a collaborative effort, funded by the NSF, with colleagues from the University of New Hampshire.  This year we returned to the Huaguruncho Massif in east-central Peru.  Two Union students, Grace Delgado ’14 and Dane O’Neil ’14, joined me and Joe Licciardi and his team from UNH for 3 weeks of field work.  The Huaguruncho Massif is important to our work because it is a presently glaciated region in the upper Amazon Basin that is far to the east of the main crest of the Andes.  Because the bulk of the moisture that nourishes glaciers in the tropical Andes comes from the tropical Atlantic Ocean, there is a steep E-W precipitation gradient across the tropical Andes.  On the western side of the Andes, mean annual precipitation (MAP) is less than 50 cm, and glaciers only exist on the very highest peaks.  From a paleoclimatic standpoint, this region is highly sensitive to precipitation change, given that precipitation is the glacier-limiting climatic variable in this region.  In contrast, on the eastern side of the Andes, MAP can exceed 300 cm, and glaciers can exist at much lower elevations.  This region is far more sensitive to changes in temperature than the western side of the Andes, and taken together our glacial geologic studies in both regions will delineate records of both temperature change and precipitation change in the tropics.  One of the problems with this approach is finding glaciated peaks in the upper Amazon Basin.  Summit elevations descend in an eastward direction in the Amazon basin, and few peaks are high enough to support glaciers in spite of the abundant precipitation.  The Huaguruncho Massif is one exception to this.  The massif is a quartz monzonite dome, with summit elevations of ~18,800’ that stand well above the regional snowline.  The massif supports numerous active glaciers and the moraine record, which we have been working on for several years, provides a temporally detailed record of glaciation spanning tens of thousands of years.  We are using the cosmogenic nuclide 10Be to date the deposition of moraines in the region.  In addition, the region is dotted with numerous glacial lakes and bogs, and we have extracted sediment cores from several of these.  The lake cores should complement the moraine dating by providing a continuous record of sedimentation that can be related to the waxing and waning of upvalley glaciers.<br />
Normally, the southern hemisphere winter (JJA) is the dry season, and most field seasons are very dry, and our rain gear remains safely stashed in the bottom of our packs.  This year, however, was the exception to the rule, and we witnessed first hand, just how wet it can be in the high elevations of the western Amazon Basin.  After the 8th day of rain, I am sure that Dane and Grace were ready to strangle me when I assured them that it “is not normally like this”!<br />
I continue to work to build the program of personnel and funding needed for the deep drilling of Lake Junin, in the central Peruvian highlands.  This lake has the potential to provide a continuous archive of glaciation and climate change that spans more than 200,000 years.  Last May, my colleagues and I were notified that the International Continental Drilling Program would contribute $550,000 to the drilling budget, and as I write this note, my colleagues and I are busy putting the final touches on a proposal to the NSF for the balance of the costs associated with drilling and basic science.  It has been 7 years since I first started the process of assembling the team and the funding needed for the Junin Drilling Project; it seems that, finally, we might be seeing the culmination of this effort!<br />
In March 2013, faculty and students from Union College attended the northeastern section meeting of the GSA in Bretton Woods, New Hampshire.  Mike Sachs ’14 presented our work on sediment cores from floodplain lakes in the Mohawk Valley as a means of reconstructing flood history.  He and all the Union students who presented performed commendably!<br />
On the home front, our daughter, Erika, is a sophomore at St. Lawrence where she is studying Conservation Biology.  Gaby is a high school junior, and the college search for her has already begun!  Ceci and I are contemplating our soon-to-be empty nest years, and I must admit, there is a certain appeal!<br />
<strong>Recent Publications from Don ( * = students):</strong><br />
Rodbell, D. T., 2013, High-resolution d18O records of hydrologic variability from the south-central Peruvian Andes: Geological Society of America Northeastern Section Meeting, Abstracts with Programs, v. 45, p. 79.<br />
Rodbell, D. T., 2013, The Long-Story: Reconstructing Flood Frequency Along The Mohawk Over The Past 1000 Years From Floodplain Lakes: In Cockburn , J.M.H. and Garver, J. I., (eds) Mohawk Watershed Symposium 2013, Union College Schenectady NY, 16 March 2013, Abstracts with Program. <br />
*Sachs, M., and Rodbell, D. T., 2013, The sedimentary record of flooding in the Mohawk River drainage basin preserved in floodplain lakes: Geological Society of America Northeastern Section Meeting, Abstracts with Programs, v. 45, p. 80.<br />
Schweinsberg, A. D., Licciardi, J. M., Rodbell, D. T., and Stansell, N., 2013, Holocene climate and glacier variability recorded in lake and bog sediments from the southern Peruvian Andes: Geological Society of America Northeastern Section Meeting, Abstracts with Programs, v. 45, p. 43.<br />
Schweinsberg, A. D., Licciardi, J. M., Rodbell, D. T., Stansell, N., and Tapia, P. M., 2012, Multiproxy records of Holocene climate and glacier variability from sediment cores in the Cordillera Vilcabamba of southern Peru, Abstract GC21D-0995 presented at 2012 Fall Meeting, AGU, San Francisco, Calif., 3-7 Dec.<br />
Stansell, N. D., Rodbell, D. T., Abbott, M. B., and Mark, B. G., 2013, Proglacial lake sediment records of Holocene climate change in the western cordillera of Peru: Quaternary Science Reviews v. 70, p. 1-14.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/don-rodbell/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/don-rodbell/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Matt Manon]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/matt-manon/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=567</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T14:28:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-09T17:29:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Fall 2013" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Newsletters" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our second daughter, Zoe was born in early March, and s [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/matt-manon/"><![CDATA[<p>Our second daughter, Zoe was born in early March, and she has kept us quite busy, mostly by being incredibly cute. Another obvious highlight of this year was the winter trip to Barbados and Dominica. It is always a treat to get students into the field, looking at a subduction zone up close. It’s a gift to take them to see the two types of rocks I’m most interested in, deformed accretionary sediments and arc volcanics! We had a great group of very motivated and interesting students, which makes any trip more exciting.<br />
I’ve had the opportunity to spend time assisting students on many different kinds of research projects during my first full year managing the department’s instrumentation under the generous support of the Sawtelle Fund. From water, to pollution, to glacial sediment and volcanic tephra, it’s been an interesting year to say the least. The advanced oceanography class analyzed samples from their trip to Florida on the ICP-MS and the ICs, getting a chance to swamp the ion chromatograph detectors with seawater in the process! I’ve been measuring arsenic samples from two different experimental studies on the ICP-MS, working with students of an environmental geologist from Bennington College, and an environmental chemist from here at Union. With Don Rodbell and students we continue to refine the procedure for determining biogenic silica values in glacial lakes. The SEM has been a real workhorse for the Volcanolgy group, producing publishable mineral analyses of feldspars, pyroxenes, amphiboles and (hopefully on Friday) oxide compositions good enough to determine eruption temperature. In short, the lab has been working very well, and is producing lots of data. I am enjoying the role I get to play, interacting with many different students and giving/gaining insights into their work.<br />
Most of my research this year has been focused on phenocryst chemistry of volcanic rocks, working with Holli and many students on the Dominica project. As I write this note, we’re acquiring trace element data on the ICP-MS for our presentation at National GSA in Denver. By the time you read this, GSA will have happened, and I’m staying home with the kids this year so hopefully Holli saw you there.<br />
I’m getting more and interested in teaching structural geology as I get to know more and more of the little details of the Taconic Orogeny. Union is a really great place to teach structure, because there are vastly different styles of deformation within an hour or so drive in any direction. The field-based nature of Structure makes it so much fun to teach at Union. This year our weekend fieldtrip toured the spine of the Taconic orogeny, including some classic localities in Western MA and Western VT (see attached photo of the Castleton Syncline).<br />
This year, I am advising Greg Brenn with his senior thesis work on aftershocks from the M 7.6 earthquake of September, 2013 on the Nicoya Peninsula. As part of the 2013 Costa Rica Keck Project Greg and a few other students installed a local seismic network, and recorded many small aftershock events from the area of fault rupture. Greg was one of only three freshmen who accompanied John Garver and I on our Costa Rica trip in 2010, and it is wonderful that he had the opportunity to return as a budding seismologist. He is presenting his work at the national AGU in San Francisco, so if you’re there, stop by and say hi.<br />
<strong>Recent  Publications from Matt ( * = students):</strong><br />
Frey, H.M., Szramek, K.J., Manon, M.R., and *Kissane, M.T. (2013) Slow weathering in a semiarid climate: changes in the mineralogy and geochemistry of subaerial lava flows in the Deschutes River Basin, central Oregon: Chemical Geology, v. 347, p. 135-152.<br />
Frey, H.M., Manon, M.R.F., *Brehm, S., and *Flake, A. (2013) Monotonous crystal-rich dacitic ignimbrites from Dominica: Implications for magma recharge: Geological Society of America Abstracts with Programs, Vol. 45.<br />
Manon, M.R. (2013) Compositional Dependence of Lawsonite Epidote Blueschist Pseudosections from Western Crete, Greece. Geological Society of America Abstacts with Programs, Vol. 45<br />
Frey, H.M., Manon, M.R.F., *Riehl, M., and *Kaminski, K. (2012) Generation of a zoned silicic pyroclastic deposit by partial melting of a sub-solidus magma chamber beneath Volcán Tepetitlic, Mexico: Geological Society of America Abstracts with Programs, Vol. 44.<br />
Frey, H.M., Manon, M.R.F., *Delagdo, G., and *Willey, T. (2012) Field characterization of fine-grained lavas and volcanic tephras using portable x-ray fluorescence: Geological Society of America Abstracts with Programs, Vol. 44.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/matt-manon/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/09/matt-manon/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Jordan Thomson &#8217;14]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/04/552/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=552</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T14:28:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-04T13:46:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Featured" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jordan Thomson &#8217;14 at the Northeast Geological So [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/04/552/"><![CDATA[<p>Jordan Thomson &#8217;14 at the Northeast Geological Society of America presenting her poster on &#8220;Hurricane Reconstruction in Pinus taeda (Loblolly Pine) using Dendrochemistry from Coastal North Carolina&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/04/552/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/04/04/552/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Keck Alaska presents at Kelowna BC]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/24/keck-alaska-presents-at-kelowna-bc/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=522</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T14:28:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-02-24T13:46:43Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Featured" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Meghan Riehl (2014), Kate Kaminski (2014), traveled wit [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/24/keck-alaska-presents-at-kelowna-bc/"><![CDATA[<p>Meghan Riehl (2014), Kate Kaminski (2014), traveled with Professor Garver and four other team members to the 2014 Cordilleran Tectonics Workshop to present their poster on the Cooling and exhumation of the Sitka Graywacke on Baranof Island in Alaska. </p>
<p>Kate and Meghan presented their thesis work on a single poster entitled: &#8220;Exhumation of the Chugach-Prince William terrane, Baranof Island, SE Alaska&#8221;  Their work shows that this part of Alaska cooled rapidly after pluton intrusion in the Late Eocene and early Oligocene (c. 30 Ma).</p>
<p>The Keck Alaska research team has six students, all of whom presented three different posters that detailed results on the age of the Sitka Graywacke, its provenance, and the evolution of the Crawfish Inlet Pluton that intrudes these rocks in SE Alaska. </p>
<p>The Cordilleran Tectonics Workshop is an annual meeting held at Canadian universities, and it is attended by students, faculty, and professionals working on understanding the evolution of the Canadian Cordillera.  The geology of Alaska, especially SE Alaska is particularly important because the rocks are allied with those of the outer belts of British Columbia.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/24/keck-alaska-presents-at-kelowna-bc/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/24/keck-alaska-presents-at-kelowna-bc/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Gregg Brenn&#8217;s Summer 2013 Keck Fellowship Summary]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/13/gregg-brenns-summer-2013-keck-fellowship-summary/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=413</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T14:28:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-02-13T14:42:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Fall 2013" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Featured" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Newsletters" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I participated in a Keck Geology Consortium project to  [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/13/gregg-brenns-summer-2013-keck-fellowship-summary/"><![CDATA[<p>I participated in a Keck Geology Consortium project to the Nicoya Peninsula of Costa Rica, where I was characterizing the aftershock seismicity above the rupture zone of the September 5, 2012 Mw= 7.6 Nicoya Earthquake.  The Keck group consisted of a geophysics team and a geomorphology team, and I was part of the the 4-student geophysics team, along with Costa Rican seismologist Dr. Marino Protti, in which we deployed a local, 5-station seismic array and GPS network.  Our goal was to monitor for earthquakes, and with the data collected, we will locate the epicenters and depths to understand where the earthquakes are occurring along the plate interface.  This was a great opportunity to gain experience deploying and servicing seismic stations in a tectonically active field environment, and I hope to use this data to contribute to future megathrust earthquake prediction on the Nicoya Peninsula.  </p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/13/gregg-brenns-summer-2013-keck-fellowship-summary/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/13/gregg-brenns-summer-2013-keck-fellowship-summary/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Meghan Riehl&#8217;s Summer 2013 Keck Fellowship]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/12/meghan-riehls-summer-2013-keck-fellowship/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=444</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T14:28:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-02-12T21:44:40Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Fall 2013" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Featured" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Newsletters" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Thermal evolution and provenance of the Sitka Graywacke [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/12/meghan-riehls-summer-2013-keck-fellowship/"><![CDATA[<p>Thermal evolution and provenance of the Sitka Graywacke from Baranof Island, Alaska revealed through detrital zircon fission track dating<br />
For about four weeks in June and July of this year, I had the opportunity to participate in the KECK project led by Prof. John Garver (Union College) and Prof. Cam Davidson (Carleton College) in Alaska. Myself and five other geology students from around the United States are currently working on our thesis work based on the samples collected in Alaska.  My samples are of the Sitka Graywacke and were collected along approximately north-south and east-west transects in locations in and surrounding the Sitka Sound near Sitka, Alaska. We do not know the source regions for the Sitka Graywacke, but all considerations involve a right-lateral strike slip movement eastward of the sample locations. The Sitka Graywacke was originally a deep-water turbidite sequence that was buried under the earth&#8217;s surface where it was later metamorphosed. Studies on the thermal history through Zircon fission track dating of the graywacke samples will provide a better understanding of the provenance of the Sitka Graywacke.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/12/meghan-riehls-summer-2013-keck-fellowship/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/12/meghan-riehls-summer-2013-keck-fellowship/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Deb</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Jordan Thomson&#8217;s  Summer Research]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/12/jordan-thomsons-summer-research/" />
		<id>http://muse.union.edu/geology/?p=441</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T14:28:14Z</updated>
		<published>2014-02-12T21:33:05Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Fall 2013" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Featured" /><category scheme="http://muse.union.edu/geology" term="Newsletters" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Over the summer I began work on my senior thesis, which [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/12/jordan-thomsons-summer-research/"><![CDATA[<p>Over the summer I began work on my senior thesis, which is looking at the isotopic signatures of carbon and oxygen in hurricane and non-hurricane years in Loblolly Pine form North Carolina.  Therefore, I set up and tested an α-cellulose extraction method on some Loblolly pine.  This process is essential to my thesis as it isolates the cellulose from each sample, which closely correlates with climate.  I was able to run my trial cellulose samples through the mass spectrometer, and learn how to trouble shoot some issues that can arise.<br />
The last week of my summer research I went to North Carolina to collect my Loblolly Pine samples.  Four sites were chosen with increasing distance from the water.  At each location three trees were cut down, as well as two soil samples from near each tree were taken (a shallow soil sample and a deeper soil sample).  Pine needles were also taken from each of the trees that were cut down.  In addition to these samples, three older trees were cored.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/12/jordan-thomsons-summer-research/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://muse.union.edu/geology/2014/02/12/jordan-thomsons-summer-research/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
