<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">StoryLink</title>
	<subtitle type="text">Connect, read, and share the stories of Messiah College</subtitle>

	<updated>2014-06-16T11:55:03Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu" />
	<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.5.1">WordPress</generator>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[A passion for science and a heart for patient care help alum excel in medical school]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1845" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1845</id>
		<updated>2014-06-16T11:55:03Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-20T13:42:34Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2010" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Biology" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Scholarship" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Study Abroad" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[“As I completed high school and started college, I realized that there is no connection as intimate and life-changing as one can have with another human being,” reflects Naomi (DeYoung) Wiens ’10 on her decision to become a physician. “I loved building a foundation in science, physiology, anatomy and chemistry in college, and I was [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1845"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/971916_804256486944_1780301964_n.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1853" style="margin: 5px;" alt="971916_804256486944_1780301964_n" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/971916_804256486944_1780301964_n.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a>“As I completed high school and started college, I realized that there is no connection as intimate and life-changing as one can have with another human being,” reflects Naomi (DeYoung) Wiens ’10 on her decision to become a physician. “I loved building a foundation in science, physiology, anatomy and chemistry in college, and I was hard pressed to see myself feeling fulfilled in any other field.”<span id="more-1845"></span></p>
<p>Wiens is a third-year medical student at the Philadelphia College of Osteopathic Medicine in Philadelphia, Pa. Looking towards a future in surgery or interventional cardiology, Wiens challenges herself each day to become not only an excellent medical provider, but also a doctor who cares deeply about her patients.</p>
<p>“A simple, yet crucial take-home point I got from Messiah,” says Wiens, “is that it is not our role to place judgment on anyone else; that’s not Christ-love. The various chapel speakers and club meetings , as well as meeting many different people with different life stories, have all helped me be more comfortable and accepting of things I am unfamiliar with. I think this has had the biggest impact on my approach to patients thus far; I have become more open-minded and eager to meet new people as well as withhold judgment.”</p>
<p>In addition to the philosophy behind her patient care, she also made another connection between her time at Messiah and her time in medical school. In 2009, Wiens traveled to the Macha Mission Hospital in Zambia as part of the Healthcare in the Developing World May-term class. In August 2013, she returned as a medical student and completed a four-week infectious disease rotation at the hospital. Since her first trip to Zambia as a Messiah student, the country has held a special place in her heart.</p>
<p>Medical school is no doubt a challenge, but Wiens is confident medicine is the career for her. “I enjoy learning, asking ‘why’ and ’how’ humans work, live, breathe, the way we do. It&#8217;s truly amazing, and it reflects how intricate we really are,” says Wiens. “Now that I am on clinical rotations and assuming this role [of physician], I can see myself doing this until I am too old and too frail to come to work. I simply love it.”</p>
<p><em>-Erin Bray &#8217;10</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1845#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1845" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Chinese program helps student advance study]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1834" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1834</id>
		<updated>2014-04-28T17:30:32Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-14T15:27:13Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Chinese" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Class of 2015" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Nursing" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Study Abroad" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keterly Steyer ’15 is from Brazil, grew up in Chicago, and spent 3.5 years in Shanghai before moving to Buffalo, N.Y., for her final years of high school. Steyer is bilingual, learning both English and Portuguese as a child, and when her family moved to Shanghai for her dad’s job in 2005, she quickly had [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1834"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Keterly-Styer.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1835" alt="Keterly Styer" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/04/Keterly-Styer.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a><br />
Keterly Steyer ’15 is from Brazil, grew up in Chicago, and spent 3.5 years in Shanghai before moving to Buffalo, N.Y., for her final years of high school.</p>
<p>Steyer is bilingual, learning both English and Portuguese as a child, and when her family moved to Shanghai for her dad’s job in 2005, she quickly had to pick up the basics of the Chinese language too.<span id="more-1834"></span></p>
<p>She took language classes at the international school she attended in Shanghai but also learned a lot through interacting with locals. “It’s much easier to learn a language when you’re living in the country,” says Steyer.</p>
<p>When her family returned to the U.S. during her sophomore year of high school, Steyer wanted to continue studying Chinese so she wouldn’t lose the progress she’d made.</p>
<p>It wasn’t until looking for colleges that she thought about continuing to pursue the language even further. Coming to Messiah, she knew she was required to take a foreign language.</p>
<p>“Since I had already been taking Chinese, I didn’t really want to begin a new language. When I saw that Messiah had Chinese I was able to reach out to Stella [Ye] and learn more about the program.”</p>
<p>Steyer spends most of her days in the lab and hospitals studying to become a registered nurse. It wasn’t until her sophomore year that she decided to pick up Chinese as a minor. Because nursing requires such a demanding curriculum, it is often hard to also have a minor, but Steyer is excelling in both and is thankful for the practical experience she’s gained through nursing and Chinese.</p>
<p>She’s even had the chance to practice her Chinese in China, returning to the country during a May-term trip in 2013. “We spent a few days in Shanghai and I was able to see my old neighborhood and school. Things looked mostly the same, but there were some noticeable differences since it had been four years since I was there.”</p>
<p>Though Steyer’s immediate plan following her graduation next year is to get a nursing job, she would love to combine her Chinese and nursing skills one day, either returning to China or working in a city with a large Chinese population.</p>
<p>-<i>Erin Bray</i> &#8217;10</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1834#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1834" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Student researches pancreatitis at Hershey Medical Center]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1820" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1820</id>
		<updated>2014-03-17T19:33:01Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-17T19:32:40Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Biochemistry" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Class of 2014" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Grad School Bound" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Honors Program" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Internships" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Scholarship" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A biopsychology major, Michael Skolka ’14 wants to influence science and human health care through medical research. For the summer of 2013, he garnered one of the 24 spots in the undergraduate research fellows program through the American Physiological Society, which allowed him to research pancreatitis at Penn State Hershey Medical Center with Alberto Travagli, [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1820"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/02-07-Michael-5-Melissa-Hess1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1822" style="margin: 5px;" alt="02-07-Michael-5-Melissa-Hess" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/02-07-Michael-5-Melissa-Hess1.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a>A biopsychology major, Michael Skolka ’14 wants to influence science and human health care through medical research. For the summer of 2013, he garnered one of the 24 spots in the undergraduate research fellows program through the American Physiological Society, which allowed him to research pancreatitis at Penn State Hershey Medical Center with Alberto Travagli, professor of neural and behavioral sciences at Penn State.<span id="more-1820"></span></p>
<p>He credits Messiah’s Sheri Boyce, professor of biology, for serving as his mentor. “She helped read over my research and proposals and gave me lots of advice,” he said.</p>
<p>Skolka studied the neurological changes that occur after a patient’s episode of acute pancreatitis (AP). Even though AP typically resolves itself in one week, patients continue to experience discomfort for up to two years. Skolka identified changes in the network of neurons connected to the pancreas that may lead to these long-lasting symptoms. With Travagli, he used these results to write a new project proposal for 2013 focusing on a medical procedure that removes stones from the pancreas. (Five to 10 percent of patients develop AP after this procedure). Skolka and Travagli tested lidocaine on rats to dull the pain during the procedure and hopefully prevent the onset of AP. Their preliminary data shows that their hypothesis was correct: lidocaine sprayed into the pancreatic duct during the procedure indeed reduced post-procedural AP.</p>
<p>“Now that we know this, the next steps include continuing to work on this model of AP in hopes of eventually transitioning these results from the lab to the bedside,” explained Skolka.</p>
<p>In April, Skolka will present his research at Experimental Biology 2014, an annual meeting of 14,000 scientists and researchers in San Diego, Calif. “Neuroscience is fascinating. To study how the complex systems function in our bodies each day without us being aware is very interesting to me,” said Skolka.</p>
<p>He plans to attend Penn State Hershey College of Medicine in July.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>Story by Adela Antal &#8217;16. Photo courtesy of Melissa Hess. </em></p>
<p align="right">
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1820#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1820" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Scholar, educator, social worker and program manager—all as a college senior]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1808" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1808</id>
		<updated>2014-02-17T21:18:27Z</updated>
		<published>2014-02-17T21:17:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="About Service" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Class of 2014" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Social Work" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kaitlyn Zook ‘14 Social Work Manheim, Pa. In case life as a college senior isn’t busy enough with finishing classes, completing internships and preparing for graduation, social work major Kaitlyn Zook takes a busy schedule one step further and also works as a project manager leading Project Ubuntu for the humanitarian nonprofit 2 Seconds or [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1808"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/kaity-zook.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1809" alt="kaity zook" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/kaity-zook.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a><strong>Kaitlyn Zook ‘14</strong><br />
<strong>Social Work</strong><br />
<strong>Manheim, Pa.</strong></p>
<p>In case life as a college senior isn’t busy enough with finishing classes, completing internships and preparing for graduation, social work major Kaitlyn Zook takes a busy schedule one step further and also works as a project manager leading <a href="http://www.2secondsorless.org/project-ubuntu/">Project Ubuntu</a> for the humanitarian nonprofit <a href="http://www.2secondsorless.org/">2 Seconds or Less</a>.</p>
<p>Zook first heard of the organization during a semester in Philadelphia. After longing to get involved with an organization she felt really met the claims they were making, Zook was eager to see how she could help.<span id="more-1808"></span></p>
<p>Combining her passion for education and her social work background, Zook worked to develop a concept the 2 Seconds or Less team was interested in pursuing and came up with Project Ubuntu. 2 Seconds or Less works in northern Zimbabwe helping impoverished communities learn how to plant, harvest and prepare food as a sustainable solution to help break the cycle of poverty. Many times, the children of these communities learn the skills.</p>
<p>To add another component to their work with children, the group wanted to start a program that would connect children in the United States to the children in Zimbabwe.  From there, Project Ubuntu, an education and pen-pal program, was born.</p>
<p>Each month, Zook and a volunteer from 2 Seconds or Less visit three schools in south central Pennsylvania and teach the children about sustainability, volunteerism, culture, Zimbabwe, and collaboration and teamwork. In turn, the students write letters to the students in Zimbabwe. Students in the U.S. also hold fundraisers to help their fellow classmates in Africa, and along the way, cross-continental friendships are born.</p>
<p>Zook says she’s had to adjust to a steep learning curve met with any new experience, but says her social work classes at Messiah helped give her a solid foundation in the skills she needs to manage a successful project.</p>
<p>“Right now I am really hands-on with the project and find myself using many of the social work skills I’ve learned to run the program,” says Zook. “I have a passion for education, and I’m excited to help children understand empathy and develop a cultural awareness. 2 Seconds or Less is a small organization that is making a big impact on the communities they work with. I am excited to be a part of that.”</p>
<p>-Erin Bray &#8217;10</p>
<p><em>*Photo courtesy of 2 Seconds or Less</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1808#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1808" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaming up in television- alum leads broadcast operations for local station]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1770" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1770</id>
		<updated>2014-01-13T15:14:01Z</updated>
		<published>2014-01-13T15:11:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="1982" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="About Leadership" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Broadcasting" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Communication" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Humanities" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Keith Blaisdell ‘82 Communication Harrisburg, Pa. On any given day, you can find Keith Blaisdell ’82 bustling around the WHTM-TV (abc27, a local abc affiliate station) studio in Harrisburg, Pa., doing everything from finding new on-air talent, to researching and purchasing equipment, to making sure reporters’ microphones work for their live shots. Those are just [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1770"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Keith-Pix-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1780" alt="Keith Blaisdell, Director of Broadcasting Operations for abc27." src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Keith-Pix-1.jpg" width="170" height="170" /></a><strong>Keith Blaisdell ‘82</strong><br />
<strong> </strong><strong>Communication</strong><br />
<strong>Harrisburg, Pa.</strong><br />
<strong> </strong></p>
<p>On any given day, you can find Keith Blaisdell ’82 bustling around the WHTM-TV (abc27, a local abc affiliate station) studio in Harrisburg, Pa., doing everything from finding new on-air talent, to researching and purchasing equipment, to making sure reporters’ microphones work for their live shots. Those are just a few of the many things that Blaisdell gives oversight to as the director of broadcast operations for the station.<span id="more-1770"></span></p>
<p>Following 25 years a as a photojournalist, news operations manager and, eventually, news director at the station, along with a four-year break working with another company, Blaisdell now excels in one of the top leadership roles at the station.</p>
<p>In a nutshell, Blaisdell oversees all news, production and engineering at the station. He makes sure the news gets from story idea in the studio to live broadcast every day. With a 24-hour news cycle, Blaisdell’s work never stops, but he emphasizes the news wouldn’t happen if it weren’t for the strong, dedicated news team he works with.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">“My main goal is to support a great group of professionals and give them the tools they need to do great work,” said Blaisdell. “Broadcasting is a team sport, and I am lucky to work with an excellent group of people who make it [news broadcast] happen.”<b><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Keith2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1776 alignright" alt="Keith2" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/01/Keith2.jpg" width="175" height="212" /></a></b></p>
<p>Blaisdell’s interest in television began as a child and continued through his time at Messiah. “I always knew I wanted to be in TV,” said Blaisdell. “I thought having a broader liberal arts degree would give me more flexibility than a radio/television major, so that’s why I chose Messiah. A liberal arts degree teaches you to listen, to think critically and, for me, taught me a great deal about working as a team, which is what broadcasting is all about.”</p>
<p>Blaisdell was part of the first graduating class of communication students at Messiah and helped spearhead a class in television production where students went out into the field and produced a 30-minute news program. In addition to his work on campus, Blaisdell secured an internship with abc27 his senior year, which helped propel him to the successful career he has today.</p>
<p>“Messiah instilled an idea of service in me,” reflected Blaisdell. “Today I take that with me and know that my faith matters—my faith helps me treat people fairly, helps me see my colleagues as family and most importantly helps me give people a voice who don’t always have that.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>-<i>Erin Bray ’10 </i></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1770#comments" thr:count="2"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1770" thr:count="2"/>
		<thr:total>2</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Two grads, two coasts, one shared love for animals]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1696" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1696</id>
		<updated>2013-12-13T20:22:09Z</updated>
		<published>2013-12-13T20:10:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2012" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Biochemistry" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Grad School Bound" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Molecular Biology" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Scholarship" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Study Abroad" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lindsey (Hayes) Jett ‘12 and Elizabeth (Lizzie) Miller ’12 both knew from an early age that they wanted to be veterinarians. For Jett, it was her passion for animals. For Miller, it was a natural progression from her inclination towards the sciences and insatiable love of animals. Both agree that although a love of animals [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1696"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_1698" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 150px"><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Jett.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1698     " style="padding: 4px 4px;" alt="Jett" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Jett.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><b><i>Lindsey Jett &#8217;12<br /></i></b></p></div>
<div id="attachment_1699" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 150px"><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Miller.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1699     " style="padding: 4px 4px;" alt="Miller" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Miller.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><b><i>Lizzie Miller &#8217;12<br /></i></b></p></div>
<p>Lindsey (Hayes) Jett ‘12 and Elizabeth (Lizzie) Miller ’12 both knew from an early age that they wanted to be veterinarians. For Jett, it was her passion for animals. For Miller, it was a natural progression from her inclination towards the sciences and insatiable love of animals.<span id="more-1696"></span></p>
<p>Both agree that although a love of animals first piqued their interest in the field of veterinary medicine, it was ultimately discovering their passion for biology, clinical medicine and human connection through science courses at Messiah that really drove them to this career path.</p>
<p>Jett, a molecular biology major, who is now a student at Western University of Health Sciences in Upland, Calif., says, “Veterinary medicine has both the unique challenge of investigative medicine, and a wonderful human connection that I strongly identify with.  Veterinarians have some of the most varied clinical jobs—we can be surgeons, pediatricians, radiologists and dentists all in the same day, and we work on a variety of species. This variety within the career was very attractive to me and largely impacted my decision to pursue veterinary medicine.”</p>
<p>On the other side of the country, Miller, who was a biochemistry and molecular biology major, is attending the University of Pennsylvania School of Veterinary Medicine, specializing in the study of small animal medicine.</p>
<p>For both Miller and Jett, the opportunity to complete undergraduate research and work as lab and teacher assistants at Messiah made a huge impact on their preparedness for veterinary school.</p>
<p>“Now that I am in the rigorous academic environment that is veterinary school, I am realizing how excellent my education at Messiah really was,” says Miller. “I am excelling in my classes and finding I really learned the material well at Messiah. I contribute that success to the similar rigor of the biology and chemistry programs at Messiah as well as the dedication and expertise of my Messiah professors.”</p>
<p>Jett also adds that her time spent on cross-cultural and medical missions trips to Zambia, Nicaragua and Costa Rica contributed to her success in veterinary school. “In addition to the quality academics, the faculty and extracurricular experiences also had a deep impact on my career goals and understanding of veterinary medicine,” says Jett. I traveled to Macha, Zambia, as part of the Healthcare in the Developing World course which really opened my eyes to the important role that animals play in the health of human communities. It completely changed my perspective of veterinary medicine from an animal-centered view, to a community/public health view, where humans are an integral part.”</p>
<p>Although both Jett and Miller say that transitioning to veterinary school brings many challenges, such as managing school with family time and moving from a small college like Messiah to a larger university, they both emphasize that pursing a Doctor of Veterinary Medicine degree is well worth the challenge if that is where your passion lies.</p>
<p>“Veterinary medicine is a competitive field, but you can set yourself apart by pursing challenging, upper-level science courses,” advises Jett. “As a molecular biology major, I had exposure to upper-level classes that really deepened my understanding of the hard sciences. This has helped me tremendously in my first two years as a veterinary student. I continue to be amazed at how well my education at Messiah prepared me for veterinary school.”</p>
<p>-Erin Bray &#8217;10</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1696#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1696" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Professor’s student teaching experience leads to invaluable partnership]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1683" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1683</id>
		<updated>2013-11-15T21:06:19Z</updated>
		<published>2013-11-15T21:00:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="1979" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="About Leadership" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="About Service" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Education" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Scholarship" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Service and Learning" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Don Murk&#8217; 79 Professor of Early Childhood Education Mechanicsburg, Pa. What makes a kid who grew up in rural, eastern Pennsylvania interested in teaching in a city? That’s the question Don Murk &#8217;79, professor of early childhood education asked himself more than 30 years ago as student at Messiah College. Murk, who was an early [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1683"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Don-Murk.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1684" alt="Don Murk" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/Don-Murk.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a> <strong>Don Murk&#8217; 79</strong><br />
<strong>Professor of Early Childhood Education </strong><br />
<strong>Mechanicsburg, Pa.<br />
</strong></p>
<p>What makes a kid who grew up in rural, eastern Pennsylvania interested in teaching in a city? That’s the question Don Murk &#8217;79, professor of early childhood education asked himself more than 30 years ago as student at Messiah College. Murk, who was an early childhood and elementary education major, decided he wanted to complete his student teaching experience in an urban school and spent his student teaching semester at Downey Elementary School in the Harrisburg School District teaching kindergarten.<span id="more-1683"></span></p>
<p>Murk isn’t sure why he felt that initial interest in city schools, but is certain since then, he has held a lifelong passion for educational reform in urban schools, and a specific interest in Downey Elementary School.</p>
<p>“Ever since that student teaching experience I’ve wanted to do something in Harrisburg,” says Murk.</p>
<p>Like many urban school districts, Harrisburg faces challenges every day. However, under the leadership of Superintendent Sybil Knight-Burney, the district is making tremendous strides through a number of improvement initiatives, including the <a href="http://tft.challengepost.com/">Together for Tomorrow School Improvement Challenge</a> and <a href="http://www.theleaderinme.org/">Leader in Me</a> training.</p>
<p>The Together for Tomorrow initiative, a joint venture of the White House and the Corporation for National and Community Service, recognized Harrisburg School District and Messiah College for their community partnership last October. Murk’s primary responsibility in this initiative is supervising Messiah College education majors who are student teaching at Downey.</p>
<p>As a member of the Harrisburg Schools Foundation board, Murk has also developed a close relationship with Knight-Burney, and when she approached the board about bringing Leader in Me training to the district, Murk was excited to help.</p>
<p>“Dr. Knight-Burney suggested Downey before she heard my story about Downey,” said Murk. “For me, this was when I knew this was a partnership that was predestined.”</p>
<p>The Leader in Me is a school transformation model. Based on Stephen Covey’s “7 Habits of Highly Effective People,” The Leader in Me produces transformational results such as higher academic achievement, fewer discipline problems and increased engagement among teachers and parents.</p>
<p>Murk attended training with teachers and staff from Downey, who in turn, were able to begin the Leader in Me at Downey. This year, they are implementing one habit a week in each classroom and the teachers are excited to see the results.</p>
<p>“The exciting part [of Leader in Me] is that all of the teachers at Downey voted to do this program,” said Murk. “The goal is to make changes in your own life and then model it for others.”</p>
<p>There’s no doubt that Murk will continue to be involved with Downey Elementary for many years to come. He, along with the superintendent, teachers and other community partners, see nothing but potential for the students.</p>
<p>“My goal in all of this is to see kids in Harrisburg get an education that is as good as anyone gets anywhere else,” says Murk. “For too many years they have been cheated for one reason or another. These kids have the same potential as kids in other districts. It doesn’t matter that a high percentage of them live in poverty or that a high percentage of them come from single parent homes. You can look at that and say ‘these kids aren’t going to amount to anything’ or you can look at it and say ‘that’s true, they don’t have much… but we can give them a high quality education, we can educate them.’  That’s the exciting part for me.”</p>
<p><i>-Erin Bray ’10 </i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1683#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1683" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[For the love of the game]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1664" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1664</id>
		<updated>2013-11-15T21:05:18Z</updated>
		<published>2013-10-04T18:03:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2009" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Athletics" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Business" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Intl&#039; Students" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Silalei (Shani) Owuor &#8217;09 Human Resource Management Nairobi, Kenya What does it take to be a professional athlete? Silalei (Shani) Owuor ’09 is learning that like any other professional pursuit, it takes time, commitment and hard work. However, for Owuor, not only is she pursuing a sport she is passionate about, she is making a [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1664"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Silalei-Nyayo-Stadium11.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1676" alt="Silalei Nyayo Stadium1" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Silalei-Nyayo-Stadium11.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a><strong></strong></p>
<p><strong>Silalei (Shani) Owuor &#8217;09</strong><br />
<strong>Human Resource Management </strong><br />
<strong>Nairobi, Kenya</strong></p>
<p>What does it take to be a professional athlete?</p>
<p>Silalei (Shani) Owuor ’09 is learning that like any other professional pursuit, it takes time, commitment and hard work. However, for Owuor, not only is she pursuing a sport she is passionate about, she is making a name for the sport and its popularity across Kenya as captain of the <a href="http://maputo2013.fibaafrica.com/index.php/en/teams?ident=312&amp;group=B">Kenyan Women’s National Basketball Team</a>.<span id="more-1664"></span></p>
<p>Owuor’s drive to the top began with a spot on her local Nairobi team, the <a href="http://kenyabasket.com/eaglewings.php">Eagle Wings</a>, which is part of the Kenya Basketball Federation’s Premier League. Her involvement in the local league led to coaches scouting her, and eventually to a spot on the national team. Owuor has been playing with the Eagle Wings since 2010 and the national team since 2011.</p>
<p>In addition to her professional basketball career, Owuor combines her degree in human resource management with her knowledge of basketball in her job with Africa Insight Communications. There, Owuor serves as human resources manager, producer and co-host of the basketball magazine show “<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=56COlOv7gGk">Baqe</a>” that airs on Zuku, East African satellite television.  The show focuses on the Kenya University Basketball League, while giving insight on basketball culture, characters and supporters too.<i> </i></p>
<p>Owuor’s love of basketball began when she was only 7-years-old and she played with her father and brothers. She continued developing her skills and then made her way to Messiah, where she was a star player on the women’s basketball team which made it to the 2008 national championship game during her junior year.</p>
<p>Owuor says the independence she gained as an international student in college helped prepare her for the world and life beyond college. “Being an international student and living miles away from home, I had to become strong and self-sufficient,” said Owuor. “Developing those characteristics has helped me handle challenges very well.”</p>
<p>As for her future in basketball, Owuor says she will always be passionate about the game and will continue to pursue the sport for the foreseeable future, but she’s taking it one step at a time and looking to God for guidance.</p>
<p>“I have other dreams, especially in the areas of African development that I want to achieve,” says Owuor, “ but I think what is great is that my current involvement in basketball is contributing to my main mission.</p>
<p>“I believe there is so much potential for growth in Africa, and I&#8217;ve always wanted to come back and give back after attaining an excellent education at Messiah,” Owuor continued. “God has provided me with skills in basketball, so I believe that is the avenue that he wants me to use to achieve my ultimate mission: to teach girls the value of education and sport, and show how important they are to the African community.”</p>
<p><i> -Erin Bray </i></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1664#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1664" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Using local resources, alum creates one-of-a-kind furniture]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1642" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1642</id>
		<updated>2013-09-13T18:26:15Z</updated>
		<published>2013-09-13T18:19:37Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="1993" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Arts" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rick Dohler &#8217;93 Marketing Nashville, Tenn. As a full-time contractor in Nashville, Tenn., Rick Dohler ’93 comes across a variety of buildings every day. From updating existing structures to building something from the ground up, one thing he continually runs into are people who desire custom furniture, and a lot of discarded materials from old [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1642"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/storylink-pic.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1646" alt="storylink pic" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/storylink-pic.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a><strong>Rick Dohler &#8217;93</strong><br />
<strong>Marketing</strong><br />
<strong>Nashville, Tenn.</strong><br />
<strong></strong></p>
<p>As a full-time contractor in Nashville, Tenn., Rick Dohler ’93 comes across a variety of buildings every day. From updating existing structures to building something from the ground up, one thing he continually runs into are people who desire custom furniture, and a lot of discarded materials from old buildings that are being torn down.</p>
<p>Inspired by that increasing demand for unique furniture and his own interest in up-cycling materials that could very easily be thrown away, Dohler created a small business selling reclaimed wood furniture on Etsy.<span id="more-1642"></span></p>
<p>“Sometimes when I’m building a house, I’ll have a person explain a piece of furniture they want but can’t find. Many times I can make it for them,” said Dohler. “I like working with my hands, and this hobby gives me a chance to make things for my wife and I, and for others who have come to like my work.”</p>
<div id="attachment_1647" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 150px"><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/furniture-2-storylink.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1647 " alt="furniture 2 storylink" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/furniture-2-storylink.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><b><i>An upcycled barnwood coffee table created by Dohler</i></b></p></div>
<p>His shop, Dohler Designs, features a variety of custom furniture. From coffee tables and dining room tables, to armoires and display pieces, Dohler crafts local Tennessee hardwoods into rustic designs that give buyers a sustainable, handcrafted piece for their home or office.</p>
<p>Dohler primarily uses reclaimed supplies from old barns and buildings, but he also works with other local suppliers. He sees it as a way to be sustainable, using existing materials instead of buying new, and as an opportunity to be a good steward of the earth.</p>
<p>“There’s a lot of real hardwood in many of these structures that are getting torn down,” says Dohler. “Making this furniture gives things another useful life before throwing it away. Instead of just getting rid of it, I’m able to help put it back into a reusable process.”</p>
<p><i>-Erin Bray ’10 </i></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1642#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1642" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alum named new program assistant for the Middle East Studies Program]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1623" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1623</id>
		<updated>2014-01-16T14:50:13Z</updated>
		<published>2013-08-12T16:17:45Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2012" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Humanities" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Journalism" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Study Abroad" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sari Heidenreich &#8217;12 Journalism Jerusalem, Israel Over the past year, journalism alumna Sari Heidenreich ’12 became very familiar with asking the right questions. After all, as senior social media producer for WHTM-TV (abc27) in Harrisburg, Pa., Heidenreich was responsible for reporting breaking news at a moment’s notice and keeping online information accurate, concise and relevant. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1623"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/sari1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1626" alt="sari1" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/sari1.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a><strong>Sari Heidenreich &#8217;12</strong><br />
<strong>Journalism</strong><br />
<strong>Jerusalem, Israel</strong></p>
<p>Over the past year, journalism alumna Sari Heidenreich ’12 became very familiar with asking the right questions. After all, as senior social media producer for WHTM-TV (abc27) in Harrisburg, Pa., Heidenreich was responsible for reporting breaking news at a moment’s notice and keeping online information accurate, concise and relevant.</p>
<p>It’s no surprise then, that when Heidenreich heard about a job opening with Best Semester’s Middle East Studies Program (MESP), a program in which she participated in during her junior year at Messiah, she started questioning if it was the right opportunity for her.<span id="more-1623"></span></p>
<p>The MESP is run by the Council for Christian Colleges and Universities (CCCU). Through the program, students spend a semester studying contemporary politics, religion and culture of the Middle East in Jerusalem, Israel.</p>
<p>“I was very happy at my current job, but I couldn’t help but get excited when I saw the open position,” said Heidenreich. “After speaking with some people I knew that held the position before, I decided to apply.”</p>
<p>After she was offered the job, Heidenreich, who has been interested in journalism since childhood, spoke with several of her mentors who reaffirmed her plans to take a year off from journalism. They were confident that international experience would help give her a broader perspective and would ultimately bring her closer to her goal of becoming an international human rights reporter.</p>
<p>Heidenreich, who grew up as a missionary kid in Ghana, Africa, has always had an interest in travel, human rights and the Middle East.</p>
<p>“My dream job would be to combine my love of travel and culture with the public service aspect of journalism. This job will definitely help me gain more international experience.”</p>
<p>Heidenreich left for Jerusalem on August 5 and will spend one full academic year working with students in the program and assisting the program director with administrative duties, and anything else that comes along.</p>
<p>She is excited about the prospect of living in Jerusalem for a year and working with the program.</p>
<p>“I see this being a year for opportunity, growth and personal reflection,” said Heidenreich.</p>
<p>Even though this is a job and not technically a year of service, Heidenreich hopes this is an opportunity to give back to a program that gave her so much. “I’ll be helping to create a new group of global citizens,” she reflected. “As a Christian I think we need to care about our brothers and sisters; this program really equips people to do that and it is great to be coming back and train a new group of students.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1623#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1623" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Philosophy, biochemistry alum serves as cardiology fellow]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1592" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1592</id>
		<updated>2013-09-13T18:28:56Z</updated>
		<published>2013-07-11T14:05:14Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2003" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Biochemistry" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Honors Program" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Humanities" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Philosophy" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kevin Driver &#8217;03 Philosophy/Biochemistry Charlottesville, Va. Coming to Messiah College as a first-year student, Kevin Driver ’03 knew he wanted to pursue a career in medicine, so he declared a major in biochemistry. He had many family members and friends that served as mentors and helped him find his passion for medicine. What he didn’t [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1592"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/AlumniProfileDriverpic-as.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1606" alt="AlumniProfileDriverpic--as" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/07/AlumniProfileDriverpic-as.jpg" width="140" height="171" /></a><strong>Kevin Driver &#8217;03</strong><br />
<strong>Philosophy/Biochemistry</strong><br />
<strong>Charlottesville, Va.</strong></p>
<p>Coming to Messiah College as a first-year student, Kevin Driver ’03 knew he wanted to pursue a career in medicine, so he declared a major in biochemistry. He had many family members and friends that served as mentors and helped him find his passion for medicine. What he didn’t know, however, was that he would spend as much time buried in books about metaphysics and epistemology as he would in the lab.<span id="more-1592"></span></p>
<p>After taking a philosophy course during his first semester at Messiah, Driver discovered a new interest in the subject. “I found the issues of reality, morality, ethics, logic and truth fascinating,” said Driver. “I also really enjoyed breaking down complex arguments. Philosophy fit well with my analytical personality.” At the end of the class, Driver made room in his schedule for a second major in philosophy.</p>
<p>After graduation, Driver studied at the prestigious Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons in New York, N.Y., where he completed his Doctor of Medicine degree. Following his residency at Duke University Medical Center in Durham, N.C., Driver moved to his current position as a cardiology fellow at the University of Virginia in Charlottesville, Va.</p>
<p>Driver is primarily involved in patient care and diagnosis. He also supervises a team of medical residents, nurses and support staff, which requires strong communication and interpersonal skills. “While a liberal arts education won’t get you a job as a scientist, engineer or computer programmer, it just might help you hone the skills necessary to excel in that field. Being able to read and think critically—and communicate effectively—are at the core of education in the humanities.”</p>
<p>As he practices medicine, Driver continues finding reward in working with patients to help treat and reverse life-threating heart conditions. Although his degree in philosophy wasn’t necessary for his current role, he says it helps him on a daily basis. “Often, it’s difficult to process the subjective—a patient’s symptoms and history—with objective findings—the physical exam, imaging, labs,” said Driver. “I’m very attuned to the process of diagnosis.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1592#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1592" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Caring for children’s soles]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1577" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1577</id>
		<updated>2013-09-13T18:31:55Z</updated>
		<published>2013-06-17T13:12:38Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="About Service" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Biology" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Class of 2015" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Service and Learning" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Andrea Cole &#8217;15 Biology/Pre-Med Winfield, Pa. As Andrea Cole ’15 walked through the streets of the small Honduran town she was visiting on a church-sponsored mission trip in 2011, she noticed that many of the children were running around on the rough terrain with no shoes. Her heart ached for those children because they were [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1577"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/andrea-cole-2.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1581" alt="andrea cole 2" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/andrea-cole-2.jpg" width="140" height="171" /></a><strong>Andrea Cole &#8217;15</strong><br />
<strong>Biology/Pre-Med</strong><br />
<strong>Winfield, Pa.</strong><br />
As Andrea Cole ’15 walked through the streets of the small Honduran town she was visiting on a church-sponsored mission trip in 2011, she noticed that many of the children were running around on the rough terrain with no shoes. Her heart ached for those children because they were missing, what seemed to her, a basic necessity.<span id="more-1577"></span></p>
<p>With hearts heavy and a desire to help, Cole and her sister Emily started Honduran Soles—an initiative aimed at providing shoes to children in developing countries. The sisters started with a goal of collecting 200 pairs of shoes. They promoted their effort by creating a Facebook page and hanging posters at their home church in Lewisburg, Pa. By Christmas 2012, they had collected more than 3,000 pairs.</p>
<p>The church and surrounding community continued to help with shoe donations and financial support allowing Cole to travel to Honduras with her mother and sister in January where they handed out 2,000 pairs of shoes to children who needed them. After returning, they decided they would continue to collect shoes in hopes of traveling to other countries in need. They primarily take flip-flops, which are easy to transport, but also collect gently used sneakers.</p>
<p>Today, Cole says they have collected more than 5,000 pairs of shoes. “I feel like it is a ministry that people are willing to help out with because it is such a simple need, but a lot of times it’s overlooked,” she said. “People focus on clothes and food, which are really important obviously, but shoes are important too.”</p>
<p>This year, the Coles have set a goal of gathering 10,000 pairs. They plan to take shoes to the Dominican Republic and Haiti by the beginning of 2014.</p>
<p>Because of their work with Honduran Soles, the two sisters were recently recognized as Youth Good Samaritans by the Sunbury, Pa., chapter of the American Red Cross.</p>
<p>To follow their mission, visit <a href="https://www.facebook.com/HonduranSoles">Facebook.com/HonduranSoles</a>.</p>
<p><i>-Erin Bray ’10 </i></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1577#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1577" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Shooting for success]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1557" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1557</id>
		<updated>2014-01-16T14:46:46Z</updated>
		<published>2013-05-24T12:52:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2013" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Nursing" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Nicky Hess &#8217;13 Nursing Marietta, Pa. Recent grad Nicky Hess ’13 knows the importance of managing her time. After all, she spent her entire college career carefully balancing her two passions: nursing and basketball. In addition to her role as starting point-guard for the Messiah College women’s basketball team, who made it to the third [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1557"><![CDATA[<p><b><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/hess_nicky_hs.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1564 alignleft" alt="hess_nicky_hs" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/05/hess_nicky_hs.jpg" width="150" height="200" /></a></b><b>Nicky Hess &#8217;13<br />
Nursing<br />
Marietta, Pa. </b></p>
<p>Recent grad Nicky Hess ’13 knows the importance of managing her time. After all, she spent her entire college career carefully balancing her two passions: nursing and basketball.</p>
<p>In addition to her role as starting point-guard for the Messiah College <a href="http://gomessiah.com/index.aspx?path=wbball&amp;tab=_basketball">women’s basketball team</a>, who made it to the third round of the NCAA tournament this season, Hess managed a full course load as a nursing student—complete with clinical practice, site visits and time-intensive labs.<span id="more-1557"></span></p>
<p>Beyond basketball and nursing, Hess also made sure to enjoy the college experience, too, spending a lot of time with friends on campus. “Even though I had a lot going on with nursing and basketball, I wanted to have friends outside of basketball and enjoy the campus experience,” reflected Hess, “so I had to balance the three.”</p>
<p>Soon Hess will carry those time management skills over to her professional career as an emergency room nurse at Harrisburg’s Pinnacle Health Hospital, where she’ll need to quickly adapt to emergency situations and respond to a variety of patient needs.</p>
<p>Thankfully, she is well prepared.</p>
<p>After an initial visit to campus to learn about the basketball program—a sport she’s been playing since first grade—Hess realized that the combined benefits of a great nursing program and the chance to play college basketball was all she needed to commit to Messiah.</p>
<p>Since then, she has never looked back. Though she definitely faced challenges balancing the demanding practice and game schedule of basketball with the rigorous academic work of the nursing program, Hess never wanted to quit.</p>
<p>“There were times where I needed to meet in the middle and couldn’t have the highest expectations for both at the same time,” said Hess. “But I chose to do this; nobody forced me. I really enjoyed nursing and basketball, so I wasn’t going to consider any other options unless I really had to.”</p>
<p>Hess’ academic accomplishments were recently recognized at the Central Penn Parent <a href="http://www.centralpennparent.com/Our-Events/Healthcare-Heroes-Awards/">Healthcare Heroes Award</a>s held April 2013. Hess, who was nominated by clinical adjunct nursing professor Jeff Stroup, received the 2013 Future of Healthcare Award. The award is presented to a young adult who demonstrates a dedication to health care, professional behavior and service to local communities.</p>
<p>Hess, who credits her family for their support and encouragement, has known from a young age that she wanted to be a nurse. “I wanted to be in a profession where I was helping people,” says Hess, “and I enjoy the sciences and studying the body, so I thought it [nursing] was the perfect combination.”</p>
<p>Eventually Hess wants to serve as a medical missionary, but for now she will continue gaining valuable nursing skills in Central Pennsylvania, striving to comfort and heal each patient she treats.</p>
<p>-<em>Erin Bray &#8217;10 </em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1557#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1557" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alum leads game operations and events for NBA team]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1533" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1533</id>
		<updated>2013-05-01T12:41:41Z</updated>
		<published>2013-05-01T12:33:54Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="1996" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Internships" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Marketing" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Todd Bosma ’96 Portland, Oregon Director of game operations and events for the Portland Trail Blazers  From the moment a fan pulls into the parking lot of the Rose Garden to the moment they leave the door, director of game operations and events for the Portland Trail Blazers Todd Bosma ’96 is in charge of [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1533"><![CDATA[<p><b><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Todd-Red2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1538 alignleft" alt="Todd Red2" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Todd-Red2.jpg" width="140" height="170" /></a>Todd Bosma ’96<br />
Portland, Oregon<br />
Director of game operations and events for the Portland Trail Blazers </b></p>
<p><b> </b>From the moment a fan pulls into the parking lot of the <a href="http://www.rosequarter.com/">Rose Garden</a> to the moment they leave the door, director of game operations and events for the <a href="http://www.nba.com/blazers/">Portland Trail Blazers </a>Todd Bosma ’96 is in charge of making sure visitors have a memorable night at the game.</p>
<p>“I am responsible for everything that goes on during a game besides the five guys on the court dribbling,” says Bosma. “It’s challenging and a bit chaotic, but I absolutely love my job.”<span id="more-1533"></span></p>
<p>Bosma’s role encompasses all aspects of the fan experience at a Trail Blazers game, including writing a 50-page script for the announcer to guide each home game; overseeing the dance team and mascot; cueing music, <a href="http://www.nba.com/blazers/video/2012/12/18/JeffriesCD1-2330539">videos</a> and cheers; and <a href="http://www.nba.com/blazers/tbtv/video.html?videoID=5416">educating fans about players</a>.</p>
<p>“There are some things we can plan for in advance, but some of the best times are when we have to think on our feet and keep the momentum going, like during a time-out. I get to push a button and have 20,000 people scream ‘defense’ at one time.”</p>
<p>Bosma’s path to the Trail Blazers began with a love of basketball and an internship with the New Jersey Nets after graduation. Working in the public relations department and the game operations department for the Nets afforded  him the opportunity to help with press conferences, assist with the NBA draft and gave him a start at what he does today—planning game operations.</p>
<p>His hard work as intern paid off, and he landed a part-time game night position with the Nets. A few years later when his Nets boss was hired by the Trail Blazers, he took Bosma with him. Fourteen years later, Bosma says he is grateful for his move to Portland, Ore., and the job he holds today.</p>
<p>“I knew I wanted to work in sports, so I pursued any opportunities I could to get there,” said Bosma, who was a marketing major at Messiah. “If I wasn’t at the game working, I would probably be there watching. Sports are a main interest of mine outside of work, so getting to combine the two is ideal.”</p>
<div id="attachment_1537" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/tb2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1537    " alt="Bosma interacts with fans during a game. " src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/tb2.jpg" width="200" height="200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><b><i>Bosma (far left) interacts with fans during a game.</i></b></p></div>
<p>For a job that requires spontaneity and an outgoing personality, Bosma says Messiah’s compassionate community helped him to find his voice and to discover his talents. As a student, Bosma pursued his passion for sports by participating in intramural leagues, hosting a sports talk radio show on WVMM and serving as a play-by-play announcer for several Messiah teams—all of which helped build the foundation for many of the skills he uses today.</p>
<p>“I have to think about how we can get people who could do many other things with their time to a Trail Blazers game. We can’t guarantee a win, but we can guarantee they have a good time. My goal is to turn what is an everyday experience for me into an extraordinary experience for the fans.”</p>
<p><i>—Erin Bray ’10</i></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1533#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1533" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Student captures magic of the silver screen in short film “Palace”]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1486" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1486</id>
		<updated>2013-04-25T18:36:06Z</updated>
		<published>2013-04-05T13:34:34Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2013" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Arts" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Communication" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Film and Media Arts" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Humanities" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Philadelphia Campus" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Scholarship" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rolando Vega Bridgewater, N.J. Film and Media Arts Combining his creative spirit, passion for technology and love of film, Rolando Vega ’13 created a professional-quality short film for his senior honors project that culminated his academic experience at Messiah and prepared him for a future career in film. With the help of his peers, Vega [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1486"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Rolando_1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1528" alt="Rolando_1" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/04/Rolando_1.jpg" width="140" height="171" /></a><strong> </strong></p>
<p><strong>Rolando Vega</strong><br />
<strong>Bridgewater, N.J.</strong><br />
<strong>Film and Media Arts</strong></p>
<p>Combining his creative spirit, passion for technology and love of film, Rolando Vega ’13 created a professional-quality short film for his senior honors project that culminated his academic experience at Messiah and prepared him for a future career in film.<span id="more-1486"></span></p>
<p>With the help of his peers, Vega spent his 2013 J-Term shooting the film that will premiere at the Messiah College Film Festival on April 28 and at the Carlisle Theatre on May 5.  “<a href="http://www.palacethefilm.com/">Palace</a>” tells the story of three generations of movie-goers and how they connect through the cinematic past.</p>
<p>“I wanted to explore how film goes from simply being a medium to becoming a movie, and examine the experience of watching these movies,” said Vega.</p>
<p>Set in the historic <a href="http://www.carlisletheatre.org/">Carlisle Theatre</a> in Carlisle, Pa., “Palace” captures the magic that old movies palaces provide despite the challenges these theaters have faced throughout the years.</p>
<p>Inspired by the film industry’s current transition from celluloid film to digital production, Vega wanted to go back to the origins of the small theaters that brought communities—and generations—together.</p>
<p>“In the past five years or so, motion picture studios realized that digital distribution and exhibition was much more affordable,” said Vega. “Because of this, studios have decided to stop distribution of 35mm film. That means that theaters must transition to all digital screening rooms. Multiplexes like AMC and Regal have the capital funds to stay alive during this transition, but it brings a financial challenge to older movie theaters.”</p>
<p>Creating a story line that touches both the technical and emotional aspects of going to the movies, Vega combines his love for historic movie palaces with the realities the industry faces today.</p>
<p>“Film is not dead, per se, but it will remain a tool for the privileged filmmakers and directors to use,” said Vega. “How do we move forward into the future while acknowledging the roots of our past? In the end, ‘Palace’ is a movie about how movies make people happy.”</p>
<p>To get a sneak peak at the film, check out the &#8220;Palace&#8221; trailer:  <a href="http://vimeo.com/62608247">http://vimeo.com/62608247.</a></p>
<p><em>Erin Bray &#8217;10 </em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1486#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1486" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Student spearheads campus composting efforts]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1446" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1446</id>
		<updated>2013-02-27T16:33:14Z</updated>
		<published>2013-02-27T16:33:04Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2013" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Arts" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Go Green!" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Studio Art" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Study Abroad" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Adam Arditi &#8217;13 Studio Art Collegeville, Pa. As Messiah College’s first-ever waste diversion coordinator, Adam Arditi ’13 works to create a more sustainable campus each day by picking up pre- and post-consumer food waste from Lottie Nelson Dining Hall and pre-consumer food waste from the Union Café and transporting the waste to campus composting piles. [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1446"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/arditi.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1457 alignleft" alt="arditi" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/arditi-280x300.jpg" width="140" height="171" /></a><strong>Adam Arditi &#8217;13<br />
Studio Art<br />
Collegeville, Pa.</strong></p>
<p>As Messiah College’s first-ever waste diversion coordinator, Adam Arditi ’13 works to create a more sustainable campus each day by picking up pre- and post-consumer food waste from Lottie Nelson Dining Hall and pre-consumer food waste from the Union Café and transporting the waste to campus composting piles.<span id="more-1446"></span></p>
<p>After spending a semester in the Creation Care Studies Program in New Zealand his sophomore year, Arditi, a studio art major, caught the bug for practicing a sustainable and hands-on approach for using the natural resources available to him. The semester-long program focuses on Biblical stewardship and allows students to participate in homestays, cultural activities and ecological studies while also learning creation care habits such as composting. Composting, says Arditi, provides a practical way to use campus resources while helping the campus community as a whole to be faithful stewards of the environment.</p>
<p>“Composting keeps things in a good, healthy cycle that applies on many levels,” said Arditi. “We’ve got all this food that’s not all being eaten. Instead of putting it into a landfill where it’s never going to properly decompose, we can put it in a process that utilizes those nutrients that will eventually come back to us.”</p>
<p>What is that process? Working with dining services, grounds and the biology department, Arditi collects the food waste, including preparation scraps (pre-consumer) and excess food that students don’t eat (post-consumer) and transports it to an area of campus known as the “back 40.” Grounds staff adds leaves, grass clippings and other dry, carbon-rich matter to meet the piles’ decomposition needs and to protect the piles from wildlife. Next, they monitor and turn the piles to help accelerate the decomposition process. The resulting compost is used for landscaping needs around the College, including the Grantham Community Garden, the athletic fields and flower beds.</p>
<div id="attachment_1447" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 197px"><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/storylink-poster.png"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1447" alt="waste revolt " src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/storylink-poster-240x300.png" width="187" height="217" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><b><i>One of the Waste Revolt campaign posters</i></b></p></div>
<p>“Compost keeps your soil diverse by providing a lot of nutrients and minerals,” said Arditi. “It also helps keep the soil aerated. Instead of paying money to buy compost, we are able to use the resources we have available on campus to make it ourselves.”</p>
<p>In addition to managing those daily tasks, Arditi also used his art expertise to partner with professor David Kasperak’s Graphic Design and Professional Practice class to develop a campaign—The Waste Revolt—to  promote food waste awareness on campus. “We compost an average of 260 pounds per day of post-consumer food waste,” said Arditi. “The goal of this campaign is to encourage students to be more mindful of how much food they take versus what they will consume.”</p>
<p>Through a series of fact-driven posters, and an interactive food-waste diagram that measures daily pre- and post- consumer waste in Lottie and tracks weekly progress, the class created meaningful artwork that Arditi hopes will have an impact on students.</p>
<p>For Arditi, the entire process—from learning about composting to implementing it—has been rewarding, and he sees nothing but future success for the project.</p>
<p>“Because of Adam’s role we are able to compost all of the post-consumer waste at Lottie,” said campus sustainability director Craig Dalen. “If you multiply that over a year, that’s how many pounds of food waste he is diverting from the landfill that we instead use on campus. Adam’s been single-handedly the person who has taken it from idea to conception. Because of Adam, we are on track to continue to be a zero-food-waste facility in Lottie.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><i>Erin Bray ’10 </i></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1446#comments" thr:count="3"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1446" thr:count="3"/>
		<thr:total>3</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alumna’s photo inspiration for Jamie Foxx short film]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1431" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1431</id>
		<updated>2013-02-26T14:06:56Z</updated>
		<published>2013-02-01T15:12:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2011" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Exercise Science" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Studio Art" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Grace Lankford &#8217;11 Health and Exercise Science alum Hummelstown, Pa. Featured on the cover of the summer 2011 issue of The Bridge, health and exercise science alum Grace Lankford ’11 continues to pursue her love of photography in addition to her job as a wellness instructor. Though she focused her major course work in the [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1431"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Grace_Lankford-e1359727104253.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1403 alignleft" alt="Grace Lankford StoryLink" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Grace_Lankford-200x300.jpg" width="122" height="171" /></a><strong>Grace Lankford &#8217;11<br />
Health and Exercise Science alum<br />
Hummelstown, Pa.<br />
</strong></p>
<p>Featured on the cover of the <a href="http://www.nxtbook.com/nxtbooks/messiah/bridge_2011summer/#/0">summer 2011</a> issue of <a href="http://www.messiah.edu/offices/publications/the_bridge/">The Bridge</a>, health and exercise science alum Grace Lankford ’11 continues to pursue her love of photography in addition to her job as a wellness instructor.</p>
<p>Though she focused her major course work in the sciences, Lankford broadened her horizons by taking many <a href="http://www.messiah.edu/departments/visual_arts/">art</a> electives during her time at Messiah. <span id="more-1431"></span>“I love art, especially photography,” said Lankford. “I wanted to take as many classes as I could and photography has continued to be a passion of mine ever since.”</p>
<p>Now, a photo from one of those classes will make it to the big screen as part of Cannon’s <a href="https://www.longliveimagination.com/">Project Imaginat10n</a>, a photo contest and film festival sponsored by Canon and noted director Ron Howard that brings together aspiring photographers and celebrity directors by using photos as inspiration for short films.</p>
<p>Lankford’s photo “<a href="https://www.longliveimagination.com/gallery/photo/344">Rest Easy</a>” was chosen as one of 10 finalists in the Backstory category and was one of 10 photos that actor <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6ET_5TmLKMs&amp;list=PLp-znpQge8Hy0RyKiQNN0uRZBMKgRNEdo&amp;index=1">Jamie Foxx selected</a> for his film inspiration. Lankford took the picture during a digital photography class, capturing a tired chick just after it hatched at the Pennsylvania Farm Show.</p>
<div id="attachment_1405" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Just-Hatched1000pxls.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1405  " alt="" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Just-Hatched1000pxls-300x200.jpg" width="200" height="150" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text"><center><b>Lankford&#8217;s winning photo</b></center></p></div>
<p>“That day for class we spent time at the Farm Show taking pictures,” said Lankford. “I saw the chicks hatching and this one just looked exhausted. Last year, after a friend told me about Project Imaginat10n, I thought it might not be the whole big idea for a film, but this photo could be an interesting background story, so I submitted it.”</p>
<p>A few months later Lankford received the call that she was a finalist. “Seeing the images my photo was up against made me realize that it was a pretty big deal to be chosen,” said Lankford. “I had actually started to forget about the contest, but when I got the call from Canon to tell me I was a finalist and that Jamie Foxx chose my photo, my heart started racing. It was pretty neat.”</p>
<p>As a finalist, Lankford won $500 worth of Cannon gear and will get to attend the premier of the film later this year.</p>
<p><em>-Erin Bray &#8217;10 </em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1431#comments" thr:count="2"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1431" thr:count="2"/>
		<thr:total>2</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alumni couple creates mobile business with Lancaster Cupcake]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1361" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1361</id>
		<updated>2013-02-26T14:18:51Z</updated>
		<published>2013-01-08T20:30:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="2008" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Nursing" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Sport Management" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jeff &#8217;08 and Emily (Barcklow) Mitchell &#8217;08 Owners of Lancaster Cupcake Lancaster, Pa. What did one alumna do while waiting for her nursing license to transfer from one state to another? She baked. Then she started a cupcake business with her husband, which led to an appearance on the Food Network’s hit television show “Cupcake [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1361"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Cupcake_2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1397 alignleft" title="Cupcake_2" alt="" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/Cupcake_2.jpg" width="140" height="171" /></a><strong>Jeff &#8217;08 and Emily (Barcklow) Mitchell &#8217;08<br />
Owners of </strong><strong>Lancaster Cupcake<br />
Lancaster, Pa.<br />
</strong></p>
<p><strong></strong>What did one alumna do while waiting for her nursing license to transfer from one state to another? She baked. Then she started a cupcake business with her husband, which led to an appearance on the Food Network’s hit television show “Cupcake Wars.”</p>
<p>That’s exactly how it happened for Emily (Barcklow) ’08 and Jeff Mitchell ’08, owners of <a href="http://www.lancastercupcake.com/">Lancaster Cupcake</a>, a mobile bakery in Lancaster, Pa.<span id="more-1361"></span></p>
<p>“It was a bit of a divine appointment,” said Jeff, a former vice president of sales and marketing. “If it wouldn’t have taken her nursing license so long to transfer, it might not have happened.”</p>
<p>Gathering a foodie following in Pennsylvania, the Mitchells came up with the name Lancaster Cupcake to represent the local ingredients they use. With business cards in hand, they started contacting wedding venues.</p>
<p>“We went to one wedding expo last year and booked our entire year of weddings,” said Emily.</p>
<p><strong>Cupcake Wars</strong></p>
<p>Friends and family then encouraged the couple to audition for “<a href="http://www.foodnetwork.com/cupcake-wars/index.html">Cupcake Wars</a>.” So they created an audition tape and were contacted for a casting call. After several rounds of interviews, they traveled to Los Angeles, Calif., to film the episode that aired in November 2012. The Mitchells and three other couples competed to make pizza-themed cupcakes in the first round for the cast of the new “Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles” animated series. Although the pair made it to the finals, they lost in the last round.</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="5" cellpadding="4" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td valign="top" bgcolor="#e8f3fa" width="319"><strong>Want to see more?</strong><strong> </strong><br />
To watch the couple’s audition video for the show, visit:<strong> </strong><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abx1kxp9qZU">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=abx1kxp9qZU</a><br />
For a behind the scene’s recap of the episode, visit: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=24XtEBaJ2Lg">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=24XtEBaJ2Lg</a></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>“’Cupcake Wars’ was very intense,” said Emily. “We were prepared [to bake], but we weren’t prepared for the entire experience of being on TV. You get kind of lost in the moment. You’re used to baking very privately, and people just see what goes out. This shows the whole process, so it’s a little more nerve-racking.”</p>
<p>Since the show, business continues to grow. With the addition of a bright pink food truck, an uptick in business and new flavors, the Mitchells continue on the sweet path to success. “It’s nice to take a leap of faith with a hobby and have it become a successful business,” said Emily. “It’s amazing.”</p>
<p>Erin Bray ’10</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1361#comments" thr:count="3"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1361" thr:count="3"/>
		<thr:total>3</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[‘God story’ inspires alum to pen children’s book]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1343" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1343</id>
		<updated>2013-02-26T14:14:18Z</updated>
		<published>2012-12-18T15:05:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="1991" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Majors &amp; Minors" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Social Work" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Spanish" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lisa (Zaleta) Williams ’91 Author and Licensed Clinical Social Worker Smyrna, De. Lisa (Zaleta) Williams ’91 has always enjoyed working with children. As a mother of three and a licensed clinical social worker who works with middle school students, she is improving the lives of children and teens every day. In addition to her social [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1343"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/version-1.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1346 alignleft" title="Lisa Williams " alt="" src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/version-1-245x300.jpg" width="196" height="240" /></a><strong>Lisa (Zaleta) Williams ’91<br />
</strong><strong> Author</strong> <strong>and Licensed Clinical Social Worker</strong><br />
<strong> Smyrna, De.</strong></p>
<p>Lisa (Zaleta) Williams ’91 has always enjoyed working with children. As a mother of three and a licensed clinical social worker who works with middle school students, she is improving the lives of children and teens every day.</p>
<p>In addition to her social work job, Williams—who graduated from Messiah with a degree in Spanish before pursuing her master’s degree in social work from Temple University—also enjoys writing psycho-educational and advocacy pieces on mental health issues for Hispanic newspapers.<span id="more-1343"></span></p>
<p>Williams recently rediscovered her passion for creative writing after witnessing what she calls a “God story” a few Christmases ago, which led her to write her first children’s book, “The Christmas Hippo.”</p>
<p>“I have always enjoyed writing,” said Williams. “Writing poetry was actually an older hobby. I put it on the side burner for quite some time for various reasons. However, this project was definitely a moment of unleashing my inner writer.”</p>
<p>Williams completed the text for “The Christmas Hippo” in just 45 minutes. “I was simply a scribe to what God wanted me to share,” she said.</p>
<p>The book tells the story of a young girl who left her favorite hippo stuffed animal on the school bus one day. When the bus driver found the hippo, he knew he had to return it her. However, the girl’s family was moving, so when he went to return it, their house was empty and the school was closed for winter break. After praying about how he would return the hippo to the girl, a group of carolers showed up at the bus driver’s door. There with Williams and the other carolers, was the sister of the little girl who lost her hippo. The girl was staying at Williams’ house that night and came caroling with the group who, unaware of the missing hippo, arrived at the bus driver’s house for their last<em> </em>stop.<em> </em></p>
<p><em></em>“I was reflecting back about that ‘great God story’ and told my husband I just had to share it with the world,” said Williams. “I originally wanted to put it in a song. However, my husband suggested a children&#8217;s book. Long story very short, in 45 minutes, that very day, the book was written.”</p>
<p>Six years later, Williams has self-published the book through WestBow Press, a division of Thomas Nelson publications, and is enjoying the success of the book so far.</p>
<p>“I want to share the story of the Christmas hippo with as many people as I can,” said Williams. “My hope is that people will know to come to God with all their cares, no matter how small they seem and that it will teach a lesson that he cares about even our smallest concerns.”</p>
<p>To learn more about the book, visit <a href="http://www.thechristmashippo.com/">www.thechristmashippo.com. </a></p>
<p><em>-Erin Bray &#8217;10 </em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1343#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1343" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>ebray</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Business admin alum recruits for the Red Sox]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1336" />
		<id>http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1336</id>
		<updated>2013-02-26T14:08:51Z</updated>
		<published>2012-12-05T17:57:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="1995" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Accounting" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://storylink.messiah.edu" term="Business" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Danubio &#8217;95 Director of Human Resources for the Boston Red Sox Boston, Mass. If someone told Mike Danubio ’95 when he was in college that he would be the director of human resources for the Boston Red Sox, he would not have believed it. But with a Messiah business degree in hand and a [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1336"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_2102-3.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1337" title="IMG_2102 (3)" alt="Mike Danubio Storylink " src="http://storylink.messiah.edu/wp-content/uploads/2012/12/IMG_2102-3-224x300.jpg" width="179" height="240" /></a><strong>Mike Danubio &#8217;95</strong></p>
<p><strong>Director of Human Resources for the Boston Red Sox</strong></p>
<p><strong>Boston, Mass.</p>
<p></strong>If someone told Mike Danubio ’95 when he was in college that he would be the director of human resources for the Boston Red Sox, he would not have believed it. But with a Messiah business degree in hand and a passion for human resources and talent acquisition, that is exactly where he is today—playing a key leadership role in the hiring, employee training and employee relations for the front office operations of the team in Boston, Mass.  <span id="more-1336"></span></p>
<p>Prior to joining the Red Sox organization though, Danubio had an interesting career path that led him to where he is today.</p>
<p>As a business student at Messiah with an accounting concentration, Danubio met with recruiters from the top accounting firms, either in class or at department networking events. Determined to score that prized first job, he was persistent and landed a position in the Boston office with the assurance and advisory services group of one of the top four U.S. accounting firms: Deloitte and Touche.</p>
<p>“When I first applied, I did not get the interview at Deloitte – at the time, no one in the Boston office had heard of Messiah College,” said Danubio, “but I wasn’t taking no for an answer. I knew my classes with professors Tom Chilcote and Jim Krimmel gave me a strong technical background, and the strong emphasis the department put on writing helped prepare me, too.  I gathered the Effective Writing curriculum along with actual assignments and sent them along. I don’t know if that’s what made it happen, but I got an interview shortly after sending those materials and they offered me a job on the spot. I’m thankful my professors knew having effective writing curriculum was important for us as accounting majors.”</p>
<p>Danubio went directly to Deloitte and Touche’s assurance and advisory services practice working for a variety of clients. Intrigued by the recruiters who had visited his accounting classes at Messiah though, he helped the firm’s recruiters, attending college fairs, participating in meet and greets and becoming an advocate for the company.</p>
<p>After four years on the client service side of the business, he then moved to the firm’s recruitment department where he led all Boston-based campus recruiting for a year and then landed a job with Staples to build and manage the company’s first ever campus recruitment program. After seven years with Staples, Danubio spent a short time at CVS and then moved to Hasbro where he developed the first talent acquisition center of excellence for the well-known toy and game company.</p>
<p>Though he enjoyed his job with Hasbro, Danubio couldn’t resist exploring the possibility of a job with the Red Sox when a networking call came his way. “All the elements fell into place,” he said. “I truly want to become a head of human resources at some point, so transitioning from recruitment to general human resources for an iconic brand that I love was a great move.”</p>
<p>So for the past eight months, Danubio goes to work every day at Fenway Park, interacting with employees—many he says who’ve been working there longer than he has been alive—building relationships, looking for new talent and building programs that save time, money and increase the overall quality of the workplace.</p>
<p>Danubio offers this advice for job seekers: Use your network, follow your passion and outlast the competition. Just like any batter swinging for the majors, there are a lot of people stepping up to the plate to get that dream job.</p>
<p>“I would have never imagined that I would be working where I am today, especially in my sophomore year of college as a new accounting student,” said Danubio. “It’s hard to know where you’re going to be 15 years down the road when you’re in college, but the best advice I can give is to embrace the opportunities because you never know where you’ll end up.”</p>
<p>Erin Bray ’10</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?p=1336#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://storylink.messiah.edu/?feed=atom&#038;p=1336" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
