<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Study Abroad Blogs</title>
	<subtitle type="text">Home and Away:  Tales from abroad - the study abroad experience as it happens.</subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-20T02:04:56Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" />
	<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.9.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Vivian Chow</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[COEX Aquarium]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/coex-aquarium/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=coex-aquarium" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4566</id>
		<updated>2014-07-20T02:04:56Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-20T02:04:56Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[So I am not a big fan of museums or aquariums or events in general where I cannot interact with the art so COEX Aquarium was just a 3 on a scale from 1 to 5. It cost 22,000 won, so about $22. It did have a lot of different aquatic animals like fishes, sharks, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/coex-aquarium/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=coex-aquarium"><![CDATA[<p>So I am not a big fan of museums or aquariums or events in general where I cannot interact with the art so COEX Aquarium was just a 3 on a scale from 1 to 5. It cost 22,000 won, so about $22. It did have a lot of different aquatic animals like fishes, sharks, octopus, seals, penguins and sting rays. I am listing a few things on the top of my head, so the aquarium probably does offer more than listed before.</p>
<p>My favorite was the seals because they kept doing cycles of back flips. I am unsure if that is just how seals are suppose to swim naturally but it felt like a little show for me. My second favorite would be the Good Doctor fishes that nibble on you, they remove the dead skin cells. I have always wanted to try that and to be honest I was a little bit of a coward so I am glad I got this little exposure before trying a whole container of them nibbling on my feet.</p>
<p>Adding on, there was the Love Machine evaluating machine. I do not think that was accurate because me and the group of friends I came with to COEX all matched well. This just shows more of the couple culture that is prominent in South Korea.</p>
<p>From Dankook University to the COEX Aquarium it takes about an hour and a half &#8211; taking the 8101 bus to Gangnam Station then transferring to the train. So it is a bit of a commute but definitely worth it because COEX is also a shopping area. Now if you are not into animals or shopping &#8230; this place is not for you. There are Korean souvenir shops &#8211; a very small Insadong, Korean souvenir district, in COEX so you may want to pick up a few items to take back home there. In addition, everything in South Korea is reasonably priced, there are not overpriced souvenirs in COEX, and the prices align well with the prices of the items in Insadong.</p>
<p>More travel posts to the coming. For now &#8230;</p>
<h3 class="r" style="color: #222222;">안녕, V</h3>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/coex-aquarium/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=coex-aquarium#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/coex-aquarium/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Breen</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The end is near]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/the-end-is-near/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-end-is-near" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4562</id>
		<updated>2014-07-17T16:58:01Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-17T16:58:01Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[My study abroad in Prague experience is ending in two days, and I am quite upset by it. It is funny to think back to crying my eyes out for the first four days, asking myself how I would ever make it through the month, and now I do not want to leave. I had [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/the-end-is-near/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-end-is-near"><![CDATA[<p>My study abroad in Prague experience is ending in two days, and I am quite upset by it. It is funny to think back to crying my eyes out for the first four days, asking myself how I would ever make it through the month, and now I do not want to leave. I had my last final today, making the end feel even more real. I learned so much in my short time in Prague,and honestly feel that I have grown as a person. It sounds cliche, but it is the truth.</p>
<p>I would like to share with you what I learned:</p>
<p>1. Keep an open mind. A study abroad experience, while rewarding and fun, is not always easy. As I mentioned before I was extremely homesick when I initially arrived. It is hard being away from family and friends. Not having the food your accustomed to, and being surrounded by people who speak a different language. There are also minor differences that I would have never even thought about before I got here. My dorm room does not have wifi or air conditioning, but I have learned to deal with it.  I have been forced to grow up by being here. Be patient and enjoy everyday, because time will seriously fly.</p>
<p>2. Make time for work and fun. The classes at Charles University were very rigorous. I had a much more demanding workload then I am used to at New Paltz. I believe that this is due to the fact that I took six credits in only three and a half weeks, therefore the classes were very much accelerated. However, I often stressed myself out worrying, rather then doing my work. It is important to stay organized, and get things done whenever you can. That way there is still time to go out and enjoy yourself, without having unfinished assignments on your mind.</p>
<p>3. Take time out to explore the surrounding areas. I had the privilege of getting outside the city of Prague this past weekend, and exploring the beautiful Czech countryside. We went on a Saturday hike, and the following day I went to a castle 40 miles outside of Prague. Being away from the place you are studying at, even for just a short time, makes you appreciate it that much more when you return.</p>
<p>I have mixed feelings about returning to the United States. I wish all my family and friends could be transported to Prague that way I would never have to leave. On the other hand, I do miss certain things about the United States, and am excited to go back to a comfortable and familiar place. I really want to come back to Prague for an entire semester, and I hope to make that happen. Hope everyone is enjoying there summer. Until next time.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/the-end-is-near/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-end-is-near#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/the-end-is-near/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tyone Haynes</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Santiago, Chile]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/santiago-chile/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=santiago-chile" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4558</id>
		<updated>2014-07-13T02:00:59Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-13T02:00:59Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[So I have arrived at my final study abroad destination.  Santiago, Chile.  I was extremely sad to leave Buenos Aires, not only for my friends but for the World Cup final&#8230; though as much as I am die hard Argentina fan there chances of beating Germany not looking so hot&#8230;. Anyways the school here is [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/santiago-chile/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=santiago-chile"><![CDATA[<p>So I have arrived at my final study abroad destination.  Santiago, Chile.  I was extremely sad to leave Buenos Aires, not only for my friends but for the World Cup final&#8230; though as much as I am die hard Argentina fan there chances of beating Germany not looking so hot&#8230;. Anyways the school here is amazing!  The professors are beyond helpful and ready to work with you.  The location is very nice and I am doing really well.  I&#8217;ve meet so many cool people from Brazil&#8230; I think in South America is full of Brazilians.  But there differences in our culture is so interesting and fun.  But at the same time I sometimes feel Americans have the most in common with Brazilians.   I actually haven&#8217;t done to many touristy things yet&#8230; I&#8217;ve been more concentrating on my spanish and gastronomy of Chile.  Which btw the food is amazing.  I really miss Argentina and I think one weekend I am going to take a trip to Mendoza but I do really like Chile&#8230; I found out they have a Taco Bell so they scored some extra points with me.  The Spanish is soooo different hear.  Once I caught on to the accent in Argentina I really did not have a problem but here they use so many words and phrases &#8230; That half the time I am like what&#8230;?  It&#8217;s cool though  by the end of this trip I should be like able to understand many regional versions of castillano.  This week ill prob do some more tourist stuff because I&#8217;ve been pretty settled.  The school is Taking us on a weekend field trip to Valpariso which is supposed kind of like Chile&#8217;s San Francisco so that could end up being really cool.   I don&#8217;t even want to think of going home yet because I have so much more to learn and so much more to do!  Hope everyone who reads this is doing well! Will try to update soon!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/santiago-chile/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=santiago-chile#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/santiago-chile/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tyone Haynes</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[fotos]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/fotos/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=fotos" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4553</id>
		<updated>2014-07-10T20:22:45Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-10T20:22:45Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Yay I can post pictures now! San Martin Plaza during the game La Boca, Buenos Aires Friends from school &#38; Argentina &#160; &#160; &#160; &#160;]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/fotos/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=fotos"><![CDATA[<p>Yay I can post pictures now!</p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/31.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4552" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/31-169x300.jpg" alt="3" width="169" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>San Martin Plaza during the game</p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4554" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/1-300x294.jpg" alt="1" width="300" height="294" /></a></p>
<p>La Boca, Buenos Aires</p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2.jpg"><img class="alignnone  wp-image-4556" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/2-300x184.jpg" alt="2" width="284" height="174" /></a></p>
<p>Friends from school &amp; Argentina</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/fotos/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=fotos#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/fotos/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Samantha Flax</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Concluding Recap]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/concluding-recap/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=concluding-recap" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4529</id>
		<updated>2014-07-09T15:52:15Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-09T15:52:15Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Concluding Thoughts: So first I would like to apologize for the major delay in this post. I did not realize that when I got home there would be so much to do. I will not get into the boring details of this past week in the United States. Rather, I shall try to entertain and [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/concluding-recap/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=concluding-recap"><![CDATA[<p>Concluding Thoughts:
</p>
<p>So first I would like to apologize for the major delay in this post. I<br />
did not realize that when I got home there would be so much to do. I<br />
will not get into the boring details of this past week in the United<br />
States. Rather, I shall try to entertain and move you with my<br />
description of my last week in Ireland.
</p>
<p>When last we left off it was a<br />
Friday and I was doing work. So as I believe I mentioned previously, the<br />
next day was our trip to the Aran islands.
</p>
<p>The Aran islands are<br />
fascinating because of the history. They are one of the traditional<br />
places in Ireland that speak the Irish language on a daily basis. They<br />
moved to the islands to escape the British oppression during the<br />
Cromwell period. Their primary industry was fishing until it turned to<br />
tourism. We arose at the crack of dawn to meet our tour.
</p>
<p>After riding<br />
down a series of winding roads which made many people ill but did not<br />
faze me at all, we reached the ferry. This ferry ride had to be one of<br />
my favorite parts of the day. Lydia and I went all the way to the top<br />
deck and let the water and wind rock us around like crazy. If you think<br />
you are good at subway surfing try it on this ferry. On the lower deck<br />
you will be successful, on the upper deck you will not. But as I stood<br />
holding on to the railing for dear life, I withdrew into my thoughts. I<br />
thought about the power of nature. How nice it can be to feel so small<br />
and controlled by the elements in the best way.
</p>
<p>When we reached the<br />
island, we went for a snack. A very nice man at the Till gave me a free<br />
chocolate bar. Then we took a walking tour around the island. If I am to<br />
be completely honest I really did not want to do this. The last time I<br />
went to one of the islands I took a hike. This time I really wanted to<br />
explore the town center. Talk to the locals and such.
</p>
<p>Unfortunately, I<br />
did not get much of a chance to do this, however, Lydia, Hayley, and I<br />
had a lovely time picking flowers. Killian our tour guide taught Hayley<br />
how to make daisy chains and she taught me. I felt like a fairy child<br />
walking around with a daisy necklace and flowers in my hair. I truly was<br />
born the wrong decade…I am a hippie.
</p>
<p>So then we ate lunch at the top<br />
of a hill next to a castle. Can you believe it, a castle in Ireland?!</p>
<p>Anyway, then came the absolute best part of the day. I have always<br />
wanted to swim in a body of water in another country. I mean, Jones<br />
Beach really is awful. Well, I finally got my chance. As I plunged into<br />
the icy cold north Atlantic, I really thought my chest, my whole body<br />
was on fire. It was the best feeling ever.
</p>
<p>Sometimes, when you<br />
experience a physical sensation along with just going through life it<br />
really makes you feel alive. I really enjoy feeling alive. Sometimes,<br />
when I travel I really don’t feel like I am experiencing anything<br />
special.
</p>
<p>So what I can read about the history the tour guide tells us in<br />
my pajamas at home. But when you can swim in the water or pick the<br />
flowers of such a special place, you understand what traveling is all about.</p>
<p>Anyway, the rest of the day was relatively uneventful. A bird crapped<br />
all over me and I got sunburned really badly. But apart from that there<br />
is nothing too interesting to report.
</p>
<p>Actually, that may be the most<br />
eventful thing of the whole week. Sunday I did homework. For the rest of<br />
the week, I went out with friends. My friend Sarah came up from Galway.<br />
It was a good time.
</p>
<p>It was really sad saying goodbye to everyone.<br />
particularly the people who live in Ireland. Yes, especially you Triona.</p>
<p>Actually, I think I will talk about this for a minute. I was frustrated<br />
that I needed so much help because I was there for such a short period of<br />
time so I really couldn’t learn the place well enough to travel<br />
independently, but if I had I might not have gotten to know Triona. So<br />
maybe it’s not so bad.
</p>
<p>Anyway, I figure because I was studying abroad<br />
after all.
</p>
<p>At the end of this post I will copy one of my assignments. If<br />
you are incredibly bored by it just skip it I really don’t care. I loved<br />
the class though. I would love to post my concluding thoughts about the<br />
trip, but honestly, right now I am just not done processing everything.</p>
<p>So in a few more weeks I will do a final travel post about my true<br />
concluding thoughts. Right now it just seems surreal.</p>
<p>Samantha Flax Human Rights</p>
<p>After the atrocities that occurred during the Second World War, the<br />
nations of the world were determined to prevent such a tragedy from<br />
taking place in the future. They created the United Nations as a means<br />
to this end. In 1948, they wrote the universal declaration of human<br />
rights. This monumental declaration was to serve as a guideline of<br />
rights that every person in the world was entitled to. One of these<br />
rights is written in article five, it states, “No one shall be subjected<br />
to torture or to cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment or punishment.”<br />
The trouble with the declaration of human rights, is that at the time<br />
there was no way of actually enforcing them. While currently the United<br />
Nations has made efforts to enforce this right there is still a long way<br />
to go until freedom from torture is recognized around the world.</p>
<p>In December, 1984, members of the United Nations got together to have a<br />
convention against torture and other cruel inhumane or degrading<br />
treatment or punishment. This was because even with article five of the<br />
Universal Declaration of Human Rights, and article seven of the<br />
international covenant on civil and political rights, which both<br />
emphasized the right to freedom from torture, there was still a great<br />
deal of torture around the world. The convention sought to define what<br />
constitutes torture, set parameters for laws for individual states, and<br />
to find a reasonable method for helping to enforce these laws. The<br />
following is a summary of the convention.</p>
<p>Article one discusses the definition of torture as a use of mental or<br />
physical abuse used for coercion or intimidation. It also addresses the<br />
extremely important question of liability, stating that using the excuse<br />
that an authority member instructed the person to commit the crime is<br />
not a valid defense. Articles two through sixteen discuss the provisions<br />
that the states who sign the agreement should follow, from what should<br />
be included in domestic laws to how these crimes should be prosecuted.<br />
It states that all states must have laws that prohibit torture. It must<br />
be considered state offense. States will aid each other in the<br />
extradition process. Law enforcement and other public officials shall be<br />
instructed in what constitutes unlawful behavior. Any victims of torture<br />
should be protected and the defendants have a right to a fair trial.</p>
<p>These are only a few of the most important provisions of the agreement.<br />
Articles eighteen through twenty-six discuss the formation of the committee<br />
that will be organized in order to investigate crimes of torture in<br />
individual states. It explains how the committee will work and the<br />
rights it has. The committee can only make suggestions to a country that<br />
it thinks is guilty of crimes against humanity. It cannot enforce these<br />
suggestions legally. The committee will be formed of elected officials<br />
and they are required to submit an annual report.
</p>
<p>The last articles,<br />
twenty-seven through thirty-three, settle any disputes regarding the<br />
convention itself in regards to states individual rights, for example,<br />
whether or not they choose to agree and whether they are required to<br />
acknowledge the competence of the committee. All of these things are<br />
optional. While this is just a summary of the details, it does clearly<br />
demonstrate while well-intentioned, and definitely a step in the right<br />
direction, it has no legal validity in terms of actual enforcement. This<br />
is represented by the crimes against humanity in the United States.</p>
<p>The United States has several provisions in its constitution and other<br />
laws that protect human rights. These rights include the fifth, eighth,<br />
and fourteenth amendments to the Constitution. The eighth amendment is<br />
perhaps the most important regarding torture because it specifically<br />
bans cruel or unusual punishment. However, despite these laws and the<br />
United States general compliance with the United Nations there is a<br />
shocking amount of neglect on countless human rights violations, from<br />
jailing homeless people and giving children life sentences. As well as<br />
various war crimes such as the use of drones. Most disturbing is the<br />
United States’ use of torture in places such as Guantanamo bay. Despite<br />
a supposed ban on torture techniques there are countless reports of<br />
torture especially in military prisons.
</p>
<p>The government uses national<br />
security as a justification for strict actions, but the United Nations<br />
has still accused the United States of several crimes against humanity<br />
especially torture. The United Nations said that changing interrogation<br />
techniques is not enough. One of the most controversial topics regarding<br />
torture is the use of the death penalty in several American states. A<br />
question that is asked by many people particularly in the United Nations<br />
is how is death not cruel and unusual punishment? The answer is usually<br />
something about how these people are killed humanely. For example, they<br />
are killed painlessly and they get a last meal of their choice. Also, a<br />
sick person cannot be killed. However, this still constitutes a<br />
violation of the right to freedom from torture.</p>
<p>There are several steps that can be taken in order to significantly<br />
decrease the amount of torture going on. Hopefully these measures can<br />
eventually lead to the eradication of torture. Firstly, and most simply,<br />
the public must be made aware of the government’s actions regarding<br />
these heinous crimes in individual states and on a global level. Once<br />
the citizens are made aware of what is happening they can petition their<br />
governments to solve the problem. The main reason torture is able to<br />
continue in America in particular, is that most citizens are not aware<br />
of the magnitude of the problem, or they are told it is necessary for<br />
national security. Next, there is a more complex solution. While the<br />
United Nations is a wonderful organization regarding diplomacy and<br />
negotiation, it holds little to no power when it comes to actually<br />
enforcing its ideals and acts. If the UN could actually prosecute crimes<br />
against humanity instead of just making suggestions, it would be much<br />
more effective. This would be difficult because countries would feel<br />
that they are losing their right to sovereignty, however, human safety<br />
should come before self-determination when it comes to human rights.<br />
This could be enforced through an international court of justice.<br />
Instead of the articles from the convention against torture being<br />
suggestions they should be requirements for at the very least anyone<br />
that signs on. Ideally, it would apply regardless of a signature but at<br />
the current time this is virtually impossible. Torture can be decreased,<br />
but it will take hard work and cooperation.</p>
<p>Sources</p>
<p>Accountability for Torture | Amnesty International USA<br />
www.amnestyusa.org &gt; Our Work &gt; Issues &gt; TortureResult details<br />
U.N. slams U.S. for torture, NSA spying | Al Jazeera America<br />
america.aljazeera.com/articles/2014/3/27/us-human-rights-reportun.htmlResult<br />
details</p>
<p>Torture &#8211; HREA<br />
www.hrea.org/learn/guides/torture.htmlResult details</p>
<p>UN Convention Against Torture &#8211; Human Rights Web<br />
www.hrweb.org/legal/cat.htmlResult details</p>
<p>The universal declaration of human rights<br />
www.un.orgt</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/concluding-recap/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=concluding-recap#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/concluding-recap/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Emily Breen</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[My Life In Prague]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/my-life-in-prague/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-life-in-prague" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4546</id>
		<updated>2014-07-05T20:10:27Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-05T20:10:27Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Shortly after my first post from Prague, I went to Berlin for the weekend. Going to Berlin, made me appreciate Prague so much more. Berlin was much more expensive, and not as pretty. Berlin, like much of Europe is on the Euro, and the majority of the city was under construction. For anyone considering study [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/my-life-in-prague/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-life-in-prague"><![CDATA[<p>Shortly after my first post from Prague, I went to Berlin for the weekend. Going to Berlin, made me appreciate Prague so much more. Berlin was much more expensive, and not as pretty. Berlin, like much of Europe is on the Euro, and the majority of the city was under construction. For anyone considering study abroad, I highly recommend Prague. At the risk of sounding biased, allow me to state my numerous reasons. First of all Prague is a beautiful city. It is full of rich culture, and amazing architecture. Also the dollar is around twice as strong as the Czech koruna. I spend only between 10-20 dollars on a typical day, which includes food, and activities such as museums. An average meal costs under five dollars. My money goes a lot farther then it would someplace. I was in Berlin for only two days, and spent as much in that time, I would in Prague for over a week. The best thing about Prague is that no day is ever the same. Tomorrow will be different then today, and today was different then yesterday. I am really enjoying my two courses. They are rigorous, but also a lot of fun. My professors are intelligent, kind, yet challenging individuals. I feel that I am learning a lot.</p>
<p>One of my favorite memories of this entire trip is from yesterday. A group of my friends got together and had an American style fourth of July celebration in Prague. My friend Chelsea has a grill, and we barbecued in the park. We made hamburgers, hot dogs, sausages, and grilled vegetables. Chelsea has been here ten months, so she has a lot of local friends as well. It was nice to meet Czech locals for the first time. It is hard being in an American program, and only speaking English to meet locals, so I was very excited. We spent hours in the park. They also had music, and one point Chelsea and I got up to dance. The park was absolutely beautiful, and I really want to go back.</p>
<p>I still have my fair share of struggles in Prague, even though I am enjoying my time here overall. I had a mini freak out last week, worrying about my classes. I underestimated how much effort would go in to taking six credits in less then a month. Charles University is also a highly ranked university. I do not think I have put forth this much effort in my entire college career thus far, since the summer program is very much accelerated. I calmed down a lot though. Midterms are on Monday and Tuesday, and once they are done, things will be a lot easier. I also worry that people do not like me, and often times find myself getting overly sensitive, and anxious. It is hard being with the same people day after day at times. It is also easy to get on each other&#8217;s nerves being in such close corridors. I have good days and bad days here, but I try very hard to just focus on the good. That seems to work for the most part. A part of me never wants to leave Prague, but a part of me is excited to go home. I miss my family and friends. I crave whats comfortable and familiar. As corny as this may sound, studying abroad really makes you grow as a person. It forces a person to step outside of their comfort zone, and navigate new situations. If you are always comfortable you are not growing, and this is not a good thing. I want home now, but once I leave I am going to want to go back to Prague. I constantly need to remind myself to relax, I do have friends, and a good time here. I tend to stress myself out over every little thing, which is something I am trying to work on. The rest of my weekend is going to be spent preparing for midterms, but hopefully I will have lots of adventures to share with you next week. Hope everyone is enjoying their summer. Until next time.</p>
<p>-Emily</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/my-life-in-prague/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=my-life-in-prague#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/my-life-in-prague/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Vivian Chow</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Late Post, Only One More Week Left]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/late-post-only-one-more-week-left/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=late-post-only-one-more-week-left" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4540</id>
		<updated>2014-07-05T16:23:17Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-05T16:23:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="South Korea" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[I&#8217;m down to the last week of teaching, and although it has only been two weeks of teaching in South Korea, it feels like two months. I am surprised at the rapid growth of my relationships with my students, and other English Village teachers. To be honest, I wish the English Village lasted a little [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/late-post-only-one-more-week-left/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=late-post-only-one-more-week-left"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m down to the last week of teaching, and although it has only been two weeks of teaching in South Korea, it feels like two months. I am surprised at the rapid growth of my relationships with my students, and other English Village teachers. To be honest, I wish the English Village lasted a little longer, I still need my students to show me around South Korea! I will be taking a Korean language during my stay here, so hopefully I will be able to grasp onto the language ad utilize it to survive everyday here.</p>
<p>Since last time I posted, I have been to Myeongdong (<span style="color: #545454;">명동) and saw the musical Ghost, which one of the three casts was Joo Won, an amazing actor. 명동 was a little too crowded for my liking, and even though I am from New York and Soho is just as comparable, I rather not have to go through crowds regardless of where I am at. WARNING: if you come to South Korea and walk through 명동, you will get lots of free samples! You do not even have to go that far to 명동, and even walking through the city of Yongin will gain you some samples. I do like that 명동 do have not only Korean fashion and cheap items, but there is also Forever 21, Uniqlo, H&amp;M, Zara, and American Apparel. So if Korean fashion is not your style, or not the right fit, there are still western brands. I also really enjoyed the underground market. The $10 clothing rack was my best friend last weekend. Transitioning to the musical. Sighs, I was not able to see Joo Won perform, but I did see Joo Won in the flesh. Me and my friend bought tickets for the last show, thus all the cast came out on stage. The musical itself was spectacular. The settings and the props used was amazing, and it was definitely worth $112 &#8211; I was pretty close to the front and little to the side but still had a great view. I could tell this production cost a lot of money and the immense amount of effort put into this production so even though I bought the ticket expecting to see Joo Won perform, I am not even mad.</span>For now, I am looking forward to getting a haircut, going to Insadong (<span style="color: #545454;">인사동), going to COEX Aquarium, and exploring all South Korea has to offer me.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #545454;">안녕, V  </span></p>
<p>P.S. Follow my instagram: viow9 for pictures!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/late-post-only-one-more-week-left/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=late-post-only-one-more-week-left#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/07/late-post-only-one-more-week-left/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tyone Haynes</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Va, Va, Vamos Argentina. Vamos a Ganar!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/va-va-vamos-argentina-vamos-a-ganar/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=va-va-vamos-argentina-vamos-a-ganar" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4537</id>
		<updated>2014-06-29T23:00:32Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-29T23:00:32Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="South America" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Well this website is not letting me post any pictures so that stinks.  I try again later in the week if I have time but.  So i&#8217;ve been in Argentina for about 2 weeks and I was actually supposed to leave to start my study abroad program in Chile yesterday but I didn&#8217;t.  I really [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/va-va-vamos-argentina-vamos-a-ganar/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=va-va-vamos-argentina-vamos-a-ganar"><![CDATA[<p>Well this website is not letting me post any pictures so that stinks.  I try again later in the week if I have time but.  So i&#8217;ve been in Argentina for about 2 weeks and I was actually supposed to leave to start my study abroad program in Chile yesterday but I didn&#8217;t.  I really like it here&#8230; so much better the NYC.  The people, the culture and the language.  I think there Spanish is so beautiful.  And my home stay mom was one of the kindest women I&#8217;ve ever meet.  The first week I was here I stood in an hostel and meet so many different people from all over the world.  It was an amazing experience, I heard study abroad makes people find themselves but I feel like im finding the world.  The coolest thing about my hostel was that it had a bar and restaurant attached to it.  The hostel gave free entry to locals and residence of the hostel.  This one thing has defined my trip.  Because of this I made real friends from Argentina&#8230; people who leave here, work here and grow up here.  I&#8217;ve hung out with so many locals because of it.  I&#8217;ve made very few study abroad friends at my university&#8230; (I think Spanglish is really becoming my first language now as well they don&#8217;t say college in SA they say university)  But I like that I don&#8217;t really hang out with those people because now I am constantly surrounded my argentine culture and language.  It&#8217;s like I really living here.  Classes are really small here 2 to 3 students per class so you really get an intimate focus I like it.  THINGS I DONT LIKE&#8230;. Not to sound so American (SA&#8217;s hate when you say your american&#8230;. were from the united states) but they walk wayyy to much here.  Its about a 30ish minute walk to my school everyday&#8230; plus we walk everywhere when were going somewhere.  My legs like actually were in pain two days again and I had to chill.  I also really not to big on the food here.  It&#8217;s kind of bland and the dairy is weird.  Plus I&#8217;m a vegetarian and Argentine&#8217;s put meat in everything!  It&#8217;s almost impossible to eat here&#8230; I had a bread and cheese sandwhich the first 3 days I was here. Also Argentine culture is very touchy feely.  I am not about that.   A lot of these things I could get used to and are no way or how running my trip I did not expect anything to be perfect.  I&#8217;m really sad I am leaving in a week to Santiago, Chile.  Not that I won&#8217;t like the country but I do not believe ill be able to make Chilean friends there.  I love being imersced in this culture in wish I could stay longer.   I told my friends here that in argentina is in the finals of the world cup I will sell a kidney to get back here!  The way the country gets about soccer is so crazy but so drawing.  At first I was like who cares, but after attending 3 &#8220;partidos de futbol&#8221; I catch myself interested in the games and wanting to watch them when I can.  This experience has been amazing so far and I am so grateful.  Thank you to my parents, family and god for allowing this to happen. I will update you soon and hopefully I can add some pictures!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/va-va-vamos-argentina-vamos-a-ganar/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=va-va-vamos-argentina-vamos-a-ganar#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/va-va-vamos-argentina-vamos-a-ganar/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>La Tasha Brown</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Jamaican Experience.com!!!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/the-jamaican-experience-com/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-jamaican-experience-com" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4473</id>
		<updated>2014-06-27T00:41:07Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-27T00:41:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="Jamaica" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey everyone!!! We are in our last week of our study abroad trip with the Jamaica Service- Learning Program! Boy, it has been an eventful 3 weeks thus far!!! We continued to learn a lot about the history of jamaica by visiting many historical places such as the Bob Marley Museum [Bob Marley's home till [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/the-jamaican-experience-com/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-jamaican-experience-com"><![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!!!</p>
<p>We are in our last week of our study abroad trip with the Jamaica Service- Learning Program! Boy, it has been an eventful 3 weeks thus far!!! We continued to learn a lot about the history of jamaica by visiting many historical places such as the Bob Marley Museum [Bob Marley's home till he died in 1981], Tuff Gong Studio [Largest Caribbean studio founded by Bob Marley], the National Gallery [public art museum], the Afro &#8211; Caribbean Institute of Jamaica and the Jamaica Memory Bank [collects documents and research about Jamaica's cultural heritage], Emancipation park, and the Gleaner (Newspaper publishing company).</p>
<p>Here are some pictures of the wonderful, interesting, historical adventures of Jamaica!!!</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4514" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-18-16.08.18-225x300.jpg" alt="2014-06-18 16.08.18" width="225" height="300" />(Emancipation Park-symbol of our Freedom to Hope, to Excel and to Be!)</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4511" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_20140609_120850-300x300.jpg" alt="IMG_20140609_120850" width="300" height="300" />(JSLP &#8217;14 with Ky-mani Marley at the Bob Marley Cafe)</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4517" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-09-13.34.03-225x300.jpg" alt="2014-06-09 13.34.03" width="225" height="300" />(real life size Bob Marley Statue #OneLove) <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3891.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4518" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3891-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3891" width="300" height="200" /></a> (after our Devon House Tour &#8211; Huge House)<img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4507" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-13.10.12-300x200.jpg" alt="2014-06-12 13.10.12" width="300" height="200" />(Tuff Gong International #ONELOVE)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We have been staying at the University of Mona and everyone has their own rooms with common area to share. The girls are on one level and the guys are on the lower level. We enjoy our own rooms for personal space but at the same time, we all have had at least one or more conversations with the another on this trip within the common area.  We have cooked together, went to the supermarket to buy kitchen supplies and ingredients. We have played Uno, card games, dominoes and just laughed, talked while enjoying each others company. This trip has brought many of us closer than before (some more than others) but overall we have been enjoying our time and the company of everyone participating on this trip!!!</p>
<p>The food has been great!! We had the chance to try jerk chicken, curry, seafood, rice and peas, pasta and other regular american foods! I think our favorite thing to eat are riped plantains (it has been apart of every meal lol). Below are two pictures of food from the &#8220;streets&#8221; and a home made meal being cooked.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4515" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-14-17.58.15-300x225.jpg" alt="2014-06-14 17.58.15" width="300" height="225" />(where we got some awesome food &#8211; we call it street food)<img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4524" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-02-21.51.58-225x300.jpg" alt="2014-06-02 21.51.58" width="225" height="300" />(cooking in our kitchen at UWI- making boiled dumplings with salt fish and beans)</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Aside from all the historical adventures we have spent a lot of time at the Alpha Boys Home! We have planned activities for both inside the classroom as well as outdoors for the boys to enjoy their time! In the classroom, we assist the teacher in charge or lead an activity. Outdoors we play all sorts of games with the boys! We definitely enjoy our time here at the Alpha Boys School!</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4520" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_39612-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3961" width="300" height="200" /><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3968.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4502" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3968-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3968" width="300" height="200" /></a><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3959.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4494" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3959-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3959" width="300" height="200" /></a><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3955.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4493" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3955-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3955" width="300" height="200" /></a><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-13-15.41.17.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4525" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-13-15.41.17-225x300.jpg" alt="2014-06-13 15.41.17" width="225" height="300" /></a></p>

<a href='http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/the-jamaican-experience-com/2014-06-20-14-52-42/'><img width="150" height="150" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-20-14.52.42-150x150.jpg" class="attachment-thumbnail" alt="2014-06-20 14.52.42" /></a>

<p>One more week, or just a couple of days and its all over <img src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-includes/images/smilies/icon_sad.gif" alt=":(" class="wp-smiley" /> </p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/the-jamaican-experience-com/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=the-jamaican-experience-com#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/the-jamaican-experience-com/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Laury Veudna</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[YESSS!! To the Experiences!!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/yesss-to-the-experiences/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=yesss-to-the-experiences" />
		<id>http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/?p=4468</id>
		<updated>2014-06-26T23:21:47Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-26T23:15:37Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hey Hawks! ! How are you guys doing? Hope everything is well on your end. &#160; I am doing great!! so no need to worry. I  just ended my second week and I am starting my third week  in Jamaica. I have been exploring this great big island of Jamaica with open arms and eyes. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/yesss-to-the-experiences/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=yesss-to-the-experiences"><![CDATA[<p>Hey Hawks!</p>
<p>!<a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_4147.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4496" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_4147-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_4147" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>How are you guys doing? Hope everything is well on your end.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I am doing great!! so no need to worry. I  just ended my second week and I am starting my third week  in Jamaica. I have been exploring this great big island of Jamaica with open arms and eyes. The sights are breathtaking and so is the culture. The experiences that I experienced are by far the best that I have ever had because each place and event that I have been to has something new to offer. Fox example, my group and I visited the Bob Marley Museum earlier this week. Although I am a Bob Marley fan, I thought I knew everything  to know about the greatest Jamaican artist but I guess I was wrong. While visiting and touring the museum, I learned even more information about who Bod Marley was. Towards the end of the tour we even ran into one of his sons Kymani Marley, who also is a musical mastermind as well.</p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_20140609_120750.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4510" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_20140609_120750-300x300.jpg" alt="IMG_20140609_120750" width="300" height="300" /></a> Kymani and I (Bod Marley&#8217;s son)</p>
<p>As the week continued, so did my adventures. We visited Tuff Gong Music studio, here we had a chance to meet where other legendary artist go to create music, Jamaica&#8217;s Fine Arts Galleria, Devon House whom was the first Jamaican millionaire, Ocho Rios beach and many more . I have come to learn that within the Jamaican culture music is used for and with everything. It has the ability to heal people, to create a community, to express yourself, to show passion and so much more.  I have experienced this while working at the Alpha Boys School each day. Our culture and experiences are indeed different but are similar also. Connecting with the Alpha Boys has been mainly through matching our cultures, music styles and experiences. It just warms my heart to see them so engaged with us.</p>
<p>The food in Jamaica is TO DIE FOR!! It is so deliciously fresh and tasty, literally I just can&#8217;t get enough. Since i love spicy food, Jerk chicken is my number one choice everywhere. They grill the chicken on a iron grill and it has the best spices and smells like heaven (or close to what I think heaven might smell lol). I will definitely have to learn how to cook this type of chicken so that I may share it with my family back home.</p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_1751.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4512" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_1751-300x225.jpg" alt="IMG_1751" width="300" height="225" /></a> Oxtail, rice and peas with festival</p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/lg_29618_0.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4513" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/lg_29618_0-300x200.jpg" alt="lg_29618_0" width="300" height="200" /></a> Jerk Chicken on the grill!!!</p>
<p><strong>MY LITTLE FAMILY AT DEVON HOUSE!</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3919.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4489" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3919-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3919" width="300" height="200" /></a>       <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3897.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4487" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3897-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3897" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3855.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4486" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3855-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3855" width="300" height="200" /></a>   <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3854.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4485" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3854-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3854" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3835.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4484" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3835-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3835" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3819.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4483" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3819-200x300.jpg" alt="IMG_3819" width="200" height="300" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3816.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4482" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3816-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3816" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3812.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4481" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3812-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3812" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3814.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4480" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3814-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3814" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3796.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4479" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3796-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3796" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3793.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4478" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3793-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3793" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3781.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4475" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3781-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3781" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3786.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4476" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3786-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3786" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3790.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4477" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3790-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3790" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3775.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4474" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3775-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3775" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>At Alpha Boys!</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3955.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4493" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3955-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3955" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3959.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4494" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3959-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3959" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_4044.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4495" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_4044-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_4044" width="300" height="200" /></a><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3968.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4502" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3968-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3968" width="300" height="200" /></a><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3963.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4501" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3963-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3963" width="300" height="200" /></a><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_39611.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4500" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_39611-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3961" width="300" height="200" /></a><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3960.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4499" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3960-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3960" width="300" height="200" /></a><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3954.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4498" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3954-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3954" width="300" height="200" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Tuff Gong Studio</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-12.29.27.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4503" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-12.29.27-200x300.jpg" alt="2014-06-12 12.29.27" width="200" height="300" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-12.34.41.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4504" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-12.34.41-300x200.jpg" alt="2014-06-12 12.34.41" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-12.36.59.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4505" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-12.36.59-300x200.jpg" alt="2014-06-12 12.36.59" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-12.39.39.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4506" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-12.39.39-200x300.jpg" alt="2014-06-12 12.39.39" width="200" height="300" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-13.10.12.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4507" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-13.10.12-300x200.jpg" alt="2014-06-12 13.10.12" width="300" height="200" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-13.14.17.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4508" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-13.14.17-200x300.jpg" alt="2014-06-12 13.14.17" width="200" height="300" /></a> <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-13.14.46.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4509" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/2014-06-12-13.14.46-300x200.jpg" alt="2014-06-12 13.14.46" width="300" height="200" /></a>  <a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_20140609_120850.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4511" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_20140609_120850-300x300.jpg" alt="IMG_20140609_120850" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Personal selfies!!</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_4151.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4497" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_4151-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_4151" width="300" height="200" /></a><img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-4492" src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3952-300x200.jpg" alt="IMG_3952" width="300" height="200" /></p>
<p><img src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3903-200x300.jpg" alt="IMG_3903" />    <img src="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/IMG_3946-200x300.jpg" alt="IMG_3946" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/yesss-to-the-experiences/?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=yesss-to-the-experiences#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://abroadblogs.newpaltz.edu/blog/2014/06/yesss-to-the-experiences/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
