<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">STEM Ready</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2014-04-18T13:08:52Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready" />
	<id>http://www.devry.edu/stemready/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.7.3">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Katie Patterson</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[STEM Ready Welcomes Mayim Bialik Back for Another National HerWorld Month]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/mayim-bialik/" />
		<id>http://www.devry.edu/stemready/?p=1553</id>
		<updated>2014-04-09T18:33:27Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-03T08:00:55Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.devry.edu/stemready" term="Articles" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Now in its 17th year, DeVry University’s HerWorld® program empowers high school girls to explore careers in science, technology, engineering and math (STEM). This year, Mayim Bialik, star of CBS’s “The Big Bang Theory,” will again partner as spokesperson for DeVry University’s National HerWorld® Month, an annual initiative to spark high school girls’ interest in [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/mayim-bialik/"><![CDATA[<p>Now in its 17th year, DeVry University’s HerWorld® program empowers high school girls to explore careers in science, technology, engineering and math (STEM).</p>
<p>This year, Mayim Bialik, star of CBS’s “The Big Bang Theory,” will again partner as spokesperson for DeVry University’s National HerWorld® Month, an annual initiative to spark high school girls’ interest in STEM. This year’s message raises the importance of female role models and mentors to increase the number of women pursuing and sustaining in STEM fields.</p>
<p>Nearly 8 million jobs will be available in STEM-related fields by 2020, yet women comprise only 24 percent of the STEM workforce. HerWorld helps prepare the next generation of female graduates for these opportunities by introducing them to successful women in STEM careers.</p>
<p>Bialik has a personal passion for STEM: she earned a Ph.D. in neuroscience in 2007.</p>
<blockquote><p>“I am partnering with DeVry University to emphasize the value of female role models in providing mentorship to high school girls and showing them that they can succeed in STEM-related careers,” Bialik said. “HerWorld is an exciting way for young women to learn directly from female leaders who persisted through challenges, and to experience the wonder and ‘cool factor’ of STEM through hands-on activities.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Throughout the month, thousands of young women from hundreds of high schools will participate in HerWorld events across the country. Attendees will experience STEM firsthand – interacting with peers through hands-on workshops and confidence-boosting activities and hearing inspirational stories from women leaders who work in STEM.</p>
<p>To learn more about the partnership, read the full press release in <a href="http://newsroom.devry.edu/article_display.cfm?article_id=1664" target="_blank">English</a> or <a href="http://www.eluniversal.com/arte-y-entretenimiento/television/140304/mayim-bialik-de-big-bang-theory-alienta-a-estudiar-carreras-cientifica" target="_blank">Spanish</a>.</p>
<h4><strong>Mayim&#8217;s Thoughts on STEM:</strong></h4>
<p><iframe width="620" height="349" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/utcQSL2V81E?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<h4><strong>Read more about Mayim and h</strong><strong>er partnership with DeVry University&#8217;s National HerWorld Month:</strong></h4>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.channelone.com/video/glory-road:-mayim-bialik/#ooid=Z3NzZqYTpIbSd3ibz1z5lRuj2tE5_ZkO">Glory Road: Mayim Bialik</a> – Channel One News</li>
<li><a href="http://www.forbes.com/sites/meghancasserly/2013/03/15/mayim-bialiks-big-bang-theory-on-girls-stem-careers-and-role-models" target="_blank">Mayim Bialik&#8217;s &#8216;Big Bang Theory&#8217; On Girls, STEM Careers and Role Models</a> – Forbes</li>
<li><a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/Mickey-goodman/big-bang-theory-star-teams-up-with-herworld_b_2845455.html?utm_hp_ref=tw" target="_blank">The Big Bang Theory Star Teams Up with HerWorld </a>– Huffington Post</li>
<li><a href="http://newsroom.devry.edu/video_display.cfm?video_id=5130" target="_blank">&#8220;The Couch&#8221; sits down with Actress Mayim Bialik to discuss National HerWorld Month</a> – CBS New York</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.esa.doc.gov/sites/default/files/news/documents/stemfinalyjuly14.pdf">*Beede, David, Tiffany Julian, David Langdon, George McKittrick, Beethika Khan, and Mark Doms. STEM: Good Jobs Now and for the Future. Rep. U.S. Department of Commerce Economics and Statistics Administration, July 2011.</a></p>]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/mayim-bialik/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/mayim-bialik/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>stemadmin</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[What do you want to be someday?]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/wanttobe/" />
		<id>http://devry.edu/stemready/?p=1476</id>
		<updated>2013-02-21T20:20:04Z</updated>
		<published>2013-02-15T17:38:40Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.devry.edu/stemready" term="Articles" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[By now, this is likely a question you’ve heard many times, and answering it may seem overwhelming. With the hundreds of careers that exist and more school courses to choose from, it may seem impossible to choose the one that is right for you. How do you begin to narrow it down? What if there’s [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/wanttobe/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1486" alt="career_profiler2" src="http://devry.edu/stemready/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/career_profiler2.jpg" width="689" height="247" /><br />
By now, this is likely a question you’ve heard many times, and answering it may seem overwhelming. With the hundreds of careers that exist and more school courses to choose from, it may seem impossible to choose the one that is right for you. How do you begin to narrow it down?</p>
<p>What if there’s a career that you haven’t heard of but could end up loving?</p>
<p>That’s why we created the <a title="Career Profiler" href="http://devry.edu/stemready/career-profiler/">STEM Career Profiler</a>. The STEM Career Profiler asks you easy multiple choice questions and then tells you what skills are your strongest and the types of careers you might enjoy! The profile tool is designed to identify and assess your personality profile, including your professional strengths and work environments that you’d enjoy. It also shares STEM-related careers you might be interested in to uncover professions, some you may have never considered, that align with your passions and interests.</p>]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/wanttobe/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/wanttobe/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>stemadmin</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Calling All Girls]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/highschool/" />
		<id>http://devry.edu/stemready/?p=1470</id>
		<updated>2013-02-20T17:03:55Z</updated>
		<published>2013-02-15T17:32:37Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.devry.edu/stemready" term="Articles" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Findings from STEM: Good Jobs Now and for the Future, a 2011 report from the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Economics and Statistics Administration, illustrates that jobs in science, technology, engineering and math are on the rise and STEM workers earn 26 percent more than their non-STEM counterparts. By introducing female leaders in STEM, HerWorld teaches [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/highschool/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://devry.edu/stemready/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/girls_technology.jpg" alt="girls_technology" width="689" height="247" class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1488" /><br />
<em>Findings from STEM: Good Jobs Now and for the Future, a 2011 report from the </em>U.S. Department of Commerce’s Economics and Statistics Administration, illustrates that jobs in science, technology, engineering and math are on the rise and STEM workers earn 26 percent more than their non-STEM counterparts. By introducing female leaders in STEM, HerWorld teaches young women that they can succeed alongside men in these positions, and gives them a checklist for preparing to get there.</p>
<p>DeVry University’s HerWorld program puts on nationwide events each year that give high school girls the opportunity to interact with peers from other high schools in the area, participate in educational and confidence-building activities, and listen to local female leaders discuss how they achieved their career goals.</p>
<p>&#8220;HerWorld helps young women realize that they have the power to make their professional ambitions a reality,&#8221; said Donna Loraine, provost/vice president of academic affairs for <a href="http://www.devry.edu" target="_blank">DeVry University.</a> &#8220;The impressive stories of female leaders expand the students&#8217; perspective and teach them the steps they need to take to forge their own career paths.&#8221;</p>
<p>Each year, DeVry University teams up with its corporate partners to hold National HerWorld Month in March reaching 7,000 young women from hundreds of high schools through more than 30 HerWorld events across the country.</p>]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/highschool/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.devry.edu/stemready/highschool/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
