<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:/news</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news.atom"/>
  <title>Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies // Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies</title>
  <updated>2014-07-10T13:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/49284</id>
    <published>2014-07-10T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T15:23:07-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/49284-sphere-of-influence/"/>
    <title>Sphere of Influence</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;Walk out the front door of Notre Dame’s “Global Gateway” in Rome and you can turn one way for the ancient Colosseum or the other for fourth century churches and catacombs — all within a few blocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="Photo by Matt Cashore '94" src="http://magazine.nd.edu/assets/135737/globe_1.jpg" title="Photo by Matt Cashore '94"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The neighborhood exhibits such a rich blend of Roman and Church history that Notre Dame created a series of nine walking tours, which all start at the Gateway building on Via Ostilia. To research and write the tours, Italian Studies at Notre Dame tapped a former instructor, Chiara Sbordoni, an expert in Roman literature and culture who actually grew up in that neighborhood. That’s only one example of the international educational connections the Gateway concept hopes to nourish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Global Gateway designation indicates that the University is setting its international sights higher than a simple expansion of its traditional study abroad programs in strategically selected major cities. The concept, which comprises Notre Dame facilities in Dublin, London, Rome, Jerusalem, Beijing and Chicago, is designed to extend the University’s international reach and create places for worldwide cultural and intellectual exchange. Increased investment in these facilities and the academic exchange opportunities they provide makes them important global nodes where Notre Dame scholars at all levels may connect and collaborate with their international peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the direction of Notre Dame International, an initiative of the provost’s office dedicated to increasing the University’s overseas influence and visibility, the Global Gateways bill themselves as “academic and intellectual centers, where scholars, students and leaders from universities, government, business and the broader community gather to discuss, discover and debate issues of topical and enduring relevance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The concept of a Global Gateway is a portal so we can look out on the world and it can look at Notre Dame,” says J. Nicholas Entrikin, the University’s vice president and associate provost who heads Notre Dame International. “It’s an opportunity to have a global footprint and let the world know more about our great research and teaching.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, this means the Global Gateways offer much more than classrooms for Notre Dame students studying overseas. The London Centre hosts more than 100 academic events every year, notes Warren von Eschenbach, assistant provost for Europe and academic director for London. The local staffs can help students find internships, facilitate special summer programs and coordinate research opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an example, von Eschenbach points to Professor Scott Appleby ’78, until recently the director of the Kroc Institute for International Peace Studies, who wants to make London the hub for Contending Modernities. That multiyear, interdisciplinary research and education initiative explores how religious and secular forces interact in the modern world. It’s much easier to convene scholars in London than South Bend, von Eschenbach explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rome Global Gateway, Photo by Matt Cashore '94" src="http://magazine.nd.edu/assets/135724/1.26.14_rome_centre_exterior_1.jpg" title="Rome Global Gateway, Photo by Matt Cashore '94"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rome facility, which on April 9 became the first to be blessed as a Global Gateway, offers similar opportunities. The Italian Studies program already has hosted a seminar there on Dante’s intellectual formation with scholars from all over Italy. In June, the Gateway hosted an interdisciplinary seminar on the historical interaction between the Church as a European institution and American culture, and the Kellogg Institute for International Studies will sponsor a conference on human dignity in the fall. Looking further ahead, the Rome Gateway can coordinate Holy Week pilgrimages for Notre Dame students studying abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father Bill Lies, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSC&lt;/span&gt;, ’93M.Div., vice president for mission engagement and Church affairs, says the expanded facility, staff and resources in Rome will enable the University to broaden its service to the Holy See.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Vatican deals with intractable problems all over the world,” Lies says. “They are often in need of great scholars to help with that. Now we can invite people to our place to really collaborate and think together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame also serves the Church at its Global Gateway in Jerusalem, the Tantur Ecumenical Institute. In 1967, the Vatican bought land to further the ecumenical spirit of Vatican II near the place where three years earlier a Roman Catholic pope had met with a patriarch of Constantinople, the nominal head of the Eastern Orthodox communion, for the first time since the ninth century. Pope Paul VI entrusted the project to Rev. Theodore Hesburgh, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSC&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame leased the land from the Holy See and opened Tantur in 1972, hosting over the years more than 5,000 Orthodox, Protestant, Anglican and Roman Catholic participants in its programs. Besides Christian unity, the Tantur institute seeks to develop understanding and relationships with other faiths, especially Jews and Muslims. Gateway opportunities range from ecumenical conferences and research to study programs for scholars that can last from three weeks to three months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the more established Gateway sites is the Keough-Naughton Notre Dame Centre in Dublin. Its home base is O’Connell House, an 18th century Georgian building that was once home to Daniel O’Connell, known as “The Liberator” for his leadership in the battle for Catholic rights in Ireland’s long struggle with England.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Whelan, the program director in Ireland, says the recent growth of internships has helped transform O’Connell House into a true Gateway. Whelan says local interest in Notre Dame peaked after the 2012 football game in Dublin, boosting the number of student work opportunities from a handful to nearly 50 today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s a very broad engagement across every sector of Irish culture, business and politics,” Whelan says. “It’s a way for us to project Notre Dame in Ireland, and the students are brilliant ambassadors. Once we get a foot in the door, people ask for more of our students.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samantha Caesar ’14 completed an internship with the Irish Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade last summer. The Long Island native assisted with a research project and also helped distribute money from a reconciliation fund to projects in Northern Ireland that bring Catholics and Protestants together, including a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YMCA&lt;/span&gt; in Belfast where she conducted a site visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It perfectly fused my interests because I’m a political science major with minors in Irish and peace studies,” Caesar says. “Working there was a little more structured than studying. They treated me like a professional from the moment I arrived. I loved discussing international politics with my co-workers, who were so informed on the issues.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other end of the Global Gateway spectrum, Notre Dame’s new program in Beijing is small but has enormous potential for growth. Acting as the hub for study abroad options springing up across Asia, the Beijing Gateway has established exchange programs with four of the top universities in Asia, including three in India. It also helps to bring hundreds of Chinese students to Notre Dame for summer research projects, as well as to identify learning opportunities for Notre Dame students in China — from business and engineering internships and projects to service programs and Chinese language classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Beijing, as the capital of the world’s second largest economy, is not just a very important place for international business but for higher education as well,” says Professor Jonathan Noble, assistant provost for ND International and director of the Institute for Asia and Asian Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closer to home, the Notre Dame facility in Chicago’s historic Motorola Building is also a Global Gateway because such University institutes as Kroc and Kellogg often use it to connect with international partners who can’t make it all the way to South Bend, associate provost Entrikin says. In May, the Kellogg Institute hosted a former president of Chile there in conjunction with a Latin American Studies Association conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been debates in higher education about how universities should approach international expansion. Some schools build large, independent branch campuses — about 100 of these currently exist overseas, according to one study — while others create smaller, collaborative hubs or global centers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one end of that scale, New York University has invested heavily in establishing brick-and-mortar campuses in Abu Dhabi and Shanghai. At the other, Columbia University has created eight global centers with temporary spaces and locally hired staffs that facilitate student and faculty projects and academic exchange. Safwan Masri, Columbia’s executive vice president for global centers, told &lt;em&gt;Inside Higher Ed&lt;/em&gt; that concerns about economic feasibility, institutional autonomy, the environment for academic freedom in certain countries and faculty interest in teaching abroad led Columbia to establish these centers while limiting long-term investment in each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame’s direction appears to be a combination of both — Global Gateways that are owned by the University and locally staffed, large enough to coordinate student programs as well as significant international conferences and events, but not so large as to become new satellite campuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ingrid Rowland, a Rome-based Notre Dame professor of classical architecture and history, says the Rome Gateway now has the space to bring in more students as well as some Italian colleagues. It also provides opportunities for interdisciplinary work and media coverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We can really upgrade the magnitude of everything,” says Rowland, who gave some members of Notre Dame’s Board of Trustees a special tour of ancient Roman churches in January. “I’ve always been interdisciplinary, but now I can really be me. The options are amazing — it reflects the interdisciplinary nature of Rome.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Brendan O’Shaughnessy is a communications writer at Notre Dame.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Brendan O’Shaughnessy ’93&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://magazine.nd.edu/news/48992-sphere-of-influence/"&gt;magazine.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 09, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Brendan O’Shaughnessy ’93</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/49176</id>
    <published>2014-07-03T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-03T15:12:18-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/49176-new-faculty-fellows-announced/"/>
    <title>New Faculty Fellows Announced</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;The Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies announces the appointment of two new faculty fellows: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="sherry150" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/136010/sherry150.jpg" title="sherry150"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.e2ma.net/click/0bvd0f/woqvzd/stb8xp"&gt;John F. Sherry,Jr.&lt;/a&gt; is the Raymond W. &amp;amp; Kenneth G. Herrick Professor of Marketing, Chair of the Marketing Department and concurrent Professor of Anthropology. His studies focus on the socio-cultural and symbolic dimensions of consumption and the cultural ecology of marketing.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His recent work involves a study of the re-imaging of murals in Northern Ireland in a joint project with Queen’s University Belfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="buttigieg150" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/136011/buttigieg150.jpg" title="buttigieg150"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://t.e2ma.net/click/0bvd0f/woqvzd/8lc8xp"&gt;Joseph Buttigieg&lt;/a&gt; is the William R. Kenan, Jr. Professor of Literature and Director, Hesburgh-Yusko Scholars Program. He specializes in modern European literature, critical theory, and the relationship between culture and politics. He has authored a book on James Joyce’s aesthetics, A Portrait of the Artist in Different Perspective.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome both John and Joseph to the Institute.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/48908</id>
    <published>2014-06-17T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-17T13:17:44-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/48908-notre-dame-scholars-contribute-to-annual-acis-conference/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame Scholars Contribute to Annual ACIS Conference</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;The American Conference for Irish Studies recently completed its annual conference.  Taking place June 11-14, 2014 in Dublin, Ireland the conference featured numerous Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies faculty fellows, graduate students and former visiting scholars.  A large multidisciplinary scholarly organization, the American Conference for Irish Studies membership draws from the United States, Ireland and Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Declan Kiberd, Donald and Marilyn Keough Professor of Irish Studies and Professor of English, was a plenary speaker and gave a talk “&lt;em&gt;Disappearing Ireland – Tir faoi Léigear.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graduate student Nathaniel Myers received the Krause Research Fellowship in Irish Studies, which funds graduate research in Irish Literature at a North American institution.  This marks the second consecutive year a Notre Dame graduate student was awarded this scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional Institute faculty fellows who chaired talks or presented papers include Susan Cannon Harris (English), Sarah McKibben (Irish Language and Literature), Brian O’Conchubhair (Irish Language and Literature) and Abigail Palko (Director of Undergraduate Studies for the Gender Studies Program).  Graduate student presenters included Ailbhe Darcy, Kathryn Sawyer, Nathaniel Myers, John Conlon, Jill Wharton, Kara Donnelly, Robinson Murphy, John Dillon and Sonia Howell.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, five former Keough National Endowment for the Humanities fellows presented papers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame has been selected the site for the 2016 ACIS conference. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/48729</id>
    <published>2014-06-12T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-12T09:33:55-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/48729-irish-seminar-opens-bloomsday-in-dublin/"/>
    <title>Irish Seminar Opens Bloomsday in Dublin</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="paul_muldoon" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/134499/paul_muldoon.jpg" title="paul_muldoon"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 16th annual Irish Seminar opens on Monday June 16th, 2014 in Dublin, Ireland.  This year the Irish Seminar explores the idea of "&lt;strong&gt;The Vernacular Imagination&lt;/strong&gt;," under the direction of Executive Director Diarmuid Ó Giolláin.  Says Ó Giolláin, “Vernacular Imagination promises to be a multidisciplinary approach to the question of the people, vernacular language and popular culture in modern (if not only in modern) societies.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intensive three week seminar designed for graduate students features distinguished faculty from Notre Dame, other notable institutions in Ireland and England, as well as writers and poets. Experts in areas of history, English, Irish language and literature, cultural studies, critical theory and folklore, the faculty will explore areas and ideas of Irish history and literature through the lens of the vernacular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lectures free and open to the public include the opening reading by &lt;strong&gt;Paul Muldoon&lt;/strong&gt; at the Royal Irish Academy. Muldoon,&lt;span style="font-size: 12px;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;described by &lt;em&gt;The Times Literary Supplement&lt;/em&gt; as "the most significant English-language poet born since the second World War," has produced numerous award winning poetry collections including &lt;em&gt;New Weather&lt;/em&gt; (1973), &lt;em&gt;Mules&lt;/em&gt; (1977), &lt;em&gt;Why Brownlee Left &lt;/em&gt;(1980), &lt;em&gt;Quoof &lt;/em&gt;(1983), &lt;em&gt;Meeting The British &lt;/em&gt;(1987), &lt;em&gt;Madoc: A Mystery&lt;/em&gt; (1990), &lt;em&gt;The Annals of Chile&lt;/em&gt; (1994), &lt;em&gt;Hay &lt;/em&gt;(1998), &lt;em&gt;Poems 1968-1998&lt;/em&gt; (2001), &lt;em&gt;Moy Sand and Gravel&lt;/em&gt; (2002),&lt;em&gt; Horse Latitudes&lt;/em&gt; (2006), and &lt;em&gt;Maggot&lt;/em&gt; (2010).  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additional public readings and lectures will be given at the Dublin Golden Gateway O'Connell House by authors &lt;strong&gt;Pat McCabe&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Kevin Barry&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Deidre Madden&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn More►&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;• &lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/134467/2014isschedule.pdf"&gt;Complete Schedule of Irish Seminar 2014&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
• &lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/134481/faculty_2014_3_june5.pdf"&gt;Faculty Biographies &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/48812</id>
    <published>2014-06-11T14:25:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-12T14:33:52-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/48812-the-keough-naughton-institute-for-irish-studies-announces-support-for-a-digital-reading-early-modern-irish-project/"/>
    <title>The Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies announces support for a Digital “Reading Early Modern Irish” Project.</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;The Keough-Naughton Institute will be one of several supporting institutions for a major Digital Humanities project entitled “&lt;strong&gt;Reading Early Modern Irish: a Digital Guide to Irish Gaelic (c.1200-1650)&lt;/strong&gt;.”  As part of a multi-year collaboration with universities in Ireland and the United States, including the University of Connecticut, Harvard, Trinity College Dublin and NUI Galway, the project will produce a web-based application for learning to read and translate Early Modern Irish in both print and manuscript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are many resources available for learning Modern and Old Irish, there are no comparable materials for learning Early Modern Irish, the written form of the language used from roughly 1200-1650.  There is no comprehensive grammar, no guide to translation and interpretation, and no dictionary.  Consequently, nearly 500 years of Irish writing remains grossly underused by scholars as the difficulty of acquiring the language limits access to a small group of specialists.  The “Reading Early Modern Irish” project addresses this scholarly gap by offering the first systematic introductory apparatus for learning to read, transcribe and translate Early Modern Irish. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In supporting this project, the Keough-Naughton Institute will stake a prominent position within the still emerging field of Digital Humanities, while also making a major, lasting contribution to Irish Studies scholarship.  Supported by the Thomas Moore and Judith Livingston Fund, the Institute’s Herbert J. Allen Fellow Wes Hamrick will begin preliminary work on the project in the fall of 2014, while also working with historian Brendan Kane at the University of Connecticut in preparing grant applications with the National Science Foundation and the National Endowment for the Humanities.  These grants would fund ongoing work on the project as well as a post-doctoral fellowship hosted by the Keough-Naughton Institute beginning in the fall of 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Wes Hamrick</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/48810</id>
    <published>2014-06-11T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-11T12:37:42-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/48810-dan-obrien-murphy-irish-exchange-program-fellow/"/>
    <title>Dan O’Brien, Murphy Irish Exchange Program Fellow</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;The Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies welcomes &lt;strong&gt;Dan O’Brien&lt;/strong&gt; of University College Cork as the 2014-2015 Murphy Irish Exchange Program Fellow.  Now in its third year, the Exchange program is fulfilling its aim to promote research in Irish studies at the graduate level through a partnership between the University of Notre Dame and the University College Cork, Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Brien is completing his second year of graduate studies in the School of English where he works on his thesis ‘The Intertwining Fictions of Philip Roth and Edna O’Brien: “A Piece of Fine Meshwork.”’  His work “looks at the relationship between the fiction of Irish writer Edna O’Brien and Philip Roth and explores how Roth uses Irish writers and texts within his fiction – including Joyce, Yeats, Wilde, Beckett and even O’Brien herself.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His project also considers the influences of American writers, especially Philip Roth, on Edna O’Brien’s writing.  O’Brien says, “her own playful relationship with Roth will be studied in its own right, but also as a metaphor for how she and Roth use other writers in their work.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O’Brien received an M.A. in American Literature and Film and a B.A. in English and History, College of Arts, Celtic Studies and Social Sciences from UCC.  He intends to build on his background in American literature and Irish literature during his time at Notre Dame. “I cannot wait to immerse myself in the Irish aspect of Notre Dame and of course in Irish literature classes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author of numerous articles and conference papers, O’Brien is the recipient of several awards and honors, including an Irish Research Council Government of Ireland Ph.D. Scholarship, the UCC School of English Scholarship, and the UCC College of Arts, Celtic Studies and Social Sciences Ph.D. Scholarship, as well as summer scholar and travel grants. He teaching experience includes leading undergraduate English classes in modern literature at UCC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Murphy Irish Exchange Fellowship is funded by a grant from the Keough-Naughton Institute of Irish Studies and is administered by Institute Director Christopher Fox.  The Fellowship is open to graduate students in the field of Irish Studies. Fellows receive a stipend of $12,000, round trip air fares and tuition waivers.  Marie-Luise Theuerkauf, a Ph.D. student in the Departments of French and Early &amp;amp; Medieval Irish at UCC and Aaron Willis, Ph.D. candidate in the Department of History at Notre Dame were the first two Exchange Fellows. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/48369</id>
    <published>2014-06-04T16:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-05T09:41:08-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/48369-president-higgins-remarks-emphasize-vital-links-between-notre-dame-and-ireland/"/>
    <title>President Higgins' Remarks Emphasize Vital Links Between Notre Dame and Ireland</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="5" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/133095/5.jpg" title="5"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael D. Higgins, President of Ireland, spoke warmly of the connections between the University of Notre Dame and Ireland at a luncheon hosted by the Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies in Chicago on May 13, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President was joined by his wife, Sabina Higgins and the Irish Ambassador to the United States, Anne Anderson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commencing with four Irishmen accompanying Fr. Sorin to Indiana, the President spoke of the University’s continuing involvement with Ireland, including its current role in the preservation of Ireland’s language and literature, its music and its history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President noted the Keough-Naughton Institute’s 20 year effort to introduce students to Irish culture and to Ireland itself, as it encouraged and enabled students to travel to Ireland to experience firsthand what they have studied, “having them as a part of the global Irish family is a gift for which I would like to thank all those involved in the Keough-Naughton Institute.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He emphasized the history of Ireland was a history of migrants and respected the contributions made by those migrants in keeping alive Irish culture. He cited the famed Chicago musician and collector Chief O’Neill, whose collection is housed in Hesburgh Libraries, as an example of this circularity of American influence on Ireland.  The President commended the contributions, efforts and energy of the two men who gave the Institute its name; one a successful Irish–American who wished to renew scholarship on Ireland and the other a prominent Irish businessman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The President made special mention of the Institute’s 1916 documentary, which is partially funded by a tax incentive program he initiated while Minister for Arts, Culture and the Gaeltacht, as another avenue to explore the interconnections between Notre Dame, Ireland and the Irish everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Institutions such as Notre Dame’s Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies are a vital link in the chain that joins our two countries.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;►&lt;a href="http://www.president.ie/speeches/speech-at-a-luncheon-hosted-by-the-university-of-notre-dames-keough-naughton-institute-for-irish-studies/"&gt;Full&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.president.ie/speeches/speech-at-a-luncheon-hosted-by-the-university-of-notre-dames-keough-naughton-institute-for-irish-studies/"&gt; text of President Higgin's remarks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/48616</id>
    <published>2014-05-30T14:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-30T14:51:01-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/48616-institute-fellows-recognized-for-superior-teaching-and-writing/"/>
    <title>Institute Fellows recognized for Superior Writing and Teaching</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="Susan Harris" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/105940/harris_web2.jpg" title="Susan Harris" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor of English&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Susan Harris&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;&amp;nbsp;article &amp;ldquo;Mobilizing Maurya: J.M. Synge, Bertolt Brecht, and the Revolutionary Mother&amp;rdquo; was awarded honorable mention by Modern Drama prize committee.&amp;nbsp; &lt;em&gt;Modern Drama&lt;/em&gt;, founded in 1958, is the most prominent journal in English to focus on dramatic literature.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sara Maure&lt;/strong&gt;r, Professor of English and &lt;strong&gt;Patrick Griffin&lt;/strong&gt;, Chair and Professor of History, were recipients of the 2014 Rev. Edmund P. Joyce, C.S.C., Award for Excellence in Undergraduate Teaching.&amp;nbsp; The awards, presented by the Office of the Provost, are selected through a process that includes peer and student nominations.&amp;nbsp; The award &amp;ldquo;honors faculty members who have had a profound influence on undergraduate students through sustained exemplary teaching at Notre Dame.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn More►&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;bull; &lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-fellows/sara-maurer/"&gt;Professor Maurer&amp;#39;s webpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; &lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-fellows/patrick-griffin/"&gt;Professor Griffin&amp;#39;s webpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;bull; &lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-fellows/susan-harris/"&gt;Professor Harris&amp;#39; webpage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/48480</id>
    <published>2014-05-21T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-21T10:42:40-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/48480-seniors-recocognized-for-excellence-in-irish-studies/"/>
    <title>Seniors Recognized for Excellence in Irish Studies</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;Two seniors were recognized graduation weekend for their scholarship in Irish studies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="samoshagx185" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/105718/samoshagx185.jpeg" title="samoshagx185" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samantha Caesar&lt;/strong&gt;, a Political Science major with minors in Irish Studies and Peace Studies, received the Donald and Marilyn Keough Award for Excellence in Irish Studies.&amp;nbsp; First introduced to Irish Studies through her Irish language classes with Professor Mary O&amp;rsquo;Callaghan, Sam enjoyed a steady diet of Irish Studies classes: Irish politics, literature, history and film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fr. Sean advised her on her capstone essay which considers Northern Irish political parties and politics since the Good Friday agreement.&amp;nbsp; She was able to write her capstone with an experienced eye, as an Institute sponsored internship in the Department of Foreign Affairs, Anglo-Irish division, prompted her to develop anti-sectarianism programs increasing tolerance between Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland.&amp;nbsp; Sam benefitted from the interdisciplinary offerings in the Institute, from language and literature, film television and theatre, history, American studies and political science. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her studies and experiences led her to Duke Law School where she will pursue an LLM in international law to supplement her J.D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="festina_lente_annie_mccarthy185" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/133532/festina_lente_annie_mccarthy185.jpg" title="festina_lente_annie_mccarthy185" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annie McCarthy&lt;/strong&gt; was awarded the Brother Simeon C.S.C. Prize for Distinction in Irish Language and Literature. &amp;nbsp;A Program of Liberal Studies major with minors in both Irish Language and Literature and Irish Studies, Annie pursued four semesters of Irish as well as classes exploring Irish history, culture, film and music.&amp;nbsp; She feels understanding the language allows her a greater understanding of the literature and culture, permitting her to dig deeper into the texts.&amp;nbsp; Annie spent a semester in Dublin, taking Kevin Whelan&amp;rsquo;s History of Ireland class.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She credits all her professors for their interest and enthusiasm. These experiences, along with her Institute sponsored summer internship with Festina Lente, a non-government organization that utilizes therapeutic equestrian training in work with disabled youth, was &amp;ldquo;amazing&amp;rdquo; and paved the way for her upcoming teaching position in history and literature in a Phoenix charter school. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/48058</id>
    <published>2014-05-12T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-12T08:34:41-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/48058-michael-d-higgins-president-of-ireland-to-speak-to-ireland-council-notre-dame-international-and-keough-naughton-institute-for-irish-studies-fellows-in-chicago/"/>
    <title>Michael D. Higgins, President of Ireland to speak to Ireland Council, Notre Dame International and Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies Fellows in Chicago</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="higgins1_2_crop" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/131975/higgins1_2_crop.jpg" title="higgins1_2_crop" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President of Ireland Michael D. Higgins is the guest of honor at a luncheon hosted by the University of Notre Dame and the Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies on Tuesday, May 13, 2014, at the Chicago Club, Chicago, Illinois.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Higgins will speak to the University&amp;rsquo;s Ireland Council, Notre Dame International and Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies Fellows about the many connections between Ireland and Notre Dame.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Says Christopher Fox, director of the Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies, &amp;ldquo;We are delighted to host President Higgins, along with his wife Sabina, and Anne Anderson, Ireland&amp;rsquo;s Ambassador to the United States. It is a perfect ending to our yearlong celebration of our 20th anniversary, as we continue our work strengthening the intellectual and cultural associations between Notre Dame and Ireland.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ninth President of Ireland, Higgins is known for his contributions to academic as well as political life. A former professor of political science and sociology, Higgins is a writer and poet. His works examine Irish politics, sociology, history and culture. Published pieces include two collections of essays, &lt;em&gt;Causes for Concern&amp;mdash;Irish Politics, Culture and Society&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Renewing the Republic&lt;/em&gt;. He has also published four collections of poetry&amp;mdash;&lt;em&gt;The Betrayal&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;The Season of Fire&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;An Arid Season&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;New and Selected Poems&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Higgins has been a public servant at nearly every level and notably served as Ireland&amp;rsquo;s first Minister for Arts, Culture and the Gaeltacht, where he promoted the Irish language, including the creation of an Irish language channel, and revitalized the Irish film industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As President, Higgins has reached out to the Irish diaspora and bolstered ties with the Irish abroad.&amp;nbsp; His dedicated efforts to promote human rights and democracy in Ireland and abroad were recognized as the first recipient of the Seán MacBride Peace Prize from the International Peace Bureau in Helsinki.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The luncheon provides the opportunity to highlight the close ties between Notre Dame and Ireland facilitated by the Keough-Naughton Institute, notably Dublin&amp;rsquo;s Global Gateway centered in O&amp;rsquo;Connell House; the summer internship program which places Notre Dame students in Irish government, arts facilities, non-profits and businesses; faculty and student exchange arrangements with Irish universities and the forthcoming 1916 documentary produced by Notre Dame and the Institute to be jointly aired on PBS and Ireland&amp;rsquo;s public television station RTÉ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Higgins is visiting the Midwest to give the commencement address and receive an honorary doctorate at Indiana University, Bloomington.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn More:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;► &lt;a href="http://www.president.ie/"&gt;Office of the President of Ireland Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;► &lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame International&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;► &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5gubNuiIVz8"&gt;Irish Studies Video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/48139</id>
    <published>2014-05-05T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-05T12:28:33-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/48139-faculty-awards-honor-exemplary-work-in-undergraduate-teaching-and-advising/"/>
    <title>Faculty awards honor exemplary work in undergraduate teaching and advising</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Blue and gold academic seal" class="noborder" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/102311/colorseal300.jpg" title="Blue and gold academic seal" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations to Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies Fellows &lt;strong&gt;Patrick Griffin&lt;/strong&gt; (History) and &lt;strong&gt;Sara Maurer&lt;/strong&gt; (English) for recognition of their teaching excellence!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: "&gt;Twenty-one University of Notre Dame faculty members have received &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://kaneb.nd.edu/assets/44448/joyce_teaching_award_2010.pdf" style="font-size: ;"&gt;Rev. Edmund P. Joyce, C.S.C., Awards for Excellence in Undergraduate Teaching&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 
"&gt;, and three faculty and staff have been honored with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://provost.nd.edu/assets/75459/dockweiler_award.pdf" style="font-size: "&gt;Dockweiler Awards for Excellence in Undergraduate Advising&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 12px;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The awards are presented by the &lt;a href="http://provost.nd.edu/"&gt;Office of the Provost&lt;/a&gt;, but recipients are selected through a process that includes peer and student nominations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dockweiler Award winners are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://history.nd.edu/faculty/directory/daniel-graff/"&gt;Daniel A. Graff&lt;/a&gt;, history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/Faculty_Directory/alisonlevey/"&gt;Alison K. Levey&lt;/a&gt;, Mendoza College of Business Dean&amp;rsquo;s Office&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://campusministry.nd.edu/about/staff/graduate-staff/priscilla-wong/"&gt;Priscilla W. Wong&lt;/a&gt;, Campus Ministry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 21 winners of Joyce teaching excellence awards represent faculty who have had a profound influence on undergraduate students through sustained exemplary teaching. Faculty committees in each of seven disciplinary areas review the peer and student nominations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Joyce Award recipients are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/carlackermann/"&gt;Carl B. Ackermann&lt;/a&gt;, finance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://chemistry.nd.edu/people/brian-m-baker/"&gt;Brian M. Baker&lt;/a&gt;, chemistry and biochemistry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ftt.nd.edu/faculty-and-staff/alphabetical-directory/christine-becker/"&gt;Christine A. Becker&lt;/a&gt;, film, television, and theater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://fys.nd.edu/fys-resources/first-year-advisors/dr-steven-j-brady/"&gt;Steven J. Brady&lt;/a&gt;, first year of studies/history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://physics.nd.edu/people/faculty/mark-caprio/"&gt;Mark A. Caprio&lt;/a&gt;, physics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://uwp.nd.edu/people/patrick-clauss/"&gt;Patrick J. Clauss&lt;/a&gt;, University Writing Program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/faculty_directory/KristenCollettSchmitt/"&gt;Kristen Collett-Schmitt&lt;/a&gt;, finance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/duffield/"&gt;Giles E. Duffield&lt;/a&gt;, biological sciences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David W. Gasperetti, German and Russian languages and literatures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://psychology.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-by-alpha/dawn-m-gondoli/"&gt;Dawn M. Gondoli&lt;/a&gt;, psychology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://history.nd.edu/faculty/directory/patrick-griffin/"&gt;Patrick N. Griffin&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; history&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://english.nd.edu/people/profiles/maurer/"&gt;Sara L. Maurer&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/strong&gt; English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://english.nd.edu/people/profiles/mcsweeney/"&gt;Joyelle McSweeney&lt;/a&gt;, English&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www3.nd.edu/~mniemier/"&gt;Michael T. Niemier&lt;/a&gt;, computer science and engineering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://chemistry.nd.edu/people/kathleen-peterson/"&gt;Kathleen A. Peterson&lt;/a&gt;, chemistry and biochemistry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://politicalscience.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-list/susan-pratt-rosato/"&gt;Susan H. Rosato&lt;/a&gt;, political science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://ftt.nd.edu/faculty-and-staff/alphabetical-directory/siiri-scott/"&gt;Siiri S. Scott&lt;/a&gt;, film, television, and theater&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://pls.nd.edu/faculty-and-staff/thomas-stapleford/"&gt;Thomas A. Stapleford&lt;/a&gt;, program of liberal studies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://math.nd.edu/people/faculty/stephan-a-stolz/"&gt;Stephan A. Stolz&lt;/a&gt;, mathematics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/ataflanidis"&gt;Alexandros A. Taflanidis&lt;/a&gt;, civil and environmental engineering and earth sciences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/michelle-whaley/"&gt;Michelle A. Whaley&lt;/a&gt;, biological sciences&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The undergraduate teaching award is supported by a gift from the late Father Joyce&amp;rsquo;s classmates in the Class of 1937. This is the eighth year that advisers and student mentors are being honored through an award supported by the Julia Stearns Dockweiler Charitable Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/48129-faculty-awards-honor-exemplary-work-in-undergraduate-teaching-and-advising/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;May 05, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/47940</id>
    <published>2014-04-24T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-24T13:00:14-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/47940-the-keough-naughton-institute-for-irish-studies-announces-the-2014-national-endowment-for-the-humanities-seminar/"/>
    <title>The Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies Announces the 2014 National Endowment for the Humanities Seminar</title>
    <content type="text/html">
&lt;p&gt;2013-2014 Keough National Endowment for the Humanities fellow James &amp;ldquo;Wes&amp;rsquo; Hamrick will present &amp;ldquo;Revising the Public Sphere in the Four Nations&amp;rdquo; at 4 pm Friday, April 25th in 424 Flanner Hall. &amp;nbsp;His presentation marks the culmination of his fellowship year as an NEH scholar within the Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamrick will be joined by distinguished professors Murray Pittock, University of Glasgow; Katie Trumpener, Yale University; Niall &amp;Oacute; Cios&amp;aacute;in, NUI Galway; and Christopher Fox, University of Notre Dame, who will offer their thoughts on his work and its subject, the concept of the eighteenth-century public sphere and the role of minority languages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I am excited to receive feedback from the review committee,&amp;rdquo; says Hamrick, &amp;ldquo;as their work has been instrumental to my research and writing.&amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp; Hamrick further credits former Irish Literature and Language Chair Breand&amp;aacute;n &amp;Oacute; Buachalla and current Donald and Marilyn Keough Professor of Irish Studies Declan Kiberd for their guidance and influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of the eighteenth-century public sphere, as proposed by cultural theorist J&amp;uuml;rgen Habermas, is the place where civil society came together to discuss cultural, political or linguistic ideas.&amp;nbsp; Often represented as the domain of English speaking nationalists, Hamrick argues that informed citizens who spoke and write in Irish and other minority languages took part in the public sphere just as those in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My work looks at the interaction between manuscript and print culture in England, Scotland and Ireland during the eighteenth century and argues that the so-called &amp;lsquo;public sphere&amp;rsquo; during this period, while dominated by English, is in fact multi-lingual, with significant roles played by writing in Irish and Scots Gaelic as well as Scots English,&amp;rdquo; Hamrick explains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fellowship enabled Hamrick to prepare his dissertation for a book length publication. New insights, including the connection with recent work on the enlightenment concerning the circulation of ideas, were added.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamrick also generated two forthcoming articles reviewing the controversy over participants in the public sphere, one for the New Hibernian Review, and another written in Irish for Irish Studies journal Éigse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NEH Keough Fellowship is highly selective and enables an outstanding scholar to continue his or her research while in residence in the Keough-Naughton Institute during the academic year. &amp;nbsp;Former scholars have published books and articles on subjects in Irish Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;► related article about &lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/40770-english-graduate-student-wins-2013-neh-keough-fellowship/"&gt;Wes Hamrick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;► related article about&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/42726-former-neh-keough-fellows-discuss-the-impact-of-their-fellowship-2/"&gt;former Keough-NEH fellows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;►&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/faculty/neh-fellows/"&gt;Keough-NEH Fellowship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;► &lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/"&gt;Irish Studies&lt;/a&gt; at Notre Dame&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left:5.8pt;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/47657</id>
    <published>2014-04-11T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-21T09:51:00-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/47657-fall-2014-irish-studies-classes/"/>
    <title>Fall 2014 Irish Studies Classes</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;The Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies announces the Fall 2014 Irish Studies classes. These classes showcase the Institute&amp;#39;s interdisciplinary nature, with classes in the Irish Language and Literature, English, History, Film, Television, and Theatre, Anthropology and Classics departments.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;►&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/academics/courses/fall-2014/"&gt;Full Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IRST 10101:01&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 12px;"&gt;MWF&amp;nbsp; 9:25-10:15&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 12px;"&gt;Tara MacLeod&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size: 12px;"&gt;Beginning Irish I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No prior knowledge of the Irish language required. &amp;nbsp;This course provides an enjoyable introduction to modern Irish. &amp;nbsp;Energetic teachers in small classes teach basic language skills and prepare students to conduct conversations and read authentic texts. &amp;nbsp;Extensive use is made of role-play and interactive teaching methods.&amp;nbsp; Irish 10101 is a superb opportunity to learn a new language, explore Irish/Celtic culture, and investigate the linguistic politics of the only minority language offered at Notre Dame. &amp;nbsp;In addition to satisfying the language requirement of the College of Arts and Letters and the College of Science, Irish satisfies the popular Irish Language and Literature and Irish Studies minors&amp;rsquo; requirements, and selected students will have an opportunity to study in Dublin, Ireland.&amp;nbsp; This class meets 3 days-a-week. &amp;nbsp;In lieu of a scheduled 4th class, students work independently on technology-based language/culture projects in the CSLC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/47392</id>
    <published>2014-04-02T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-02T11:34:01-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/47392-alumni-share-sacred-music-in-ireland/"/>
    <title>Alumni Share Sacred Music in Ireland</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="house_of_brigid_tapestry_200" src="http://al.nd.edu/assets/128690/house_of_brigid_tapestry_200.jpg" title="house_of_brigid_tapestry_200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The healing power of music, the joyful celebration of faith&amp;mdash;Teach Bhr&amp;iacute;de (the House of Brigid) seeks to enrich these elements of the Notre Dame spirit in a people who helped form this institution&amp;rsquo;s mission and heart: the Irish themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The House of Brigid began in 2009, when recent graduates of Notre Dame, aided by generous donors from the Notre Dame community and the Notre Dame Folk Choir, started a yearlong service program to assist in spiritual ministry and liturgical music in the Catholic Church in Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Their ministry focuses primarily within the Diocese of Ferns at the Church of the Annunciation in Clonard, County Wexford, Ireland, but a second branch is projected to begin serving Dublin within the next few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The members of the House of Brigid, all recent college graduates from the United States, are responsible for the liturgical planning and direction of the choir for Clonard&amp;rsquo;s Vigil Mass, assisting with Clonard&amp;rsquo;s family liturgy group, teaching catechetical and liturgical lessons at the two primary schools in the parish of Clonard, partaking in sacramental preparation, teaching diocesan music workshops, and organizing retreats across the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Our mission stems from a spirit of gratitude to the missionaries of Ireland who brought the Catholic faith to America, an effort to strengthen in today&amp;rsquo;s Irish Catholics the faith that sustained their ancestors, and a desire to give young Americans the opportunity to immerse themselves in Irish culture and Celtic spirituality,&amp;rdquo; the House of Brigid&amp;rsquo;s official mission statement reads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="houseofbrigid_kids_200" src="http://al.nd.edu/assets/128691/houseofbrigid_kids_200.jpg" title="houseofbrigid_kids_200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Three of the four recent graduates currently serving at House of Brigid are alumni of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s College of Arts and Letters: Mary Atwood &amp;rsquo;12 (theology), Cameron Cortens &amp;rsquo;13 (philosophy and theology), and Ben Zelmer &amp;rsquo;13 (American studies). They are joined by Joy Viceroy, a 2013 Saint Mary&amp;rsquo;s graduate who studied music and theatre.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Though Notre Dame owes much of its Catholic vigor to present and former Irish students, faculty, and staff, the Catholic faith in Ireland has been dwindling in recent years. While Ireland was once heralded as a stronghold for the Church, reports have shown that the percentage of Catholics in Ireland attending Mass regularly has greatly declined, especially among young people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;While some things in Ireland have changed, others have not. The things that still have a foothold: a high regard for hospitality; a far less hurried lifestyle that emphasizes human awareness; a deep respect for song, story and intellect; a reverence for family life, even if church-going is not a significant part of their week,&amp;rdquo; explains Steven Warner &amp;rsquo;80, director of the Notre Dame Folk Choir and one of the individuals who spearheaded the House of Brigid initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Over the last five years, the 16 volunteers who have worked in the House of Brigid have been blessed with warm hospitality from the Irish people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="House of Brigid" src="http://al.nd.edu/assets/128703/house_of_brigid_house_200.jpg" title="House of Brigid" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Their goodness has helped to support the House of Brigid in its endeavors, and any success the community has enjoyed has been in large part due to the faith and trust of the parish staff and the parishioners themselves,&amp;rdquo; says Carolyn Pirtle, M.S.M &amp;rsquo;08, the assistant director at the Notre Dame Center for Liturgy, who was a founding member and the first house director of the House of Brigid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Enriched by the care of their Irish supporters, four new volunteers each year have lived out their mission by working with the community of Wexford in a variety of ways. They have seen great results. Beginning as a dream, the House of Brigid has become a prosperous reality, thanks to many dedicated advocates in the United States and abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;I was the Irish dreamer, on the other side of the Atlantic, hoping to bring an outreach program to Ireland,&amp;rdquo; says Monsignor Denis Lennon, P.P., beloved pastor of Church of the Annunciation, Clonard. &amp;ldquo;The main objective from the beginning was to further liturgical music in Ireland and use liturgical music as a vehicle to bring Irish people who have drifted from the faith back to the faith.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Joyful, fresh liturgical music is a central part of the work done by the House of Brigid volunteers. In Ireland, most parishes are without music hymnals and have no full-time musicians to assist in the Mass. One essential way that the House of Brigid has brought music into the Church is by relying on the rich Irish musical tradition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;They have begun to invigorate the faith landscape again, not only by introducing songs from America, but mostly by giving the Irish permission to use their own songs, stories, saints, feasts, and customs in beautifully expressive ways. That amazing, grace-filled interchange is at the heart of the House of Brigid,&amp;rdquo; says Warner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Coming from Notre Dame, Saint Mary&amp;rsquo;s, and now, Marquette, with interests in theology and music, many of the members of the House of Brigid are living testaments to music&amp;rsquo;s evangelizing power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="House of Brigid" src="http://al.nd.edu/assets/128704/house_of_brigid_group_200.jpg" title="House of Brigid" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Music was the way that I found my faith. I hated going to Church on Sundays. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t connect my faith to anything. But then I found a connection through music. Ever since, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to strengthen my faith through song,&amp;rdquo; explains Joy Viceroy, a 2013 Saint Mary&amp;rsquo;s graduate and current member of the House of Brigid. &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s the approach I try to take with the children. If I can help them find their niche, whether it&amp;rsquo;s music or discussion or something else, I can help them love themselves and help them see that God loves them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	A large part of their service is directed toward young children who attend Catholic elementary schools, usually up to the sixth grade. In Ireland, the large majority of adolescents attend public high schools, so one of the House of Brigid&amp;rsquo;s greatest goals is to foster the faith of the children so that as they grow older, they stay in touch with their faith.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;A major blessing is to have four passionate, lovely American young people who are not ashamed to be Catholic, not ashamed to talk about God and praise God, not ashamed to admit how large a role their faith plays in their lives. They inspire many parishioners, young and old, to find pride in the Church and in their faith,&amp;rdquo; says Sr. Mary Rowsome, S.S.J.G., pastoral associate to Father Lennon at the Church of the Annunciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The blessings created through the House of Brigid have been lasting and plentiful, not simply for the people of Wexford, but also for the American young people who have served there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;I learned how to be truly hospitable, how to slow down and enjoy the company of others over a cup of tea. I learned that it&amp;rsquo;s okay to try something and have it fail&amp;mdash;that success is best measured in terms of quality of experience, not necessarily in terms of numbers, and that failure can often be more helpful in directing ministerial efforts than success can,&amp;rdquo; says Pirtle. &amp;ldquo;Most of all, I learned that the people of Ireland, particularly those of Clonard Parish, are truly the salt of the earth.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;
	Learn More &amp;gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://sacredmusic.nd.edu"&gt;Sacred Music at Notre Dame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://music.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Music&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu"&gt;Department of Theology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://liturgy.nd.edu"&gt;Notre Dame Center for Liturgy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://campusministry.nd.edu/basilica-of-the-sacred-heart/basilica-choirs/folk-choir/"&gt;Notre Dame Folk Choir&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://www.houseofbrigid.org"&gt;House of Brigid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/31005-senior-mary-atwood-illuminates-andean-legends/"&gt;Related story on Mary Atwood&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published at &lt;a href="http://ndtoday.alumni.nd.edu/s/1210/nl-subpage.aspx?sid=1210&amp;amp;gid=1&amp;amp;pgid=18493"&gt;ndtoday.alumni.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Gabriela Leskur&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/47387-alumni-share-sacred-music-in-ireland/"&gt;al.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;April 02, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Gabriela Leskur</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/47223</id>
    <published>2014-03-27T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-27T13:09:02-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/47223-institute-fellows-and-graduate-students-present-at-the-2014-asecs-conference/"/>
    <title>Institute Fellows and Graduate Students Present at the 2014 ASECS Conference</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;u5:p&gt;&lt;/u5:p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="asecsconference1" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/128200/asecsconference1.jpg" title="asecsconference1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies annual conference is the major academic event for scholars working, teaching and researching in this particular rich and multifaceted period. Established in 1969, the American Society for Eighteenth-Century Studies is committed to advancing the study of a time period that has profoundly influenced our world.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The 2014 conference, in colonial Williamsburg, Virginia, featured several Keough-Naughton fellows including Professors&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Jim Smyth&lt;/strong&gt; and&lt;strong&gt; Peter McQuillan&lt;/strong&gt; as well as 2013-204 Keough National Endowment for Humanities fellow &lt;strong&gt;James &amp;#39;Wes&amp;#39; Hamrick &lt;/strong&gt;who gave a well-received paper entitled &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;Ossian and the Public Sphere: Literary Forgery or the Translation of Culture?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Continuing a long tradition of Keough-Naughton graduate students presenting at the conference were &lt;strong&gt;Erin Kraus &lt;/strong&gt;(Irish Exiles in the Age of Atlantic Revolutions: Immigrant Responses to Post-Revolutionary America) and &lt;strong&gt;Sam Fisher &lt;/strong&gt;(Redefining Britishness: Poets, Prophets, and Pontiac). Both these doctoral students presented on their current research and impressed those in attendance not with only their poise at the podium and their in-depth knowledge of their respective topics, but with their detailed responses in the lengthy question and answer session that followed. Also in attendance was former Keough NEH fellow &lt;strong&gt;Michael Griffin&lt;/strong&gt;, now head of the School of English at the University of Limerick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The two Keough-Naughton sponsored panels at the conference highlighted the distinct interdisciplinary research into the eighteenth century currently being undertaken by Keough-Naughton fellows and their doctoral students. These panels featured presentations on linguistic anthropology, transatlantic history, Scottish, Irish, French connections and politics, the Midnight Court and exiled Irish revolutionaries and their social networks in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The conference venue provided Keough-Naughton fellows an excellent opportunity to visit nearby museums and exhibits in colonial Jamestown and Yorktown. The 2015 conference will convene in Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Learn More►&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-fellows/jim-smyth/"&gt;Jim Smyth faculty page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-fellows/peter-mcquillan/"&gt;Peter McQuillan faculty page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/academics/graduate-program/"&gt;Graduate Studies in Irish Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Brian Ó Conchubhair</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/47140</id>
    <published>2014-03-25T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-26T09:08:32-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/47140-institute-fellow-edits-newly-released-sherlock-holmes-compilation/"/>
    <title>Institute Fellow Barry McCrea Edits Second Edition Sherlock Holmes Compilation</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="newsherlockholmes" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/127848/newsherlockholmes.jpg" title="newsherlockholmes" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Barry McCrea&lt;/strong&gt;, Keough Family Professor of Irish Studies and Professor of English, edited the second edition of&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Sherlock Holmes: Selected Stories &lt;/em&gt;(Oxford World Classics, April, 2014).&amp;nbsp; Professor McCrea provides the introduction and notes to this new selection of twelve of the best Sherlock Holmes stories.&amp;nbsp; His introduction considers the reasons for Sherlock Holmes&amp;rsquo; lasting popularity, while giving historical context to the late Victorian and Edwardian setting and examining the many afterlives inspired by the detective stories. Notably, this work is the&amp;nbsp;first new Oxford World&amp;#39;s Classics edition of Selected Stories of Sherlock Holmes since 1950, and the first to have a full set of scholarly notes&lt;span style="font-size: 12px;"&gt;. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Learn More►&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-fellows/barry-mccrea/"&gt;Professor McCrea&amp;#39;s faculty page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/"&gt;Irish Studies at Notre Dame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://ukcatalogue.oup.com/product/9780199672066.do"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sherlock Holmes: Selected Stories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/46879</id>
    <published>2014-03-13T14:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-14T10:44:49-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/46879-a-global-st-patrick-s-day-and-the-irish-who-celebrate/"/>
    <title>A Global St. Patrick's Day and the Irish who Claim It</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p align="center"&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day is a global festival. The great majority of the earth&amp;rsquo;s population, of course, remains blissfully ignorant of or indifferent to it, but at the same time it is celebrated on every continent and in every city in which there is a significant population of Irish descent, an Irish pub, or both. Compared to the other Irish festivals of the year the traditional rural customs associated with St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day were meagre. Organised within a newly independent Irish state in the 1920s, St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day parades asserted ideals of national community in the union of state and civil society, in the pre-eminence of the national church, and in the self-control of the citizens (facilitated by the mandatory closing of the pubs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	If in the Republic of Ireland, St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day is both a religious festival and a national holiday, there are occasionally contradictions: for example the liturgical norms require the religious feast to be moved when it clashes with Holy Week (as last happened in 2008), while the national holiday holds its place in the calendar. Where St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day is an ethnic festival, outside of Ireland, ethnic gate-keepers can assert ownership and insist on their ideal of what it means to be Irish and Catholic - which is at the root of the controversy in New York City. In Buenos Aires a few years ago, the popularity of St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day as an excuse to drink excessively in the Irish pubs of the city&amp;rsquo;s financial district was opposed by the long established Irish-Argentine community with a poster campaign asserting that St. Patrick was the patron saint of the Irish, not of beer. In Ireland in recent decades with growing diversity, relative peace in Northern Ireland, unprecedentedly good relations between the Republic of Ireland and Britain, and the late lamented economic boom, there have been successful attempts to make the St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day festival less monolithic, more playful and more inclusive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In Montreal, St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day was first celebrated in 1760 by Irish officers in Wolfe&amp;rsquo;s army, which had just conquered Canada. In 1766, in Vienna, the Spanish ambassador Count O&amp;rsquo;Mahoney hosted a St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day banquet for other Irish imperial officials and generals, but this time the empire they served was Austrian. In that same year another group of Irish officers celebrated New York City&amp;rsquo;s first St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day, and a decade later their army would depart in defeat, leaving St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day to become, in time, the archetypal American ethnic festival. The razzmatazz of American St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day parades has more recently provided the model for public celebrations of the day in Ireland where the festival today is unthinkable without this global dimension, which indeed tends to overshadow it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Neither Ireland nor the Irish diaspora was ever ethnically, linguistically or denominationally homogeneous. O&amp;rsquo;Mahoney&amp;rsquo;s guests were Irish Catholics, some Irish speakers, some English speakers, some of Old English, some of Gaelic descent, whereas the Irish officers in Montreal and New York City were Protestants. Exiled in their hundreds of thousands from the 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;century, the Irish have been a constant presence in the formation of the modern world, as merchants, missionaries and soldiers. St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day is also the national holiday of the West Indian island of Montserrat, where on that day in 1768 the slaves revolted against their largely Irish Catholic masters. St. Patrick himself was a slave. It was in that capacity that he first saw Ireland, abducted by Irish pirates from his home in a Romanized part of Britain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day is important to millions of people who have a variety of sometimes conflicting relationships and often tenuous connections to Ireland: priests celebrating the religious feast, businessmen in Shanghai, policemen in Boston, Dublin kids whose parents came from Nigeria, Irish-Argentines whose native language is Spanish, Irish gays in New York, soldiers of the Royal Irish regiment of the British army, barmaids in Irish pubs in Berlin, the family of the Irish prime minister (who never see him on that day). No tradition can pass on without tacit or indeed vocal interrogation, without the possibility of borrowing, rejecting and re-interpreting. That is constantly being done, often before our eyes, in the case of St. Patrick&amp;rsquo;s Day. The fact that it already belong to millions of very different people makes it the most inclusive of symbols, and augurs well for the continuing relevance of the festival.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;Diarmuid &amp;Oacute; Gioll&amp;aacute;in&lt;/strong&gt; is a professor of Irish Language and Literature and Concurrent professor of Anthropology whose&amp;nbsp;interests include popular religion in Ireland as well as folklore and popular culture in the history of ideas and of institutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;Learn more&lt;/strong&gt;►&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-fellows/diarmuid-o-giollain/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diarmuid &amp;Oacute; Gioll&amp;aacute;in&amp;#39;s faculty web page&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishlanguage.nd.edu/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Department of Irish Language and Literature&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Diarmuid Ó Giolláin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/46829</id>
    <published>2014-03-12T13:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-14T14:55:53-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/46829-inaugural-breandan-o-buachalla-memorial-lecture/"/>
    <title>Keough-Naughton Institute Announces Inaugural Breandán Ó Buachalla Memorial Lecture</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Obuachalla150" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/123778/obuachalla.jpg" title="Obuachalla150" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies announces the inaugural &lt;strong&gt;Breandán Ó Buachalla Memorial Lecture&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;at 4 p.m. Thursday, March 27, 2014&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;in the Hesburgh Library, Rare Books Room.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	As part of the Twentieth Anniversary Speakers and Public Talks Series, the lecture honors the late Breandán Ó Buachalla, the first Thomas J. and Kathleen M. O&amp;rsquo;Donnell Chair of Irish at the University of Notre Dame, who was instrumental to the success of both the Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies and the Department of Irish Language and Literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The inaugural lecture &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Gaeilge&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; anois labharfar: Travails of the Irish Language&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; will be presented by Distinguished Naughton Fellow Cormac &amp;Oacute; Gr&amp;aacute;da, emeritus professor of economics at University College Dublin. &amp;ldquo;We are pleased to have Cormac &amp;Oacute; Gr&amp;aacute;da deliver this inaugural lecture on the experience of the Irish language as Breandán regarded the Irish language as a living tradition, symbolic of an unbroken practice with the past,&amp;rdquo; says Christopher Fox, Director of the Keough-Naughton Institute. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Cormacograda150" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/123780/ogradac150.jpg" title="Cormacograda150" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Professor &amp;Oacute; Gr&amp;aacute;da&amp;rsquo;s major books include Ireland: &lt;em&gt;A New Economic History 1780-1939 &lt;/em&gt;(1994), &lt;em&gt;Jewish Ireland in the Age of Joyce &lt;/em&gt;(2006) and&lt;em&gt; Famine: A Short History&lt;/em&gt; (2009). Co-editor of the European Review of Economic History, Professor &amp;Oacute; Gr&amp;aacute;da is a member of the Irish Economic and Social History Society as well as the Royal Irish Academy, where he received the Academy&amp;#39;s Gold Medal in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The memorial lecture will provide an opportunity to recognize a premier scholar of Irish culture, literature and linguistics. &amp;nbsp;&amp;quot;Breand&amp;aacute;n had mythic, larger-than-life status in Irish language and Irish Studies circles where he was known as &amp;#39;The Great &amp;Oacute; Buachalla,&amp;#39; the scholar who had written the most important book on Irish-speaking culture in the last fifty years, his classic 800 page study of Jacobite Ireland,&amp;quot; according to Professor Fox.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	When Breand&amp;aacute;n &amp;Oacute; Buachalla took the Thomas J. and Kathleen M. O&amp;rsquo;Donnell Chair, he became the first new endowed chair of Irish in North America since the Hibernian Chair at Catholic University in 1896--a point of which he was proud. &amp;nbsp;Known for his sense of humor, devotion to his family, commitment to his students and intolerance of shoddy work, his presence is felt today.&amp;nbsp; Because of Breand&amp;aacute;n&amp;rsquo;s work and vision, the new Department of Irish he built now receives international recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Breandán is &amp;ldquo;much missed,&amp;rdquo; says Professor Fox, &amp;ldquo;but his legacy at Notre Dame will live on in the classroom and in the field of Irish language and literature for many years to come.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Learn more►&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishlanguage.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Irish Language and Literature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/"&gt;Irish Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/research-and-publications/special-projects/north-american-catalogue-of-irish-manuscripts/"&gt;North American Catalogue of Irish Manuscripts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/46855</id>
    <published>2014-03-12T13:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-12T13:30:06-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/46855-irish-historical-archaeology-project-planned-for-summer-2014/"/>
    <title>Irish Historical Archaeology Project Planned for Summer 2014</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="nd_mag_ireland_19_200" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/126578/nd_mag_ireland_19_200.jpg" title="nd_mag_ireland_19_200" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	This June, Ian Kuijt, professor of anthropology and Keough-Naughton Institute for Irish Studies fellow will direct the Notre Dame Irish Historical Archaeology field project on Inishark, a remote island off the west coast of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The project draws on the success of earlier field work undertaken on the islands of Inisbofin and Inishark, County Galway, Ireland where significant gains were made in understanding island life.&amp;nbsp; Once home to a vibrant community but abandoned in the 1960&amp;rsquo;s, Inishark&amp;rsquo;s remains provide a unique window into life in western Connemara from the 1750&amp;rsquo;s trough the 1950&amp;#39;s.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The project, in the past open only to Notre Dame undergraduate and graduate students, this year welcomes interested students from other institutions.&amp;nbsp; Students will earn academic credit for the three week field course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	According to Professor Kuijt, the team will focus on two initiatives: a detailed excavation of a buried and well preserved sod and stone house dating to 1870 and the excavation of part of a 7th-10th century enclosure with an oratory, or small chapel, as well as exploratory excavations of a nearby water mill which dates to the 10th -12th century.&amp;nbsp; The project will expose students to the early medieval period in addition to post 17th century island life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The overall aim is to &amp;ldquo;document how residential and economic practices within the fishing village of Inishark changed with Irish national policies of improvement, changes in land ownership and local change at the community and household level due to immigration and famines from the 1850&amp;rsquo;s through the 1890&amp;rsquo;s,&amp;rdquo; says Professor Kuijt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The 2014 Notre Dame Irish Historical Archeology field excavation is an extension of past Cultural Landscapes of the Irish Coast projects funded by the Keough-Naughton Institute and the Ireland Council. &amp;nbsp;The Cultural Landscapes of the Irish Coast initative&amp;nbsp;seeks to research, document and ultimately preserve island culture and heritage.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Interested students are encouraged to visit the website: &lt;a href="http://clicproject.wordpress.com/"&gt;http://clicproject.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Learn more►&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-fellows/ian-kujit/"&gt;Ian Kuijt&amp;#39;s faculty page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://clicproject.wordpress.com/"&gt;Notre Dame Irish Historical Archaeology Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;a href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/"&gt;Irish Studies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:irishstudies.nd.edu,2005:News/46904</id>
    <published>2014-03-12T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-14T13:38:54-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/news/46904-fellow-recognized-in-irish-language-journal-2/"/>
    <title>Fellow Recognized in Irish Language Journal</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Brian O'Conchumhair" src="http://irishstudies.nd.edu/assets/105967/oconchubhair_brian.jpg" title="Brian O'Conchumhair" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Brian &amp;Oacute; Conchubhair, Keough-Naughton for Irish Studies Institute Fellow and Professor of Irish Language and Literature was recognized by &lt;em&gt;Comhar&lt;/em&gt;, a monthly literary journal in the Irish Language, for writing one of the 10 best books in Irish since 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	His work &lt;em&gt;Fin de Si&amp;egrave;cle na Gaeilge: Darwin, An Athbheochan agus Smaointeoireacht na hEorpa&lt;/em&gt; (Cl&amp;oacute; Iar-Chonnacht, 2009) also received the 2009 Oireachas non-fiction award and Duais Leabhar Taighde na Bliana Fhoras na Gaeilge/ACIS Prize for Books in the Irish Language.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Margaret Lloyd</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
