<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:enrollmentdivision.nd.edu,2005:/news</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/news.atom"/>
  <title>Enrollment Division // Enrollment Division</title>
  <updated>2014-04-15T15:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:enrollmentdivision.nd.edu,2005:News/47736</id>
    <published>2014-04-15T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-15T15:59:49-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/news/47736-a-more-qualified-pool-than-ever-before/"/>
    <title>A More Qualified Pool than Ever Before</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;A record number of high-achieving applicants fought for admission to the University this year, illustrating Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s increasing selectivity and marking this particular class as &amp;ldquo;a more qualified pool than ever before,&amp;rdquo; Don Bishop, associate vice president for undergraduate enrollment, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We had 17,897 [applications], and what was more interesting than just that number was there was about a 15 percent increase in the highest ability applicants, and by highest ability they would rate in the top two percent of the nation in accomplishment by national testing standards, by class performance,&amp;rdquo; Bishop said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bob Mundy, director of admissions, said the number of highly qualified applicants rose independently of the total number of applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;That increase in the applicant pool was only about one and a half percent,&amp;rdquo; Mundy said. &amp;ldquo;So it&amp;rsquo;s a disproportionate jump.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bishop said the Office of Undergraduate Admissions strives to fulfill a freshmen enrollment goal of 1,985 to 2,000 freshmen. He said the dramatic increase in highly qualified applicants allows for the Office of Admissions&amp;rsquo; to have increasing selectivity in choosing among the nation&amp;rsquo;s brightest high school seniors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We were about 20 percent more selective this year,&amp;rdquo; Bishop said. &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; We had 6,300 applicants out of that 17,897 &amp;hellip; that were in the top one percent in the nation in either their high school class performance and/or their national testing, many of them both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Less than half of those students gained admission. So when you have that sort of talent, you have to look at other factors.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;higher profile&amp;rdquo; of the applicant pool not only permitted but also forced admissions counselors to consider factors beyond a student&amp;rsquo;s test scores to create the most &amp;ldquo;well-rounded&amp;rdquo; class, Bishop said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are using the test scores less,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;If you look at four years ago compared to today, there&amp;rsquo;s a significant increase in our willingness to look beyond, and the reason being is we&amp;rsquo;re getting so many high numbers that they&amp;rsquo;re now so high &amp;hellip; to distinguish between this score and that score is not very meaningful.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expanding applicant pool and its strong qualifications also offers the Office of Undergraduate Admissions a &amp;ldquo;growing opportunity&amp;rdquo; to partner with faculty and administrators to recruit a class of students that will serve the University and ultimately the world, Bishop said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;With our selection process, with this elevated pool, we&amp;rsquo;re able to make those distinctions more directly as we review the applicants,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bishop said admissions counselors focused on four main goals throughout the process: to increase socioeconomic, cultural, racial and intellectual diversity, to expand outreach to international students, to enhance the quality of the application pool and to foster creative selections by considering an &amp;ldquo;EQ,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;emotional quotient.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The emotional quotient, the potential for leadership and service to others, maintains Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s focus on what sort of students will have the most impact in the world if they use their Notre Dame degree properly for impactful values that Notre Dame believes in,&amp;rdquo; Bishop said. &amp;ldquo;This desire for Notre Dame to be one of the major forces for good in the world is what we want.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bishop said Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;core mission value&amp;rdquo; of selecting students who will be impacted by the University and then in turn impact the world makes Notre Dame unique among the nation&amp;rsquo;s top 20 private institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;At other universities, there are a lot of students that believe in those things, but there&amp;rsquo;s not necessarily considered core to that university experience,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not a transformational goal of the other universities, whereas here, we&amp;rsquo;re looking to transform students to be highly energetic, not only towards the intellectual but what impact are they going to have?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Factors admissions counselors might consider beyond test scores include extraordinary talents, dedication to extracurricular activities and motivation to succeed in a particular field or with challenging coursework, Mundy said. He said more than 40 application readers try to project how a student would enhance the Notre Dame community and continue to further the University&amp;rsquo;s mission after graduation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I think what the staff&amp;rsquo;s been able to do is find the students [about] who they say, &amp;lsquo;The way this student is currently living [his or her] life really seems to mesh well with the values that we feel make this place so special,&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mundy said the staff members in the Office of Undergraduate Admissions look forward to welcoming admitted students to campus this month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This time of year we literally come off this real grinding selection period or evaluation period, and there&amp;rsquo;s always just this immediate burst of excitement as you start to meet some of these admitted students,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;These are the students who are going to shape this place for the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You just meet one or two of these students, and you just feel good again. I&amp;rsquo;m really excited about this class in so many ways.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Lesley Stevenson, The Observer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:enrollmentdivision.nd.edu,2005:News/46480</id>
    <published>2014-02-26T07:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-02-26T07:06:57-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/news/46480-notre-dame-to-adjust-admission-practices-for-prospective-business-undergraduates/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame to Adjust Admission Practices for Prospective Business Undergraduates</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	In response to the growth of its undergraduate business school,&amp;nbsp;the University of Notre Dame is adopting new admission practices for students interested in enrolling in the Mendoza College of Business. &amp;nbsp;The new policy, which will commence with the fall 2015 first-year class, will cap enrollment at 550 per graduating class.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Students at Notre Dame are admitted to the University&amp;rsquo;s First Year of Studies, not to an individual school or college. However, upon application to Notre Dame, all students are asked to make a non-binding indication of the college or school, and specific major or discipline, in which they intend to major. In the past, there was no limit put on the number of students who could transfer into any college or school, including Mendoza.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In the future, when first admitted to Notre Dame, students who indicate an intent to major in business will be informed, at the time of admission, whether they are &amp;ldquo;pre-approved&amp;rdquo; to do so at the end of their first year, should that remain their goal. If they are not pre-approved, students will be advised that they will be free to enroll in any other college or school, but that the chances of being approved to major in business after the first year will be extremely limited. Such students will be advised that they should reconsider enrolling in Notre Dame if they are only interested in majoring in business. If a student who is pre-approved to major in business later decides not to do so, she or he will be free to major in any other college or school at Notre Dame.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Notre Dame is the first choice for most of our applicants, and we anticipate many who indicate business on their application will opt to enroll here without the pre-approved status and seek other majors,&amp;rdquo; said Don Bishop, associate vice president for undergraduate enrollment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	After the first year, a small number of students, who were not pre-approved to major in business, will be allowed to do so. This number will include both students currently matriculated at Notre Dame as well as some students applying to Notre Dame from other universities.&amp;nbsp; The number of openings will be managed to ensure the University achieves the 550 degree goal per class for Mendoza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The selection process for first-year students without a pre-approved status and transfer students will be conducted by the Office of Undergraduate Admissions.&amp;nbsp; Decisions will be made based on academic performance to date (at Notre Dame or elsewhere), a written statement addressing the reasons the student wants to pursue a business major, and a holistic evaluation of the non-academic accomplishments of the student that is consistent with the evaluation the University currently provides to all applicants for first-year and transfer admission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Notre Dame&amp;nbsp;will maintain an overall undergraduate enrollment at approximately 8,500 students, of which some 2,200 will be business majors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	More information is available at &lt;a href="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/mendoza-admissions-policies"&gt;https://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/mendoza-admissions-policies&lt;/a&gt;/.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;
	###&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;From: Dennis Brown, assistant vice president for public information and communications&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Office of Public Relations</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:enrollmentdivision.nd.edu,2005:News/45282</id>
    <published>2013-12-20T17:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-12-20T17:11:53-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/news/45282-notre-dame-admits-1-960-early-action-applicants-to-the-class-of-2018-from-a-record-6-551-early-action-applicants/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame admits 1,960 Early Action Applicants to the Class of 2018 from a record 6,551 Early Action applicants</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	The University of Notre Dame admitted 1,960 Early Action applicants who attended 1,240 different high schools in 46 states and 30 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The students were selected from a record number of 6,551 Early Action applicants. In addition, another 900 were deferred to the Regular Action admission process where they will receive another full evaluation for admission in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The academic and personal profile of the 2014 applicant pool was the highest achieved by a Notre Dame early admission admit cohort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Don Bishop, Associate Vice President of Undergraduate Enrollment, noted, &amp;ldquo;This year while applications for Early Action increased by 7%, we also saw another elevation in the overall quality and diversity of the entire applicant pool. &amp;nbsp;The number of applicants with academic credentials and a record of service and leadership that have traditionally gained admission to Notre Dame was up 13%. We are exceptionally impressed with the students who aspire to join the Notre Dame family.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The median profile of the admitted students place them among the top 1% of the nation in their high school class performance and/or national test scores. &amp;nbsp;However, more impressive was their leadership and service accomplishments. Notre Dame practices a holistic admission process that views students for their exceptional academic and intellectual promise and creativity as well as their leadership and entrepreneurial records and their heart and sense of service to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;We look forward to talking with these students about their goals in life and how Notre Dame can show them a bigger world and an intellectual experience greater than even they can imagine. We also are excited over the next three months to read the Regular Action applicants and introduce them to those who plan to join them in the fall of 2014,&amp;rdquo; stated Bishop.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Enrollment Division</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:enrollmentdivision.nd.edu,2005:News/45004</id>
    <published>2013-12-11T16:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-12-18T11:07:21-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/news/45004-unveiling-the-new-enrollment-division/"/>
    <title>Unveiling the New Enrollment Division</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	Over the past year the Enrollment Division began to implement a reorganization strategy after completing the new OADI process. This reorganization is tiered over a three-year period, and the Division has just completed its first year. The focus of the reorganization transforms our admissions, financial aid, pre-college and early outreach programs, and student accounts capabilities. Notre Dame will increasingly shape its future applicant pools to align with the University&amp;rsquo;s strategic goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;In an evermore competitive environment among the top universities for the most talented students and leaders, this restructuring provides the University with a dynamic organization designed to be assertive in identifying and engaging the best students around the nation and globe that fit Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s mission,&amp;quot; Don Bishop, Associate Vice President, Undergraduate Enrollment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	During the reorganization process, several new initiatives emerged as part of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s recruitment strategy. One key strategy will incorporate the use of research-informed decision making to make optimal use of resources and to create the best possible outcomes based on strategically constructed goals. In addition, the division will also develop a more sophisticated selection process intended to strengthen our tradition of producing thinkers and leaders that will impact the world in their post-Notre Dame careers. These new initiatives, in addition to others, will advance the quality and diversity of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s applicant pool and elevate the University&amp;rsquo;s competitive position among the top 20 universities in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Due to early retirements and the OADI restructuring process, several new positions and hires were made over the past year. These include Dr. Tom Bear, Executive Director of Student Financial Strategies; Kristin Butz, Associate Director of Financial Aid; Dr. Renate Crawford, Director of Engagement for Academic Recruitment; Cindy Santana Cubillo, Event Specialist; Dr. Paulette Curtis, Faculty Director of Pre-College Programs and the AnBryce Scholarship Program; Brian Lohr, Director of Admissions Operations and Management; Dr. Paul Mueller, Director of Enrollment Division Research; Kelly Pratt, Program Coordinator, Pre-College Programs; Karen Putt, Associate Director for Alumni and Parent Relations, RaeLee Ray, Program Coordinator, Pre-College Programs; Rev. Doug Smith C.S.C., Director of Operations and Finance; and Geoff Young, Associate Director of Communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Additionally, some staff responsibilities have been elevated. These include Sue Brandt, Director of Strategic Services; Ashley Carlin, Assistant Director, Early Outreach and Engagement Recruitment; Dr. Alicia Coates, Director of Early Outreach and Engagement Recruitment; Alisa Fisher, Senior Associate Director of Admissions; Joyce Lantz, Director of Recruitment and Communications; Mary Nucciarone, Director of Financial Aid; and Gene Pilawski, Director of Student Accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	It is the mission of the Enrollment Division to identify, cultivate, recruit, and enroll the top Catholic scholars from across the United States and the world.&amp;nbsp; The Division strives to increase diversity, broadly understood, first-generation and international students, while remaining attentive to our alumni, student athletes, faculty and staff children, and others.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Enrollment Division</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:enrollmentdivision.nd.edu,2005:News/41825</id>
    <published>2013-09-06T16:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-01-08T11:31:30-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/news/41825-meet-the-class-of-2017/"/>
    <title>Meet the Class of 2017</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	The freshman class of 2017 has shaped up to be one of the most diverse and academically richest classes in Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="student_spring" src="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/assets/113641/student_spring.jpg" title="student_spring" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	There were a total of 17,647 freshman applications for the class of 2017. This was an all-time record for&amp;nbsp;freshman applications. The admit rate was 22% and the expected total number of the incoming freshman will be 2,075. There were a total of 676 transfer applications with an admit rate of 25% for an estimated total of 130 new transfer students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The class of 2017 also broke another record with 53% of the admitted students deciding to enroll at Notre Dame. This figure ranks among the top eight in the nation among highly selective national research universities for yield rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Academically, 55% of the incoming freshmen were in the top 1% of the nation in either high school performance and/or on national testing and had exceptional records of service, leadership, and involvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Notre Dame uses a holistic admissions process where other attributes are also valued&amp;mdash;less than 45% of applicants ranked in the top 1% for class performance or national test scores gained admission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	This class will also be one of the most diverse classes in Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s history with 26% U.S. students of color and 5% international. Alumni children comprise 24% of the class &amp;mdash; double the 12% average of other top 15 private universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Regional Diversity of the Freshman Class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table align="left" border="1" cellpadding="1" cellspacing="1" style="width: 500px;"&gt;
	&lt;tbody&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				32%&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				East or Southeast&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				675 freshmen&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				42%&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				Midwest&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				863 freshmen&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				20%&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				West/Southwest&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				413 freshmen&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				6%&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				Outside of U.S.&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
				124 freshmen&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The incoming class will travel an average distance of 850 miles to begin their freshman year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Enrollment Division</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:enrollmentdivision.nd.edu,2005:News/41826</id>
    <published>2013-08-15T15:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-12-18T11:28:20-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/news/41826-summer-scholars-hit-the-campus/"/>
    <title>Pre-College Students Hit the Campus</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	Summer Scholars and Leadership Seminar students hit the campus in July for two weeks of intensive academic, spiritual, and social growth opportunities and the chance to experience daily life as a Notre Dame student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	For over a dozen years, the Summer Scholars program has offered incomparable summer opportunities for bright, motivated and curious high school students who seek to be challenged and inspired. Whether delving into classic texts, modeling solutions to disasters or global health challenges, or finding the best lighting and angle to shoot a scene for an original film, students learn what college-level academics require in the company of like-minded peers from across the nation and the world.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="7" src="http://enrollmentdivision.nd.edu/assets/120901/7.9.13_pre_college_08.jpg" title="7" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;This experience has by far been one of the best I have had up to this point in life. I feel as if I have matured, I have found new friendships, new passions, new goals, and have developed an attitude of confidence,&amp;rdquo; stated Eniyah Willingham, 2013 Summer Scholars student.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The Leadership Seminars expand students&amp;rsquo; horizons by placing them directly into in-depth discussions with Notre Dame faculty. In discourse with University professors and their peer leaders from around the country, students depart our campus with the ability to appreciate and value diverse perspectives while confidently voicing their own questions and answers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;quot;What I learned in just 10 days makes me so excited for my future as I begin the college process. I have seen in just that short time what Notre Dame and its students have to offer. I want to go back to my home state and continue reading and researching about the topics we discussed in the program. I am so honored that I was chosen to take part in this incredible opportunity,&amp;rdquo; stated Meghan Flyke, 2013 Leadership Seminars student.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Enrollment Division</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
