<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>In Memoriam</title>
<link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
<link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/index-atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
<id>tag:reed.edu,2013:/reed_magazine/in-memoriam</id>
<updated>2014-07-21T10:00:23-0700</updated>
<subtitle>Lost friends of Reed - Mon Jul 21 10:00:23 PDT 2014</subtitle>
<generator uri="http://www.hannonhill.com/products/">Cascade Server</generator>

    
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>William Wood Wessinger, Trustee</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/william-wessinger-trustee.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/william-wessinger-trustee.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    William Wood Wessinger,&#160;February 7, 2014, in Portland.&#160;Great-grandson of Portland brewing legend Henry Weinhard, Bill earned a BA in economics from Cornell in 1940. During World War II, he served in the army in the Aleutian...
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
        
                                    <p><img alt="A picture of William Wessinger" src="assets/images/june 2014/IMwessinger.jpg" width="277"/></p>
                                
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">William Wood Wessinger,&#160;February 7, 2014, in Portland.&#160;Great-grandson of Portland brewing legend Henry Weinhard, Bill earned a BA in economics from Cornell in 1940. During World War II, he served in the army in the Aleutian Islands, and after the war worked as a freight forwarder in Pendleton and for a steamship company in Portland, before becoming assistant treasurer for the family-owned Blitz Weinhard Brewing Company. Through night classes, he became a CPA and took on additional responsibilities for the company, later operating the business with his brother, <strong>Frederic G. Wessinger &#8217;50.</strong> They sold the brewery to Pabst Brewing Company in 1979. Bill was elected to Reed&#8217;s board of trustees in 1967 and served until 1978. He believed in supporting the state and the community, and among the list of organizations he supported were the High Desert Museum, the Portland Opera, Boys Club of Oregon, the Nature Conservancy of Oregon, and the Oregon Shakespeare Festival. He was appointed to a number of state commissions and committees, and helped create the first student housing for Portland State University and purchased land that would expand the boundaries of Forest Park. He directed both the Blitz Weinhard Foundation and the Wessinger Family Foundation and established the Henry W. and Romayne Wessinger Scholarship Fund. Bill and Patricia Lue, noted philanthropist, were married in 1946 and had five children. Weekends provided time for the family to camp, hike, and ski, and summers were spent in central Oregon. Bill, who was an early member of the Mazamas, hiked with Pat throughout the Cascades; they explored the Canadian Rockies, and took other extensive and challenging travels abroad. Pat died in 2011. Survivors include 3 daughters, 2 sons, 14 grandchildren, and 3 great-grandchildren.</p>
                            ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>Grace E. Frazier Courts, Friend</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/grace-frazier-courts-friend.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/grace-frazier-courts-friend.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    Grace E. Frazier Courts,&#160;December 22, 2013, in Portland.&#160;Grace was raised in Detroit and Kalamazoo, Michigan, and learned to be a stenographer after graduating from high school. Her parents were friends with the parents of Prof....
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
            
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">Grace E. Frazier Courts,&#160;December 22, 2013, in Portland.&#160;Grace was raised in Detroit and Kalamazoo, Michigan, and learned to be a stenographer after graduating from high school. Her parents were friends with the parents of Prof. <strong>Frederick A. Courts</strong> [psychology 1945&#8211;69]. Grace and Fred met in childhood and married in 1936. They lived in California and Missouri as Fred completed his education and began his teaching career. Grace was a wonderful homemaker and mother, &#8220;the best cook, friend, and counsel to all of her family.&#8221; She volunteered with the Red Cross, the Sierra Club, and the Democratic League of Women Voters. She opened her home to faculty and students of Reed and made many friends in the Reed community. Survivors include two daughters and sons; two grandchildren; and four great-grandchildren. Fred died in 1969.</p>
                            ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>Jennifer Ariane Nonas '00</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/jennifer-nonas-2000.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/jennifer-nonas-2000.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    Jennifer Ariane Nonas &#8217;00,&#160;January 1, 2014, from pneumonia.&#160;Jen had an intense two-year struggle with cancer, which she charted in her blog, jenandlumpy.blogspot.com. Jen&#8217;s blog, while created for her to...
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
        
                                    <p><img alt="A picture of Jennifer Nonas" src="assets/images/june 2014/IM00nonas.jpg" width="277"/></p>
                                
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">Jennifer Ariane Nonas &#8217;00,&#160;January 1, 2014, from pneumonia.&#160;Jen had an intense two-year struggle with cancer, which she charted in her blog, jenandlumpy.blogspot.com. Jen&#8217;s blog, while created for her to chronicle her experience with cancer, serves as an exemplary resource guide for those navigating the journey of cancer as a bystander. Along with narrating the battles with the cancer forms she named Lumpy, Sneaky, and the Rebel Forces, Jen catalogued what forms of support are actually helpful (and not helpful), and provided insight into how cancer may affect relationship roles. Jen came to Reed from West Milford, New Jersey, and earned a BA in psychology, completing the thesis &#8220;How Happy Will I be if I Lose? The Effect of Sensation Seeking on the Self-Prediction of Emotional States&#8221; with her adviser, Prof. <strong>Kathryn Oleson</strong> [psychology 1995&#8211;], who, along with Jen&#8217;s friend <strong>Moira Tofanelli &#8217;99,</strong> contributed significantly to this memorial. After Reed, Jen worked as a web developer with CollegeNet in Portland and then attended Drexel University, where she earned a master&#8217;s degree in art therapy; most recently, she worked for WES Health Care in Philadelphia. Jen&#8217;s graduate thesis was on optimism, a practice she herself engaged in throughout her life and health struggles: continuing to delight in tastes of gelato when well enough; scripting an anticancer lullaby; creating a cancer cell cat toy so that her cat &#8220;could kill some cancer, too&#8221;; relishing chance meetings with neighbors while practicing walking on her prosthetic leg on sunny days through her Philadelphia neighborhood, Passyunk; and finding pride in her daily accomplishments.</p>
                                <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">While a consistently cheerful and lighthearted person, Jen held a depth of understanding of the world and herself that many can only hope to manifest. She demonstrated such self-awareness when, postamputation, she penned on her &#8220;little leg&#8221; a quote from Walt Whitman:</p>
                                <p align="left" class="InMemoriambody"><i>Henceforth I ask not good-fortune, I myself am good-fortune,</i></p>
                                    ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>Cynthia Natalee Thatcher '88</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/cynthia-thatcher-1988.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/cynthia-thatcher-1988.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    Cynthia Natalee Thatcher &#8217;88,&#160;August 8, 2013, in Denver, Colorado, following a long illness.&#160;News of her death came from her mother, Margarita Thatcher, who conveyed Cindy&#8217;s love for Reed. Cindy earned her BA...
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
        
                                    <p><img alt="A picture of Cynthia Thatcher" src="assets/images/june 2014/IM88thatcher.jpg" width="277"/></p>
                                
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">Cynthia Natalee Thatcher &#8217;88,&#160;August 8, 2013, in Denver, Colorado, following a long illness.&#160;News of her death came from her mother, Margarita Thatcher, who conveyed Cindy&#8217;s love for Reed. Cindy earned her BA in philosophy, working with faculty advisers <strong>Marvin Levich</strong> [philosophy 1953&#8211;94] and <strong>C.D.C. Reeve</strong> [philosophy 1976&#8211;2001], and completing the thesis &#8220;Characterizations of Love in <i>The Brothers Karamazov.</i>&#8221; In 2000, she completed an MA in creative writing at the University of Colorado at Boulder. She became a Buddhist teacher and was a contributor to many online resources for Buddhist study. In 2008, she published <i>Just Seeing: Insight Meditation and Sense-Perception </i>through the Buddhist Publication Society. The book explored in depth the Buddha&#8217;s significant teaching &#8220;When seeing, just see; when hearing, just hear,&#8221; relating to the practice of insight meditation. Cindy touched on the two kinds of reality&#8212;ultimate and conventional&#8212;expounded in the Abhidhamma, through the example of a pointillist painting that can be viewed in two ways. In addition, the book contains meditation instructions for beginners, an appendix on the perceptual process as described in Buddhist metaphysics, and a crossword puzzle of Pali terms. <i>Just Seeing </i>has been translated into Spanish and German. Describing the book, one reader noted Cindy&#8217;s eloquent and expressive language. Memorial services were held for Cindy at Buddhist temples in California, Colorado, Sri Lanka, and Thailand.</p>
                            ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>Michael J. Owren '77</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/michael-owren-1977.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/michael-owren-1977.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    Michael J. Owren &#8217;77,&#160;January 15, 2014, in Atlanta, Georgia.&#160;A teacher and scientist who analyzed the biological foundations of animal and human communication, Michael was born in Oslo, Norway, and raised in Alaska; New...
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
        
                                    <p><img alt="A picture of Michael Owren" src="assets/images/june 2014/IM77owren.jpg" width="277"/></p>
                                
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">Michael J. Owren &#8217;77,&#160;January 15, 2014, in Atlanta, Georgia.&#160;A teacher and scientist who analyzed the biological foundations of animal and human communication, Michael was born in Oslo, Norway, and raised in Alaska; New Hampshire; and Bergen, Norway. He attended Reed, along with his sister, <strong>Turid L. Owren &#8217;74,</strong> and earned a BA from Reed in psychology, working with adviser Prof. <strong>Allen Neuringer</strong> [psych 1970&#8211;2008] to complete the thesis &#8220;Dejection, Disgust, and Despair: A Layman&#8217;s Guide to Two Theories of Blocking and Overshadowing.&#8221; Michael went on to earn a doctorate from Indiana University in experimental psychology in 1986 and taught psychology and neuroscience for over 25 years, first while doing postdoctoral work at the University of California, Davis, and later at the University of Colorado at Denver, the University of Otago (New Zealand), Reed (1995&#8211;97), Cornell University, and Georgia State University. At the time of his death, he was an adjunct professor at Emory University. Michael loved teaching and served as a mentor to many undergraduate and graduate students. His research analyzed vocal phenomena in both animals and humans. He pioneered digital spectral analysis techniques, first developed in speech science for use in studies of animal communication. His work challenged a predominant view by showing that animal vocalizations &#8220;work&#8221; by influencing attentional, arousal, emotional, and motivational states in the listener, rather than by imparting representational messages. Michael&#8217;s empirical studies are widely recognized for their rigor and attention to detail. Longtime colleague Drew Rendall, chair of the University of Lethbridge psychology department, characterized Michael&#8217;s work as exceptional in its clarity of thought, expression, and vision. &#8220;His research techniques were widely embraced and became a standard part of the analytic toolkit of animal bioacousticians. Michael deployed his technical and methodological rigor investigating phenomena of very broad importance to theories of the origins and evolution of signaling systems in animals and humans, and he thus made enduring theoretical contributions to the discipline.&#8221; In addition to its academic recognition, Michael&#8217;s work generated interest in the popular media, including a <i>Chicago Tribune </i>article in 2003, which described his feline communication research as the &#8220;how of the meow.&#8221; Throughout his life, Michael enjoyed running and singing, and performed professionally with an a cappella group, Cool Shooz, in Denver. Friends and family enjoyed his dry wit and extensive knowledge on a great many topics&#8212;from beer to basketball to politics and world geography. Survivors include Turid, brothers Henry and Thomas, and 13 nieces and nephews. A memorial service for Michael was held in the Psychology building at Reed in March. Michael&#8217;s family, who provided this memorial, suggests remembrances to Reed College.</p>
                            ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>Marian Dorothy Brennan '76</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/marian-brennan-1976.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/marian-brennan-1976.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    Marian Dorothy Brennan &#8217;76,&#160;November 25, 2013, in Washougal, Washington.&#160;Marian received a BA in English literature from Reed and went on to study law at Lewis &amp; Clark College. She later earned a black belt in...
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
        
                                    <p><img alt="A picture of Marian Brennan" src="assets/images/june 2014/IM76brennan.jpg" width="277"/></p>
                                
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">Marian Dorothy Brennan &#8217;76,&#160;November 25, 2013, in Washougal, Washington.&#160;Marian received a BA in English literature from Reed and went on to study law at Lewis &amp; Clark College. She later earned a black belt in karate and taught at Karate for Women in Portland. She is remembered for her wit, her kindness, her generosity, and her fabulous cooking. Survivors include her life partner, Susan Helene Fletcher, two sisters, and a brother.</p>
                            ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>Jennifer  Craven '74</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/jennifer-craven-1974.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/jennifer-craven-1974.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    Jennifer Craven &#8217;74,&#160;September 30, 2012, in Washington.&#160;We recently learned of Jennifer&#8217;s death from her cousin, Philip Craven. Jennifer attended Reed for three years, with a focus on biology and psychology....
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
        
                                    <p><img alt="A picture of Jennifer Craven" src="assets/images/june 2014/IM74craven.jpg" width="277"/></p>
                                
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">Jennifer Craven &#8217;74,&#160;September 30, 2012, in Washington.&#160;We recently learned of Jennifer&#8217;s death from her cousin, Philip Craven. Jennifer attended Reed for three years, with a focus on biology and psychology. In the &#8217;70s, she also worked with children in day care centers and with special-needs children in shelter homes. She organized and supported the newly established Outside In Clinic in Portland, and was a bookkeeper, debt collector, and salesperson for other businesses in Portland and Seattle. Jennifer earned an AAS in digital electronics technology and an AA in business and accounting at North Seattle Community College in Seattle, Washington. One of her instructors reported, &#8220;Jennifer was not only an &#8216;A&#8217; student in my class, but she was also a delightful person, helpful to her classmates, cooperative with the school faculty, and, in general, well liked by all.&#8221; For Hewlett Packard in Everett, she calibrated, tested, and repaired electronic instruments. She then became a caregiver for her father when his health deteriorated, and studied health information technology at Shoreline Community College. Following her father&#8217;s death in 1999, Jennifer completed a course in medical records, and in 2009, she earned a BS in audiology from the University of Washington. She was thrilled to complete the degree, though shortly thereafter, reports Philip, she received a diagnosis of cancer. &#8220;She was extremely intelligent and a lifelong student. Very warm, with a lovely laugh,&#8221; Philip recalls. &#8220;I was proud of her courage during treatment and, especially, in using the Death with Dignity statute when treatment failed.&#8221; In addition to Philip, survivors include her mother, Clare, brother, Gilbert, and the Ferris families. Her sister, <strong>Bronwen Craven &#8217;72,</strong> died in the &#8217;70s.</p>
                            ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>Pamela B. Canty '73</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/pamela-canty-1973.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/pamela-canty-1973.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    Pamela B. Canty &#8217;73,&#160;February 11, 2014, at her home in Portland.&#160;Pam earned a BA from Reed in psychology, completing the thesis &#8220;Reality and the Psychoanalytic Theory.&#8221; and following graduation...
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
        
                                    <p><img alt="A picture of Pamela Canty" src="assets/images/june 2014/IM73canty.jpg" width="277"/></p>
                                
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">Pamela B. Canty &#8217;73,&#160;February 11, 2014, at her home in Portland.&#160;Pam earned a BA from Reed in psychology, completing the thesis &#8220;Reality and the Psychoanalytic Theory.&#8221; and following graduation worked as a mental health therapist for several years. She later did banking collections and was a credit manager, while taking courses at Portland State University with the goal of earning an MBA. Pam and <strong>Robert R. Granville &#8217;76</strong> married and had one son, Joseph; they lived for a time in Panama, where Robert served as a medical officer in the army. Her friend Sandy Sheehy, who notified the college of Pam&#8217;s death, wrote, &#8220;Pam always valued the education she received and the friends she made at Reed.&#8221;</p>
                            ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>Margaret  Clark Potheau '70</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/margaret-clark-potheau-1970.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/margaret-clark-potheau-1970.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    Margaret Clark Potheau &#8217;70,&#160;October 31, 2013, in Sherborn, Massachusetts, from metastatic melanoma.&#160;Margo was at Reed for two years and completed her undergraduate education at Boston University. A talented horsewoman,...
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
            
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">Margaret Clark Potheau &#8217;70,&#160;October 31, 2013, in Sherborn, Massachusetts, from metastatic melanoma.&#160;Margo was at Reed for two years and completed her undergraduate education at Boston University. A talented horsewoman, she won many dressage and jumping competitions in her youth in El Paso, Texas, and later, before her children were born, she drove a BMW in stock car races and was a member of the BMW Car Club of America. Margo ran a mail-order business and was certified as an EMT and a medic. She worked as a home health aide and as a volunteer for the Sherborn Fire Department. She enjoyed athletic competitions and celebrated the successes of the Patriots and the Red Sox. A woman of strength and a gentle spirit, Margo is survived by her daughter and son and her sister.</p>
                            ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
        
        
    
        
        
                  
    <entry>
    <title>Bonnie Anne Stockman '69</title>
    <link href="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/obituaries/june2014/bonnie-stockman-1969.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/>
    <id>tag:reed.edu,$_DateTool.format('yyyy-MM-dd',$pubDate):/obituaries/june2014/bonnie-stockman-1969.html</id>
    <published>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$pubDate)</published>
    <updated>$_DateTool.format("yyyy-MM-dd'T'HH:mm:ssZ",$updatedDate)</updated>
    <summary>
    <![CDATA[
    Bonnie Ann Stockman &#8217;69,&#160;October 8, 2013, from ovarian cancer, at home, in Oregon City, Oregon.&#160;An &#8220;army brat,&#8221; Bonnie grew up in various places, including Georgia, Alaska, Monterey, California, and...
    ]]>
    </summary>
    <author>
        <name>$byline</name>
    </author>
    <category label="obituary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" term="obituary"/>
    <content type="html" xml:base="http://www.reed.edu/reed_magazine/in-memoriam/" xml:lang="en">    
        <![CDATA[
        
        
                                    <p><img alt="A picture of Bonnie Stockman" src="assets/images/june 2014/IM69stockman.jpg" width="277"/></p>
                                
                    <p class="InMemoriamnamesInMemoriam">Bonnie Ann Stockman &#8217;69,&#160;October 8, 2013, from ovarian cancer, at home, in Oregon City, Oregon.&#160;An &#8220;army brat,&#8221; Bonnie grew up in various places, including Georgia, Alaska, Monterey, California, and Washington state, before coming to Reed, where she studied psychology when she wasn&#8217;t folk dancing or having other adventures. She took a break from Reed to study Zen Buddhism at the San Francisco Zen Center and Tassajara Zen Monastery, and spent a summer living in a miner&#8217;s cabin above Amador City, California. In 1974, Bonnie graduated from Portland State University with a BA in psychology and a certificate in social service. Her husband, <strong>David Lynn &#8217;70,</strong> writes: &#8220;Bonnie combined a tremendous technical ability with a deep abiding passion and concern for other living creatures and the world they inhabit. That shows up in her early social work and community action jobs, her time as an ombudsperson for the startup HMO Cascade Health Care, later as a customer care specialist and systems analyst in the information technology department for various banks and finally Con-Way Trucking. While she was holding all of those positions, she actively participated with Oregon Equestrian Trails, which campaigns to keep Oregon trails and the environment generally open for use by people and their horses. Poet <strong>Gary (&#8217;51) Snyder&#8217;s</strong> book <i>Mountains and Rivers without End</i> was everywhere in her thoughts and actions.&#8221; Bonnie was diagnosed with stage four ovarian cancer in 2009, shortly after returning from a trip to Iran in search of oriental rugs. Her response to her diagnosis was a renewed determination to live every moment to its fullest. She took early retirement, which freed her to travel to Turkey and China (more carpets!), and to Hawaii, Washington, and California. She went horse camping on Mount Hood and participated in maintaining various horse campgrounds. Not content with that, she embarked upon the study of Argentine tango and tai chi chuan, including the sword form. She volunteered with the Ovarian Cancer Alliance of Oregon and Southwest Washington and with support groups for women with reproductive cancers. She served as a consumer reviewer for Ovarian Cancer Research Program proposals for the Department of Defense Congressionally Directed Medical Research Programs. Bonnie spent the final weeks of her life at home in rural Oregon, surrounded by her family and close friends. According to her wishes, she was cremated wearing an old pair of jeans, a T-shirt with the John Muir quote &#8220;The mountains are calling and I must go,&#8221; earrings from the Grand Bazaar in Istanbul, sexy underwear, and red satin tango shoes. This memorial was written by <strong>Deborah Ross &#8217;68,</strong> who helped care for Bonnie and her family in the final weeks of Bonnie&#8217;s life. Survivors include David and two grown children.</p>
                            ]]>
    </content>
    </entry>
            </feed>