<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Santa Cruz Pumas</title>
	<subtitle type="text">A UC Santa Cruz mountain lion habitat fragmentation study.</subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-06T00:18:21Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org" />
	<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.8.3">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cwilmers</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Mountain lion kills deer on camera.]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/07/05/mountain-lion-kills-deer-on-camera/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1478</id>
		<updated>2014-07-06T00:18:21Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-06T00:17:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="puma ecology" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="video" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="deer" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="kill" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="puma" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="scrape" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We recently captured this rare footage of a mountain lion killing a deer fawn in front of one of our remote cameras. Notice that the puma is holding the neck of the fawn and the fawn occasionally tries to wriggle free. This appears to be the strategy by which pumas kill their prey (at least [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/07/05/mountain-lion-kills-deer-on-camera/"><![CDATA[<p>We recently captured this rare footage of a mountain lion killing a deer fawn in front of one of our remote cameras. Notice that the puma is holding the neck of the fawn and the fawn occasionally tries to wriggle free.  </p>
<p><iframe width="640" height="480" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/ioxeAZtgiho" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>This appears to be the strategy by which pumas kill their prey (at least deer). Namely that they bite on to the trachea (breathing tube) and kill the prey by suffocating it to death.  A quick search on youtube reveals two more videos. In this first video, the puma jumps on the deer&#8217;s back and then eventually kills it be biting and holding on the trachea.</p>
<p><iframe src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/YeOWbPBNYPE?start=19" height="360" width="640" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>In this second video, the puma has already felled the deer and again finally kills the deer by holding on to its trachea.  </p>
<p><iframe width="640" height="360" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/OGfxD5hcInw?start=9" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/07/05/mountain-lion-kills-deer-on-camera/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/07/05/mountain-lion-kills-deer-on-camera/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Veronica</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Hollywood Puma and Rat Poison]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/06/10/hollywood-puma-and-rat-poison/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1414</id>
		<updated>2014-06-12T20:51:57Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-10T19:38:34Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="puma ecology" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="pumas in the news" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[You may remember the beautiful National Geographic photo of a male puma, P-22, who lives in Griffith Park.  His territory is very close to humans, but, as far as we know, he&#8217;s never had a problem with that.  That is, until now. It turns out that P-22 has never bothered any people, but we have [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/06/10/hollywood-puma-and-rat-poison/"><![CDATA[<p>You may remember the beautiful National Geographic photo of a male puma, P-22, who lives in <a href="https://www.google.com/maps/place/Griffith+Park/@34.1304175,-118.2747432,20098m/data=!3m1!1e3!4m2!3m1!1s0x80c2c08d21749ff7:0x4731b4ee89bae4aa">Griffith Park</a>.  His territory is very close to humans, but, as far as we know, he&#8217;s never had a problem with that.  That is, until now.</p>
<div id="attachment_1279" style="width: 625px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/hollywood-cougar-615.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-1279" alt="Hollywood Cougar" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/hollywood-cougar-615.jpg" width="615" height="462" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">December: Healthy P-22 strolling around his territory in Griffith Park</p></div>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<p style="text-align: left;">It turns out that P-22 has never bothered any people, but we have unintentionally hurt him.  Just 4 months after the National Geographic photo was taken, male P-22 was recaptured by biologists.  This time, they noticed he didn&#8217;t look like he was doing very well &#8211; he was thin, his hair was patchy, and his skin was crusty.</p>
<div id="attachment_1466" style="width: 560px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/p-22.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1466 " alt="p-22" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/p-22.jpg" width="550" height="374" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">April: P-22, skinny and loosing his hair, just 4 months after the previous photo was taken. He contracted mange after being exposed to rodenticide.</p></div>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<p>From his blood sample, they were able to tell that he had been exposed to rat poison, a potentially deadly anti-coagulant.  If these poisons don&#8217;t kill a puma directly, but they can weaken their immune systems and cause secondary problems that may prove fatal.  In P-22&#8242;s case, rat poison had compromised his immune system and had a severe case of mange.  He was lucky this time, he was treated and released, but many other animals are not as fortunate.</p>
<p>P-22 is by no means the first animal biologists have found with health problems associated with exposure to rodenticides; biologists have been <a href="http://www.urbancarnivores.com/poisons/">studying this problem</a> in bobcats and coyotes in Southern California.  We may have seen this in <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/tag/rodenticide/">our study area as well</a>.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Toxic compounds, like rat poisons, may not kill their intended rodent target right away.  Rodents may ingest a small amount of rat poison, and then get eaten by a puma, bobcat, raptor, or other carnivore.  Once these carnivores have eaten a few rodenticide-exposed rodents, the carnivores may accumulate a dose large enough to have toxic effects.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;">Luckily, starting July 1st, the state will put new restrictions in effect to limit the availability of rodenticides.  However, that doesn&#8217;t mean that the rat poisons you can still buy are safe.  <a href="http://saferodentcontrol.org/site/rodent-control/">Here</a> are some tools to help control rodents in your home that will be safer for your family, pets, and wildlife.</p>
<p style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Rodenticide-Infographic.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-1468" alt="Rodenticide-Infographic" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Rodenticide-Infographic.jpg" width="600" height="595" /></a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/06/10/hollywood-puma-and-rat-poison/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/06/10/hollywood-puma-and-rat-poison/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cwilmers</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[A detailed look at 46m&#8217;s journey from Big Basin to Mountain View #MVpuma]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/08/a-detailed-look-at-46m-s-journey-from-big-basin-to-mountain-view-mvpuma/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1438</id>
		<updated>2014-05-10T15:34:12Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-08T19:04:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="field notes" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="pumas in the news" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="46m" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="dispersal" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="MVpuma" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[By now many of your have read about 46m&#8217;s big adventure into downtown Mountain View.   Here we take a closer look at how he got there based on data we retrieved from his collar after we anesthetized him in a parking lot in Mountain View.  We originally collared 46m in January just south of [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/08/a-detailed-look-at-46m-s-journey-from-big-basin-to-mountain-view-mvpuma/"><![CDATA[<p>By now many of your have read about 46m&#8217;s <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/07/46ms-big-adventure-in-mountain-view/" target="_blank">big adventure into downtown Mountain View</a>.   Here we take a closer look at how he got there based on data we retrieved from his collar after we anesthetized him in a parking lot in Mountain View.  We originally collared <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/01/17/learn-from-your-siblings/" target="_blank">46m</a> in January just south of Big Basin State Park.  You can see from the image below that for the first few months that we had a tag on him, he stayed in his <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/02/41m-and-46m-have-a-mom-after-all/" target="_blank">mother&#8217;s </a>territory.  Then, like all young males, he dispersed from his mom&#8217;s territory to seek out one of his own.  In other studies, young males have been known to travel up to hundreds of miles before settling down in a place to call home.  Part of our research is trying to understand what kind of obstacles and barriers these animals face as they disperse.  In this case 46m wandered north for roughly 2 weeks across the Santa Cruz Mountains into downtown Mountain View.  Note that each yellow point here represents one of 46m&#8217;s locations derived from a GPS unit on his collar.  Points are anywhere from 5 minutes to 4 hours apart in time.  We connect the points with a yellow line, but that doesn&#8217;t necessarily mean he traveled along that line between points.</p>
<p><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-10.42.54-AM.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1439" alt="Screen Shot 2014-05-08 at 10.42.54 AM" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-10.42.54-AM.png" width="604" height="683" /></a></p>
<p>If we zoom in on the northern part of his track, we can see where he left the wild and entered a sea of urban development below.  He crossed highway 280 and enterd the Los Altos hills, where he wanderd around and then hunkered down for the day.  The next night he started moving around again and found his way into downtown Mountain View nearly 4 miles from the wildlands he came from.  That&#8217;s two nights and parts of three days so far that he was wandering around this highly developed area, and no one had seen him yet.  He&#8217;s looking for a territory with potential mates, but clearly this was not it.  My best guess at this point, is that he was looking for a way out, but he was so deep into the urban area, that he was not sure where to go to get back to open space.  In the meantime he evaded detection by moving at night, and hiding in whatever places he can find &#8212; in a bush, under a parked car, up in a tree etc.</p>
<p><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-11.00.12-AM.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1445" alt="Screen Shot 2014-05-08 at 11.00.12 AM" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-11.00.12-AM.png" width="604" height="639" /></a></p>
<p>Finally at dawn after his second night, he settled down around 5:45 am and spent the next 9 hours hiding behind a bush in front of an apartment complex on a busy street.</p>
<p><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-11.16.26-AM.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1443" alt="Screen Shot 2014-05-08 at 11.16.26 AM" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-11.16.26-AM.png" width="604" height="683" /></a></p>
<p>Here is what that bush looks like.  Amazingly, despite being walked and driven past by hundreds of people, nobody saw him.  Nobody noticed him, and perhaps people will find it reassuring that he didn&#8217;t bother anyone either.</p>
<p><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-11.27.31-AM.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1447" alt="Screen Shot 2014-05-08 at 11.27.31 AM" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-11.27.31-AM.png" width="604" height="416" /></a></p>
<p>At around 3pm he decided he didn&#8217;t like that spot any more, and he decided to try and find a better place to hang out, as you can see his movement path in the figure above.  Around 7pm we got our first calls from the Mountain View police about a possible collared puma wandering around their town, and we read on the Twitter feeds about a helicopter circling overhead to try to locate him.  Fortunately, the police surrounded him in a safe spot in a parking garage, and we were able to safely assist Cal Fish and Wildlife with anesthetizing him and getting him back to open space!</p>
<p>We&#8217;ll keep you up to date on 46m&#8217;s future movements and let you know how he is doing.</p>
<p><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-11.55.37-AM.png"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-1450" alt="Screen Shot 2014-05-08 at 11.55.37 AM" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-08-at-11.55.37-AM.png" width="604" height="427" /></a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/08/a-detailed-look-at-46m-s-journey-from-big-basin-to-mountain-view-mvpuma/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/08/a-detailed-look-at-46m-s-journey-from-big-basin-to-mountain-view-mvpuma/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Veronica</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[#46M &#8216;s (aka #MVpuma) big adventure in Mountain View!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/07/46ms-big-adventure-in-mountain-view/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1426</id>
		<updated>2014-05-09T21:56:51Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-07T18:23:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="field notes" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="puma bios" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="pumas in the news" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="santa cruz pumas" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In October, we introduced you to 41M and his brother, 46M, who taunted him through the bars when 41M was in our trap.  Then in January, 46M wandered into a trap we set for him and we gave him a collar to match his brother&#8217;s.  We didn&#8217;t see any sign of their mom until February, [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/07/46ms-big-adventure-in-mountain-view/"><![CDATA[<p>In October, we introduced you to <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2013/10/09/welcome-41m-goodbye-27m/">41M</a> and his brother, 46M, who taunted him through the bars when 41M was in our trap.  Then in January, <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/01/17/learn-from-your-siblings/">46M</a> wandered into a trap we set for him and we gave him a collar to match his brother&#8217;s.  We didn&#8217;t see any sign of their mom until February, when we <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/02/41m-and-46m-have-a-mom-after-all/">caught her on video</a>, feeding on a deer she had killed.  Up until now, it looked like 41M and 46M have had a pretty typical life with their mom.  That all changed last night!</p>
<div id="attachment_1433" style="width: 1034px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/46m-in-tree-january-2014.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-1433" alt="46M in a tree when he was captured in January." src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/46m-in-tree-january-2014-1024x768.jpg" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">46M in a tree when he was captured in January.</p></div>
<p>To back up for a minute, imagine you are a young male puma:  You spend your first couple years with your family, learning what you need to know to be a grown up.  Sometime between the ages of 18 to 24 months old, you have to leave the protection of your  mom and look for territory and mates of your own.  Ideally you&#8217;ll want to find a large amount of space (approximately a 100 square miles) with abundant food and a few female pumas to mate with.  But, before you can get there, you have to contend with roads, cars, people, development, unknown country, finding food, and resident male pumas ready to kill you to defend their territory.</p>
<p>41M and 46M have hit the age where it&#8217;s time for them to disperse, leaving their home and family, and set out exploring unfamiliar land.  It looks like 46M left the area in which he grew up, east of Boulder Creek, in search or a territory and mate of his own.  Unfortunately, instead of finding his way into a nice patch of unoccupied woods, his wanderings took him into Mountain View!</p>
<div id="attachment_1429" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/46M-under-a-car.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1429" alt="46M under a car" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/46M-under-a-car-300x225.jpg" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">46M under a car in Mountain View before he was tranquilized and released back in the mountains.</p></div>
<p>Imagine his surprise &#8211; thinking he could probably push through dispersed human development to get to more forest that was surely on the other side, only to find himself surrounded by cars, buildings, dogs, and people.  He did manage to get himself to a spot &#8211; a parking garage &#8211; where the authorities could feel comfortable capturing him.</p>
<p>Many people from CA Fish and Wildlife and the Mountain View Police Department worked late into the night with the Puma Project to safely dart and take 46M back to the mountains where he belongs.  We are grateful and encouraged to be involved with such a successful collaborative effort to help give 46M a happy ending to what must have been a harrowing adventure!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/07/46ms-big-adventure-in-mountain-view/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/07/46ms-big-adventure-in-mountain-view/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Veronica</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Meet 48M]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/06/meet-48m/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1419</id>
		<updated>2014-05-07T06:00:13Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-07T06:00:13Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="field notes" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="puma bios" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="santa cruz pumas" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Last night we caught a new uncollared male, 48M.  We were expecting to catch a juvenile that we had seen on the camera traps earlier, but caught a 112 pound adult male instead!  He was a very polite cat &#8212; he went into the trap around 9pm last night, much earlier than many of our [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/06/meet-48m/"><![CDATA[<p>Last night we caught a new uncollared male, 48M.  We were expecting to catch a juvenile that we had seen on the camera traps earlier, but caught a 112 pound adult male instead!  He was a very polite cat &#8212; he went into the trap around 9pm last night, much earlier than many of our captures.</p>
<div id="attachment_1422" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/48m.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1422" alt="48m" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/48m-300x175.jpg" width="300" height="175" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">48M is presumably the resident male living in Loch Lomond. We&#8217;ll know more about where he lives and what he&#8217;s up to after we download his first round of data!</p></div>
<p style="text-align: left;">The pumas are often very calm when they&#8217;re in the trap. Sometimes they sit down to munch the bait, like we saw with <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/01/17/learn-from-your-siblings/">46M</a>, and don&#8217;t seem concerned about being in the trap until we approach them.  We try not to spend much time at the cage before the cat is sedated, and only approach the trap for long enough to assess the size of the animal.  The size of the animal determines how much drug we give them.  We were so convinced that it was going to be a small cat, that we only got a small amount of drugs.  When we approach the cage with the pole syringe in hand, we quickly realized that we were going to need more than we had loaded up. It was a smooth capture and we&#8217;re excited to see where 48M goes next!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/06/meet-48m/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/06/meet-48m/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Justine Smith</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[An Easter Kitten!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/01/an-easter-kitten/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1406</id>
		<updated>2014-05-01T18:38:00Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-01T18:37:32Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In mid- April, we noticed from 43F’s GPS data that she appeared to be denning. On April 20, when we suspected that the kittens were 4 weeks old, we hiked into the den. We had retrieved an updated location from the den the day before, and felt confident that we knew where to find it. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/01/an-easter-kitten/"><![CDATA[<p>In mid- April, we noticed from 43F’s GPS data that she appeared to be denning. On April 20, when we suspected that the kittens were 4 weeks old, we hiked into the den. We had retrieved an updated location from the den the day before, and felt confident that we knew where to find it.</p>
<p>Upon arriving at the den site, we immediately noticed signs of puma presence. We located what looked very much like a den, but there were no kittens to be found. After an exhaustive search of the area, we concluded that 43F might have moved her litter, and decided to head back.</p>
<p>Unwilling to accept defeat, Paul took a different path down the ravine, looking and listening for more sign. A slight rustling sound in the bushes caught his attention and he went to investigate. There she was, one kitten at a new den site that was just established since we had checked the day before.</p>
<div id="attachment_1407" style="width: 287px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1407 " style="line-height: 1.5em;" title="47F, kitten of 43F" alt="47F" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/47F-277x300.jpg" width="277" height="300" /><p class="wp-caption-text">47F, kitten of 43F</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>We gave 47F a small, expandable kitten collar and an ear tag. Because the kitten collars are built to eventually fall off, the ear tag allows us to identify the kitten even after it is already an adult.  After taking a few measurements, we returned 47F to her den. Because 43F lives in a very remote location (between Castle Rock and Big Basin State Parks), following her kitten will be an interesting contrast to our other females that have had litters in much more fragmented areas.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/01/an-easter-kitten/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/05/01/an-easter-kitten/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>paulh</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[How to tell if a lion or coyote killed a deer]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/03/22/lion-kills-vs-coyote-kills/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1393</id>
		<updated>2014-05-07T17:48:22Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-22T21:22:15Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="field notes" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="santa cruz pumas" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="Uncategorized" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="coyote" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="kill" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="mountain lion" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="public" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="puma" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We frequently receive calls and messages from local landowners telling us about a fresh-dead deer in their yard.  This is fascinating information and helpful to our research &#8211; we’ve trapped and collared several mountain lions in this way.  In many cases, the deer was killed by a lion.  In many other cases, the deer was [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/03/22/lion-kills-vs-coyote-kills/"><![CDATA[<p>We frequently receive calls and messages from local landowners telling us about a fresh-dead deer in their yard.  This is fascinating information and helpful to our research &#8211; we’ve trapped and collared several mountain lions in this way.  In many cases, the deer was killed by a lion.  In many other cases, the deer was killed by coyotes.  What are some ways to tell the difference?</p>
<p><strong>Mountain lion kill is typically…<br />
</strong><br />
…under cover (brush, shrubs, trees).  Lions tend to not leave their food out under open sky.  An exception may be if the deer was killed in a fence enclosure, and then the lion is likely to have dried dragging it past the fence.</p>
<div id="attachment_1394" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/IMG_1742.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1394" alt="Note how the forest debris has been raked into a pile. Cats do this." src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/IMG_1742-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Note how the forest debris has been raked into a pile. Cats do this.</p></div>
<p>…covered with leaves, sticks, grass.  There will be an area around the deer where the raking of the lion’s paws left bare dirt.</p>
<p>…eaten starting at the ribs.  Lions tend to eat the chest-area organs first (lungs, heart, liver).  They chew a hole in the ribs to get to these tasty and most-nutritious morsels.</p>
<p>…missing the stomach.  Lions remove the stomach (called the rumen) when they first open the check cavity and bury is a few feet away from the body.  This prevents stomach acids from spoiling the meat over the 3-5 days it will take the lion to finish eating the entire deer.</p>
<p>…”shaved”!  Yes, you read that right.  Lions will nip the hair off of the body of a deer before they start chewing into it.  Think of a surgeon shaving the patient before cutting.  The clumps of nipped hair are about 1” across – the distance between the lion’s canine teeth.  They snip the hair with their incisors.</p>
<p>…neat and tidy.  The deer is usually in one piece (rather than scattered about – a leg here, a leg there…).</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong>Coyote kill is typically…</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1395" style="width: 210px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/IMG_1478.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-1395" alt="Note how the hindquarters are the first part to be fed on, and there's no attempt to drag the deer out; it's lying in the open." src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/IMG_1478-200x300.jpg" width="200" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Note how the hindquarters are the first part to be fed on, and there&#8217;s no attempt to drag the deer; it&#8217;s in the open.</p></div>
<p>…in the open.  We seem to find several deer killed by coyotes along fencelines, as if coyotes trap the deer against the fence or run the deer into the fence and kill it by injury.</p>
<p>…uncovered.  Coyotes don’t cache their leftover food.  That’s a cat behavior.</p>
<p>&#8230;eaten starting at the hind end.</p>
<p>…messy.  Picture a group of dogs playing tug-o-war and that’s largely what you’ll find.  A piece here, a leg there.  Stomach contents spilled and guts dragged around.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Another good clue is whether coyotes are regularly seen or heard in the neighborhood.  Not everyone has coyotes in their neighborhood.  Coyotes tend to be found in certain areas in the Santa Cruz Mountains such as rural residential areas and coastal grassland prairies.  It’s likely because their preferred foods are in those places more than in the deep redwoods and oak forests that make up most of these mountains.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>If you find a deer that has been recently killed and you’re willing to allow us to use it to trap a mountain lion for our research, please contact us ASAP.  If possible, we’ll come and investigate.  If you’re unsure whether the deer was killed by a lion or coyote, please &#8211; still contact us and we’ll come take a look.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/03/22/lion-kills-vs-coyote-kills/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/03/22/lion-kills-vs-coyote-kills/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Veronica</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Chris&#8217;s Talk at the Rio]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/03/14/chriss-talk-at-the-rio/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1381</id>
		<updated>2014-03-19T03:27:17Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-15T02:02:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="events and outreach" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="media" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="pumas in the news" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For those of you who missed Chris&#8217;s sellout talk at the Rio, here is a great writeup about it in the Sentinel.  Chris gave an exciting talk about our work so far with over 600 people filling the auditorium!  We&#8217;d like to thank the Land Trust of Santa Cruz County for hosting him and making [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/03/14/chriss-talk-at-the-rio/"><![CDATA[<p>For those of you who missed Chris&#8217;s <strong>sellout</strong> talk at the Rio, here is a great writeup about it in the <a href="http://www.santacruzsentinel.com/santacruz/ci_25340620/puma-pursuit-leader-santa-cruz-puma-project-sheds">Sentinel</a>.  Chris gave an exciting talk about our work so far with over 600 people filling the auditorium!  We&#8217;d like to thank the Land Trust of Santa Cruz County for hosting him and making the talk possible.</p>
<p>If you missed that talk, join Chris at Bridging the Gap night, March 19th at 7:00 pm.  For more information on this upcoming talk, check out the event <a href="http://www.eventsantacruz.com/next-event/">website</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_1386" style="width: 624px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/chris1f.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1386 " alt="Chris discussing our first puma (photo by Mike Bolte)." src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/chris1f.jpg" width="614" height="356" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Chris discussing our first puma (photo by Mike Bolte).</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1385" style="width: 624px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/chrisaudience.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-1385 " alt="Chris engaging with the audience" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/chrisaudience.jpg" width="614" height="345" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Chris engaging with the audience (photo by Mike Bolte)</p></div>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/03/14/chriss-talk-at-the-rio/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/03/14/chriss-talk-at-the-rio/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Veronica</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Why did the puma cross the road?&#8230;]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/09/why-did-the-puma-cross-the-road/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1368</id>
		<updated>2014-02-13T05:28:04Z</updated>
		<published>2014-02-09T19:43:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="puma ecology" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="pumas in the news" /><category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="santa cruz pumas" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[&#8230;Well, maybe why isn&#8217;t as important as how.  Thanks to the Land Trust of Santa Cruz County, the pumas of the Santa Cruz Mountains are on their way to having a safe way to cross Highway 17!  Read more about it in their press release! We&#8217;ve talked before about how habitat connectivity is a very [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/09/why-did-the-puma-cross-the-road/"><![CDATA[<p>&#8230;Well, maybe why isn&#8217;t as important as how.  Thanks to the Land Trust of Santa Cruz County, the pumas of the Santa Cruz Mountains are on their way to having a safe way to cross Highway 17!  Read more about it in their <a href="http://www.landtrustsantacruz.org/press/140131_PR_Laurel_Curve.pdf">press release! </a></p>
<p>We&#8217;ve talked before about how <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2012/08/10/habitat-fragmentation-and-inbreeding/">habitat connectivity </a>is a very important part of puma biology.   Pumas need to be able to around the landscape to find prey, mates, places to have their young, and safe places to be wild animals.  As we increase development, we decrease the amount of habitat available to them, and we often isolate remaining habitat patches.  Large, busy roads, like Highway 17, create barriers that are <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2013/10/31/crossing-highways/">dangerous</a> for pumas to <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2012/08/25/16ms-fifteen-minutes-of-fame/">cross</a>.</p>
<p>Crossing structures, such as <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2013/08/19/crossing-highway-17/">culverts</a> and wildlife overpasses, reconnect <a href="http://www.scpr.org/blogs/environment/2014/02/11/15819/three-mountain-lion-kittens-killed-in-traffic/">fragmented habitat patches</a>.  The Land Trust of Santa Cruz County used some of our data to locate land to purchase near Laurel Curve, a particularly dangerous stretch of road, with the hopes of restoring connectivity across the highway.  This is a very exciting new project that could help keep pumas from suffering the same fate as <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2012/07/03/survivor/">16M</a>, <a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2013/05/16/the-downtown-puma-39m/">39M,</a> 18F, and many others.  With any luck, creating a safe way to cross Highway 17 will serve the dual purpose of keeping pumas safe from cars, and people safe from collisions with wildlife!</p>
<div id="attachment_293" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/16m-scar.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-293" alt="16M's battle scar" src="http://santacruzpumas.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/16m-scar-300x172.jpg" width="300" height="172" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">16M with a large injury after getting hit by a car on Highway 17.  He survived this encounter, but he was one of the lucky ones.</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/09/why-did-the-puma-cross-the-road/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/09/why-did-the-puma-cross-the-road/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Justine Smith</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[41M and 46M have a mom after all!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/02/41m-and-46m-have-a-mom-after-all/" />
		<id>http://santacruzpumas.org/?p=1364</id>
		<updated>2014-02-02T20:44:20Z</updated>
		<published>2014-02-02T20:44:20Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://santacruzpumas.org" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Since October 2013, when we caught 41M while 46M looked on, we have repeatedly seen the brothers together. However, until just now, there has been no sign of a mom. We wondered if they had perhaps been orphaned, but their mom finally appeared on a fresh deer kill when our team was out tracking 41M a [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/02/41m-and-46m-have-a-mom-after-all/"><![CDATA[<p>Since October 2013, when we caught 41M while 46M looked on, we have repeatedly seen the brothers together. However, until just now, there has been no sign of a mom. We wondered if they had perhaps been orphaned, but their mom finally appeared on a fresh deer kill when our team was out tracking 41M a few days ago. In the video below, you can see the mom jumping back and forth across the stream next to her kill. Eventually 41M joined her to feed as well.</p>
<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/7dJdiAsk0RU" height="315" width="560" allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>Having both 41M and 46M collared before they disperse away from their mom&#8217;s territory will allow us to get really valuable information on how pumas establish new territories in the Santa Cruz Mountains. We hope to learn about how dispersing animals interact with human disturbance and if they ever attempt to disperse out of the Santa Cruz Mountains east across the 101 or south toward Monterrey and Big Sur.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/02/41m-and-46m-have-a-mom-after-all/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://santacruzpumas.org/2014/02/02/41m-and-46m-have-a-mom-after-all/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
