<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:/news</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news.atom"/>
  <title>Global Development // Global Development</title>
  <updated>2014-07-09T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/49243</id>
    <published>2014-07-09T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-10T09:24:49-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/49243-notre-dames-initiative-for-global-development-takes-first-steps-toward-building-a-primary-school-in-uganda/"/>
    <title>NDIGD takes first steps toward building a primary school in Uganda</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;div&gt;A group of students and faculty from the University of Notre Dame completed research in a poor, underserved area of Uganda as a first step toward building a primary school there. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;Notre Dame’s Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD) is working with the not-for-profit organization &lt;a href="http://www.buildingtomorrow.org/zeta/" target="_blank"&gt;Building Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt; to help make this new school a reality in the village of Kongota—one of the poorest communities in the Rakai District of Uganda.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/LuYs9YfnrkM" width="560"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Through surveys of local households and interviews with key stakeholders, the Notre Dame students―in partnership with students from &lt;a href="http://www.umu.ac.ug/" target="_blank"&gt;Uganda Martyrs University&lt;/a&gt;―conducted a survey of schooling models for community development. The students visited several existing schools in Uganda, collecting background information from community leaders, teachers, and parents on school programming, design, and community participation to better determine what variables best predict school success and sustainability.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;The team also helped Building Tomorrow digitize their school needs assessments through the use of iPod touches and survey software training, which can be used to collect data based on Building Tomorrow’s approach to &lt;a href="http://www.buildingtomorrow.org/zeta/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/BT-Access-Learning.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Access &amp;amp; Learning&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research team included Notre Dame political scientist and &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/index.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="font-family: arial, sans-serif; font-size: 13px;"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development Studies and Solidarity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Fellow &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/bleck.shtml" target="_blank"&gt;Jaimie Bleck&lt;/a&gt;, Notre Dame students Liana Cramer, Megan Reineccius, and Meghan Gallagher, and Uganda Martyrs University students Fiona Zawedde and Prosper Niwagaba. The student team’s blog, &lt;a href="http://ittakesavillagend.wordpress.com/2014/05/30/the-power-of-maama/"&gt;the power of maama&lt;/a&gt;, highlights some of the experiences they encountered while conducting the study in Uganda. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Their completed study will help determine which factors promote the success, sustainability, and sense of community ownership for the new University of Notre Dame partner school that will be built in Kongota. &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="img_0088" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/136288/img_0088.jpg" title="img_0088"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;“We are excited to provide Building Tomorrow research that can help them in their mission to improve educational opportunities for children in Uganda," said Professor Bleck. "Our students at Notre Dame and Uganda Marty’s University have been fully committed to this project and look forward to continued interactions with the new Notre Dame School that will be built in Kongota.”&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Children currently living in Kongota must depend on neighboring schools that are located miles from their homes. This inefficiency has affected the children’s education, with some of them dropping out of school because of the long distance they have to walk.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Building Tomorrow has worked closely with the Ugandan government for several years to improve the level of educational services in poor, rural communities such as Kongota. Historically, community members provide unskilled labor and other assistance to the various building sites, while the Ugandan government buys textbooks and furniture and provides ongoing maintenance support for the schools.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Michael Sweikar, NDIGD managing director, said “We’d like to thank Tim and Diane Madden for providing a generous gift to the University of Notre Dame through their family foundation. Their support has enabled Notre Dame students to complete this research project prior to building the new school in Kongota.”&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;NDIGD, based in &lt;a href="http://research.nd.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;Notre Dame’s Office of Research&lt;/a&gt;, is a multidisciplinary enterprise on the Notre Dame campus. It leverages the University’s signature strengths to help develop solution-oriented research focused on rigorous, data-driven impact evaluation and assessment; the design and planning of development projects; and training.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Click &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LuYs9YfnrkM" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to view a video about the Building Tomorrow project.&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/48923</id>
    <published>2014-06-18T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-18T11:18:46-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/48923-ford-program-helps-train-young-african-leaders/"/>
    <title>Ford Program Helps Train Young African Leaders</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="p1"&gt;This week, 25 students from across Africa begin six weeks of training in business and entrepreneurship on the Notre Dame campus as part of the &lt;a href="http://youngafricanleaders.state.gov/washington-fellows/"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Washington Fellowship&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the flagship program of President Obama’s &lt;a href="http://youngafricanleaders.state.gov"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Young African Leaders Initiative&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;T&lt;/span&gt;he University of Notre Dame was selected as one of the Washington Fellowship’s host institutions after partnering with the &lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com/us/en/"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;IBM Corporation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt; to&lt;/span&gt; expand a 2012 Notre Dame &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/news/LEAD.shtml"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;pilot program&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to provide training to young African leaders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="leaders" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/135255/leaders.jpg" title="leaders"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;This summer, IBM experts and Notre Dame faculty and staff have designed courses specifically for these aspiring young entrepreneurs, who hope to assume leadership roles or start their own business ventures in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The training program will be led by faculty and staff from the Mendoza College of Business &lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/npd/nonprofit_executive_programs/"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Nonprofit Executive Education Program&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, supported by the &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD), the Kellogg Institute’s &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/index.shtml"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development and Solidarity&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and the University’s Engineering, Science, Technology and Entrepreneurship Master’s (&lt;a href="http://esteem.nd.edu/"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;ESTEEM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;) program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;Ford Program Director &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/dowd.shtml"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Rev. Robert Dowd, CSC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a political scientist and Africa expert, is teaming up with two other members of the Kellogg community with experience in Africa—Kellogg Guest Scholar Peter John Opio, the academic director of the summer institute, and Ford Program Associate Director Dennis Haraszko—to coteach an integration seminar that will help the students strategize about how to take their new knowledge back to their home countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p3"&gt;“We're thrilled to partner with the next generation of business, community, and political leaders and help furnish them with the skills, tools and perspective they need make a positive difference within their communities back home,” says Dowd.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Notre Dame has received $100,000 from the US Department of State to facilitate the program. The IBM Corporation and the &lt;a href="http://www.coca-colacompany.com/our-company/community-requests-guidelines-application"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;Coca-Cola Foundation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; have committed additional funding and training support. In addition, IBM will provide follow-up internship opportunities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;In 2012, the University hosted six young African leaders for a seven-week training program led by Fr. Dowd and facilitated by Mendoza College of Business faculty and IBM representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The “&lt;span class="s2"&gt;Leadership for Excellence and Africa’s Development” (LEAD)&lt;/span&gt; student participants were integrated into the Notre Dame MBA curriculum, while also participating in seminars designed for them by the Ford and ESTEEM programs. IBM representatives taught once per week, and the students attended a weeklong seminar at IBM before returning to East Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The 2014 Washington Fellowship program will provide 500 African fellows with a US experience that includes a six-week academic institute at 20 host institutions around the country and a three-day summit in Washington, DC. Up to 100 participants will receive an eight-week follow-on internship with an American NGO or business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;The summer training is only the beginning of a long-term investment in these young leaders. Upon their return to Africa, the United States will provide opportunities for networking, ongoing professional development, seed funding for entrepreneurs, and community service. Fellows will have access to enrichment seminars, local and regional networking events, and an innovative on-line platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="p1"&gt;Contact: Joya Helmuth, Outreach Associate, Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development, &lt;a href="mailto:jhelmuth@nd.edu"&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;jhelmuth@nd.edu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joya Helmuth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/48830</id>
    <published>2014-06-12T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-12T13:18:29-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/48830-ndigd-and-nd-gain-awarded-project-from-3ie-to-design-impact-evaluation-in-mozambique/"/>
    <title>NDIGD and ND-GAIN awarded project from 3ie to design impact evaluation in Mozambique</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;The Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development (NDIGD) and the Notre Dame Global Adaptation Index (ND-GAIN) will work with faculty and staff from the &lt;a href="http://www.ucm.ac.mz/cms/en-en"&gt;Universidade Católica de Moçambique&lt;/a&gt; (UCM) to assess the impacts of early-warning systems for climate-related disasters in the country of Mozambique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozambique is densely populated and located in low-lying coastal and river zones, making it extremely susceptible to natural disasters and climate change including cyclones, storms, and floods. The creation of Community-based Disaster Management Committees (CLGRCs) and decentralized early-warning systems are being created to cope with climate risks. Notre Dame will help to evaluate the success of programs established by aid from the German government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funded by the &lt;a href="http://www.3ieimpact.org/en/about/"&gt;International Initiative for Impact Evaluation&lt;/a&gt; (3ie), the research consortium composed of NDIGD, ND-GAIN, and UCM experts will design a study to evaluate the impacts of CLGRCs and early-warning systems to show what and how interventions lead to increased climate resilience, and explore the degree of relevance and effectiveness of interventions across multiple sectors of the human and natural environment. The main focal zones of the project are Maputo, and the Beira and Búzi districts.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Notre Dame Vice President of Research Dr. Robert Bernhard says, “NDIGD and ND-GAIN look forward to developing this new partnership with 3ie. This project extends Notre Dame’s faculty expertise to measure the impact of disaster risk management and climate change adaptation, implemented by &lt;a href="http://www.giz.de/en/"&gt;Gesellschaft für Internationale Zusammenarbeit&lt;/a&gt; (GIZ) to enhance local resilience by building up early warning systems.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="jessica_hellmann_3" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/134984/jessica_hellmann_3.jpg" title="jessica_hellmann_3"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading the research team from the University of Notre Dame is &lt;a href="http://gain.org/our-team/dr-jessica-hellmann"&gt;Dr. Jessica Hellmann&lt;/a&gt;, Research Director of ND-GAIN and Associate Professor in the Department of Biological Sciences. NDIGD and ND-GAIN researchers collaborating on the project include &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/juan-carlos-guzman-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Dr. Juan Carlos Guzman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/lila-khatiwada-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Dr. Lila Khatiwada&lt;/a&gt;, Monitoring and Evaluation Specialists with NDIGD, and Dr. Chen Chen, research fellow from ND-GAIN.  UCM will provide support through lead researcher, Dr. Dennis Eucker, Research Coordinator and Senior Lecturer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hellmann says, “We are excited to be part of helping communities adapt to climate change, something that is desperately needed around the world as sea level rises and storms, drought and heat waves become more intense.” Scientists, including a recent report from the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, explain that large-scale adaptation to climate change will be necessary in the coming decades. “But we do not yet know how to evaluate the effectiveness of adaptation actions. Our project will be among the first to develop adaptation assessment so that efforts to make Mozambique more resilient can be replicated around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/a&gt; provides expertise in monitoring and evaluation through teaching and research faculty of the University and a dedicated staff of experienced researchers and administrators, integrated across multiple disciplines.  &lt;a href="http://gain.org/"&gt;ND-GAIN&lt;/a&gt;’s mission is to enhance the world’s understanding of the importance of adaptation and facilitate public and private investments in vulnerable communities. ND-GAIN prepares the world’s leading Index showing which countries are best prepared to deal with global changes brought about by overcrowding, resource-constraints and climate disruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3ie’s vision is to improve lives through impact evaluation, by increasing development effectiveness in developing countries. 3ie’s strategy is to generate new evidence of what works, synthesize and disseminate this evidence, build a culture of evidence-based policy-making, and develop capacity to produce and use impact evaluations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact: Joya Helmuth, NDIGD Outreach Associate, jhelmuth@nd.edu&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joya Helmuth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/48393</id>
    <published>2014-05-16T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-16T10:22:05-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/48393-kellogg-researchers-win-usaid-grants-to-investigate-democracy-human-rights-and-governance-in-africa/"/>
    <title>Kellogg researchers win USAID grants to investigate democracy, human rights and governance in Africa</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;When USAID announced winners of a new, nationwide competition for innovative projects in the field of democracy, human rights and governance last week, scholars associated with the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt; had won two of the coveted nine awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame political scientist &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/bleck.shtml"&gt;Jaimie Bleck&lt;/a&gt; and economist Philippe LeMay-Boucher of Scotland&amp;rsquo;s Heriot-Watt University received a $90,000 grant to &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/48370-political-scientist-jaimie-bleck-wins-acls-usai/"&gt;examine the role of Malian discussion groups known as grinw&lt;/a&gt; in rebuilding civil society and democracy in Mali, where a recent coup and insurgency has torn apart a state known for inter-ethnic tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="jaimie_bleck_300" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/133151/jaimie_bleck_300.jpg" style="height: 250px; width: 200px;" title="jaimie_bleck_300" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are interested in the role these indigenous informal institutions play in Mali&amp;rsquo;s post-conflict reconstruction &amp;mdash; and in particular if they are able to help rebuild trust between ethnic groups and faith in democracy,&amp;rdquo; said Bleck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame political scientist &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/dowd.shtml"&gt;Rev. Robert Dowd, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, and University of Virginia economist Molly Lipscomb received a $75,000 grant to study the link between public health, good governance and democratic politics in East Africa. They are building on a project already underway in western Uganda to examine whether citizens view local leaders who promote public-health initiatives as more popular and effective than other leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is in the best interest of politicians is not always in the best interest of the public in the developing world,&amp;rdquo; said Dowd. &amp;ldquo;We want to see how good public service delivery can also be good politics at the local level.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both projects, combining regional expertise in Africa with cutting-edge methodology, stem from interdisciplinary research collaborations developed at the Kellogg Institute, where Bleck and Dowd are faculty fellows and Dowd directs the &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/index.shtml"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development Studies and Solidarity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bleck, the Ford Family Assistant Professor of Political Science, and LeMay-Boucher found immediate common interest in West Africa when he arrived at the institute last fall on a &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/vfellowships/index.shtml"&gt;Kellogg Visiting Fellowship&lt;/a&gt;. Lipscomb and Dowd&amp;rsquo;s collaboration dates to her time as a Kellogg faculty fellow, before moving to the University of Virginia in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The projects benefited from initial Kellogg grants that the researchers leveraged for additional funding. In the case of Bleck and LeMay-Boucher, the Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development (&lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/a&gt;) provided expert assistance as the pair developed their USAID proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="father_bob_dowd_300" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/133150/father_bob_dowd_300.jpg" style="height: 280px; width: 200px;" title="father_bob_dowd_300" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;NDIGD has been working closely with faculty across the University to grow partnerships with USAID,&amp;quot; said NDIGD managing director Michael Sweikar. &amp;quot;It is a tremendous accomplishment for our faculty to be involved in two out of the nine grants awarded by the USAID DRG Center.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selected from a pool of 103 proposals, the USAID grants are issued through the &lt;a href="http://www.iie.org/Programs/USAID-Democracy-Fellows-and-Grants-Program"&gt;Democracy Fellows and Grants Program&lt;/a&gt; implemented by the Institute of International Education. The research findings will inform the field programs of USAID&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://www.usaid.gov/what-we-do/democracy-human-rights-and-governance"&gt;Center of Excellence on Democracy, Human Rights and Governance&lt;/a&gt; (DRG Center), which is integrating human rights, accountability and civil society issues throughout its core development work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new grants were made possible with support from the American people and by funding from the DRG Center and the Bureau for Africa&amp;rsquo;s Office of Sustainable Development.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joya Helmuth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/48321</id>
    <published>2014-05-14T09:25:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-14T09:46:15-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/48321-ndigd-and-the-kellogg-institute-for-international-studies-partner-with-avsi-to-study-impact-of-educational-services-in-uganda/"/>
    <title>NDIGD and the Kellogg Institute partner with AVSI to study impact of educational services in Uganda</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD) and the &lt;a href="https://kellogg.nd.edu"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt; have received a $15,000 grant from AVSI-USA to provide technical expertise related to the monitoring and evaluation of educational services offered by the Permanent Centre for Education (PCE) in East Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the provision of training, PCE helps teachers, head teachers, and parents better understand their educational role and how they interact with children. The training workshops draw on a long tradition of Catholic social thought as applied to education and use as their starting point the intrinsic value of each and every human being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="uganda_article" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/132968/uganda_article.jpg" title="uganda_article" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NDIGD Monitoring and Evaluation Specialist &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/juan-carlos-guzman-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Juan Carlos Guzman&lt;/a&gt; is working with AVSI-USA and PCE local staff providing statistical and technical support for a randomized control trial, data analysis, and report writing. Kellogg Institute Director &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/about/paolo_carozza.shtml"&gt;Paolo Carozza&lt;/a&gt; serves as faculty advisor to the project. The objective of the PCE evaluation is to understand how effective the PCE standard teacher training workshops are at influencing key teacher behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Good intentions alone are not enough for us to know whether development projects are in fact making a positive difference in people&amp;#39;s lives,&amp;rdquo; says Carozza. &amp;ldquo;A rigorous evaluation helps to ensure that projects are supported by solid evidence of their efficacy. Notre Dame is helping AVSI and PCE to assess the real value and effect of their interventions in education in Uganda.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://avsi-usa.org"&gt;Association of Volunteers in International Service&lt;/a&gt; (AVSI) is an international nongovernmental organization founded in Italy in 1972 that supports human development in developing countries with special attention to education and the promotion of the dignity of every human person, according to Catholic social teaching. AVSI plans and implements sustainable medium and long-term projects and emergency relief operations in partnership with local associations, institutions, governments, and international agencies. The global AVSI Network links together over 60 organizations, most of which are local institutions in the developing world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://pceuganda.org/Home.php"&gt;Permanent Centre for Education&lt;/a&gt; is a nonprofit organization growing out of AVSI&amp;rsquo;s work in Uganda, where it has worked since 1984 in education, child development, health care, food security, and emergency humanitarian relief. The mission of the PCE is to contribute to human development and protection of children through education. Its teacher training curriculum challenges teachers to engage their whole selves and to return to the core substance of education which is much more than simply ensuring the acquisition of knowledge and skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though education has been always at the heart of AVSI&amp;rsquo;s social protection interventions, a specific and deeper concern for education started in 1997 with the Psycho-social Support Projects in Kitgum, Northern Uganda. Since 2002, the PCE has increased its institutional capacity and now delivers tailor-made capacity building workshops for professionals in Uganda, South Sudan, Kenya, Thailand, Burundi, Rwanda, Republic of Congo, and Palestine.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joya Helmuth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/47430</id>
    <published>2014-04-03T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-14T09:47:57-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/47430-notre-dame-works-with-diocese-and-students-in-the-democratic-republic-of-congo-to-build-reliable-electricity-and-renewable-energy-skills/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame works with diocese and students in DRC to build reliable electricity and renewable energy skills</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p align="left"&gt;The &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD) successfully delivered and, with the help of local staff, installed a solar microgrid for the &lt;a href="http://www.panoramio.com/photo/57292751"&gt;Universit&amp;eacute; de Notre Dame de Tshumbe&lt;/a&gt; (UNITSHU) in January, 2014. Keith and Janet Sherin, Brad Pattelli, and &lt;a href="http://www.ge.com/?gclid=CL75i5mcob0CFYtDMgod10sAtw"&gt;General Electric&lt;/a&gt; provided generous sponsorship to complete this ambitious project in a remote area of the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="g0010451sm" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/128934/300x/g0010451sm.jpg" title="g0010451sm" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left"&gt;Tshumbe is a diocese of almost one million people in remote central Congo. While in another country a population of this size would indicate a metropolis, its remoteness and dire lack of infrastructure mean that Tshumbe is actually a very large&amp;mdash;and impoverished&amp;mdash;set of distant villages. Water, sanitation, and electricity are scarce and only intermittently available. Fuel comes in the form of expensive diesel, which must be flown in by seaplane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left"&gt;The local Catholic diocese constitutes the largest and most reliable component of Tshumbe&amp;rsquo;s civil infrastructure. More than half of the village&amp;rsquo;s population is Catholic, and the Church is the largest landowner and employer in the region. The Diocese of Tshumbe is led by &lt;a href="http://www.catholicnewsagency.com/news/bridge-building-bishop-works-for-peace-in-africa/"&gt;Bishop Nicholas Djomo Lola&lt;/a&gt;, who also currently presides over the Conference of Catholic Bishops of the Democratic Republic of the Congo. &lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu/people/faculty/john-c-cavadini/"&gt;John Cavadini&lt;/a&gt;, associate professor and chair of theology and the McGrath-Cavadini Director of the Institute for Church Life at Notre Dame, has a longstanding relationship with Bishop Djomo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left"&gt;It was through the relationship between Prof. Cavadini and the Bishop&amp;mdash;as well as input from Father Emery Longanga, who recently returned to Tshumbe after completing his master&amp;rsquo;s degree at Notre Dame&amp;mdash;that the University learned of the opportunity to help our sister university obtain reliable power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left"&gt;The Universit&amp;eacute; de Notre Dame de Tshumbe (UNITSHU) consists of several simple buildings used as lecture rooms and offices for about 800 students. Tshumbe offers an abbreviated, but highly relevant, menu of educational programs: computer science, management and economics, psychology and educational sciences, and medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of a reliable energy source to power computers and even reading lamps for after dark presents a tremendous obstacle to student achievement. It is, moreover, not simply the lack of reliable energy that hinders Tshumbe&amp;rsquo;s students, but also the incredible cost of that energy when it is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development (NDIGD), in an effort initiated by the College of Engineering&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/kpeter/"&gt;Dean Peter Kilpatrick&lt;/a&gt; to help UNITSHU obtain reliable power, and with input and research coordination with&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/mlemmon"&gt;Professor Michael Lemmon&lt;/a&gt; of the Department of Electrical Engineering, designed and installed a solar hybrid microgrid, complete with battery storage and energy monitoring systems on the grounds of UNITSHU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left"&gt;Generous donations from Keith (ND &amp;lsquo;81) and Janet Sherin, matching funds provided by General Electric, and Brad Pattelli (ND &amp;rsquo;88), underwrite this effort. In addition, &lt;a href="http://www.lymanmorse.com/lyman-technologies"&gt;Lyman Technologies&lt;/a&gt; has provided hardware, design, and integration for the solar microgrid at cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left"&gt;Notre Dame and UNITSHU, with the sponsorship and generosity of alumni and corporate partners, have addressed the immediate energy needs of the school.&amp;nbsp; UNITSHU now generates up to 20kWh per day, enough to power their new computer lab, provide study halls after sundown, recharge phones for students and faculty, and begin to bring the remote university into the information age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left"&gt;This is just a beginning. Data from the solar microgrid is collected and shared with Notre Dame electrical engineering faculty working on improved control systems for remote power generation.&amp;nbsp; Notre Dame and UNITSHU have won an additional grant from The Loyola Foundation to upgrade the computers at UNITSHU.&amp;nbsp; Future projects in development include Notre Dame student internships, faculty research, and service projects at UNITSHU and in the broader Tshumbe community to support the solar research, improve internet connectivity, and build bridges and other infrastructure to make Tshumbe more accessible and more connected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align="left"&gt;Contact: Joya Helmuth, NDIGD Outreach Associate, &lt;a href="mailto:jhelmuth@nd.edu?subject=DRCongo%20Article%20Online"&gt;jhelmuth@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joya Helmuth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/47338</id>
    <published>2014-03-31T14:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-31T16:01:04-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/47338-ndigd-awarded-hilton-foundation-grant-to-measure-impact-of-cook-stoves-in-uganda/"/>
    <title>NDIGD Awarded Hilton Foundation Grant to Measure Impact of Cook Stoves in Uganda</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	The Conrad N. Hilton Foundation awarded a $445,000 grant to Blue Planet Network, who will lead a global partnership between &lt;a href="https://ndigd.nd.edu"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD), Africa Ahead, and the International Lifeline Fund to implement the Clean Cook Stoves for Health (CCSH) project in Uganda. NDIGD will serve as the lead research partner for the CCSH project, and will monitor and evaluate the community health impact of replacing traditional cook stoves with energy-efficient models in over 3,000 households in 35 northern Ugandan villages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Acute respiratory disease is a leading cause of morbidity in Uganda and causes more than 8% of infant deaths. Nearly 95% of rural households cook on open fires, resulting in one-third of Uganda&amp;rsquo;s forest lost in the last 25 years and explaining the high rate of acute respiratory disease, typically in women and girls. Traditional cook stove smoke may contribute to many chronic illnesses and acute health impacts such as early childhood pneumonia, emphysema, cataracts, lung cancer, bronchitis, cardiovascular disease, and low birth weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="2010_uganda_gulu_2" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/128506/300x/2010_uganda_gulu_2.jpg" title="2010_uganda_gulu_2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The CCSH project will replace the traditional cook stove with an improved cook stove that is expected to have significant impact on health and the environment. NDIGD&amp;rsquo;s role in this project is to perform rigorous evaluation using household surveys in 70 villages in Uganda before, during, and after project implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	CCSH is part of a larger H20 Health Plus (H20+) initiative, a three-to-five year project that also includes the provision of sustainable safe drinking water and sanitation, and women-led leadership development for rural villages throughout districts in northern Uganda. H20+, led by Blue Planet Network, is demonstrating the unique power of sustainable safe drinking water, use of clean cook stoves, and better hygiene and sanitation practices to provide measurable improvements in health, health clinic capacity, economic vitality, and increased school enrollment of girls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The Notre Dame team includes &lt;a href="http://acms.nd.edu/people/faculty/fang-liu/"&gt;Dr. Fang Liu&lt;/a&gt;, Huisking Foundation, Inc. Assistant Professor in the Department of Applied and Computational Mathematics and Statistics; information technology product expert &lt;a href="http://oit.nd.edu"&gt;Tom Marentette&lt;/a&gt;; and &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/juan-carlos-guzman-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Dr. Juan Carlos Guzman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/lila-khatiwada-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Dr. Lila Khatiwada&lt;/a&gt;, NDIGD monitoring and evaluation specialists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;This three-year evaluation will provide an opportunity to use a statistically rigorous approach in assessing the long-term impact of efficient cook stoves in natural settings,&amp;rdquo; says Dr. Liu.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The &lt;a href="http://www.hiltonfoundation.org"&gt;Conrad N. Hilton Foundation&lt;/a&gt; was created in 1944 by international business pioneer Conrad N. Hilton, who founded Hilton Hotels and left his fortune to help the world&amp;#39;s disadvantaged and vulnerable people. The Foundation currently conducts strategic initiatives in six priority areas: providing safe water, ending chronic homelessness, preventing substance abuse, helping children affected by HIV and AIDS, supporting transition-age youth in foster care, and extending Conrad Hilton&amp;#39;s support for the work of Catholic Sisters. In addition, following selection by an independent international jury, the Foundation annually awards the $1.5 million Conrad N. Hilton Humanitarian Prize to a nonprofit organization doing extraordinary work to reduce human suffering. From its inception, the Foundation has awarded more than $1 billion in grants, distributing $92 million in the U.S. and around the world in 2013. The Foundation&amp;#39;s current assets are approximately $2.4 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href="https://blueplanetnetwork.org"&gt;Blue Planet Network&lt;/a&gt;, a division of &lt;a href="https://www.eastmeetswest.org"&gt;East Meets West&lt;/a&gt;, connects funders, NGOs, the public and communities in need to improve the planning, selection, management and monitoring of water and sanitation programs. The &lt;a href="http://lifelinefund.org"&gt;International Lifeline Fund&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s mission is to bring clean water and fuel-efficient stoves to displaced and impoverished communities in Sub-Saharan Africa and Haiti.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Contact: Joya Helmuth, NDIGD Outreach Associate, &lt;a href="mailto:jhelmuth@nd.edu"&gt;jhelmuth@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joya Helmuth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/46966</id>
    <published>2014-03-17T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-17T13:45:49-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/46966-second-largest-research-award-at-notre-dame-fights-malaria-and-dengue-fever/"/>
    <title>Second Largest Research Award at Notre Dame Fights Malaria and Dengue Fever</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	University of Notre Dame biologists Nicole Achee and Neil Lobo are leaders of an international $23 million research grant from the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation. Their five-year project will generate the data required to show the effectiveness of a new paradigm in mosquito control &amp;mdash; spatial repellency &amp;mdash; for the prevention of two important mosquito-borne diseases: malaria and dengue fever. The grant is the second largest award to a single grant proposal in Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s history. A Microelectronics Advanced Research Corp. award to fund the Center for Low Energy Systems Technology totaled $29 million and is the largest award to a single grant proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Read full article &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/46769-third-largest-research-award-at-notre-dame-fights-malaria-and-dengue-fever/" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Marissa Gebhard</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/46849</id>
    <published>2014-03-12T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-09T10:27:21-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/46849-the-coca-cola-foundation-awards-notre-dame-250-000-grant-to-train-african-leaders-2/"/>
    <title>The Coca-Cola Foundation Awards Notre Dame $250,000 Grant</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;As part of its commitment to provide training and capacity building in the developing world, the University of Notre Dame will welcome 25 African leaders for business and entrepreneurship training this summer. &lt;a href="http://www.coca-colacompany.com/our-company/the-coca-cola-foundation"&gt;The Coca-Cola Foundation&lt;/a&gt; has awarded Notre Dame a $250,000 five-year grant to help implement the program, which builds on a pilot program held at Notre Dame in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="vt1k9428" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/126538/vt1k9428.jpg" title="vt1k9428" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame is an institutional partner in the &lt;a href="http://youngafricanleaders.state.gov/washington-fellows/"&gt;Washington Fellowship&lt;/a&gt; Program, the flagship program of President Obama&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://youngafricanleaders.state.gov"&gt;Young African Leaders Initiative&lt;/a&gt;. The training program will be led by the faculty and staff from the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s Mendoza College of Business &lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/npd/nonprofit_executive_programs/"&gt;Nonprofit Executive Education Program&lt;/a&gt;, supported by the &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD), the Kellogg Institute for International Studies&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/index.shtml"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development Studies and Solidarity&lt;/a&gt;, and the University&amp;rsquo;s Engineering, Science, Technology and Entrepreneurship Excellence Masters (&lt;a href="http://esteem.nd.edu/"&gt;ESTEEM&lt;/a&gt;) program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame aims to bring government resources and corporate commitments together with Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s research and teaching expertise toward a common goal of making a positive, relevant impact in the developing world. The Washington Fellowship program is an ideal example of how Notre Dame, IBM, and The Coca-Cola Foundation are educating and training African men and women, who will continue to serve as leaders, entrepreneurs, and mentors upon returning to their home countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;NDIGD is helping to grow the University&amp;rsquo;s collaborations with key corporate partners for training and research programs that will impact developing countries, and we are very pleased to be able to work with The Coca-Cola Foundation and IBM to help train the next generation of African leaders,&amp;rdquo; says NDIGD Managing Director Michael Sweikar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Coca-Cola Foundation is supporting the Washington Fellowship with a particular interest in women. The Coca-Cola Company has made a global commitment to empower women to thrive in business. In 2010, The Coca-Cola Company announced plans to empower 5 million women entrepreneurs by the year 2020. It also launched the Global Women&amp;rsquo;s Leadership Council, an internal initiative, that works with senior women executives at Coca-Cola to identify strategies to attract and develop women into general management positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to The Coca-Cola Foundation&amp;rsquo;s award, &lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com/us/en/"&gt;IBM Corporation&lt;/a&gt; is assisting the program by providing additional funding and training support. Notre Dame was also awarded $100,000 from the U.S. Department of State earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This summer&amp;rsquo;s U.S. Department of State Washington Fellowship program will provide 500 African Fellows with a U.S. experience that begins with a six-week academic institute at one of several university campuses across the country. A three-day summit in Washington, D.C., will immediately follow the institute program, and up to 100 selected participants will receive an eight-week follow-on internship with an American NGO or business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an address introducing the Washington Fellowship Program, President Obama said, &amp;ldquo;Africa&amp;rsquo;s future belongs to its young people. We need young Africans who are standing up and making things happen, not only in their own countries but around the world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Washington Fellows&amp;rsquo; U.S.-based training is only the beginning of a long-term investment in these young leaders. In Africa, YALI will provide ongoing opportunities for networking, professional development, seed funding for entrepreneurs, and community service. Fellows will have access to enrichment seminars, local and regional networking events, and an innovative on-line platform for future collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact: Joya Helmuth, NDIGD Outreach Associate,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="mailto:jhelmuth@nd.edu"&gt;jhelmuth@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joya Helmuth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/46711</id>
    <published>2014-03-05T12:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-03-05T13:27:58-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/46711-ibm-and-notre-dame-expand-partnership-to-help-train-young-african-leaders/"/>
    <title>IBM and Notre Dame Expand Partnership to Help Train Young African Leaders</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	As part of its commitment to provide training and capacity building in the developing world, the University of Notre Dame has partnered with the &lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com/us/en/"&gt;IBM Corporation&lt;/a&gt; to expand a Notre Dame &lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu/news/36044-leadnotre-dame-collaboration-supports-next-generation-of-leaders-for-east-africa/"&gt;pilot program&lt;/a&gt; that began in 2012 to provide training to young African leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In the summer of 2014, the University will partner with IBM experts to provide 25 young students from across the continent of Africa with six weeks of training in the areas of business and entrepreneurship. IBM instructors and Notre Dame faculty and staff will design courses for aspiring entrepreneurs who hope to assume leadership roles or start their own business ventures in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Areas where IBM will provide expertise include: &lt;a href="http://www.smetoolkit.org/smetoolkit/en"&gt;practical tools&lt;/a&gt; for small and medium size businesses; ethics; and how mobile, data analytics, and cloud can spur the creation of innovative solutions that can help African business and public leaders drive business growth and cost-effective, sustainable service delivery to the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	This program will be part of the &lt;a href="http://youngafricanleaders.state.gov/washington-fellows/"&gt;Washington Fellowship&lt;/a&gt;, the flagship program of President Obama&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://youngafricanleaders.state.gov"&gt;Young African Leaders Initiative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt="10" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/126051/10.16.12_mcob.jpg" style="float: right;" title="10" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The training program will be led by the faculty and staff from the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s Mendoza College of Business &lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/npd/nonprofit_executive_programs/"&gt;Nonprofit Executive Program&lt;/a&gt;; supported by the &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD), the Kellogg Institute for International Studies&amp;rsquo; &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/index.shtml"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development Studies and Solidarity&lt;/a&gt;, and the University&amp;rsquo;s Engineering, Science, Technology and Entrepreneurship Excellence Masters (&lt;a href="http://esteem.nd.edu/"&gt;ESTEEM&lt;/a&gt;) program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The IBM Corporation and &lt;a href="http://www.coca-colacompany.com/our-company/community-requests-guidelines-application"&gt;The Coca-Cola Foundation&lt;/a&gt; have committed funding and training support to Notre Dame to facilitate the Washington Fellowship program, in addition to $100,000 from the U.S. Department of State. IBM will also provide internship opportunities for the African leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;We look forward to continuing our partnership with IBM to train a new group of Young African Leaders on Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s campus, and to scaling-up the program that we started with IBM in 2012. The summer 2014 session will bring leaders from across the continent of Africa, expanding the program beyond the East Africa region where it started,&amp;rdquo; says Notre Dame Executive Vice President, &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/about/leadership/council/john-affleck-graves/"&gt;John Affleck-Graves&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The IBM Corporation&amp;rsquo;s involvement began with a pilot program at Notre Dame in 2012. The University hosted six African leaders for a seven-week training course that was integrated into the MBA curriculum. Led by Rev. Robert Dowd, C.S.C., director of the Ford Program and assistant professor of political science, the training was facilitated by Mendoza College of Business faculty and IBM representatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The summer 2014 U.S. Department of State Washington Fellowship program will provide 500 competitively selected African Fellows with a U.S. experience that begins with a six-week course at one of several university campuses across the country. A three-day summit in Washington, D.C., will immediately follow the institute program, and up to 100 selected participants will receive an eight-week follow-on internship with an American NGO or business.The 2012 student participants were housed at the University and fully integrated into the Notre Dame&amp;nbsp;MBA&amp;nbsp;curriculum, while also participating in seminars designed specifically for them by the Ford and&amp;nbsp;ESTEEM&amp;nbsp;programs. Representatives from&amp;nbsp;IBM&amp;nbsp;taught once per week, and the students had the chance to attend a weeklong seminar at&amp;nbsp;IBM&amp;nbsp;before returning to East Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Notre Dame aims to bring government resources and corporate commitments together with Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s research and teaching expertise toward a common goal of making a positive, relevant impact in the developing world. The Washington Fellowship program is an ideal example of how Notre Dame, the IBM Corporation, and The Coca-Cola Foundation are educating and training African men and women, who will continue to serve as leaders, entrepreneurs, and mentors upon returning to their home countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In an address introducing the Washington Fellowship Program, President Obama said, &amp;ldquo;Africa&amp;rsquo;s future belongs to its young people. We need young Africans who are standing up and making things happen, not only in their own countries but around the world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The Washington Fellows&amp;rsquo; U.S.-based training is only the beginning of a long-term investment in these young leaders. In Africa, YALI will provide ongoing opportunities for networking, professional development, seed funding for entrepreneurs, and community service. Fellows will have access to enrichment seminars, local and regional networking events, and an innovative on-line platform for future collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Contact: Joya Helmuth, Outreach Associate, Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development, &lt;a href="mailto:jhelmuth@nd.edu"&gt;jhelmuth@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joya Helmuth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/46603</id>
    <published>2014-02-28T09:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-09T10:20:55-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/46603-notre-dame-awarded-u-s-department-of-state-grant-to-train-young-african-leaders/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame Awarded U.S. Dept. of State Grant to Train Young African Leaders</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;As part of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(NDIGD), a group of collaborators at the University of Notre Dame has received a grant from the U.S. Department of State to train young African leaders. The collaborators include the faculty and staff from the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s Mendoza College of Business&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/npd/nonprofit_executive_programs/"&gt;Nonprofit Executive Program&lt;/a&gt;; the Kellogg Institute for International Studies&amp;rsquo;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/index.shtml"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development Studies and Solidarity&lt;/a&gt;, and the University&amp;rsquo;s Engineering, Science, Technology and Entrepreneurship Excellence Masters (&lt;a href="http://esteem.nd.edu/"&gt;ESTEEM&lt;/a&gt;) program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The $100,000 grant was awarded through the State Department&amp;rsquo;s implementing partner,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.irex.org/"&gt;IREX&lt;/a&gt;. Additional funding and technical support for the training program has been provided by the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.ibm.com/us/en/"&gt;IBM Corporation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and The&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.coca-colacompany.com/our-company/the-coca-cola-foundation"&gt;Coca-Cola Foundation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grant will position Notre Dame to serve as a host institution for the &lt;a href="http://youngafricanleaders.state.gov/washington-fellows/"&gt;Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders program&lt;/a&gt;. In the summer of 2014, the University will partner with IBM experts to provide 25 young students from across the continent of Africa with six weeks of training in the area of business and entrepreneurship. Courses will be designed by IBM instructors and Notre Dame faculty and staff for aspiring entrepreneurs who hope to assume leadership roles or start their own business ventures in Africa.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders is the new flagship program of President Barack Obama&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;Young African Leaders Initiative (YALI). The Initiative was launched in 2010 to support young African leaders as they spur growth and prosperity, strengthen democratic governance, and enhance peace and security across Africa. Beginning this summer, the&amp;nbsp;Washington Fellowship will bring 500 young leaders to the United States each year for academic coursework and leadership training. The program is expected to create unique opportunities in Africa for Fellows to use their new skills in leading organizations, communities, and countries.iversity will partner with IBM experts to provide 25 young students from across the continent of Africa with six weeks of training in the area of business and entrepreneurship. Courses will be designed by IBM instructors and Notre Dame faculty and staff for aspiring entrepreneurs who hope to assume leadership roles or start their own business ventures in Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="president_washington_fellowship_program" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/125659/president_washington_fellowship_program.jpg" style="float: right;" title="president_washington_fellowship_program" /&gt;This summer&amp;rsquo;s Washington Fellowship program will provide 500 African Fellows with a U.S. experience that begins with a six-week academic course at one of several university campuses across the country. A three-day summit in Washington, D.C., will immediately follow the institute program, and up to 100 selected participants will receive an eight-week follow-on internship with an American NGO or business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are very pleased to welcome these young African leaders to the University of Notre Dame under this U.S. Department of State flagship program, and we look forward to helping to train the next generation of business leaders in Africa,&amp;rdquo; says Notre Dame Mendoza College of Business Dean,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/RogerHuang/"&gt;Roger Huang&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Notre Dame, the Fellowship participants will be hosted by the Nonprofit Executive Program at the Mendoza College of Business, which has a proven leadership record in ethics, corporate social responsibility, business for good, and value-based leadership. The Ford Program has established strong relationships with universities in East Africa, and seeks to work with partners to build local capacity for solving the challenges associated with extreme poverty. The ESTEEM program marries science and technology with business expertise to encourage outside-the-box thought processes that lead to innovative ventures in a complex world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NDIGD combines the existing strengths of these programs with a dedicated staff of experienced international development professionals, administrators, and researchers in the areas of training and capacity building, monitoring and evaluation, and policy analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an address introducing the Washington Fellowship Program, President Obama said, &amp;ldquo;Africa&amp;rsquo;s future belongs to its young people. We need young Africans who are standing up and making things happen, not only in their own countries but around the world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Washington Fellows&amp;rsquo; U.S.-based training is only the beginning of a long-term investment in these young leaders. In Africa, YALI will provide ongoing opportunities for networking, professional development, seed funding for entrepreneurs, and community service. Fellows will have access to enrichment seminars, local and regional networking events, and an innovative on-line platform for future collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact: Joya Helmuth, NDIGD Outreach Associate&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="mailto:jhelmuth@nd.edu"&gt;jhelmuth@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/46477</id>
    <published>2014-02-25T16:35:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-09T10:22:43-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/46477-notre-dame-haiti-program-expands-distribution-of-disease-preventing-salt-nationwide/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame Haiti Program expands distribution of disease-preventing salt nationwide</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;Published: February 21, 2014 &amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Author:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Marissa Gebhard&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="bon_sel_300" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/125033/bon_sel_300.jpg" style="margin: 1px 3px; border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; float: right;" title="bon_sel_300" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame &lt;a href="http://haiti.nd.edu/"&gt;Haiti Program&lt;/a&gt; has established a partnership with Carribex S.A., one of the largest food corporations in Haiti, to distribute the program&amp;rsquo;s Bon Sel Dayiti, co-fortified salt that will reduce preventable disease in Haiti. With Carribex&amp;rsquo;s nationwide distribution network, the salt is now available to most of Haiti&amp;rsquo;s 10 million people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 2 million Haitians are infected with lymphatic filariasis, a mosquito-borne disease that is the second leading cause of long-term disfigurement and disability worldwide. The debilitating and socially marginalizing disease, also known as elephantiasis, is carried by mosquitoes. It can be eliminated in Haiti through mass drug administration and the distribution of co-fortified salt. Bon Sel Dayiti contains diethylcarbamazine citrate &amp;mdash; the medication that kills the parasitic worms that cause lymphatic filariasis &amp;mdash; and potassium iodate, which supplies iodine, an essential nutrient needed for brain development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2006, the Haiti Program, based in the &lt;a href="http://science.nd.edu/"&gt;College of Science&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Notre Dame, has produced Bon Sel Dayiti, the only locally produced, food-grade fortified salt in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earl Carter, assistant dean in the College of Science, has recently been named managing director of the program. The Haiti Program founder and principal investigator, &lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/streit/"&gt;Rev. Thomas Streit, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, completed a stateside leave, which concluded with teaching duties during the fall semester, and a return to Haiti in mid-January. Father Streit will continue to work closely with Carter; &lt;a href="http://science.nd.edu/about/office-of-the-dean/"&gt;Greg Crawford&lt;/a&gt;, dean of the College of Science; and others in support of program development while also leading in-country research efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The strategic partnership with Carribex has increased demand tenfold for Bon Sel Dayiti. Carter said, &amp;ldquo;To supply the tenfold increase in demand for the salt resulting from this important distribution breakthrough, the Haiti Program recently purchased a shipload of 1,500 tons of raw solar salt from program partner Cargill Salt&amp;rsquo;s facility on the Caribbean island of Bonaire, N.A. This large re-supply of salt, delivered in early December, will augment the existing stock of local and imported raw salt, and will support the production of Bon Sel Dayiti throughout 2014.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carribex S.A. is taking delivery of some 75,000 bags of salt per week in support of sales. The corporation&amp;rsquo;s nationwide distribution network will take the vital product well beyond the Leogane area where initial distribution efforts were focused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1993, the University of Notre Dame Haiti Program seeks to achieve the ambitious goal of eliminating lymphatic filariasis in Haiti by 2020. The Haiti Program is partnering with the Haitian Ministry of Health, corporations and nongovernmental organizations to eliminate the disease in Haiti and alleviate the suffering of Haitians infected with lymphatic filariasis.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/45543</id>
    <published>2014-01-14T17:50:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-09T10:23:35-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/45543-ndigd-awarded-contract-to-provide-post-project-evaluation-of-usaid-funded-project-in-indonesia/"/>
    <title>NDIGD Awarded Contract to Provide Post-project Evaluation of USAID-Funded   Project in Indonesia</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;Published: January 14, 2014 &lt;strong&gt;Author: &lt;/strong&gt;Hillary Bengtsson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="screen_shot_2014_01_14_at_1" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/121830/screen_shot_2014_01_14_at_1.46.30_pm.png" title="screen_shot_2014_01_14_at_1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD) was recently awarded a contract from &lt;a href="http://www.pciglobal.org/"&gt;Project Concern International&lt;/a&gt; (PCI) to conduct a post-project sustainability study. The study will evaluate the long-term impact of Project CHOICE (Child Health Opportunities Integrated with Community Empowerment) in Indonesia. CHOICE was a four-year USAID-funded project designed to improve the health and nutrition status among children and their caretakers. The project ran from October 2003 to September 2007 in the Pandeglang District of Indonesia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Significant poverty, low employment, limited access to education, and corruption among elected leaders characterized the project sites. PCI aims to shed light on the determinant factors which may contribute to, or work against, the likelihood of project sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After six years of completion of CHOICE activities in Indonesia, PCI is interested in returning to the communities to complete an in-depth post-project sustainability study. The project was designed to provide improved access to quality primary health care services; improved health seeking and care giving behaviors among caretakers; and successful implementation of PCI&amp;rsquo;s community-based health development model by partner NGOs. Post-project sustainability studies measure whether program benefits are still present after project completion and examines what factors contribute to the success or failure in the sustainability of the program. Thus, NDIGD Monitoring and Evaluation experts will determine whether the benefits achieved during the program operation are still present in both the new cohort of children and in children that received services during the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NDIGD will integrate a data collection and evaluation plan to synthesize the outcomes of this project. NDIGD&amp;rsquo;s previous experience in collecting data from rural and hard-to-reach population using rigorous research methods will be helpful in designing and executing this evaluation. For this study, NDIGD will use mobile phones in data collection. Survey questionnaires will be programmed in smart phones or tablets, and responses will be collected during the interview using the mobile devices. NDIGD has successfully applied this technology in data collection in other countries around the world. In addition, NDIGD will also conduct focus group discussions with project beneficiaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research team includes&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/edwin-michael/"&gt;Edwin Michael&lt;/a&gt;, professor of biological sciences and a member of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://globalhealth.nd.edu/"&gt;Eck Institute for Global Health&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;Conducting a post-project evaluation is a unique opportunity to identify the longer-term impacts of the health and nutrition program. It is the type of evaluation that should be conducted more often for global health interventions. I am delighted to see that PCI has taken such evaluations seriously, and am pleased that I will be able to work with NDIGD in developing and conducting this evaluation,&amp;rdquo; Michael said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="screen_shot_2014_01_14_at_1" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/121831/screen_shot_2014_01_14_at_1.45.46_pm.png" title="screen_shot_2014_01_14_at_1" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NDIGD monitoring and evaluation specialists&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/lila-khatiwada-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Lila Khatiwada&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/juan-carlos-guzman-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Juan Carlos Guzman&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;will oversee the data collection in Indonesia in early 2014. &amp;ldquo;Post-project sustainability study is rarely done in international development arena. This opportunity will provide us to better understand what works and what does not when we go back to same communities after six years&amp;rdquo; Khatiwada said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NDIGD embraces a holistic approach in areas including: commerce and economic development, security and peacebuilding, rule of law; global health, infrastructure, human development, energy and the environment, and education. Notre Dame strengths will help advance PCI goals via an evidence-based, multidisciplinary approach that will combine stringent project monitoring &amp;amp; evaluation, development policy and cooperation, and policy improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Indonesia is a country of increasingly strategic importance to the University, and we are very pleased with this new research opportunity to assist PCI in measuring the outcomes of the health intervention conducted in the Pandeglang District,&amp;rdquo; says Notre Dame Vice President and Association Provost for Internationalization, &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/about/leadership/council/nicholas-entrikin/"&gt;Nicholas Entrikin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact: Michael Sweikar, NDIGD Managing Director&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="mailto:msweikar@nd.edu"&gt;msweikar@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/45043</id>
    <published>2013-12-12T16:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-09T10:23:58-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/45043-carozza-trains-justices-of-ecuador-s-constitutional-court/"/>
    <title>Kellogg Institute Director Carozza trains justices of Ecuador's Constitutional Court</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;Published: December 9, 2013&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Authors&lt;/strong&gt;: Elizabeth Rankin and Kevin Fye&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="carozza" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/120418/carozza.jpg" title="carozza" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the terms of a new agreement between the University of Notre Dame and Ecuador&amp;rsquo;s Constitutional Court, Kellogg Institute Director Paolo Carozza is in Quito this week providing Ecuadorian justices with a foundation in procedural and theoretical aspects of precedent-based law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the enactment of a new national constitution in 2008, the Ecuadorian Court has been developing new methods of adjudication. As it does so, justices are interested in learning more about practices in other countries, including the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is a really dynamic time for constitutionality in Latin America,&amp;rdquo; says Carozza. &amp;ldquo;There is a great deal of ferment and experimentation. This is a wonderful opportunity to contribute to what is going on as well as an opportunity to learn from the Ecuadorian process.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intensive week-long seminar, cotaught by Professor of Law Amy Barrett, touches upon a broad range of issues, from the organization of the court&amp;rsquo;s docket and drafting of judgments to theories of constitutional interpretation and the handling of precedents.In addition, Carozza is offering a comparative analysis of other foreign courts, examining the rationale and procedures for citing these courts in judgments, as well as a lecture on issues of human dignity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of particular value to Ecuador&amp;rsquo;s Court, the seminar is also examining the ways that other jurisdictions handle freedom of expression cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first stage of an anticipated long-term relationship between the Notre Dame Law School and the Ecuadorian Court, the seminar is cosponsored by the Center for Civil and Human Rights and the Program on Constitutional Structure. It is being held at CIESPAL, the Center for Advanced Studies in Communication for Latin America.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/44210</id>
    <published>2013-11-08T08:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-04-09T10:24:40-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/44210-ndigd-awarded-375-000-contract-to-evaluate-mcc-water-project-in-ghana/"/>
    <title>NDIGD Awarded $375,000 Contract to Evaluate MCC Water Project in Ghana</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;Published: November 8, 2013&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Author: &lt;/strong&gt;Hillary Bengtsson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="ghana" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/117765/ghana.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; margin: 1px 3px; float: left;" title="ghana" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD) was recently awarded a $375,000 contract from the &lt;a href="http://www.mcc.gov/"&gt;Millennium Challenge Corporation&lt;/a&gt; (MCC) to conduct an evaluation of MCC&amp;rsquo;s water project in Ghana.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, MCC signed a 5-year, $547 million Compact with the Republic of Ghana aimed at reducing poverty through agribusiness development. The University of Notre Dame will help evaluate the benefits of the water component of that project, which was designed to provide water systems to communities in Ghana. A total of 392 water points were constructed, including boreholes, small town water systems, and pipe extensions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The evaluation will help determine whether improving water systems in participating districts has reduced the prevalence of illness&amp;mdash;particularly diarrhea&amp;mdash;and generated health improvements, and whether beneficiary productivity and incomes have increased with the availability of better water. Some 137 selected communities in the intervention areas are benefiting from the improved water systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NDIGD will work with MCC to evaluate the water activity of these improved water systems, integrating a survey and data collection to synthesize outcomes of the project. NDIGD&amp;rsquo;s previous experience in using rigorous research methods to collect data from communities will be helpful in designing and executing the evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="ghana_2" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/117764/ghana_2.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; margin: 1px 3px; float: right;" title="ghana_2" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research team includes &lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/edwin-michael/"&gt;Edwin Michael&lt;/a&gt;, professor of biological sciences and a member of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://globalhealth.nd.edu/"&gt;Eck Institute for Global Health&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;We are excited about investigating whether the model used for the water intervention has led to improved health outcomes, particularly in the case of diarrhea, which continues to be a leading cause of death among the developing world&amp;rsquo;s children,&amp;rdquo; Michael said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NDIGD monitoring and evaluation specialists &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/lila-khatiwada-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Lila Khatiwada&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/juan-carlos-guzman-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Juan Carlos Guzman&lt;/a&gt; will travel to Ghana in December to develop the design for the survey and data collection that will be implemented in 2014. &amp;ldquo;We are collaborating with several experts in Ghana to assist in providing local expertise and knowledge as we design the study and carry out the evaluation,&amp;rdquo; Khatiwada said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economics professor &lt;a href="http://economics.nd.edu/the-faculty/joseph-kaboski/"&gt;Joseph Kaboski&lt;/a&gt; will provide input into the design of the evaluation and assist in analyzing the data. Other researchers on the project, including &lt;a href="http://environmentalchange.nd.edu/programs/climate/"&gt;ND-GAIN&lt;/a&gt; research fellow &lt;a href="http://gain.org/team/chen-chen/"&gt;Chen Chen&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://csr.nd.edu/about-us/"&gt;Andres Martinez&lt;/a&gt;, data management consultant for the &lt;a href="http://csr.nd.edu/"&gt;Center for Social Research&lt;/a&gt;, also serve as part of the research team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Notre Dame is most grateful to be able to partner with the Millennium Challenge Corporation on this potentially transformative project in Ghana,&amp;quot; said University of Notre Dame provost &lt;a href="http://provost.nd.edu/about/"&gt;Dr. Thomas Burish&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;quot;Splendid faculty from several different disciplines, working through Notre Dame&amp;#39;s Initiative for Global Development, will contribute to several applied research projects that will benefit not only communities in Ghana but also many others world-wide.&amp;quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A United States foreign aid agency created by Congress in January, 2004, the Millennium Challenge Corporation is committed to providing smart U.S. foreign assistance by focusing on good policies, country ownership, and proven results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact: Michael Sweikar, NDIGD managing director, at&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="mailto:msweikar@nd.edu"&gt;msweikar@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/44107</id>
    <published>2013-11-05T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-12-12T16:37:42-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/44107-varieties-of-democracy-project-to-receive-5-8-million/"/>
    <title>Kellogg Institute 'V-Dem' project to receive grant for research</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	Published: October 31, 2013&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Author: &lt;/strong&gt;Elizabeth Rankin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="coppedge" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/117383/coppedge.jpg" title="coppedge" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	An ambitious international research effort to illuminate why democracies around the world succeed or fail has been awarded approximately $5.8 million (37.5 million SEK) over six years by the Swedish foundation Riksbankens Jubileumsfond (RJ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/projects/vdem/index.shtml"&gt;Varieties of Democracy&lt;/a&gt; project (V-Dem), based in the US at the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt; and in Europe at the University of Gothenberg&amp;rsquo;s Varieties of Democracy Institute, promises to make entirely new kinds of democracy research and policy assessment possible by quantifying democracy in all countries from 1900 to the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The effort is led by Notre Dame political scientist &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/coppedge.shtml"&gt;Michael Coppedge&lt;/a&gt;, John Gerring of Boston University, and in Sweden, Staffan I. Lindberg of the University of Gothenburg and Jan Teorell of Lund University. Their team includes 18 researchers at 13 universities in the US, Europe, and Latin America, as well as the input of nearly 2000 country experts around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;V-Dem has amassed a database of 11 million data points, and by the time this grant starts, we will be nearly finished with data collection,&amp;rdquo; says Coppedge. &amp;ldquo;This grant will make it possible to immediately dive into analysis of key questions: What are the main dimensions of democracy? What are the internal and external drivers of regime changes toward or away from democracy?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The RJ funding will allow the research team to aggregate and simplify vast quantities of data on 329 aspects of democracy as well as to identify much more precisely than has previously been possible the sequencing of various stages of democratization and the processes by which democracy spreads from one country to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;The V-Dem approach stands out as a large global collaboration among scholars with diverse areas of expertise and as the first project attempting to explain different varieties of democracy,&amp;rdquo; says Coppedge. &amp;ldquo;Thanks to the highly disaggregated V-Dem data, it is also the first project to explore causal mechanisms linking different aspects of democracy together.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	V-Dem researchers plan to produce a working paper series, at least one edited volume, and many journal articles over the time period of the grant, Coppedge says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In mid-2014, the data will be made freely available to anyone interested in democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;V-Dem data will be used not only by researchers who want to understand the nature, causes, and consequences of democratization but also by governments and international organizations that need to assess the effectiveness of their democracy-promotion programs, students and journalists tracking progress toward democracy, and local NGOs that need reliable evidence to hold their own governments accountable,&amp;rdquo; says Coppedge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Riksbankens Jubileumsfond (RJ) is an independent Swedish foundation that promotes research in the humanities and social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/43938</id>
    <published>2013-10-29T12:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-08T09:03:04-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/43938-taflanidis-named-one-of-nation-s-most-innovation-young-engineering-educators/"/>
    <title>Alexandros Taflanidis named one of nation's most innovation young engineering educators</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	Published: October 8, 2013&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Author: &lt;/strong&gt;Nina Welding&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="taflanidis" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/116637/taflanidis.jpg" title="taflanidis" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/taflanidis.shtml"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/taflanidis.shtml"&gt;lexandros Taflanidis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, associate professor of civil and environmental engineering and earth sciences, concurrent associate professor of aerospace and mechanical engineering and faculty fellow of the Kellogg Institute of International Studies at the University of Notre Dame, has been selected as one of the nation&amp;#39;s 73 most innovative young engineering educators by the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nae.edu/" target="_blank"&gt;National Academy of Engineering&lt;/a&gt;. These early career faculty members, who have already been honored for their development and implementation of novel educational approaches in a variety of engineering disciplines, will participate in the academy&amp;#39;s 2013&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nae.edu/Projects/CASEE/26338/69844/20742.aspx" target="_blank"&gt;U.S. Frontiers of Engineering Education Symposium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Scheduled for Oct. 27-30 (Sunday-Wednesday) in Irvine, Calif., this year&amp;#39;s program will focus on the development of new teaching practices as well as the design and implementation of innovative courses and curricula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;quot;Through this forum, our engineering faculty are empowered to create the conditions to meaningfully engage engineering students in innovation and entrepreneurship to meet 21st-century challenges and are encouraged to be agents of change at their home institutions,&amp;quot; said Stephen W. Director, provost and senior vice president for academic affairs at Northeastern University and chair of the Frontiers of Engineering Education advisory committee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Taflanidis joined Notre Dame in 2008. His research focuses on the development and implementation of advanced computational methodologies for assessment/mitigation of risk due to natural hazards, such as earthquakes and hurricanes, and for probabilistic/robust design of engineering systems. He also works on sustainable solutions for low-income residential housing in the developing world under the banner of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/engineering2empower" target="_blank"&gt;Engineering2Empower&lt;/a&gt;. His contribution in this year&amp;#39;s symposium is titled &amp;quot;Incorporation of Simulation-Based Science in the Engineering Curriculum through Integration of High Performance/Soft-Computing Techniques.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Established in 1964, the NAE is an independent, nonprofit institution that serves as an adviser to government and the public on issues in engineering and technology. Its members consist of the nation&amp;#39;s premier engineers, who are elected by their peers for their distinguished achievements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;First posted here:&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/news-publications/pressreleases" target="_blank"&gt;http://engineering.nd.edu/news-publications/pressreleases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/43456</id>
    <published>2013-10-10T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-11-05T10:15:19-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/43456-ndigd-awarded-blanket-purchase-agreement-to-provide-impact-evaluation-for-millennium-challenge-corporation/"/>
    <title>NDIGD Awarded Blanket Purchase Agreement to Provide Impact Evaluation for MCC</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	Published: October 10, 2013&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Author: &lt;/strong&gt;Hillary Bengtsson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt="10" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/114741/10.9.13_golden_dome_1042.jpg" style="margin: 1px 3px; border: 0px solid currentColor; width: 150px; height: 225px; float: right;" title="10"http://ndigd.nd.edu/&gt;The &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (NDIGD) was recently awarded a Blanket Purchase Agreement (BPA) to partner with the &lt;a href="http://www.mcc.gov/"&gt;Millennium Challenge Corporation&lt;/a&gt; (MCC) to provide impact evaluation research for MCC projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	MCC is a U.S. foreign aid agency created by the U.S. Congress in January, 2004, that is committed to providing smart U.S. foreign assistance by focusing on good policies, country ownership, and proven results. MCC is working toward improving the lives of people in developing countries by creating the markets of the future, with whom global companies can do business and trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	To support MCC objectives, NDIGD will draw from multidisciplinary resources at the university that align with MCC objectives to help foster demand-driven, interdisciplinary approaches to major development challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	NDIGD will work to support MCC goals by 1) providing monitoring and evaluation services that will measure the impact of programming on institutions and the impact of reforms on desired outcomes; and 2) conducting project design and policy analysis for the implementation of global development projects. In addition, the new partnership will support training and capacity building through the integration of multidisciplinary teams and proven approaches to developing training and education programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt="2010_kellogg_uganda_1" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/114745/2010_kellogg_uganda_1.jpg" style="margin: 1px 3px; border: 0px solid currentColor; width: 200px; height: 133px; float: left;" title="2010_kellogg_uganda_1" /&gt;NDIGD embraces a holistic approach in areas that include commerce and economic development, security and peacebuilding, rule of law; global health, infrastructure, human development, energy and the environment, and education. Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s strengths will help advance MCC goals via an evidence-based, multidisciplinary approach that will combine stringent project monitoring and evaluation, development policy and cooperation, and policy improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;We are very pleased to leverage our university-wide expertise across multiple disciplines to support MCC in monitoring and evaluation, as well as the design of development projects that are well-matched to the university&amp;rsquo;s expertise, capacity, and mission,&amp;rdquo; says Notre Dame vice president for research&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/about/leadership/council/robert-bernhard/"&gt;Robert Bernhard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The new partnership between NDIGD and MCC will help provide a strong framework for the rigorous evaluation of the impact of integrated global development projects that assist in the development of peaceful nations and assist people suffering from extreme poverty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Contact: Michael Sweikar, NDIGD Managing Director&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="mailto:msweikar@nd.edu"&gt;msweikar@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/42785</id>
    <published>2013-09-17T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-10-29T12:53:54-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/42785-ndigd-projects-and-monitoring-evaluation-work-recently-highlighted-by-devex-impact-usaid/"/>
    <title>NDIGD projects and Monitoring &amp; Evaluation work highlighted by Devex Impact / USAID</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	Published at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.devex.com/en/news/5-ways-to-better-measure-corporate-partnerships/81819"&gt;Deveximpact Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, September 17, 2013,&amp;nbsp; &lt;strong&gt;Author: &lt;/strong&gt;Michael Sweikar&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt="logo_usaid" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/112134/logo_usaid.png" style="float: right;" title="logo_usaid" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt="logo_devex_impact_beta" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/112131/logo_devex_impact_beta.png" style="float: left;" title="logo_devex_impact_beta" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Today businesses are increasingly involved in international development. This new involvement is visible at high-profile venues like the Clinton Global Initiative or the &lt;a href="https://www.devex.com/en/organizations/46616"&gt;World Economic Forum&lt;/a&gt;, where companies present major social commitments, and at a quieter, more local level through country-based business roundtables where companies align their efforts around common development objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="tiny-miced"&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		While this trend toward private-sector partnerships is positive, there is one area in which this trend has not kept pace with another trend in international development &amp;ndash; an increasing emphasis on rigorous monitoring and evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		As described in Dean Karlan and Jacob Appel&amp;rsquo;s recent book, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.poverty-action.org/book/index.html"&gt;More Than Good Intentions: Improving the Ways the World&amp;rsquo;s Poor Borrow, Save, Farm, Learn, and Stay Healthy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;randomized control trials can demonstrate that positive changes may result from development intervention,&lt;img alt="Microgrid" src="https://neo-assets.s3.amazonaws.com/assets/0071/6942/Uganda_microgrid_Devex_Impact_400x335.jpg" style="width: 346px; height: 221px; float: right;" title="Microgrid" /&gt; rather than from external factors alone.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Although this type of experimental design has been used for more than 50 years, there has been renewed interest lately in using this form of validation to fund development projects. This is due in part to the limited resources available for funding projects, and the fact that researchers are finding new ways to use impact evaluation studies across varied disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		It is difficult to find data on the number of companies that have measured the benefits of their corporate responsibility programs, and it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to determine if companies that do measure are assessing anything more than outputs.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		For example, a 2011 survey conducted by the Corporate Responsibility Officers Association, Corporate Responsibility Magazine, and NYSE Euronext found that only 33 percent of the 300 global companies surveyed indicated that they measure the benefits of their corporate responsibility programs. And even when they do, it is not evident that they are measuring anything more than the numbers of individuals trained or workshops held.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		So what can universities contribute to the task of evaluating and improving corporate partnerships for development?&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		First, by their very nature, universities are interested in learning and applying research. This means that universities can leverage existing expertise and infrastructure to develop an understanding of whether global development interventions are working or not.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		And, secondly, because universities are naturally linked with research in the minds of many, companies may perceive universities as less &amp;ldquo;threatening&amp;rdquo; when it comes to having their programs evaluated. As many of my colleagues know, companies can perceive monitoring and evaluation as an intrusive &amp;ldquo;audit&amp;rdquo; that seeks to uncover flaws.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		The fact is, companies are not always incentivized to integrate rigorous monitoring and evaluation components into their corporate responsibility programs. Shareholders may not be concerned with either process or results; implementing partners may not insist on a joint evaluation system, and the company itself may not want to fund the evaluation process.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		When companies &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; set high standards for evaluating the benefits of their corporate responsibility programs, they are demonstrating leadership in an area where other companies may follow. These corporate leaders often find that a university makes a strong partner.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		As director of the University of &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen first-hand how universities can play a key role in enhancing the monitoring and evaluation components of these programs.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Take, for example, the &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/40497-hp-joins-notre-dame-initiative-for-global-development-partnership-in-uganda/"&gt;Connectivity, Electricity, and Entrepreneurship partnership&lt;/a&gt; in northern Uganda partnership, which involves &lt;a href="https://www.devex.com/en/organizations/22331"&gt;Accenture&lt;/a&gt; and the Accenture Foundations,&lt;a href="https://www.devex.com/en/organizations/42869"&gt; HP&lt;/a&gt; and NDIGD.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		The project aims to empower disconnected communities by providing solar panel microgrids to small businesses. These businesses not only use the energy to power their businesses but also resell the energy to others in the community, who can then start their own entrepreneurial businesses. The project also installs power-efficient computers connected to the Internet via a wireless network provided by nonprofit &lt;a href="http://boscouganda.com/"&gt;BOSCO Uganda&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		NDIGD evaluation experts and Accenture employees will implement an evaluation plan to measure outcomes such as the performance of the microgrid and entrepreneurial training.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Performance of the microgrid will be measured by equipment that uploads information wirelessly to the Cloud, so that indicators are accessible in real time. These indicators will measure the use, intensity, and management of the electricity produced and will help optimize the ongoing design and use of the microgrid for the next phase of the project.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		The entrepreneurial component will be evaluated through a difference-in-differences approach, with propensity score matching. Information has been collected on micro- and small businesses in areas where the pilot project is under way. Business data also will be collected annually to monitor economic activity in the area and to compare the outcomes of people who attend and graduate from the entrepreneurial program.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		These participants will be part of a longitudinal data collection effort designed to measure the program&amp;rsquo;s impact on income and entrepreneurial activity. This aspect of the project reflects Accenture&amp;rsquo;s global corporate citizenship initiative, &lt;a href="http://www.accenture.com/us-en/company/citizenship/Pages/skills-succeed.aspx"&gt;Skills to Succeed&lt;/a&gt;, which will equip 500,000 people globally by 2015 with the skills to get a job or build a business.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		In another project funded by the &lt;a href="http://www.verizonfoundation.org/"&gt;Verizon Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, NDIGD monitoring and evaluation experts and the &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development Studies and Solidarity&lt;/a&gt; at the Notre Dame &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt; are conducting a randomized control trial to help determine the effectiveness of a mobile health project in Nnindye, Uganda. Using a RCT method, the evaluation process will test whether text messages increase health-seeking behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Comparable data will be collected from similar &amp;ldquo;control&amp;rdquo; communities to ascertain the impact attributable to the project&amp;rsquo;s intervention. Data collected by the research team will help assess the impact of updated technology on health outcomes when health center workers are able to send electronic messages to remind women of prenatal and well-baby appointments or to spread the word when supplies such as anti-malarial bed nets or vaccines become available.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		From these and other partnership experiences, NDIGD has learned five important lessons about monitoring and evaluating company-led partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Start at the design stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Begin considering monitoring and evaluation in the initial stages of the project. Universities can be most useful in helping to develop research collaboration and systems for impact evaluation if they are brought in as a partner from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;2. Recognize the other partner&amp;rsquo;s expertise&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Both company partners and university partners should be open to understanding the benefits that each brings to the table. Universities should be willing to help design the project so it can support both corporate responsibility goals &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; also longer-term business strategies of the company. In turn, companies should consider that including research and learning as part of their corporate program means the impact may affect not only beneficiaries but others who work in development and would benefit from research-based best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;3. Continue the dialogue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Keep communication channels open throughout project implementation. We have found that regular update calls work well, even when there is no big decision to make. In almost all environments where these types of projects are implemented, circumstances on the ground change rapidly and new obstacles to implement occur. Partners should go into the collaboration knowing that challenges will arise &amp;ndash; and committed to find ways to work together to address them.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Focus on beneficiaries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		Any research efforts and impact evaluations should aim to give a clearer picture of how the project has affected its intended beneficiaries. This data can be used as a resource when, during the course of the partnership, new decision points arise. At these moments, beneficiary-focused research can help company and university partners keep the initial goals of the project on track.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		&lt;strong&gt;5. Look for opportunities to scale-up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		The benefits of partnering include not only the expertise and resources of both sides, but also the opportunity to scale up successful projects. Look for ways to work together to take an initial pilot project to large scale, possibly through adding new partners and resources that both partners might be able to share. Always remember that a small increase in investment and scope to prepare for scale-up at the pilot stage can reap huge rewards when scaling occurs.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;
		As corporations increasingly make a greater effort to improve health, education, gender equality, and employment in developing countries, it&amp;rsquo;s important that they identify ways to measure how effectively their time and resources are being spent. Leveraging university expertise in monitoring and evaluation as a component of project design and implementation can contribute to better outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Contact: Michael Sweikar, NDIGD Managing Director &lt;a href="mailto:msweikar@nd.edu"&gt;msweikar@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:ndigd.nd.edu,2005:News/42555</id>
    <published>2013-09-09T12:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-10-10T12:00:44-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/news/42555-the-crisis-in-syria-a-kroc-institute-current-events-panel/"/>
    <title>The Crisis in Syria: A Kroc Institute Current Events Panel, Tuesday September 10, 2013</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;h2&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;Featuring&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	&lt;img alt="syria" src="http://ndigd.nd.edu/assets/111268/syria.jpg" style="border-width: 0px; border-style: solid; margin: 1px 3px; float: right;" title="syria" /&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="margin: 0px 0px 1.23em; color: rgb(25, 24, 18); line-height: 16px; font-family: ff-meta-web-pro, Meta, TrebuchetMS, &amp;quot;Helvetica Neue&amp;quot;, Helvetica, &amp;quot;Nimbus Sans L&amp;quot;, sans-serif; font-size: 13px; -webkit-font-smoothing: antialiased;"&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;Free and open to the public.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp; If you can&amp;#39;t join us in person, &lt;a href="http://kroc.nd.edu/news-events/events/2013/09/10/1550"&gt;watch the live stream here&lt;/a&gt; (4:30 p.m. Tues. Sept. 10) U.S. Eastern Time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	Asher Kaufman&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;Associate Professor of History and Peace Studies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	Mary Ellen O&amp;#39;Connell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;Professor of Law and Research Professor of&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;International Dispute Resolution&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;
	Michael Desch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;Professor of Political Science&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;br /&gt;
	Moderated by &lt;strong&gt;David Cortright,&lt;/strong&gt; Director of Policy Studies at the Kroc Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;strong&gt;As the crisis in Syria intensifies, the United States and its allies are considering a response, including possible military strikes on Syria.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	This panel of experts will provide context on regional dynamics in the Middle East (Kaufman), explain international legal issues surrounding the use of force (O&amp;#39;Connell), and discuss the implications for U.S. and international security (Desch). Panelists will consider the arguments both for and against military action and leave plenty of time for questions, answers, and participation from students, faculty, staff, and the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael Sweikar</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
