<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:/news</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news.atom"/>
  <title>Office of the Provost // Office of the Provost</title>
  <updated>2014-07-18T08:10:00-04:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49428</id>
    <published>2014-07-18T08:10:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-18T08:11:50-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49428-john-uhran-named-2014-asee-fellow/"/>
    <title>John Uhran named 2014 ASEE fellow</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="John J. Uhran Jr." src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136857/john_uhran_300.jpg" title="John J. Uhran Jr."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/juhran"&gt;John J. Uhran Jr.&lt;/a&gt;, senior associate dean emeritus and professor emeritus of &lt;a href="http://cse.nd.edu/"&gt;computer science and engineering&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Notre Dame, has been named a fellow of the &lt;a href="http://www.asee.org/"&gt;American Society for Engineering Education&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ASEE&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grade of fellow is conferred upon an individual who has been an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ASEE&lt;/span&gt; member for a minimum of 10 years and in recognition of his or her outstanding contributions to engineering or engineering technology education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although his research interests focused initially on communication theory and systems and simulation techniques, more recently he devoted time to artificial intelligence. Uhran maintained a special interest in engineering education throughout his career, providing significant leadership in the development of many undergraduate programs in Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu"&gt;College of Engineering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A faculty member since 1966, Uhran helped develop several laboratories at Notre Dame and published more than 90 technical papers and 30 reports. He is co-developer of NDTran, a software package used to simulate large systems. Before retiring, he began a series of conferences on First Year Engineering Education. The sixth in the series is being held at Texas A&amp;amp;M in August. He has been actively involved in both the Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ASEE&lt;/span&gt;, served as an adviser for Tau Beta Pi and is a member of Eta Kappa Nu, Sigma Xi and Alpha Phi Omega.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uhran received his doctorate in electrical engineering from Purdue University in 1967. He earned his master’s and bachelor’s degrees, both in electrical engineering, from Purdue (1963) and Manhattan College (1957).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Nina Welding&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49422-john-uhran-named-2014-asee-fellow/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 17, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Nina Welding</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49427</id>
    <published>2014-07-18T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-18T08:04:45-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49427-notre-dame-to-offer-certificate-in-patent-prosecution/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame to offer certificate in patent prosecution</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Statue of St. Thomas More, Biolchini Hall of Law" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136695/biolchini_thomas_more_300.jpg" title="Statue of St. Thomas More, Biolchini Hall of Law"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame, beginning this fall, will offer a &lt;a href="http://patentlaw.nd.edu/"&gt;Certificate in Patent Prosecution&lt;/a&gt;, with six courses available either online or in Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The certificate courses are a subset of those offered on campus in the &lt;a href="http://patentlaw.nd.edu/mspl/"&gt;MS in Patent Law&lt;/a&gt;, and are designed for working professionals who can’t relocate to Notre Dame for an academic year. Certificate students will learn the basics of patent law and necessary skills for a patent agent: how to write a patent application, how to negotiate with the U.S. Patent Office on behalf of an inventor, how to determine whether an invention is patentable and the ethical obligations of a patent agent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students receive the same level of instruction whether taking the courses online, in Chicago or in the MS in Patent Law at Notre Dame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Certificate in Patent Prosecution is a 12-credit curriculum. Courses run on a traditional, semester-based academic calendar. “Patent Prosecution Law I,” “Patent Application Drafting” and “Patent Searching” will be available for students to begin taking entirely online or in Chicago this fall. The remaining three courses, “Patent Prosecution Law II,” “Patent Prosecution” and “Patent Practitioner Ethics,” will be available online or in Chicago in the spring. The online certificate will have both fall and spring start dates. Prospective students can apply by visiting &lt;a href="http://patentlaw.nd.edu/mspl/apply-now/"&gt;patentlaw.nd.edu/mspl/apply-now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://patentlaw.nd.edu/onlinecpp/"&gt;online certificate&lt;/a&gt; courses blend live and pre-recorded lectures to provide maximum flexibility and efficiency, and meet in fall and spring semesters with summers off. The &lt;a href="http://patentlaw.nd.edu/chicagocpp/"&gt;Chicago certificate&lt;/a&gt; courses are taught in-person. All instructors are successful patent agents or patent attorneys who work at law firms, in corporations or at the U.S. Patent Office. Students can take courses as personal schedules allow, as long as all 12 credits are completed by the end of the third year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact: &lt;/strong&gt;Karen Deak, director, Patent Law, 574-631-6695, &lt;a href="mailto:kdeak@nd.edu"&gt;kdeak@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Shannon Chapla&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49348-notre-dame-to-offer-certificate-in-patent-prosecution/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 15, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Shannon Chapla</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49429</id>
    <published>2014-07-18T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-18T08:26:00-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49429-tea-party-support-linked-to-educational-segregation-new-study-shows/"/>
    <title>Tea Party support linked to educational segregation, new study shows</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tea Party" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136830/tea_party_2010_300.jpg" title="Tea Party"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2009, Barack Obama assumed the U.S. presidency in the midst of the most severe recession since the great depression of the 1930s. While many Americans hoped the new administration would take an active role in providing relief for those harmed by the economic collapse, a “Tea Party” movement emerged to oppose Obama’s agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Notre Dame political sociologist &lt;a href="http://sociology.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-by-alpha/rory-mcveigh/"&gt;Rory McVeigh&lt;/a&gt;, whose study “&lt;a href="http://asr.sagepub.com/content/early/2014/05/23/0003122414534065.abstract"&gt;Educational Segregation, Tea Party Organizations, and Battles over Distributive Justice&lt;/a&gt;” was recently published in the American Sociological Review, says, “The political polarization that we witness today is linked to the way in which Americans live in segregated worlds.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McVeigh and his coauthors, &lt;a href="http://sociology.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-by-alpha/kraig-beyerlein/"&gt;Kraig Beyerlein&lt;/a&gt;, Burrel Vann and Priyamvada Trivedi, examine why certain U.S. counties are conducive to the establishment of Tea Party organizations. Their statistical analyses show that even after accounting for many other factors, Tea Party organizations were much more likely to form in counties with high levels of residential segregation based on education levels, and that college graduates were more likely to indicate support for the Tea Party if they resided in a county characterized by high levels of educational segregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Acceptance or rejection of the Tea Party’s views on the government’s role in redistributing wealth is shaped, to a large degree, by the extent to which those who have benefited from higher education are set apart in their daily lives from those who have not,” says McVeigh, who specializes in inequality, social movements, race and ethnicity. “As the article explains, the commonly held view that individuals and families who are struggling to get by are undeserving of government assistance is reinforced when the highly educated have limited contact with those who have been less fortunate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rory McVeigh" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136828/mcveigh_rory_small.jpg" title="Rory McVeigh"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research focused on identifying Tea Party organizations in 2010, when the grassroots component of the movement was at its peak and supporters were protesting the proposed Affordable Care Act. McVeigh says the grassroots component of the Tea Party was especially important because it helped send a message that there was something more going on than elite sponsorship from highly resourced conservative groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the grassroots aspects of the movement have died down; yet as mid-term elections approach, Republican politicians are still focused on appealing to Tea Party supporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If they represent a district where there is a lot of Tea Party support, they are vulnerable to challenges in primary elections from candidates who claim to be representing the Tea Party agenda — supporting sharp spending cuts and low taxes and vigorously resisting most any proposal that Obama and the Democrats have put forth,” McVeigh says. “So even without the protests and the rallies, politicians have to be mindful of the Tea Party, and there are highly resourced conservative organizations that are willing to back candidates advancing the Tea Party agenda and oppose those who are not.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The analyses help us understand,” McVeigh says, “how a movement enabled by highly resourced conservative organizations has been able to draw the support it needed to credibly present itself as a grassroots movement representing ordinary Americans, and thus exert influence on voters and the political process.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Rory McVeigh, 574-631-0386, &lt;a href="mailto:rmcveigh@nd.edu"&gt;rmcveigh@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Shannon Chapla&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49416-tea-party-support-linked-to-educational-segregation-new-study-shows/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 17, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Shannon Chapla</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49426</id>
    <published>2014-07-18T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-18T08:31:21-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49426-falcon-10-aircraft-donation-enables-research-at-transonic-speeds/"/>
    <title>Falcon 10 aircraft donation enables research at transonic speeds</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe allowfullscreen="" frameborder="0" height="338" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/XgllCPlxeF0?rel=0" width="600"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent donation to the University of Notre Dame’s Airborne Aero-Optics Laboratory (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AAOL&lt;/span&gt;) is about to give laser-directed energy and free-space communication a transonic boost: researching at the speed of sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dr. Eric Jumper, professor of aerospace and mechanical engineering, thanks Matthew McDevitt for the donation of a Falcon 10 during a news event at the South Bend Airport." src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136471/falcon_300.jpg" title="Dr. Eric Jumper, professor of aerospace and mechanical engineering, thanks Matthew McDevitt for the donation of a Falcon 10 during a news event at the South Bend Airport."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Falcon 10 aircraft, donated by Philadelphia-area businessman Matthew McDevitt, will enable the University to continue its groundbreaking aerospace research and development that will advance technology for weapons systems and communications. The results could pave the way to high-field-of-regard, point-to-point airborne laser propagation for directed energy and communications as fast and robust as fiber-optic Internet connectivity. In other words, high-flying research at Notre Dame is not only helping to refine the U.S.’s weapons systems, but it could lead to a television show streaming just as fast on a commercial flight as it does in a living room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the mid-1990s, aerospace engineering research has found its home at Notre Dame through the &lt;a href="http://www3.nd.edu/~flowpac/"&gt;Institute for Flow Physics and Control’s&lt;/a&gt; Aero-Optics Group, directed by &lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/ejumper"&gt;Eric Jumper&lt;/a&gt;, professor of aerospace and mechanical engineering. With support from the High Energy Laser-Joint Technology Office (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;HEL&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;JTO&lt;/span&gt;), Notre Dame faculty and researchers have been working with the Air Force Institute of Technology’s &lt;a href="http://www.afit.edu/CDE/"&gt;Center for Directed Energy&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CDE&lt;/span&gt;) and &lt;a href="https://www.mza.com/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MZA&lt;/span&gt; Associates Corp.&lt;/a&gt; to conduct studies focused on directed energy, specifically laser interactions with turbulence, or aero-optics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AAOL&lt;/span&gt; — one of the research programs within the Aero-Optics Group — has taken the lasers to the skies, studying the effects of turbulence on a laser directed from one aircraft to a turret installed on a tandem-flying aircraft about 50 meters away flying at transonic speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Planes have difficulty using lasers because even a tiny amount of turbulence can effectively turn a laser into a really expensive flashlight,” said Jumper. “Supported by funding from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HEL&lt;/span&gt;-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;JTO&lt;/span&gt;, we have developed aero-optic wave front beam-control architectures that overcome aircraft vibration and mitigate the effects of turbulence, which could enable such technologies as free-space communication.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the obvious improvements to directed energy applications, the research will also lead to more than just in-flight streaming entertainment for bored airplane passengers. If brought to market, point-to-point airborne laser communications could improve transmissions between aircraft systems and other aircraft, satellites or ground stations and create a foundation for video feeds from unmanned flights over battlefields or disaster areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AAOL’s research has been conducted in wind tunnel labs on Notre Dame’s campus to simulate flight conditions, and in 2010 the team successfully completed laser-based testing in-flight on two leased Cessna Citations outfitted as sophisticated airborne aero-optics laboratories. The following series of in-flight tests helped ensure the performance of the aero-optic system developed at the University, but testing was required at higher Mach speeds — and the need for a Falcon 10 arose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To really continue our research, we needed to realize higher levels than we could achieve in wind tunnel studies and with previous aircraft,” said Jumper. “With a Falcon 10, we can conduct research at Mach numbers above Mach 0.8, providing an authentic environment that produces more accurate results than a simulated set-up.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up in a Catholic family and attending 12 years of Catholic school, McDevitt, who previously owned the aircraft for private use with his family, learned about the University’s need for a fast-flying jet and generously donated the aircraft. Since the donation, the Falcon 10 has been transformed into a high-speed, high-altitude flying lab, outfitted with the laser-tracking turret and additional aero-optic technology. And, with an engine protection program donated from longtime Notre Dame research partner and South Bend neighbor &lt;a href="http://aerospace.honeywell.com/"&gt;Honeywell Aerospace&lt;/a&gt;, the Falcon 10’s engines will be maintained at no cost to the University for six years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This dedicated plane allows the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AAOL&lt;/span&gt; team to set up, troubleshoot and conduct complex experiments, which was not available when we leased aircraft one week at a time,” said Jumper. “This is about a $1.25 million gift, and without it we would certainly have a less robust program.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a recent visit to Notre Dame, McDevitt got a first-hand look at the aircraft since it was converted to a state-of-the-art component of AAOL’s aerospace research. To see a video with an inside look at how Jumper and his team are taking laser-directed energy to the skies with the Falcon 10 flying research lab, &lt;a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XgllCPlxeF0&amp;amp;amp;feature=youtu.be"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Mandy Kinnucan&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49299-falcon-10-aircraft-donation-enables-research-at-transonic-speeds/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 11, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Mandy Kinnucan</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49325</id>
    <published>2014-07-11T17:30:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-11T17:45:01-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49325-african-leaders-learn-business-entrepreneurship-at-notre-dame/"/>
    <title>African leaders learn business, entrepreneurship at Notre Dame</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="YALI" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136462/yali_300.jpg" title="YALI"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 15 marked the arrival of 25 young African leaders from 17 countries to the University of Notre Dame, where they are training for six weeks in business and entrepreneurship as part of the Obama administration’s &lt;a href="https://youngafricanleaders.state.gov/"&gt;Young African Leaders Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;YALI&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Barack Obama launched &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YALI&lt;/span&gt; in 2010 to support young African leaders as they spur growth and prosperity, strengthen democratic governance and enhance peace and security across Africa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame is among an elite group of colleges and universities chosen by the U.S. Department of State as a host institution for the &lt;a href="https://youngafricanleaders.state.gov/washington-fellowship/"&gt;Washington Fellowship for Young African Leaders&lt;/a&gt; program. The new flagship program will bring 500 students to the U.S. each year for leadership training, academic coursework and mentoring, and will create unique opportunities in Africa to put those new skills to practical use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“These participants are exceptional leaders who will return to Africa with new ideas to help take their respective country’s future to a new and higher level,” said &lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/marchardy/"&gt;Marc Hardy&lt;/a&gt;, director of Nonprofit Executive Programs at Notre Dame. “This is an extremely engaged group of successful entrepreneurs in many different areas. They are absorbing what we are teaching in the areas of innovation, business and leadership. It is an honor for the &lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu"&gt;Mendoza College of Business&lt;/a&gt; at Notre Dame to host such a motivated and distinguished cohort of Washington Fellows.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The African fellows’ U.S. experience begins with the six-week academic course at university campuses across the country. A three-day summit in Washington, D.C., will immediately follow the institute program, and as many as 100 selected participants will receive an eight-week internship with an American nongovernmental organization or business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to their coursework, the Notre Dame fellows are visiting businesses in the South Bend area, including Better World Books, an internationally acclaimed social enterprise started at Notre Dame, and Union Station Technologies, one of the leading data centers in the Midwest. In Chicago, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt; Innovation Center, Capsim, PricewaterhouseCoopers and the Chicago Cubs served as enthusiastic hosts for Notre Dame’s Washington Fellows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also focusing heavily on community service, the fellows have been working with the Boys and Girls Club, Habitat for Humanity, Unity Gardens and the Center for Hospice. “YALI offers a unique opportunity for Notre Dame to enact the global dimension of its mission by reaching out to Africa’s brilliant and promising young entrepreneurs and leaders,” said &lt;a href="http://business.nd.edu/Faculty_Directory/PeterJohnOpio/"&gt;Peter John Opio&lt;/a&gt;, academic director of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;YALI&lt;/span&gt; Institute at Notre Dame. “The Washington Fellowship at Notre Dame is a vital aspect of the University’s global gateway into a continent that faces great challenges but presents vital opportunities. It’s an opportunity for Notre Dame to become an effective partner toward the socio-economic transformation of Africa in a more concrete way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of the &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt;, the University’s six-week institute is supported by a $100,000 grant from the U.S. Department of State. Courses are led by the University’s Mendoza College of Business faculty, with additional support from the Kellogg Institute’s &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development Studies and Solidarity&lt;/a&gt;, the University’s &lt;a href="http://esteem.nd.edu/"&gt;Engineering, Science, Technology and Entrepreneurship Excellence Masters&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ESTEEM&lt;/span&gt;) program, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt; Corp. and Coca-Cola Foundation’s &lt;a href="http://www.coca-colacompany.com/stories/5by20"&gt;5by20 program&lt;/a&gt;, focused on female entrepreneurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Joya Helmuth, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/span&gt; Outreach Associate, 574-631-2940, &lt;a href="mailto:jhelmuth@nd.edu"&gt;jhelmuth@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Shannon Chapla&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49279-african-leaders-learn-business-entrepreneurship-at-notre-dame/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 10, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Shannon Chapla</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49323</id>
    <published>2014-07-11T17:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-11T17:19:58-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49323-biologist-david-lodge-named-jefferson-science-fellow/"/>
    <title>Biologist David Lodge named Jefferson Science Fellow</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="David Lodge" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136344/lodge_cropped.jpg" title="David Lodge"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/lodge/"&gt;David Lodge&lt;/a&gt;, Ludmilla F. and Stephen J. Galla Professor of Biological Sciences at the University of Notre Dame and a world-renowned expert on invasive species, has been named a 2014-15 &lt;a href="http://sites.nationalacademies.org/PGA/Jefferson/"&gt;Jefferson Science Fellow&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;a href="http://sites.nationalacademies.org/PGA/Jefferson/"&gt;Jefferson Science Fellowship Program&lt;/a&gt; is designed to further build capacity for science, technology and engineering expertise with the &lt;a href="http://www.state.gov/"&gt;U.S. Department of State&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://www.usaid.gov/"&gt;U.S. Agency for International Development&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;USAID&lt;/span&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jefferson Science Fellows spend one year at the State Department or &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USAID&lt;/span&gt; for an on-site assignment in Washington, D.C., that may involve extended stays at U.S. foreign embassies and missions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lodge is the founder and director of Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://environmentalchange.nd.edu/"&gt;Environmental Change Initiative&lt;/a&gt; (ND-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ECI&lt;/span&gt;), which focuses on the interrelated problems of invasive species, land use and climate change, and their synergistic impacts on water resources. He is one of the world’s leading experts on aquatic invasive species, and has extensive research experience in ecological forecasting and risk assessment, publishing more than 180 scientific papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lodge has testified numerous times before the U.S. Congress. He served as the first chair of the U.S. government’s national Invasive Species Advisory Committee in 2000-01, led research on freshwater biodiversity as part of the United Nations’ &lt;a href="http://www.unep.org/maweb/en/index.aspx"&gt;Millennium Ecosystem Assessment&lt;/a&gt; in 2000-05, and led an expert subcommittee providing advice to the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency on reducing invasions from the ballast water of ships in 2010-11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lodge is a member of the scientific advisory boards of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the International Joint Commission. He also has a long history of working with outside organizations such as &lt;a href="http://www.nature.org/"&gt;The Nature Conservancy&lt;/a&gt; to help translate and transfer his scientific work to the public policy arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; David Lodge, 574-631-6094, &lt;a href="mailto:David.M.Lodge.1@nd.edu"&gt;David.M.Lodge.1@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;William G. Gilroy&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49268-biologist-david-lodge-named-jefferson-science-fellow/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 09, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>William G. Gilroy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49324</id>
    <published>2014-07-11T17:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-11T17:44:07-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49324-notre-dame-to-receive-father-badins-bible/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame to receive Father Badin’s Bible</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rev. Stephen Badin" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136450/father_stephen_theodore_badin_224.jpg" title="Rev. Stephen Badin"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame has acquired a Bible once owned by Rev. Stephen Badin, the pioneer priest on whose mission grounds Notre Dame’s founder, Rev. Edward Sorin, C.S.C., began to build the University 172 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father Badin’s Bible was purchased from the Sisters of Loretto of Nerinx, Kentucky, and a delegation of sisters is coming to Notre Dame on Monday (July 14) to deliver it by hand during a Mass that will be celebrated in the Log Chapel where Father Badin is buried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Catholic priest ordained in the United States, Father Badin served as a missionary on the Kentucky, Indiana and Illinois frontiers. In 1831, he built the Log Chapel for his mission headquarters on the site where its replica stands today, the original having burned down in 1858. The 542 acres around that site, of which much of the campus (including a student residence hall named after him) is now comprised, Father Badin donated to Bishop Celestine de la Hailandiere of Vincennes, Indiana, who subsequently gave the land to Father Sorin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Badin Bible is a rare book. A three-volume edition of the Douay-Rheims version published by Mathew Carey in 1790, it was the first “Catholic” Bible for sale in the United States. Carey, an expatriate Irish journalist, printer and publisher in Philadelphia, issued and sold fewer than 500 copies at a time when Catholics were an extremely small minority (some 35,000 of 4 million, or roughly 1 percent) of the nation’s population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to this book’s distinction and historical significance is that it was given to Father Badin at his ordination in 1793, the gift of Bishop John Carroll of Baltimore, himself the first Catholic bishop of the United States. The Bible is inscribed to Father Badin by Bishop Carroll, who ordained him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Notre Dame’s acquisition of the Badin Bible will link Father Badin’s Kentucky home with his Indiana one, and his early ministry as a priest with his final resting place,” said &lt;a href="http://cushwa.nd.edu/about/cushwa-center-staff/kathleen-sprows-cummings/"&gt;Kathleen Sprows Cummings&lt;/a&gt;, director of the &lt;a href="http://cushwa.nd.edu/"&gt;Cushwa Center for the Study of American Catholicism&lt;/a&gt;. “Far beyond the campus connection, however, Badin’s Bible represents a number of historic firsts in American Catholicism. This is a real treasure that will benefit the teaching and research of historians and Bible scholars at Notre Dame and beyond.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible will be on display in the &lt;a href="http://rarebooks.library.nd.edu/"&gt;Rare Books and Special Collections Room&lt;/a&gt; on the main floor of the Hesburgh Library during the fall semester. “The Badin Bible will be one of the most significant additions to the collection of Catholic Americana held in the Rare Books and Special Collections department of the Hesburgh Libraries,” said Catholic Studies librarian Jean McManus. “The later work of Stephen Badin, as a missionary to the Middle West, connects this Bible to the University of Notre Dame.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Heather Grennan Gary, Cushwa Center for the Study of American Catholicism, 574-631-4696&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49291-notre-dame-to-receive-father-badins-bible/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 10, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49179</id>
    <published>2014-07-03T18:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-03T18:38:49-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49179-two-arts-and-letters-professors-awarded-neh-fellowships/"/>
    <title>Two Arts and Letters professors awarded NEH Fellowships</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="National Endowment for the Humanities" src="http://al.nd.edu/assets/135975/neh_logo_300.jpg" title="National Endowment for the Humanities"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two faculty members from the University of Notre Dame’s College of Arts and Letters — &lt;a href="http://germanandrussian.nd.edu/german-faculty/"&gt;Tobias Boes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu/people/emeritus-faculty/eugene-ulrich/"&gt;Eugene Ulrich&lt;/a&gt; — have been awarded fellowships from the &lt;a href="http://www.neh.gov/"&gt;National Endowment for the Humanities&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEH&lt;/span&gt;) for the 2014–15 academic year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fellowships continue Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/about/the-faculty/fellowship-record/"&gt;record success with the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which supports advanced research across a broad spectrum of the humanities. Since 1999, Arts and Letters faculty members have been awarded 51 total &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEH&lt;/span&gt; grants — more than any other university in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ulrich, Rev. John A. O’Brien Professor of &lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu/"&gt;Theology&lt;/a&gt; Emeritus, is one of the world’s leading scholars of the Dead Sea Scrolls, a collection of ancient texts discovered after World War II in caves along the shore of the Dead Sea near Jerusalem. He also specializes in areas of the Hebrew Scriptures and the Septuagint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boes, an associate professor in the &lt;a href="http://germanandrussian.nd.edu"&gt;Department of German and Russian Languages and Literatures&lt;/a&gt;, focuses on the modernist period, the theory and history of the novel, and in cultural interactions between Germany and the world at large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tobias Boes" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135996/200x/tobias_boes_300.jpg" title="Tobias Boes"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Winning an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEH&lt;/span&gt; is a great honor,” said Boes, “not just because of all the great scholarship that has resulted from this program, but also because public funding for the humanities has been tragically cut in recent years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I see the award as a recognition of the continued importance of intercultural understanding, which my colleagues in the department and I try to communicate to our students every day.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boes will use the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEH&lt;/span&gt; fellowship to pursue work on his second book, “Down from the Magic Mountain: Thomas Mann, American Culture, and the Making of a Twentieth-Century Author.” The book focuses on the American reception of the German writer Thomas Mann during the 1930s and 1940s, a period that Mann largely spent in U.S. exile because he was a known enemy of the Nazis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I want to explore how Mann, who was an ardent German nationalist during the time of the First World War, could become one of the biggest champions of the American war effort during the Second World War,” he said. “He was a guest in the Roosevelt White House, an orator who praised the virtues of American democracy to capacity crowds all over the country, and the author of propaganda messages that were broadcast into occupied Europe.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, Boes plans to investigate the social networks that made it possible for Mann to reinvent himself — the publishers who marketed him, the translators who rendered him into English in a certain way, and the academic critics, journalists and tastemakers who presented him to a broader public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Ultimately, I want to argue that Mann is the first example of a new kind of writer who is still very much with us today,” he said, “the author who is read not just for the quality of his or her work, but also because people want to learn more about foreign and usually war-torn places that happen to be in the news.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Eugene Ulrich" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135997/200x/ulrich_248.jpg" title="Eugene Ulrich"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recipient of the John Simon Guggenheim fellowship as well as several previous &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEH&lt;/span&gt; grants, Ulrich has spent virtually his entire academic career editing and studying the Dead Sea Scrolls — arguably the greatest archeological find of the 20th century. In 1977, he received an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEH&lt;/span&gt; fellowship to publish his first Dead Sea Scroll, a scroll of the Book of Samuel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ulrich received this latest &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NEH&lt;/span&gt; fellowship for his work “Second Isaiah: A Critical Edition of the Hebrew Bible.” This edition, he said, is “made possible by the rich and surprising learnings these scrolls have taught us about the early stages of biblical composition — what we now know about the Bible that we didn’t 60 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This new book will be the first critical Hebrew edition of the major prophet whose work so greatly influenced both the Jewish Scrolls community and early Christianity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A member of the translation teams for both the New Revised Standard Version of the Bible and the “New American Bible: Revised Edition,” Ulrich also co-authored “The Dead Sea Scrolls Bible.” He is one of the three general editors of the Scrolls International Publication Project and chief editor of the Biblical Scrolls. He published six volumes of critical editions of the biblical scrolls in “Discoveries in the Judaean Desert,” and he was an Area Editor for Oxford’s “Encyclopedia of the Dead Sea Scrolls.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ulrich, who was accorded emeritus status in 2014, is a past president of the Catholic Biblical Association of America and a fellow of the &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/about/the-faculty/aaas-fellows/"&gt;American Academy of Arts and Sciences&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by Carrie Gates at &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/49166-two-arts-and-letters-professors-awarded-neh-fellowships/"&gt;al.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; on July 2.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Carrie Gates</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49180</id>
    <published>2014-07-03T18:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-03T18:46:39-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49180-notre-dame-energy-frontier-research-center-receives-further-doe-funding/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame Energy Frontier Research Center receives further DOE funding</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Graduate engineering research in Peter Burns' lab in Stinson-Remick" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135990/300x/burns_lab_full.jpg" title="Graduate engineering research in Peter Burns' lab in Stinson-Remick"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A University of Notre Dame research center has once again been designated an &lt;a href="http://science.energy.gov/bes/efrc/"&gt;Energy Frontier Research Center&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt;) by the U.S. Department of Energy (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOE&lt;/span&gt;) and will receive funding to help accelerate the scientific breakthroughs needed to build the 21st-century energy economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://science.energy.gov/bes/efrc/centers/msa/"&gt;Notre Dame &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, titled “Materials Science of Actinides,” was first &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/11640-doe-to-establish-energy-frontier-research-center-at-notre-dame/"&gt;designated as an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt; in 2009&lt;/a&gt; along with 45 other centers. This year, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOE&lt;/span&gt; awarded $100 million in funding to 32 projects. Ten of this year’s projects are new, while the rest received their funding based on both their achievements to date and the quality of their proposals. The 32 projects receiving funding were selected from more than 200 proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Notre Dame &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt;, which is directed by &lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/pburns"&gt;Peter Burns&lt;/a&gt;, Henry J. Massman Chair and Professor of Civil Engineering and Geological Sciences and concurrent professor of chemistry and biochemistry, received a $12 million, four-year grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With this renewed funding, we will continue to focus the efforts of a team of gifted scholars on issues related to nuclear energy that are of great importance to the nation,” Burns said. “The center structure allows us to unite experts from several disciplines to address scientific challenges that would be intractable with smaller, discipline-specific funding models. Continuation of the center also permits us to provide the best possible education to students at all levels who are involved in our research program.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of the center, which includes participants from several other universities and a national laboratory, is the elements that are the basis of nuclear energy — uranium, plutonium and other actinides. Research in the center will seek to understand and control materials that contain actinides at the nanoscale, which is about one-millionth of the size of the tip of a ball-point pen. This research is intended to lay the scientific foundation for advanced nuclear energy systems that may provide much more energy while creating less nuclear waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are mobilizing some of our most talented scientists to join forces and purse the discoveries and breakthroughs that will lay the foundation for our nation’s energy future,” U.S. Energy Secretary Ernest Moniz said in announcing the centers. “The funding we’re announcing today will help fuel scientific and technological innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A National Research Council report, titled “Assuring a Future U.S.-Based Nuclear and Radiochemistry Expertise,” stated: “The growing use of nuclear medicine, the potential expansion of nuclear power generation, and the urgent needs to protect the nation against external nuclear threats, to maintain our nuclear weapons stockpile, and to manage the nuclear wastes generated in past decades, require a substantial, highly trained, and exceptionally talented workforce.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its establishment in 2009, Notre Dame’s Materials Science of Actinides &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt; has supported 32 graduate students, including 16 women, in actinide sciences, eight of whom have graduated; 28 post-doctoral researchers; 53 undergraduate researchers, including 29 women; and it has hosted 19 visiting scholars. The center has organized and taught three short courses with 172 total participants, and organized five sessions at national and international conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame’s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt; partners include Stanford University, The University of California-Davis, the University of Minnesota, Oregon State University, the University of Tennessee, George Washington University, the University of Akron and Los Alamos National Laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Peter Burns, 574-631-7582, &lt;a href="mailto:pburns@nd.edu"&gt;pburns@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;William G. Gilroy&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49160-notre-dame-energy-frontier-research-center-receives-further-doe-funding/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 03, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>William G. Gilroy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49167</id>
    <published>2014-07-03T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-03T07:32:22-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49167-notre-dame-and-unc-chapel-hill-philosophers-to-examine-religious-and-transformative-experiences/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame and UNC-Chapel Hill philosophers to examine religious and transformative experiences</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Experience Project" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135687/sun_300.jpg" title="The Experience Project"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether as dramatic as the divine visions that inspired Mother Teresa’s work or as commonplace as the decision to have a child, certain events have the power to transform us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explore aspects of these religious and transformative experiences, philosophers &lt;a href="http://philosophy.nd.edu/people/faculty/michael-rea/"&gt;Michael Rea&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://philosophy.nd.edu/people/faculty/samuel-newlands/"&gt;Samuel Newlands&lt;/a&gt; of the University of Notre Dame’s College of Arts and Letters and philosopher &lt;a href="http://philosophy.unc.edu/people/faculty/laurie-a.-paul"&gt;L.A. Paul&lt;/a&gt; from the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill’s College of Arts and Sciences will co-direct “&lt;a href="http://the-experience-project.org/"&gt;The Experience Project&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a generous grant from the &lt;a href="http://www.templeton.org/"&gt;John Templeton Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, the project will examine questions such as: When and why do people have experiences that transform them? What effects do specific transformative experiences have on a person’s identity, values, beliefs or behaviors? How might a religious experience affect a person’s concept of God? How are religious transformative experiences different from other sorts of transformative experiences?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The $4.8 million project encompasses four major research initiatives. The first seeks to support scholars in philosophy, theology and religious studies who will explore various aspects of religious experiences. The remaining three initiatives will focus on the philosophy, psychology and sociology of transformative experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, The Experience Project will award funding to as many as 30 research teams. In addition, it will offer residential fellowships at both Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="https://philreligion.nd.edu/"&gt;Center for Philosophy of Religion&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://unc.edu/"&gt;University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill&lt;/a&gt; and invite scholars to a series of collaborative workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am genuinely excited about the potential for interdisciplinary dialogue,” Rea said, “and for cross-fertilization — people discovering ideas and results from other disciplines that will be of real use to them in their research.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Evidence of God&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame is the ideal place to engage in questions of religious experience and transformation, noted Rea, a professor in the &lt;a href="http://philosophy.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Philosophy&lt;/a&gt; who also co-directs the Center for Philosophy of Religion with Newlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This project will naturally immerse the researchers in the Catholic intellectual tradition,” he said. “And, the questions are significant not only to Christians, but to anyone whose beliefs and interests include religious experiences.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="Michael Rea" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135719/200x/mrea_300.jpg" title="Michael Rea"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Led by Rea, the religious experience component of the project will evaluate what constitutes a religious experience, whether these experiences provide evidence of the existence of God, and how such experiences alter the course of an individual’s life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers will explore the commonality of various types of religious experience — from historic examples like Blaise Pascal’s “night of fire” to a modern churchgoer feeling awash in divine love during a Sunday service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rea also plans to examine the implications of not having a religious experience. In a world of religious ambiguity, he said, the phenomenon of “divine hiddenness” is often cited as evidence that God does not exist or does not care. While he does not expect to find a definitive explanation for the absence of religious experience, Rea hopes to “undercut the inference” that a hidden God is not a loving God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If divine love is only analogically related to human love,” said Rea, “then perhaps you can’t infer from the fact that God is hidden that God doesn’t love us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ordinary, but momentous events&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Religious experiences are just one type of life-changing event The Experience Project will examine. Other components of the project focus on the broader realm of transformative experiences — from a student joining the Peace Corps to a person hearing music for the first time after a cochlear implant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Samuel Newlands" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/130824/samuel_newlands_200.jpg" title="Samuel Newlands"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A transformative experience,” said Paul, “is an enduring reorganization of a person’s thinking — for instance, his or her beliefs, attitudes, traits or emotions — that substantially alters life as one experiences it or lives it.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connecting these “ordinary, but momentous events people face every day” with precise philosophical and social science research, she said, has the potential to impact the decisions people make and the way they live their lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul, a professor in the &lt;a href="http://philosophy.unc.edu/"&gt;Department of Philosophy at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNC&lt;/span&gt;-Chapel Hill&lt;/a&gt;, said she is particularly interested in examining life-changing choices — whether having a baby or entering the priesthood — whose impacts can only be truly understood after they occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make such a decision rationally, Paul argues, requires a different mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can’t know what the lived experience is going to be like, because it’s going to be so radically different from your previous experience,” she said. “What we have to do when we approach these big decisions is to think of it explicitly in terms of a discovery or a revelation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So, life involves taking the plunge by discovering what kind of person you’re going to be when you become a parent, for example. That’s what living your life authentically is all about.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Life-changing experiences&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transformative experiences may be sudden or gradual, intentional or imposed, positive or negative, solitary or social. Whether they occur in the context of religion, family, social movement activism or another setting, they have the power to change not only our lives, but also our knowledge of what life can be like, Paul said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="L.A. Paul" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135721/lapaul_200.jpg" title="L.A. Paul"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Where an experience is both radically new and personally transformative — that’s where the interesting questions come up,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Rea and Paul’s work will focus on philosophical questions, The Experience Project will also include research led by psychology director &lt;a href="http://www.isites.harvard.edu/icb/icb.do?keyword=k3007&amp;amp;amp;panel=icb.pagecontent177929%3ArlistAlpha%248%3Falpha%3DC%26templateId%3D8729&amp;amp;amp;pageid=icb.page29924&amp;amp;amp;pageContentId=icb.pagecontent177929&amp;amp;amp;view=viewBio.do&amp;amp;amp;viewParam_bioUserId=AgFSTlNQTlBWVQAF%0D%0A&amp;amp;amp;viewParam_templateId=8729#a_icb_pagecontent177929"&gt;Fiery Cushman&lt;/a&gt; from Harvard University and sociology director &lt;a href="http://sociology.duke.edu/people?Gurl=&amp;amp;amp;Uil=14914&amp;amp;amp;subpage=profile"&gt;Stephen Vaisey&lt;/a&gt; from Duke University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul said she is particularly looking forward to jointly developing the project alongside psychologists and sociologists. This innovative approach, she said, “is making it possible for us to really push the frontiers of the idea forward.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href="http://the-experience-project.org/"&gt;the-experience-project.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Joshua Seachris, program director, Center for Philosophy of Religion, 574-631-5377, &lt;a href="mailto:jseachris@nd.edu"&gt;jseachris@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Carrie Gates&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49074-notre-dame-and-unc-chapel-hill-philosophers-to-examine-religious-and-transformative-experiences/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 30, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Carrie Gates</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49086</id>
    <published>2014-06-27T17:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-30T07:31:34-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49086-notre-dame-turbomachinery-facility/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame collaborating with five partners to build nation’s top turbine engine component research and testing facility</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135586/300x/turbomachinery_news.jpg" title="Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame and five public and private partners announced today Thursday (June 26) a &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/turbomachinery/"&gt;$36 million project&lt;/a&gt; that will be the nation’s foremost research and test facility for advancing the technology used in the massive gas turbine engines used by commercial and military aircraft, power plants, and the oil and gas industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Construction in South Bend’s &lt;a href="http://www.ignitionpark.com/"&gt;Ignition Park&lt;/a&gt; on a 43,000-square-foot building — of which 25,000 square feet will be for the &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/turbomachinery/"&gt;Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility&lt;/a&gt; — will begin this summer and be completed by March. The facility will be fully operational in July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This venture will be a cutting-edge research and testing facility for the turbine engine industry as well as a tremendous economic driver for our region,” said Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C., the University’s president. “Notre Dame is grateful to our partners for their support of this project and excited about all that it will mean to our University, the city and state, the industry as a whole and our nation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame will contribute $7.5 million to the project. Other partners are the General Electric Co., which has committed $13.5 million to fund research and testing for five years; the city of South Bend, which is contributing $4.4 million inclusive of equipment, land for a new power substation and tax abatements; the state of Indiana, through the Indiana Economic Development Corp., which is providing up to $600,000 in training grants and up to $2 million in infrastructure assistance; Great Lakes Capital, which is providing upfront capital of approximately $6 million to construct the facility; and Indiana Michigan Power, which will be investing $2 million in a new substation to provide the considerable power needed to operate the facility’s multiple test cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The center will allow GE’s industrial businesses to simulate full-scale engine operating environments,” said Rick Stanley, vice president and chief technologist for GE’s Power and Water business and a Notre Dame graduate. “The important rig testing we will do at the center builds upon GE’s already strong and long-standing technical relationship with the University. For years, GE has turned to Notre Dame for top technical talent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When fully operational, the Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility will provide about 60 new jobs to directly operate the center, with an average salary and benefits package of about $79,000. An additional 60 jobs are expected through the growth of local suppliers to support the facility’s need for precision manufactured components. At full operation, research expenditures generated through work conducted at the facility are expected to exceed $15 million annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The aerospace industry is reaching new heights in Indiana,” said Gov. Mike Pence. “Universities like Notre Dame and others across the state are providing avenues for discovery, proving that the sky is the limit in Indiana when it comes to bringing a big vision to life. The next great technological innovation could come from the mind of a Hoosier, highlighting for the world the full range of possibilities when investing in a state that works.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Neal, deputy mayor of South Bend, added: “Attracting such major investment speaks to South Bend’s economic future and its capacity to attract high-tech businesses. This project continues our city’s history of innovation and is more evidence of the benefits that South Bend’s economic and geographic advantages offer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame’s current Turbomachinery Laboratory has worked with industry and government partners to advance gas turbine engine technologies since 2003. Center researchers focus on the design and operation of test facilities that simulate full-scale engine operating environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new facility, which will feature five test bays for compressor and turbine rig testing, will take previous work to new heights by testing engine components at pressures and temperatures higher than any that exist at current U.S. university facilities. It also will be used to advance current working relationships with both government sponsors and all manufacturers of gas turbine engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are very excited to be launching the Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility,” said Robert J. Bernhard, the University’s vice president for research. “It will be a significant combination of world class research, building on an outstanding program, and local economic development. We are very grateful to our collaborating organizations, who have been outstanding partners in putting this project together.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the industry and government partnerships, Notre Dame plans to collaborate with researchers and staff at local and state colleges and universities in order to widen the educational mission of the new facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information is available at &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/turbomachinery/"&gt;http://www.nd.edu/turbomachinery/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Dennis Brown&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49032-notre-dame-turbomachinery-facility/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 26, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Dennis Brown</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49087</id>
    <published>2014-06-27T17:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-27T17:31:10-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49087-notre-dames-echo-program-ten-years-of-giving-jesus-a-good-name/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame’s Echo program: Ten years of 'giving Jesus a good name'</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Institute for Church Life Echo program" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/112062/icl_echo_300.jpg" title="Institute for Church Life Echo program"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://echo.nd.edu"&gt;Echo program&lt;/a&gt; will mark its 10th anniversary this weekend (June 27-29) with a campus reunion of its graduates, a dinner and a Mass celebrated by &lt;a href="http://studentaffairs.nd.edu/residential-life/residence-halls/dillon-hall/"&gt;Rev. Paul Doyle, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, rector of Dillon Hall, who once quipped of Echo’s graduates, “These people give Jesus a good name.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Established in 2004 by Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://icl.nd.edu/"&gt;Institute for Church Life&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ICL&lt;/span&gt;), Echo, a two-year service and master’s degree program, is intended to address a need for a new generation of catechetical leaders in the Catholic Church. While pursuing a Notre Dame master’s degree in theology, its participants also serve as apprentice ministers in parishes nationwide, living in small communities and sharing in the parish sacramental life. Most Echo graduates continue in professional ministry in parishes, Catholic high schools and dioceses, or in campus ministry at colleges and universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am so proud of our program and of the students we have graduated,” said &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ICL&lt;/span&gt; director &lt;a href="https://professorships.nd.edu/professorships/the-mcgrath-cavadini-director-of-the-institute-for-church-life-1/"&gt;John C. Cavadini&lt;/a&gt;. “They have assumed important leadership positions in dioceses, parishes and Catholic schools across the country. They are the avant garde in catechetical leadership for a new generation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Echo has graduated 96 such leaders in the last 10 years, and 46 Catholic dioceses and archdioceses, more than a quarter of those in the United States, have been served by them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s gratifying to know that Echo has given so many young Catholics who otherwise might not have considered parish catechetical ministry a great way to learn more about their faith and serve the Church around the country,” said Echo director &lt;a href="http://echo.nd.edu/meet-the-echo-community/echo-staff/colleen-moore"&gt;Colleen Moore&lt;/a&gt;. “It’s moving to hear from our partner dioceses, parishes and Catholic schools of the real impact Echo apprentices and graduates have on the faith lives of their communities. I’m proud of all that our graduates, diocesan partners and the University have done together to build up the catechetical mission of the Church over the last 10 years and look forward to seeing the fruit of the next 10.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last spring, Echo admitted its largest class to date, with 19 graduates from 14 colleges and universities, including six from Notre Dame. These graduate students will be serving as parish apprentice ministers in the archdioceses of Galveston-Houston, Texas; Indianapolis; and Salt Lake City; and in the dioceses of St. Augustine and St. Petersburg, Florida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://echo.nd.edu/baumbach"&gt;Jerry Baumbach&lt;/a&gt;, director emeritus of Echo, said that “this is such an exciting time for all who are or have been associated with Echo over the past decade. Their emerging leadership, commitment to catechesis and spirit of service carry forward Notre Dame’s hope-filled outreach to church and society.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Colleen Moore, 574-631-4920, &lt;a href="mailto:cmoore@nd.edu"&gt;cmoore@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49059-notre-dames-echo-program-ten-years-of-giving-jesus-a-good-name/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 27, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/49066</id>
    <published>2014-06-27T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-27T06:49:58-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/49066-ndigd-and-nd-gain-awarded-project-from-3ie-to-design-impact-evaluation-in-mozambique/"/>
    <title>NDIGD and ND-GAIN awarded project from 3ie to design impact evaluation in Mozambique</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Maputo, Mozambique" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135386/maputo_300.jpg" title="Maputo, Mozambique"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/span&gt;) and the &lt;a href="http://gain.org/"&gt;Notre Dame Global Adaptation Index&lt;/a&gt; (ND-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GAIN&lt;/span&gt;) will work with faculty and staff from the &lt;a href="http://www.ucm.ac.mz/cms/en-en"&gt;Universidade Católica de Moçambique&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;UCM&lt;/span&gt;) to assess the impacts of early-warning systems for climate-related disasters in Mozambique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mozambique is densely populated and located in low-lying coastal and river zones, making it extremely susceptible to natural disasters and climate change including cyclones, storms and floods. Community-based disaster management committees (CLGRCs) and decentralized early-warning systems are being created to cope with climate risks. Notre Dame will help to evaluate the success of programs established by aid from the German government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funded by the &lt;a href="http://www.3ieimpact.org/en/about/"&gt;International Initiative for Impact Evaluation&lt;/a&gt; (3ie), the research consortium composed of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/span&gt;, ND-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GAIN&lt;/span&gt; and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UCM&lt;/span&gt; experts will design a study to evaluate the impacts of CLGRCs and early-warning systems to show what and how interventions lead to increased climate resilience, and explore the degree of relevance and effectiveness of interventions across multiple sectors of the human and natural environment. The main focal zones of the project are Maputo and the Beira and Búzi districts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Notre Dame Vice President of Research &lt;a href="https://www.nd.edu/about/leadership/council/robert-bernhard/"&gt;Robert Bernhard&lt;/a&gt; said, “&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/span&gt; and ND-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GAIN&lt;/span&gt; look forward to developing this new partnership with 3ie. This project extends Notre Dame’s faculty expertise to measure the impact of disaster risk management and climate change adaptation, implemented by &lt;a href="http://www.giz.de/en/"&gt;Gesellschaft für Internationale Zusammenarbeit&lt;/a&gt; to enhance local resilience by building up early warning systems.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading the research team from the University of Notre Dame is &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/for-the-media/nd-experts/faculty/jessica-hellmann/"&gt;Jessica Hellmann&lt;/a&gt;, research director of ND-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GAIN&lt;/span&gt; and associate professor in the department of biological sciences. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/span&gt; and ND-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GAIN&lt;/span&gt; researchers collaborating on the project include &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/juan-carlos-guzman-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Juan Carlos Guzman&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/about-the-initiative/staff/lila-khatiwada-monitoring-and-evaluation-specialist/"&gt;Lila Khatiwada&lt;/a&gt;, monitoring and evaluation specialists with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/span&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://gain.org/our-team/dr-chen-chen"&gt;Chen Chen&lt;/a&gt;, research fellow from ND-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GAIN&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UCM&lt;/span&gt; will provide support through lead researcher Dennis Eucker, research coordinator and senior lecturer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hellmann said, “We are excited to be part of helping communities adapt to climate change, something that is desperately needed around the world as sea level rises and storms, drought and heat waves become more intense.” Scientists, including a recent report from the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, explain that large-scale adaptation to climate change will be necessary in the coming decades. “But we do not yet know how to evaluate the effectiveness of adaptation actions. Our project will be among the first to develop adaptation assessment so that efforts to make Mozambique more resilient can be replicated around the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/span&gt; provides expertise in monitoring and evaluation through teaching and research faculty of the University and a dedicated staff of experienced researchers and administrators, integrated across multiple disciplines. ND-GAIN’s mission is to enhance the world’s understanding of the importance of adaptation and facilitate public and private investments in vulnerable communities. ND-&lt;span class="caps"&gt;GAIN&lt;/span&gt; prepares &lt;a href="http://index.gain.org/"&gt;the world’s leading index&lt;/a&gt; showing which countries are best prepared to deal with global changes brought about by overcrowding, resource-constraints and climate disruption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3ie’s vision is to improve lives through impact evaluation, by increasing development effectiveness in developing countries. 3ie’s strategy is to generate new evidence of what works, synthesize and disseminate this evidence, build a culture of evidence-based policy-making and develop capacity to produce and use impact evaluations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Joya Helmuth, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NDIGD&lt;/span&gt; outreach associate, &lt;a href="mailto:jhelmuth@nd.edu"&gt;jhelmuth@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Joya Helmuth&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/48951-ndigd-and-nd-gain-awarded-project-from-3ie-to-design-impact-evaluation-in-mozambique/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 24, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Joya Helmuth</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/48970</id>
    <published>2014-06-20T19:10:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-20T19:14:30-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/48970-notre-dame-haiti-program-completes-yearly-mass-drug-administration/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame Haiti Program completes yearly mass drug administration</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Children at JUVENAT School in Haiti receive their annual medication from the Notre Dame Haiti Program to prevent lymphatic filariasis" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135293/mda_300.jpg" title="Children at JUVENAT School in Haiti receive their annual medication from the Notre Dame Haiti Program to prevent lymphatic filariasis"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of &lt;a href="http://haiti.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Haiti Program&lt;/a&gt; will complete the final mass drug administration (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt;) for this year in Arcahaie, Haiti, from Thursday-Sunday (June 19-22). The program, which aims to eliminate &lt;a href="http://haiti.nd.edu/lymphatic-filariasis/"&gt;lymphatic filariasis&lt;/a&gt;, a mosquito-borne endemic disease, from Haiti by the year 2020, has successfully completed &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; this year in Léogâne, Port-au-Prince and 19 other communes in the Caribbean country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the program completed &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; in the Carrefour commune, located at western end of the Port-au-Prince metropolitan area. More than 1,000 students at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;JUVENAT&lt;/span&gt; School, a private school in the region, were among those who received a combination of two drugs designed to treat the parasitic worm that causes lymphatic filariasis. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; site at the school was one of almost 500 such sites across the commune, about 20 percent of which were at schools, and each of which was expected to treat about 1,000 individuals during the four-day period. The Haitian Ministry of Health, with support from Notre Dame and its partner, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, was responsible for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; in the Port-au-Prince metropolitan area, as well as the Central Plateau and four other provinces, with close to 50 percent of the Haitian population being potential beneficiaries of the treatments sponsored by Notre Dame benefactors in 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; is one of several activities managed by the Notre Dame Haiti Program, founded by &lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/streit/"&gt;Rev. Thomas Streit&lt;/a&gt; two decades ago. The program also administers other activities including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A rapidly growing salt business, &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/46453-notre-dame-haiti-program-expands-distribution-of-disease-preventing-salt-nationwide/"&gt;Bon Sel Dayiti&lt;/a&gt;, that provides the Haitian population for the first time with clean salt that is co-fortified with diethylcarbamazine to combat lymphatic filariasis and with potassium iodate to address iodine deficiency disorder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A robust monitoring and evaluation program, led by lead researcher Father Streit, addressing the progress of both &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; and salt in eliminating lymphatic filariasis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A clinical partnership with a local hospital in the Léogâne area, about 20 miles west of Port-au-Prince, where the prevalence of lymphatic filariasis has been the highest and where wound care and psychosocial counseling help those afflicted with the disfiguring disease to regain their self-esteem, adapt to their physical challenges and remain productive members of the local community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continued advocacy to eliminate this and other neglected tropical diseases, possible only through the partnerships and the benevolence of the Notre Dame family.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://science.nd.edu/about/office-of-the-dean/carter/"&gt;Earl Carter&lt;/a&gt;, managing director of the Notre Dame Haiti Program, attributed the program’s success to Father Streit’s unwavering vision and the generosity and compassion of others. “We have been tremendously blessed these past years; corporations and foundations have stepped up, starting with the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates Foundation in 1999 and continuing with many others, who hand-in-hand with the extremely generous Notre Dame family have had a heart for helping the people of Haiti meet a significant problem head-on. By God’s grace, and through the sustained generosity of our partners and friends, we will be able to continue to partner in the fight to eliminate lymphatic filariasis, and meet the needs of those affected by the disease,” said Carter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year’s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MDA&lt;/span&gt; efforts, overseen by the Notre Dame Haiti Program, are made possible by the generous support of the Abbvie Foundation, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, Inter-American Development Bank, an anonymous philanthropic organization and the gifts of many other friends of the Notre Dame family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Earl Carter, 574-631-5404, &lt;a href="mailto:Earl.Carter@nd.edu"&gt;Earl.Carter@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Marissa Gebhard&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/48927-notre-dame-haiti-program-completes-yearly-mass-drug-administration/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 18, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Marissa Gebhard</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/48954</id>
    <published>2014-06-20T07:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-03T07:37:23-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/48954-trophy-wife-stereotype-is-largely-a-myth-new-study-shows/"/>
    <title>'Trophy wife' stereotype is largely a myth, new study shows</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Melania Knauss-Trump" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135196/trump_300.jpg" title="Melania Knauss-Trump"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t be so quick to judge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are familiar with the “trophy wife” stereotype that attractive women marry rich men, placing little importance on their other traits, including physical appearance, and that men look for pretty wives but don’t care about their education or earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New research, however, by University of Notre Dame sociologist &lt;a href="http://sociology.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-by-alpha/elizabeth-mcclintock/"&gt;Elizabeth McClintock&lt;/a&gt; shows the trophy wife stereotype is largely a myth fueled by selective observation that reinforces sexist stereotypes and trivializes women’s careers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In “&lt;a href="http://asr.sagepub.com/content/early/2014/05/29/0003122414536391.abstract"&gt;Beauty and Status: The Illusion of Exchange in Partner Selection?&lt;/a&gt;” forthcoming in American Sociological Review, McClintock resolves the paradox between the trophy wife stereotype and the evidence that couples match on both physical attractiveness and socioeconomic status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using, for the first time, a nationally representative sample of young couples in which both partners were interviewed and rated for physical attractiveness, McClintock was able to control for matching on attractiveness. She says prior research in this area has ignored two important factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I find that handsome men partner with pretty women and successful men partner with successful women,” says McClintock, who specializes in inequality within romantic partnerships. “So, on average, high-status men do have better-looking wives, but this is because they themselves are considered better looking — perhaps because they are less likely to be overweight and more likely to afford braces, nice clothes and trips to the dermatologist, etc. Secondly, the strongest force by far in partner selection is similarity — in education, race, religion and physical attractiveness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McClintock’s research shows that there is not, in fact, a general tendency for women to trade beauty for money. That is not to say trophy wife marriages never happen, just that they are very rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Donald Trump and his third wife, Melania Knauss-Trump, may very well exemplify the trophy wife stereotype,” McClintock says. “But, there are many examples of rich men who partner with successful women rather than ‘buying’ a supermodel wife. The two men who founded Google (Larry Page and Sergey Brin) both married highly accomplished women — one has a Ph.D. and the other is a wealthy entrepreneur.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="Elizabeth McClintock" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/92629/elizabeth_mcclintock_200x.jpg" title="Elizabeth McClintock"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McClintock says the trophy wife stereotype is most often wrongly applied among non-celebrities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve heard doctors’ wives referred to as trophy wives by observers who only notice her looks and his status and fail to realize that he is good-looking too and that she is also a successful professional — or was before she had kids and left her job,” McClintock says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McClintock’s research also indicates that, contrary to the trophy wife stereotype, social class barriers in the marriage market are relatively impermeable. Beautiful women are unlikely to leverage their looks to secure upward mobility by marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Elizabeth McClintock, 574-631-5218, &lt;a href="mailto:emcclint@nd.edu"&gt;emcclint@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Shannon Chapla&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/48903-trophy-wife-stereotype-is-largely-a-myth-new-study-shows/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 17, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Shannon Chapla</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/48953</id>
    <published>2014-06-20T06:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-20T06:59:01-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/48953-heidelberg/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame and Heidelberg University sign memorandum of understanding</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Nick Entrikin (front left) poses with Bernhard Eitel, rector of Heidelberg University, Germany, and other representatives of Heidelberg University" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135154/heidelberg_notre_dame_300.jpg" title="Nick Entrikin (front left) poses with Bernhard Eitel, rector of Heidelberg University, Germany, and other representatives of Heidelberg University"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representatives of the University of Notre Dame and &lt;a href="http://www.uni-heidelberg.de/index_e.html"&gt;Heidelberg University&lt;/a&gt; signed a general memorandum of understanding April 11 that will serve as the basis for an exploration of joint research, academic exchanges and other cooperative activities between the two institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heidelberg’s Rector &lt;a href="http://www.uni-heidelberg.de/institutions/rectorate/bernhard_eitel.html"&gt;Bernhard Eitel&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/about/leadership/council/nicholas-entrikin/"&gt;Nicholas Entrikin&lt;/a&gt;, Notre Dame’s vice president and associate provost for internationalization, signed the memorandum. Notre Dame will be the first American partner of Heidelberg University.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The institutions will be exploring areas such as joint meetings and conferences; academic exchanges involving undergraduates, graduate students, professional students and faculty; and joint research activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The memorandum of understanding comes on the heels of ongoing cooperation between Notre Dame and Heidelberg, including a visit to Heidelberg by a Notre Dame delegation last year. “We are pleased to have a growing partnership with the Heidelberg, one of the leading universities in Germany,” said Entrikin. “This agreement represents the beginning of many new opportunities for our faculty and students to collaborate in research, international study programs, academic conferences and other exchange programs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1386, Heidelberg University, a state university of Baden-Württemberg, is Germany’s oldest university. In addition to strong programs in the humanities, Heidelberg has many notable strengths, especially in the natural sciences. It has a leading medical school, and its &lt;a href="http://www.dkfz.de/en/index.html"&gt;German Cancer Research Center&lt;/a&gt; is one of the world’s leaders in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another strength of Heidelberg lies in its numerous collaborations and alliances with non-university research institutions and companies in Heidelberg and the Rhine-Neckar region and its strong involvement in two top-level clusters of the &lt;a href="http://www.bmbf.de/en/"&gt;Federal Ministry of Education and Research&lt;/a&gt;. It also has a strong international network of partners in research and teaching and has demonstrated excellence in research through the &lt;a href="http://www.dfg.de/en/research_funding/programmes/excellence_initiative/"&gt;German Research Foundation Excellence Initiative&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;William G. Gilroy&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/47700-heidelberg/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 16, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>William G. Gilroy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/48886</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-16T09:10:38-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/48886-theodore-j-cachey-jr-named-academic-director-of-notre-dames-rome-global-gateway/"/>
    <title>Professor Theodore J. Cachey Jr. named director of Notre Dame’s Rome Global Gateway</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Theodore J. Cachey Jr." src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135002/cachey_166.jpg" title="Theodore J. Cachey Jr."&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Professor &lt;a href="http://romancelanguages.nd.edu/people/all-faculty-by-alpha/theodore-j-cachey-jr/"&gt;Theodore J. Cachey Jr.&lt;/a&gt;, the Albert J. and Helen M. Ravarino Family Director of Dante and Italian Studies at the University of Notre Dame, has been named the inaugural academic director of the University’s Rome &lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu/about/notre-dame-global-gateways/"&gt;Global Gateway&lt;/a&gt;. The appointment, effective July 1, was announced by &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/about/leadership/council/nicholas-entrikin/"&gt;J. Nicholas Entrikin&lt;/a&gt;, vice president and associate provost for internationalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are delighted that Ted has joined the &lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu"&gt;Notre Dame International&lt;/a&gt; team,” Entrikin said. “He is a visionary, innovative academic leader who brings a wealth of experience working collaboratively across disciplines, a quality that is vital to success in his new role.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/47393-notre-dame-to-bless-new-global-gateway-in-rome/"&gt;Rome Global Gateway&lt;/a&gt;, based in a newly renovated building on Via Ostilia within two blocks of the Colosseum, serves as the focal point for academic, cultural and Catholic mission-related endeavors of the University in Rome. Notre Dame’s presence in Rome dates back nearly five decades, through faculty research and student programs of the &lt;a href="http://architecture.nd.edu"&gt;School of Architecture’s&lt;/a&gt; Rome Studies Program. It has expanded over the years through participation of other colleges and schools, most notably, the &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu"&gt;College of Arts and Letters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the gateway’s director, Cachey will work with Notre Dame colleagues — and other partners from across Italy, Europe and elsewhere — to increase the University’s engagement in the world through student programs, research, scholarly conferences and events, and a variety of outreach initiatives. He is charged with ensuring the overall quality, diversity and integrity of the programming at the facility. Through Notre Dame International, the University also maintains Global Gateways in &lt;a href="http://www.notredameasia.org/"&gt;Beijing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://oconnellhouse.nd.edu/"&gt;Dublin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://tantur.org/"&gt;Jerusalem&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu/about/notre-dame-global-gateways/london-global-gateway/"&gt;London&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://provost.nd.edu/about/assistant-provosts/assistant-provost-for-europe/"&gt;Warren von Eschenbach&lt;/a&gt;, who has been serving as interim director of the Rome Global Gateway since November 2013, will continue in his role as assistant provost for Europe and director of Notre Dame’s London Global Gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Notre Dame is well on its way to building a strong presence in Europe,” according to von Eschenbach, “and because of his talent and creativity, Ted will be a key partner in ensuring that the European Global Gateways enhance the international experience of our students and extend the international reach of our faculty’s scholarship and research.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A professor of Italian, Cachey also serves as director of &lt;a href="https://italianstudies.nd.edu/"&gt;Italian Studies&lt;/a&gt; at Notre Dame and as director of the &lt;a href="http://www.dante.nd.edu/"&gt;William and Katherine Devers Program in Dante Studies&lt;/a&gt;. He earned his B.A. from Northwestern University and his Ph.D. from the University of California, Los Angeles. His primary research interests are in Italian Medieval and Renaissance literature (particularly Dante, Petrarch and Boccaccio), the history of the Italian language and the literature and history of travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For additional information on the Rome Global Gateway, contact Cachey at &lt;a href="mailto:tcachey@nd.edu"&gt;tcachey@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
For information on academic programming for all of Notre Dame’s Global Gateways, contact Robert Norton at &lt;a href="mailto:rnorton@nd.edu"&gt;rnorton@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;. For information on Notre Dame Global Gateway facilities, contact Tom Guinan, &lt;a href="mailto:tguinan@nd.edu"&gt;tguinan@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Notre Dame News&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/48831-theodore-j-cachey-jr-named-academic-director-of-notre-dames-rome-global-gateway/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 12, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Notre Dame News</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/48887</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-16T09:37:35-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/48887-notre-dame-partners-with-edx-to-offer-open-online-courses/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame partners with edX to offer open online courses</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="edX Consortium" class="noborder" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/134734/edx_logo_200x.jpg" title="edX Consortium"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame on Wednesday (June 11) announced that it has joined the &lt;a href="https://www.edx.org/"&gt;edX Consortium&lt;/a&gt; as a charter member. A not-for-profit partnership of leading global universities, edX is committed to innovations in online and blended learning, improving access to education, and researching effective learning for use on and beyond college campuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, edX members offer more than 200 open online courses to learners worldwide in a range of academic areas, including engineering, the humanities, natural sciences, computer science and public health. Notre Dame will use edX courses — along with educational media, innovative tools and strategies and the data they yield — in the service of effective teaching and learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Notre Dame and edX have shared philosophical interests,” said &lt;a href="http://president.nd.edu"&gt;Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, Notre Dame’s president. “We are delighted to partner with edX to advance the cause of open learning and improve access to education on a global scale. Notre Dame looks forward to joining the other extraordinary colleges and universities in the edX Consortium to improve human flourishing through education.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Open online education done well extends the values and aspirations of a residential university such as Notre Dame,” said &lt;a href="http://english.nd.edu/people/profiles/visconsi/"&gt;Elliott Visconsi&lt;/a&gt;, the University’s chief academic digital officer. “By joining the edX Consortium, we reaffirm our broader commitment to provide an unparalleled education for our students, assert our intention to create new knowledge for the public good and pledge to use technology to enhance rather than erode the bond between teacher and learner.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://online.nd.edu/"&gt;Office of Digital Learning&lt;/a&gt; will announce its first four edX courses, to be launched in spring 2015, at a later date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in April 2012 by Harvard and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;MIT&lt;/span&gt;, edX was created for students and institutions that seek to transform themselves through cutting-edge technologies, innovative pedagogy and rigorous courses. It presents the best of education online, offering opportunity to anyone who wants to achieve, thrive and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the other edX charter members are institutions including UC Berkeley, Tsinghua University, Cornell University, Rice University, Peking University, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IIT&lt;/span&gt; Bombay, Catholic University of Louvain, Columbia University and the University of Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Elliott Visconsi, chief academic digital officer, &lt;a href="mailto:eviscons@nd.edu"&gt;eviscons@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/EVisconsi"&gt;@EVisconsi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Shannon Chapla&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/48799-notre-dame-partners-with-edx-to-offer-open-online-courses/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 11, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Shannon Chapla</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/48857</id>
    <published>2014-06-13T11:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-27T06:50:12-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/48857-peter-kogge-receives-2014-babbage-award/"/>
    <title>Peter Kogge receives 2014 Babbage Award</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Peter M. Kogge" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/134617/pmkogge_281.jpg" title="Peter M. Kogge"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Notre Dame computer science and engineering professor &lt;a href="http://www3.nd.edu/~kogge/"&gt;Peter M. Kogge&lt;/a&gt;, developer of the space shuttle I/O processor, the world’s first multicore processor, and a number of other important innovations, was awarded the &lt;a href="http://www.ipdps.org/babbage_award.htm"&gt;Charles Babbage Award&lt;/a&gt; at the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers’ (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IEEE&lt;/span&gt;) 2014 International Parallel &amp;amp; Distributed Processing Symposium in Phoenix earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Babbage Award, presented since 1989, is bestowed in recognition of exceptional contributions to the field. Considered the father of the computer, Babbage is the English mathematician, philosopher, inventor and mechanical engineer who originated the concept of a programmable computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kogge, who has served as the Ted H. McCourtney Professor of the &lt;a href="http://cse.nd.edu"&gt;Department of Computer Science and Engineering&lt;/a&gt; at Notre Dame since 1994, was recognized “for innovations in advanced computer architecture and systems.” His research areas include massively parallel processing architectures, advanced &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VLSI&lt;/span&gt; and nanotechnologies and their relationship to computing systems architectures, non-von Neumann models of programming and execution, and parallel algorithms and applications and their impact on computer architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kogge has been at the forefront of several innovations that have shaped the computing industry over the past several decades. While working on his doctorate at Stanford University in the 1970s, he invented the Kogge-Stone adder process, what is still considered the fastest way of adding numbers in a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During his 26-year career at &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt;, Kogge, an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt; Fellow, designed the space shuttle I/O processor, one of the first multithreaded computers and the first to fly in space. Kogge was also inventor of the world’s first multicore processor, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;EXECUBE&lt;/span&gt;, which he and his &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBM&lt;/span&gt; team placed on a memory chip in an early effort to solve the data bottleneck problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IEEE&lt;/span&gt; Fellow, Kogge also won the &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/34281-professor-peter-kogge-named-recipient-of-ieee-computer-society-2012-seymour-cray-award/"&gt;2012 Seymour Cray Award&lt;/a&gt;. He is the co-inventor on more than three dozen patents and the author of two textbooks, including the first textbook on pipelining, a now ubiquitous technique for executing multiple instructions in a computer in parallel. He has also led a team of computer professionals for the U.S. Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency to explore development of a supercomputer capable of executing a quintillion mathematical operations per second.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Nina Welding&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/48764-peter-kogge-receives-2014-babbage-award/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 09, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Nina Welding</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:provost.nd.edu,2005:News/48862</id>
    <published>2014-06-13T11:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-13T12:06:58-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://provost.nd.edu/news/48862-ace-bus-homecoming/"/>
    <title>Alliance for Catholic Education's National Bus Tour comes home</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/assets/134644/original/ace_bus_infographic_6_14_300_dpi.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="ACE Bus infographic" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/134644/300x/ace_bus_infographic_6_14_300_dpi.jpg" title="ACE Bus infographic"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After traveling 30,000 miles to visit more than 16,000 Catholic school students throughout the past year, the &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu"&gt;Alliance for Catholic Education’s&lt;/a&gt; celebration of the gift of Catholic schools is just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu/20"&gt;Fighting for Our Children’s Future National Bus Tour&lt;/a&gt; visited 65 K-12 Catholic schools across 35 states to celebrate the vital role these and thousands of other Catholic schools play in serving poor and marginalized students and their communities. According to ACE’s founders, those 30,000 miles are just the first step in changing the narrative on Catholic schools — a narrative that has been plagued with school closures for the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The story being told in Catholic schools should be one of zeal, one of joy and one of promise,” &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu/directory/fr-tim-scully-csc"&gt;Rev. Timothy R. Scully, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, founder of the Alliance for Catholic Education at the University of Notre Dame, said. “We set out with the mantra that ‘Catholic schools are good for America,’ that they are absolutely vital for our children, our communities and our nation. The stories we have witnessed on the road and the amazing people we have met along the way have deepened our commitment to Notre Dame’s mission to serve these sacred places.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father Scully noted that research clearly shows a continuing Catholic school advantage. Ninety-nine percent of Catholic school students graduate high school on time, and 85 percent attend college. Studies also show that Catholic school graduates tend to be more civically engaged, more likely to vote, more tolerant of diverse views, more committed to service as adults and less likely to be incarcerated than their peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this advantage, Catholic schools have struggled in recent years. ACE’s tour, and its mission to strengthen, sustain and transform these schools, set out to raise awareness of the success of this proven model and of the profound impact the schools have on nearly two million students who attend them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The future of Catholic schools is bright, but our work is just beginning,” said &lt;a href="http://politicalscience.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-list/sean-mcgraw-csc/"&gt;Rev. Sean McGraw, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, who co-founded &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt; 20 years ago with Scully. “We continue to engage in an effort to provide solutions to what is certainly America’s greatest civic challenge: ensuring that every American child, especially the most vulnerable, has the opportunity for a quality education.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/43146-notre-dame-kicks-off-fighting-for-our-children-s-future-national-bus-tour/"&gt;National Bus Tour&lt;/a&gt; kicked off in Dallas in October 2013 in conjunction with the &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/43154-notre-dame-to-go-big-in-texas-with-shamrock-series-events/"&gt;Notre Dame Shamrock Series&lt;/a&gt; football game before visiting schools and honoring local education champions in the Midwest and on the East Coast. In November, as the bus rolled into New York City, the Manhattan Institute honored Father Scully with the &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/44231-rev-tim-scully-receives-manhattan-institute-s-william-e-simon-prize/"&gt;William E. Simon Prize for Lifetime Achievement in Social Entrepreneurship&lt;/a&gt; for his founding and leadership of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bus headed south in February to revisit ACE’s roots and long-standing partnerships throughout the Gulf Coast. March featured visits throughout Oklahoma, Colorado and Texas, while April included trips to Chicago and Minnesota. The tour wrapped up the 2013-2014 academic year in May with trips through West Coast cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday (June 9), the University of Notre Dame will welcome the bus and the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt; team home, and will honor two members of the South Bend and Notre Dame communities — &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu/about/south-bend-homecoming"&gt;Jay Caponigro and Maritza Robles&lt;/a&gt; — with the University of Notre Dame Champion for Education Award. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt; will also present the Notre Dame Sorin Award for Service to Catholic Schools to Brian and Jeannelle Brady, without whom the bus tour would not have been possible. The homecoming coincides with the start of the &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu/summer"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt; Summer&lt;/a&gt;, when more than 800 teachers, school leaders and Catholic school supporters — including 95 new teachers who make up &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu/teach/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt; Service through Teaching’s&lt;/a&gt; 21st cohort — converge on Notre Dame’s campus for leadership formation and other opportunities focused on building a brighter future for Catholic schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Bill Schmitt, 574-631-3893, &lt;a href="mailto:wschmitt@nd.edu"&gt;wschmitt@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/ACEatND"&gt;@ACEatND&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://twitter.com/theACEBus"&gt;@theACEBus&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Notre Dame News&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/48746-ace-bus-homecoming/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 09, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Notre Dame News</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
