<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>School of Education Blog</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/atom.xml" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2011-07-20:/education/blog//93</id>
    <updated>2014-07-11T23:48:09Z</updated>
    <subtitle>This is the blog for the School of Education at Sonoma State University</subtitle>
    <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type 4.26</generator>

<entry>
    <title>A (Tues)Day in the Life of a Multiple Subject Credential Student Teacher at Sonoma State</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/06/life-of-a-credential-student-teacher.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17422</id>

    <published>2014-06-30T18:55:36Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-11T23:48:09Z</updated>

    <summary>By Guest Author: Jessica Hernandez Being a credential student at times can be challenging, especially if you are a mother and a wife as well. Being a credential student requires discipline and commitment. But, knowing you&apos;re making a difference in...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byGabrielle Cordero</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Literacy, Elementary, and Early Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="jessicahernandez" label="Jessica Hernandez" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomacountyofficeofeducation" label="sonoma county office of education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<p>By Guest Author: Jessica Hernandez</p>

<p>Being a credential student at times can be challenging, especially if you are a mother and a wife as well.  Being a credential student requires discipline and commitment. But, knowing you're making a difference in the lives of children validates everything.</p>

<p>For part-time student teachers in the <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/leee/multiple-subject/index.html">Multiple Subject Program</a> like me, you usually have two days at the university taking classes and two days at your placement site. In one of those site days you have a seminar class. On the other days you have an option to spend time substitute teaching during the day and in the afternoon doing homework if you want more experience. The following is a snap shot of a typical Tuesday in my life this semester.</p>

<img alt="quote from blog: Being a credential student takes hard work and dedication.  But, knowing you are helping children validates everything" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/quote2.jpg" width="250" class="border left"  /><p>On Tuesday, up at 6:00 a.m get ready and everything ready for my twins for Day Care. At 7:30 I head to my school site. It's a 30 minute to and from the site in Santa Rosa to my home in Cloverdale. Arrive at 8:00, sign in at the office and drop my reflection sheet for the week for the site supervisor to read. Class starts, for the first half hour students come to my desk for help. Teacher opens the class each morning allowing students to work on things that they may need to catch up on. After my mentor teacher starts the class. The full-time student teacher and I (the part-time student teacher) sit and correct papers for the teacher. From time to time I will stop and take notes on what I observe. Later I take a group of students to the library for reading. After reading we go back to class. The full-timer student teacher is doing a lesson. I help, in whatever she wants me to help her. During recess, our mentor teacher has study hall and the full-timer and I take turns going to the restroom since students cannot be left unsupervised.</p>

<p>From 12:00 -1:30 p.m we have our site seminar, this seminar will be different depending of which school site you are in. For us it was on Tuesday and typically between this time. In seminar we learned about different things we wanted to learn about teaching. At the beginning of the semester we brainstormed ideas and decided on the topics. Some seminar days were exclusively about PACT (Performance Assessment for California Teachers) for the full-timers, one was about CWS-1 (Candidate Work Sample)  for the part-timers. But, most of the time the seminars were in teachers' classrooms where different teachers talked to us about topics like; classroom management, back to school night, Common Core Standards, etc. Most of the time, it was during upper grades' lunch, so we had to eat our lunches during that time as well.

<p>After seminar, we went back to class, assisted our mentor in whatever she wanted us to do. Sometimes it was correcting, copying, taking down projects from the wall and displaying new projects on the wall. Sometimes, I would leave the class to observe other peers doing a lesson in different classrooms.as a part-timer you're required to do four peer observations After we would have a debrief session where we talked about what we observed about the lessons. Then I would return to my class and walk around helping students and observing. Then we head to the gym for P.E. before school ended. I always participate in the lesson. I believe it's important for students to see you as the teacher willing to do what you want them to do. Plus, it's fun to move around and play with your students. Class is dismissed at 2:54 p.m.</p>

<p>We went back to the classroom to plan for the next day and next week. Sometimes we would have auto duty in that case we would be doing that for at least 40 minutes. After school is your opportunity to ask questions about anything you saw or anything you have questions about. During this time I would plan with my mentor on anything she wanted to let me teach for the next day or what I could teach next week. Sometimes we would leave this planning for the next day. Usually I would stay at the site until 3:30. Headed to the university for a class from 4-6:40. Then head back home.</p>

<p>When I got home I attended to my parental duties. Once my twins were in bed. I finished doing homework. Work on my lesson plan for the next day or for the following week. Usually this was a two hour deal on a good day. Then off to sleep I went.</p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Alumna Kaki McLachlan selected as 2014 PBS Digital Innovator </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/06/alumna-kaki-mclachlan-selected-as-2014-pbs-digital-innovator.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17411</id>

    <published>2014-06-20T22:15:37Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-26T18:56:04Z</updated>

    <summary> Kaki McLachlan shares an interactive project at the 2013 Teacher Technology Showcase at Sonoma State As education is rapidly running to catch up with today&apos;s digital advances, institutions have begun to acknowledge and reward educators who are helping pave...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byLina Raffaelli</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Curiculum Studies and Secondary Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Graduate Studies" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="School of Education News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="alumna" label="alumna" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="alumni" label="alumni" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="cirriculumteachingandlearning" label="Cirriculum Teaching and Learning" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="ctl" label="CTL" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="digitalliteracy" label="digital literacy" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="digitalmedia" label="digital media" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="edtech" label="EdTech" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="educationaltechnology" label="educational technology" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="innovation" label="innovation" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="kakimclachlan" label="Kaki McLachlan" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="pbs" label="PBS" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="science" label="science" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="singlesubject" label="single subject" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="whitehillmiddleschool" label="White Hill Middle School" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<div class="caption right" style="width:305px;">
<img src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/kaki.jpg"  width="305" height="" alt="Kaki McLachlan at the 2013 Teacher Technology Showcase at Sonoma State" /><p><sub>Kaki McLachlan shares an interactive project at the 2013 Teacher Technology Showcase at Sonoma State </sub></p> </div> 

<p>As education is rapidly running to catch up with today's digital advances, institutions have begun to acknowledge and reward educators who are helping pave the way through useful and creative classroom strategies.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.pbslearningmedia.org/collection/digitalinnovators/">PBS LearningMedia Digital Innovators Program</a> is a year-long professional development program designed to foster and grow a community of ed-tech leaders. Each year PBS hand-selects 100 digitally-savvy K-12 educators who are effectively using digital media and technology in their schools to further student engagement and achievement.</p>

<p>School of Education Alumna Kaki McLachlan, graduate of the <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/csse/single-subject/index.html">Single Subject Credential Program</a> and Master's in Education in&nbsp;<a href="https://www.sonoma.edu/education/graduate/masters/ctl/index.html">Curriculum, Teaching, and Learning</a>, has been selected for this honor for the 2014-2015 school year.</p>

<p> "When students use technology in the classroom it allows them to take ownership of what they are learning," said McLachlan. "It is also an engaging way for students to gather up-to-date information in a variety of ways and share what they have learned in more exciting ways then ever before!" </p>

<p><img alt="Kaki McLachlan" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/kaki-mclaughlin.jpg" width="200" class="border left" style="" />She acknowledges that all the new technology can be confusing for teachers.  "New amazing resources are available each and every day for teachers. At times, it can be overwhelming, but it's not necessary to know it all!" Trying a new technology with students can be a risk, and doesn't always work perfectly. She notes, "It's important to remember, as a teacher, that not every lesson is going to be a success. This is especially important to remember when you begin to implement new projects with technology in the classroom. It is okay to fail! We are students too."  </p>

<p>McLachlan teaches science and technology to 6th-8th graders at <a href="http://www.rossvalleyschools.org/index.php/whitehill">White Hill Middle School</a> in Fairfax. In addition to teaching life science, this year she took on two brand new technology elective courses focusing on digital citizenship and media. </p>

<p>Throughout the year McLachlan will participate in various virtual trainings in educational technology. As a Digital Innovator, she is expected to lead several professional development activities in the 2014-2015 school year to share her innovations with other educators within her school and district&nbsp;</span></p>

<p>The PBS Learning Media Digital Innovators Summit was held in June, hosted at the PBS headquarters in Washington D.C. You can learn more about Digital Innovators by following the event on Twitter at #pbsdigitalinnovator and #pbsdisummit.</p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Summer Technology Institute engages faculty with new tools </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/06/draft-summer-technology-institute.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17442</id>

    <published>2014-06-20T17:47:48Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-20T21:19:29Z</updated>

    <summary>Faculty members across different departments discuss resources As summer break got underway, faculty and staff of Sonoma State gathered for the Summer Technology Institute May 20-22. Attendees spent three days discussing and engaging with educational technology tools The mantra of...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byLina Raffaelli</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="EdTech" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="School of Education News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="collaborative" label="collaborative" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="discussion" label="discussion" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="edtech" label="Ed tech" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="educationaltechnology" label="Educational Technology" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="faculty" label="faculty" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="googledocs" label="Google Docs" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="group" label="group" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="hybridcourse" label="hybrid course" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="ipads" label="iPads" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="learning" label="learning" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="lecture" label="lecture" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="moodle" label="Moodle" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="padlet" label="Padlet" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="professionaldevelopment" label="professional development" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="schoolofed" label="School of Ed" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="schoolofeducation" label="School of Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="soesti" label="SOESTI" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastate" label="Sonoma State" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastateuniversity" label="Sonoma State University" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="ssu" label="SSU" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="staff" label="staff" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="summerinstitute" label="summer institute" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="technology" label="technology" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="training" label="training" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="workshop" label="workshop" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<div class="caption right" style="width:302px;"><img alt="Faculty members across different departments discuss resources" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/blog2.jpg" width="300" height="" class="mt-image-right"/><p>Faculty members across different departments discuss resources</p></div>

As summer break got underway, faculty and staff of Sonoma State gathered for the <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/edtech/soesti.html">Summer Technology Institute</a> May 20-22. Attendees spent three days discussing and engaging with educational technology tools<br><br> 
The mantra of the 3-day session was "Ask, Play, Learn, Share!" This idea was developed in hopes of creating a stress-free environment for experimentation.<br><br>

The Summer Institute combined lectures, hands-on workshops and discussions all based around educational technology. Attendees were introduced to a variety of tools and platforms to try. Presentations included using Twitter to build a "professional learning network," ways to increase engagement using Moodle, and group participation using the <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2013/10/ed-tech-tips-blog-post---padlet-vialogues-todaysmeet.html">Padlet</a> web application. Faculty were also introduced to Google Drive and the opportunities for collaborative work, hybrid course development, and introductions to iMovie.<br><br>


<div class="caption right" style="width:302px;"><img alt="iPad instruction" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/blog7.jpg" width="300" height="" class="mt-image-right"/><p>Workshop included iPad instruction & classroom app integration</p></div>
Presentations and workshops were led both by School of Education faculty as well as outside sources. Speakers included Sarah Fountain, principal of <a href="http://crpusd.schoolwires.net/montevista">Monte Vista Elementary School</a>, Shira Katz from <a href="https://www.commonsensemedia.org/">Common Sense Media</a>, and Robin Mencher from <a href="http://blogs.kqed.org/education/">KQED Education</a>. <br><br>


Professor Michael Lesch said he was appreciative of the light-hearted approach to the workshop. Appreciative of both the structure and atmosphere at the institute, he noted   "Jessica [Parker] was sensitive to our fears about technology."  Other participants expressed similar sentiments.
 
"For children today technology is just an extension of their identities," said Parker. "But for those of us who haven't grown up with it we need to adopt and share this mindset to help lessen anxiety," she said about the mantra. "We can't do it as separate individuals, it must be collaborative," she added.<br><br>

During the debrief on the final day attendees broke into discussion groups to consider the practical applications of the tech tools they'd learned. 

Anthropology professor Karin Jaffee put many of the ideas to use right away in her summer class. "I used a Google Doc to have students 'build' our first lecture by filling in a table with terms and answering questions I would normally answer in a PowerPoint presentation. I also used Padlet to get students to answer questions that I would also normally address with a PowerPoint. Both assignments resulted in much conversation among the students, who were divided into groups, and also allowed me to have a class discussion to highlight good answers and address problematic ones. And I've already received feedback from the students indicating that they like the increased in-class participation! I'm thrilled with what I learned at SOESTI and so glad I've been able to implement ideas so quickly and successfully!"
<br><br>

Faculty member Erma Jean-Sims said she saw the potential for Padlet in her classes. "I like that it's instantaneous. Students are seeing and responding in real time," she said. "It could be especially helpful for getting more introverted students to participate, those who wouldn't normally raise their hands." <br><br>

The general consensus was that educational technology needs to be used in practical, purposeful and usable ways. It's important to strike a delicate balance between engagement and distraction for students. Robin Mencher of KQED summed up this idea by saying "technology is the vehicle, but not the driver," said Robin Mencher of KQED. Educators must be the facilitators to help guide their classes. 
<br><br><b>
<a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2013/10/ed-tech-tips-blog-post---padlet-vialogues-todaysmeet.html">Click here to view list of Summer Tech resources</a></b>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Why Learn About Being an Entrepreneurial Educator--an #Edupreneur?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/06/why-learn-about-being-an-entrepreneurial-educator.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17501</id>

    <published>2014-06-13T18:38:14Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-13T19:15:03Z</updated>

    <summary><![CDATA[Guest Blogger Dr. Paul Porter, SSU Professor of Educational Leadership Educators + Entrepreneurialism = Edupreneurialism"Edupreneurialism?" &nbsp;Just another term or something meaningful?&nbsp; As an instructor in this course The Entrepreneurial Educator, of course, I lean towards the term having great meaning.&nbsp;...]]></summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byPamela Van Halsema</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Careers" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Curiculum Studies and Secondary Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="EdTech" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Educational Leadership and Special Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Graduate Studies" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="paulporter" label="Paul Porter" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="schoolofbusinessandeconomics" label="School of Business and Economics" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="schoolofeducation" label="School of Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Guest Blogger <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/else/faculty/porter-p.html">Dr. Paul Porter</a>, SSU Professor of <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/else/edel.html">Educational Leadership</a></p>

<a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/edupreneur/"><img alt="logo-ssulogo-web-border.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/logo-ssulogo-web-border.jpg" width="250" class="left" /></a>
<p>Educators + Entrepreneurialism = Edupreneurialism</p><p>"Edupreneurialism?" &nbsp;Just another term or
something meaningful?&nbsp; As an instructor in this course <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/edupreneur/course.html">The Entrepreneurial Educator</a>, of course, I lean
towards the term having great meaning.&nbsp; For too many years educators have
avoided any ties to business, and business has criticized education's
graduates.&nbsp; This artificial separation has led to neither side being able
to benefit from the depth and wisdom of the other.&nbsp; Every business must
see itself as a learning organization.&nbsp; Every school and student must see
themselves as a bit more like a business.&nbsp; </p>

<p>If we are to truly move to 21st century learning
and embrace the concepts of the Common Core, our students (and teachers) must begin
to think of themselves not as passive recipients of knowledge but as finders
and shapers of their own future.&nbsp; In the course we explore the concept of
every student and teacher seeing themselves as an "economic unit of one,"&nbsp;
not in just a financial sense, but with the belief that each student must,
early in their education, begin to see themselves as responsible for developing
themselves, for marketing themselves, for discovering their passions and for
aligning these passions and interests with the realities of today's
world.&nbsp; This is not a task for a career project as a senior in High School,
but a way of thinking that needs to be nurtured at an early age.</p>

<p>Come and join us in exploring this concept. Begin
looking at yourself as an entrepreneurial educator. Our course begins on June 23 and is hosted on Canvas.net. &nbsp;Enrollment is free.</p>

]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Education Specialist Clear Induction Program at Sonoma State University</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/06/education-specialist-clear-induction-program-at-sonoma-state-university.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17499</id>

    <published>2014-06-12T18:29:34Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-12T19:53:56Z</updated>

    <summary><![CDATA[The Educational Leadership and Special Education (ELSE) Department is pleased to announce that we have preliminary approval from the California Commission on Teacher Credentialing (CTC) to offer a Clear Education Specialist Induction Program. What does this mean for you?&nbsp; All...]]></summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byPamela Van Halsema</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Educational Leadership and Special Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Graduate Studies" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="btsa" label="BTSA" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="jennifermahdavi" label="Jennifer Mahdavi" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastateschoolofeducation" label="sonoma state school of education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastateuniversity" label="sonoma state university" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<p><img alt="education specialist clear induction program now accepting applications for Fall 2014" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/esclear.jpg" width="250" class="left" style="font-size: 1em;" />The <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/else/">Educational Leadership and
Special Education (ELSE) Department</a> is pleased to announce that we have
preliminary approval from the California Commission on Teacher Credentialing
(CTC) to offer a <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/else/clear-induction-es/index.html">Clear Education Specialist Induction Program</a>.<o:p></o:p></p>

<p><b>What does this mean for
you?&nbsp;</b></p>

<p>All teachers are initially
issued a preliminary credential, which must be "cleared" within a period of
time after it is earned. The induction process has been designed based on
research that indicates that teachers are more successful, and that they stay
in the profession longer when they have been provided support during the early
years of their career. The CTC has given candidates holding a <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/else/preliminary-education/es-description.html">Preliminary
Education Specialist Credential </a>two options to receive early career support and
clear their credentials: Beginning Teacher Support and Assessment (<a href="http://www.btsa.ca.gov/">BTSA</a>), or a university based induction program. Now
that SSU has an approved program in special education, you can pick us to
complete your induction into the profession of teaching!</p>

<p><b>Advantages of the SSU Induction
program over BTSA include:</b></p>

<p></p><ul><li><span style="font-size: 1em;">The option to clear
your credential even if you are not employed as a teacher.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: 1em;">A one-year timeline
to complete the clear credential.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: 1em;">Coursework aligned
with </span><a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/else/specialed-masters/index.html" style="font-size: 1em;">our master's degree program in special education</a><span style="font-size: 1em;">; you can earn 12 of the
30-36 units you need for the MA by completing induction.</span></li><li><span style="font-size: 1em;">Core induction
courses offered in a hybrid format;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: 1em;">Come to campus on 5
Saturdays, do the rest of the work online.&nbsp;</span></li><li><span style="font-size: 1em;">(This will account
for 6 of the 12 units you need to complete for induction).</span></li><li><span style="font-size: 1em;">Supportive
professors and rigorous instruction, similar to what you enjoyed as a SSU
credential candidate.</span></li></ul><p></p>













<p>We will offer the <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/else/clear-induction-es/index.html">Clear
Education Specialist Induction Program</a> at SSU for the first time in the fall
semester of 2014. Find more information and an application on our website: <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/else/clear-induction-es/index.html">http://www.sonoma.edu/education/else/clear-induction-es/index.html</a>
&nbsp;We will be taking applications until August 10. We hope you will consider
being a member of our inaugural cohort of clear credential candidates!</p>

<p>Please contact Dr. Jennifer
Mahdavi (<a href="mailto:jennifer.mahdavi@sonoma.edu" style="font-size: 1em;"><span style="color:#7030A0">jennifer.mahdavi@sonoma.edu</span></a>)
with any questions you have about this exciting new opportunity.</p> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>FREE Summer Science and Math Foundational Level Institute for Teachers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/05/free-summer-science-and-math-foundational-level-institute-for-teachers.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17450</id>

    <published>2014-05-27T21:13:38Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-26T20:26:13Z</updated>

    <summary> If you are a credentialed teacher who wants to teach math or science, Sonoma State University has just the program for you! This summer the School of Education at Sonoma State University is offering a Foundational Level Mathematics Institute...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byLina Raffaelli</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Careers" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="School of Education News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="cset" label="CSET" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="flmi" label="FLMI" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="flsi" label="FLSI" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="foundationlevelcredential" label="foundation level credential" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="free" label="free" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="schoolofed" label="School of Ed" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="schoolofeducation" label="School of Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="smtri" label="SMTRI" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastateuniversity" label="Sonoma State University" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="ssu" label="SSU" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="stem" label="STEM" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="summer" label="summer" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="teachingcredential" label="teaching credential" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="testprep" label="test prep" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<img alt="Student looking through microscope" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/microscope.jpeg" width="300" height="" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" />

If you are a credentialed teacher who wants to teach math or science, Sonoma State University has just the program for you! This summer the School of Education at Sonoma State University is offering a Foundational Level Mathematics Institute at SSU, as well as two Foundational Level Science Institutes, located in Santa Rosa and Napa. These free programs are designed for teachers who currently hold a Multiple or Single Subject Teaching Credential and provides them the opportunity to add an additional credential. <br><br>
 The Institutes offer both a content methods course and content review to prepare and assist teachers to pass the CSET's.  Participants will earn 5 units of credit and will only need cover the cost of their own books.<br><br>

For more information about the <em>Foundational Level Mathematics Institute</em>, please visit <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/smtri/foundationalmath.html">sonoma.edu/education/smtri/foundationalmath</a>. Information on the <em>Foundational Level Science Institute</em> can be found at <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/smtri/foundationalscience.html">sonoma.edu/education/smtri/foundationalscience</a>

<big><big><strong><h3>Both program application deadlines have been extended to May 30th.</strong></big></big></h3>
<h3>Napa Science Institute deadline: June 15th EXTENDED TO JUNE 30!  We still have room!</h3>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>ieSonoma Event June 9 Features Design Thinking in Education</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/05/iesonoma-event-june-9-features-design-thinking-in-education.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17438</id>

    <published>2014-05-21T17:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-22T18:53:39Z</updated>

    <summary><![CDATA[Sonoma State School of Education is pleased to be a co-host of the 2014 ieSonoma event on Monday, June 9, 8:30am-12:30pm at Sonoma Country Day School in Santa Rosa. &nbsp;The event is focused&nbsp;the changing demands of the 21st century and...]]></summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byPamela Van Halsema</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Curiculum Studies and Secondary Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="EdTech" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Educational Leadership and Special Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Literacy, Elementary, and Early Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="commoncore" label="common core" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="iesonoma" label="iesonoma" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="nirvanmullick" label="nirvan mullick" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomacountrydayschool" label="sonoma country day school" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomacountyofficeofeducation" label="sonoma county office of education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sugatamitra" label="sugata mitra" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="teachers" label="teachers" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Sonoma State School of Education is pleased to be a co-host of the 2014 <a href="http://www.iesonoma.org">ieSonoma</a> event on Monday, June 9, 8:30am-12:30pm at Sonoma Country Day School in Santa Rosa. &nbsp;The event is focused<span style="font-size: 1em;">&nbsp;the changing demands of the 21st century and how our community, and its schools, must respond to meet those demands. Two keynote speakers will be featured, Dr. Sugata Mitra and Nirvan Mullick. A discussion on "Design Thinking in Education" will include a panel of experts, including Greg Bamford, Kristen Swanson, and others to be announced.</span></p><br clear="all" /><img src="http://www.scoe.org/images/mitra.jpg" alt="Sugata Mitra" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px 15px 0px 0px; border: 0px; float: left;" /><b>Dr. Sugata Mitra</b>&nbsp;is Professor of Educational Technology at the School of Education, Communication and Language Sciences at Newcastle University, England. His 30 years of research spans a wide range of disciplines, but he has earned the greatest recognition for his creative experiment known as the&nbsp;<a href="http://www.ted.com/talks/sugata_mitra_shows_how_kids_teach_themselves.html" target="_blank" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border-width: 0px 0px 1px; border-bottom-style: dotted; border-bottom-color: rgb(74, 130, 163); color: rgb(74, 130, 163); text-decoration: none;">Hole in the Wall</a>, which showed that children can teach themselves and each other when they're motivated by curiosity and peer interest. This work inspired the book and award-winning movie&nbsp;<i>Slumdog Millionaire</i>. Dr. Mitra received the 2013 TED Prize and was named one of the Top 10 Thinkers of 2013 by CNN.<p></p><p><img src="http://www.scoe.org/images/mullick.jpg" alt="Nirvan Mullick" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px 15px 0px 0px; border: 0px; float: left;" /><b>Nirvan Mullick</b>&nbsp;is a filmmaker, creative consultant, speaker, and entrepreneur. His animated short films have screened in festivals worldwide. In 2001, he began an ongoing collaborative experiment called&nbsp;<a href="http://www.the1secondfilm.com/" target="_blank" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border-width: 0px 0px 1px; border-bottom-style: dotted; border-bottom-color: rgb(74, 130, 163); color: rgb(74, 130, 163); text-decoration: none;">The 1 Second Film</a>, which was one of the first crowd-funded films. In 2012, he directed&nbsp;<a href="http://cainesarcade.com/" target="_blank" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border-width: 0px 0px 1px; border-bottom-style: dotted; border-bottom-color: rgb(74, 130, 163); color: rgb(74, 130, 163); text-decoration: none;">Caine's Arcade</a>, an 11-minute film that became a viral phenomenon, receiving over 8 million views and sparking a global movement of "cardboard creativity." Mullick subsequently founded the non-profit Imagination Foundation to find, foster, and fund creativity and entrepreneurship in children. He has received the Dan Eldon Creative Activist Award and Innovation in Action award.</p>

<strong><p>Registration is free for teachers and students using the promotional code innovate14 on the registration form, but tickets are limited. &nbsp;General admission is $40 for non-teachers. &nbsp;To register, see&nbsp;this <a href="http://www.scoe.org/pub/htdocs/21c-iesonoma.html" "="" www.scoe.org="" pub="" htdocs="" class.html?class_id="5504&quot;">registration page
</a></p></strong><a href="www.iesonoma.org" "="" www.scoe.org="" pub="" htdocs="" class.html?class_id="5504&quot;">

</a><a href="http://www.iesonoma.org"><img alt="iesonoma.png" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/iesonoma.png" width="150" class="border left" /></a><h3>About ieSonoma</h3><p></p><p><a href=" http:=" "="" www.scoe.org="" pub="" htdocs="" class.html?class_id="5504&quot;"></a><a href="www.iesonoma.org" target="_blank" style="margin: 0px; padding: 0px; border-width: 0px 0px 1px; border-bottom-style: dotted; border-bottom-color: rgb(74, 130, 163); color: rgb(74, 130, 163); text-decoration: none;"><b>ieSonoma</b></a>&nbsp;is a partnership of educational institutions and the larger community dedicated to exploring the research, theory, and practice of transforming education for the 21st century. The partnership was initiated by SCOE in collaboration with founding partners Sonoma Country Day School and Sonoma State University and is aligned to the Cradle to Career Sonoma County goal of ensuring that every child succeeds academically</p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Making Student Teaching a Rewarding Journey: Tips from Suzi Fischer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/05/tips-from-a-student-teacher-suzi-fischer.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17391</id>

    <published>2014-05-07T20:53:55Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-29T18:07:40Z</updated>

    <summary> By Guest Author: Suzi Fischer Tips from a Student Teacher: Suzi Fischer I contemplated what might be more helpful for prospective and beginner student teachers--a glimpse into the life of a student teacher, or a list of suggestions to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byGabrielle Cordero</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Curiculum Studies and Secondary Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="candidate" label="candidate" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="classroommanagement" label="classroom management" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="credential" label="credential" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="firstyear" label="first year" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="lessonplans" label="lesson plans" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="mentor" label="mentor" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="multiplesubject" label="multiple subject" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="schoolofeducation" label="school of education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="singlesingle" label="single single" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastate" label="sonoma state" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="ssu" label="SSU" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="ssuschoolofeducation" label="SSU School of Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="student" label="student" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="suzifischer" label="suzi fischer" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="teachertips" label="teacher tips" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="teaching" label="teaching" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="tips" label="tips" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="wisdom" label="wisdom" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<img alt="suzifischer.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/suzifischer.jpg"  height="230" class="border right">
<p>By Guest Author: Suzi Fischer</p>

<h4>Tips from a Student Teacher: Suzi Fischer</h4>

<p>I contemplated what might be more helpful for prospective and beginner student teachers--a glimpse into the life of a student teacher, or a list of suggestions to help create a successful student teaching experience. I decided to follow in my colleague's footsteps and share the personal insights that I have discovered on this incredibly rewarding journey. Some of these tips might be repeated from other blog contributors--that just means they are extra important!</p>

<h4>1. Get to Know Your Students</strong></h4>
<p>They are the entire reason you're considering this profession, so make sure you take the time to really get to know them, and enjoy the process of learning more about their unique interests, personalities, and backgrounds. This is my favorite part about teaching--forging these relationships and being a positive force in these students' lives. Knowing your students also helps immensely when formulating your lesson plans--it allows you to create a lesson that meets the specific needs and interests of your particular class and students.</p>

<h4>2. Show Them That You Care</strong></h4>
<p>When students know that you care about them, not just their interests and background but their well-being and individual growth as well, they begin care about you too. So greet your class every morning, express that you're happy to see them, check in on them one-on-one to make sure they're doing alright, and support them. This means carving out a chunk of your busy day to go to their basketball game, or show up at their band concert, or even just take the time to sit and talk to lonely students through lunch instead of rushing home to finish that 459 assignment or grade that mountain of papers. Even if they don't verbally express it, they care. They care that you care. Additionally, showing students that you care also ties into your classroom management and creating a safe environment for your students.</p>

<h4>3. Consult with Your Mentor Teacher, and Often</strong></h4>
<p>Where would Luke Skywalker be if he didn't have an Obi-Wan or Yoda to guide him through the challenging process of becoming a Jedi Knight? Just as your students look up to you as a role model and guide, so too, do student teachers need to rely on an experienced mentor to navigate the murky waters of first-year teaching. It is so important to have easy and open lines of communication with your mentor teacher. I meet with my mentor teacher twice a week to collaborate on lesson plans and assess how previous lessons have gone; on top of this, we email and text regularly to ensure that our co-teaching flows smoothly and we are on the same page. It's all about teamwork, collaboration, and constant self-assessment and reflection.</p>

<h4>4. Feedback is Your Friend!</strong></h4>
<p>The feedback that your mentor teacher and SSU supervisor provide for you is extremely helpful--take their constructive criticism to heart to learn from mistakes and benefit from their wisdom. Now is the time to create positive habits and correct negative ones before they become routine and are ingrained in your everyday teaching.</p>

<p>Also don't be afraid to ask for feedback. There is no such thing as too much feedback, as long as you take the suggestions with a grain of salt and make sure that you stay true to your style of teaching. What works for one teacher may not work for another--it all depends on who you are, the relationship you have with your students, and how you approach teaching.</p>

<p>The advice that helped me the most was gathered from a survey I took from my Senior Honors English class, in which I asked them to anonymously and thoughtfully give suggestions and feedback that would help me to be a better educator. They took the task to heart and I was rewarded with a treasure trove of insightful and helpful information. They were very honest, and while some of the criticism was hard to hear, their willingness to help and perceptive observations aided greatly in my growth as a teacher. I had a short discussion with the class openly examining areas where I need improvement and discussing specific ways in which I could strengthen my skillset. They were pleased that I was genuinely interested in what they had to say and the entire experience was very rewarding for both parties.</p>

<h4>5. Be Prepared!</strong></h4>
<p>I cannot stress this enough! Always, always, always have a backup plan! Teaching demands flexibility, thinking on your feet, and being able to roll with the punches. One of my favorite sayings is "keep calm and pretend it's on the lesson plan--" it's funny to laugh about, but you will face the unexpected--even when you're expecting it! There have been many times when the classroom wifi has failed when the entire lesson depended on our ability to access the internet. Additionally, you will have days when equipment breaks (like a projector), teachers "borrow" your Elmo on the day you really need it (like during your instruction section of the PACT Teaching Event), or all of the electrical outlets in your room will suddenly decide to stop working. The more prepared you are, the easier it is to whip up a secondary lesson on the spot and proceed just as if it was always on the lesson plan.</p>
]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>School of Education 27th Annual Jack London Award for Educational Innovation to honor three Sonoma County public school programs at May 13th award ceremony</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/05/school-of-education-27th-annual-jack-london-award-for-educational-innovation-to-honor-three-sonoma-c.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17382</id>

    <published>2014-05-05T20:07:59Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-08T23:44:18Z</updated>

    <summary>For almost 30 years Sonoma State School of Education has recognized innovative programs in Sonoma County public schools with The Jack London Award for Educational Innovation. The Jack London Award is designed to recognize, encourage and spread good ideas about...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byPamela Van Halsema</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<img alt="jack_london_portrait.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/images/jack_london_portrait.jpg" width="279" height="317" class="border right" style="" /><p>For almost 30 years Sonoma State School of Education has recognized innovative programs in Sonoma County public schools with <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/jack-london/index.html">The Jack London Award for Educational Innovation.</a>  </p>

<p>The Jack London Award is designed to recognize, encourage and spread good ideas about innovative educational programs.  Innovation required creativity and risk taking, two qualities that author Jack London himself embodied in his life and work.</p>  

<p>This year the committee conducted site visits and is naming three recipients of the Jack London Award--two in the Early/Elementary category and one in the Secondary.</p>  
<h3>2014 Jack London Award Recipients</h3>

<h3>Secondary Category</h3>
<div class="caption left" style="width:215px;">
<img alt="Jack London Award Comstock Middle School Project Make Kids.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/images/school/awards/projectmake.jpg" width="200" class="border left" style="" /><p>Project Make students at Comstock Middle School</p></div>

<p><strong>Comstock Middle School</strong> of Santa Rosa is being acknowledged for their<strong> "Project Make" </strong>program, which gives students the opportunity to delve into hands-on, technical education that promotes problem-solving and real-world applications.  </p>

<p>In January of last year, Comstock Middle School converted one of three existing elective sections devoted to Art into a Project Make elective. Teachers John Lundblad and Dawn Thomas spearheaded the class,  providing a rich "making" environment, including access to diverse tools and materials from which students can develop and apply academic, aesthetic, technical and interpersonal skills by creating and building meaningful products appropriate to the middle school level.   The program gained momentum from a summer Project Make camp offered at the school.  </p>

<h3>Early/Elementary Category</h3>

<p><strong>Santa Rosa Charter School </strong>[LaDonna Moore and Catherine McCracken, Directors] is receiving the Jack London Award for the Adlerian Positive Discipline Program which extends to their whole school community--from staff, to students to families.  At the school, students learn self-discipline, responsibility, cooperation and problem solving skills through non-punitive and non-permissive techniques. </p>

<p>According to this approach, all ages learn more effective communication and encourage one another, developing skills that will help them in the present and as they grow and move on to high school and beyond.  Monthly training for parents, and professional development for teachers in the Adlerian approach has created a safe and nurturing environment for students from preschool through 8th grade for many years. </p>
<p>
Finally,<strong> Park Side School in Sebastopol </strong>is receiving a Jack London Award for their International Baccalaureate World School program, which has the goal of helping students grow to be compassionate, knowledgeable and caring lifelong learners.  [Jude Kreissman, IB Program Coordinator]</p>

<p>Park Side teachers have developed curriculum in accordance with International Baccalaureate Primary Years Program (IB PYP) guidelines, with Units of Inquiry that encompass learning, action and reflection.  Developed in collaboration, these units address the California Standards while providing a global perspective for students and following a pedagogical model based on inquiry.  Park Side is the only IB PYP school in Sonoma County.</p>

<h3>Award Criteria</h3>

<p>Schools self-nominate their programs, and the committee narrows down the field to just four finalist programs based on their written applications.   Programs are judged on their innovative approach, ability to engage teachers and their school community collaboratively, and the impact of the program on students.  </p>

<p>For many years one award was presented each year, but in 2011 the Jack London Award Advisory committee decided to expand the award to honor exemplary programs in two categories:  Early/Elementary and Secondary level programs.  </p>

<h3>Award Ceremony</h3>

<p>The Jack London Award recipients will be honored at the Annual Education Recognition and Awards Ceremony on Tuesday, May 13 at the Sonoma State Cooperage from 5-7 p.m.   Admission is free to the public; all ages are welcome.  Parking pass required.</p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>School of Education honors local educators and alumni at annual awards ceremony</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/05/post-3.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17381</id>

    <published>2014-05-05T19:03:21Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-12T22:13:54Z</updated>

    <summary> Sonoma County Assistant Superintendent of Special Education Ron Whitman For over 20 years Sonoma State&apos;s School of Education has acknowledged alumni and community partners for their excellence in local education at the annual School of Education Recognition and Awards...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byPamela Van Halsema</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="School of Education News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<div class="caption left" style="width:315px;">
<img alt="Assistant Superintendent of Special Education Ron Whitman" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/images/whitman.jpg" width="300" class="border left" style="font-size: 1em;" /><p>Sonoma County Assistant Superintendent of Special Education Ron Whitman</p> </div>

<div>For over 20 years Sonoma State's School of Education has acknowledged alumni and community partners for their excellence in local education at the annual School of Education Recognition and Awards Ceremony. &nbsp;This year's event is slated for Tuesday, May 13 at 5:00 PM on SSU's campus.</div><div><br /></div><div>The <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/school/circleofexcellence.html">Circle of Excellence Awards</a> recognize the accomplishments and contributions to the local education community by School of Education Alumni and community partners. Faculty members nominate alumni, mentor teachers, and friends of the program for this recognition.&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div>

<div>This year's recipients of the Circle of Excellence Award include: Andy Gibson (Sonoma Valley High School), Tom Griffin (Casa Grande High School), Ron Whitman (Sonoma County Office of Education) and the mentor teachers at Santa Rosa's Kid Street Learning Center.</div><div><br /></div>

<div class="caption left" style="width:315px;">
<img alt="teacher Erin Fightmaster in her classroom at Kid Street Learning Center" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/images/kidstreet1.jpg" width="300" class="border left" style="font-size: 1em;" /><p>Teacher Erin Fightmaster in her classroom at Kid Street Learning Center</p> </div>
<div>
Professor Emiliano Ayala nominated Assistant Superintendent Ron Whitman for his support and ongoing collaboration with the Special Education programs at Sonoma State. "As a strong leader in our community, his colleagues offer high praise for his student-centered approach to decision making that upholds the mission of Sonoma County Office of Education," said Ayala.&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div>Tom Griffin, department chair at Casa Grande High School, Petaluma, was nominated by Susan Victor, faculty member in the Curriculum Studies and Secondary Education department. "He has been a tireless advocate for English learners and a supportive mentor teacher for Single Subject teaching candidates," said Victor.&nbsp;</div>

<div><br /></div>


<div>Strong teacher mentors play an essential role in the field experience component of SSU's teacher preparation programs, and both Andy Gibson and three educators from Kid Street Learning Center (Principal Kathleen Mallamo, Clare McKenzie and Erin Fightmaster) are nominated for their exemplary work supporting and mentoring new teacher candidates in the classroom.&nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div>In addition to the Circle of Excellence honors, the School of Education will present the <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/jack-london/index.html">Jack London Awards </a>at the event on May 13, and acknowledge the recipients of two scholarships. Early Childhood Studies major Alyx Fritz will receive the Patricia Nourot Early Childhood Scholarship. Veteran science teacher Linn Briner will receive the F. George Elliott Exemplary Professional Renewal Scholarship, providing the funds for Briner to work on a M.A. in Education in the School of Education.</div>

<div>
<div class="caption left" style="width:315px;">
<img alt="Sonoma Valley High School teacher Andy Gibson standing outdoors with a group of his students" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/images/gibson.jpg" width="300" class="border right" style="font-size: 1em;" /><p>Sonoma Valley High School teacher Andy Gibson standing outdoors with a group of his students</p> </div>

<br /></div><div>The Circle of Excellence and scholarship recipients will be honored at the Annual Education Recognition and Awards Ceremony on Tuesday, May 13 at the Sonoma State Cooperage from 5-7 p.m. The event is free and open to the public. &nbsp;</div><div><br /></div><div>The event is sponsored by The SSU Alumni Association, the SSU Office of the President, The California Faculty Association, The Sonoma County Educators Council CTA/NEA, the F. George Elliott Scholarship Fund and the Patricia Nourot Scholarship Fund. is free and open to the public.</div><div><br /></div> ]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>5 Tips from a Novice Student Teacher: Amy Nelson</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/04/5-tips-from-a-novice-student-teacher-amy-nelson.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17206</id>

    <published>2014-04-15T20:22:48Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-16T20:11:41Z</updated>

    <summary> By Guest Author: Amy Nelson 5 Tips from a Novice Student Teacher Accept the Awkward There are going to be MANY uncomfortable and awkward moments during your student teaching year. Embrace them, laugh about them, and learn from them....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byGabrielle Cordero</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Curiculum Studies and Secondary Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<img alt="a picture of Amy Nelson Student Teacher" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/amynelson.jpg" width="150" height="230" class="border right">
<p>By Guest Author: Amy Nelson</p>

<h4>5 Tips from a Novice Student Teacher</h4>

<h4>Accept the Awkward</strong></h4>
<p>There are going to be MANY uncomfortable and awkward moments during your student teaching year. Embrace them, laugh about them, and learn from them. Nothing can really prepare you for the moment when you are staring at a room full of 35 seventh graders, and somebody tells you that you have spilt coffee down your white shirt and didn't even notice. You will have moments when you simply don't know what to say or can't recall the brilliant point you'd planned on making. Student teaching is a time when you can make mistakes, you won't be perfect. In fact, I've learned the most from the lessons I created that didn't work out whatsoever. So when you're "onstage" and the lesson doesn't turn out like a clip from Freedom Writers... just roll it.   

<h4>Work with Your Mentor</strong></h4>
<p>One of the first things my mentor told me was that picking a student teacher is like picking a roommate or a spouse. Having a good relationship with your mentor truly makes a huge difference in your experience. Your mentor is there to coach and guide you: ask them questions, admit defeat and confusion, talk to them about what you're doing well and what you need to work on. Don't be offended when they offer you constructive criticism about your instructional approaches. RELY on your mentor, for they are there to support you in every situation, a.k.a. when the class has gotten out of control and you have absolutely no idea how to quiet them down before the principal walks in.</p>  

<h4>Get to Know Your Students</strong></h4>
<p>This seems obvious, but as a novice teacher it is easy to get caught up in the chaos of prepping for your next class, remembering how to work the copy machine at break, trying to find the assignments for a student who hasn't been to class in two weeks, etc. Make it a goal to just talk to your students when time permits--ask them about their lives and what is going on in their world. Just the other day I noticed while putting in grades that Lilly, a quiet student who doesn't "hide" from me nor shout out and demand my attention, has been performing exceptionally well during my  "Outsiders" unit. Sometimes I get so caught up with interacting with the students who require so much attention, that I don't get to check in with the students who don't beg to be noticed. I made sure to approach Lilly at her desk the next day and tell her that I have seen how well she has been doing, and that I was really proud of her. The smile that stretched across her face sent chills down my arms--she beamed with pride and it surprised me how just that one comment meant so much to her. You are the teacher, but you will learn so much from your students... so talk to them.</p>

<img alt="a picture of Amy Nelson Student Teacher" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/snapshot.png" height="210" class="border right" /></form>
<h4>Make a Name for Yourself</p>
<p>Student teaching isn't a time to be shy. Talk to the other teachers and administrators at your school, there is no better time to observe the teaching styles and techniques of others. Ask educators why they got into the profession. Don't be afraid to put yourself out there and be the student teacher who is always shaking people's hands and roaming around campus.  

<h4>Remember Why You Want to Teach</strong></h4>
<p>During your student teaching you will be completely stressed out, overwhelmed, and unsure of yourself--it's okay. You will have one million things to do: papers to write, projects to make, and essays to grade, but be sure to take time for yourself. Take a deep breath and remind yourself why you want to be a teacher. There have been many days where I've felt like I'm doing a horrible job and question whether or not I have what it takes to be an English teacher. Days like that happen, but then, a student tells me that I'm their favorite teacher -or--someone spells the correct form of "your" and "you're" on their essay and I know that I'm exactly where I'm supposed to be. It is easy to get caught up in the stress of it all, but remember that the kids are what make it all worth it in the end... teaching is truly a joy.</p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Activist Dolores Huerta rouses crowd at SSU during social justice lecture </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/04/dolores-huerta-speaks-at-ssu-about-social-justice.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17103</id>

    <published>2014-04-10T20:12:47Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-17T23:40:56Z</updated>

    <summary>There are not many women in their eighties who have the gusto and vivaciousness to rouse a crowd of a thousand faces, not only inspiring their audience but eliciting a mixture of laughter and serious reflection; Dolores Huerta is a...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byLina Raffaelli</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="School of Education News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="activism" label="activism" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="andreaneves" label="Andrea Neves" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="andreanevesandbartonevanssocialjusticelectureseries" label="Andrea Neves and Barton Evans Social Justice Lecture Series" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="bartonevans" label="Barton Evans" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="carlosayala" label="carlos ayala" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="cesarchavez" label="Cesar Chavez" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="civilrights" label="civil rights" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="doloreshuerta" label="Dolores Huerta" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="empowerment" label="empowerment" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="equalrights" label="equal rights" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="farmworkers" label="farmworkers" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="lectureseries" label="lecture series" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="linaraffaelli" label="Lina Raffaelli" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="markfabionar" label="mark fabionar" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="schoolofed" label="school of ed" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="schoolofeducation" label="school of education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sisepuede" label="si se puede" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="socialjustice" label="social justice" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastate" label="sonoma state" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastatehub" label="sonoma state HUB" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastateschoolofeducation" label="sonoma state school of education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="ssu" label="ssu" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="thehub" label="the HUB" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<p>There are not many women in their eighties who have the gusto and vivaciousness to rouse a crowd of a thousand faces, not only inspiring their audience but eliciting a mixture of laughter and serious reflection; Dolores Huerta is a rare exception. </p>

<p>On March 27 Huerta, activist and co-founder of the United Farmworkers Union, spoke at Sonoma State as part of the <a href="https://www.sonoma.edu/education/Neves-Evans/lecture-series.html">H. Andra Neves and Barton Evans Social Justice Lecture Series.</a> </p>

<p>The evening kicked off in <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/hub/">The HUB</a>,  SSU's multicultural center, where Huerta spoke directly with students in an intimate and open discussion about her life and work as an organizer. Students asked thought provoking questions and sought advice for young people who desire to organize and work towards social justice in their own communities. </p>

<p>She later spoke in the Student Center ballroom, an event that sold-out at just over 1,000 tickets, distributed to high school and college students, community members, and faculty. Huerta covered a variety of topics, such as women rights, workers right, and marriage equality. She emphasized the importance of organizing and empowering people to make a change. "Poor people don't often think they have any power." She explained how, alongside Cesar Chavez, she helped spread a grassroots movement towards workers rights by visiting the homes of farmworkers and speaking to them face to face.&nbsp;</p>

<p>She also strongly encouraged the audience to go see "<a href="http://www.cesarchavezmovie.com/#landing">Cesar Chavez</a>," the feature film directed by Diego Luna, which was set to hit theaters the following day. "If enough people go and see the film, maybe we can show Hollywood that these kinds of films are important, and maybe we will see more like them in the future," said Huerta, who is portrayed in the film by Rosario Dawson. </p>

<p>By the end of the evening Huerta had 1,000 attendees on their feet chanting "<a href="http://www.ufw.org/_board.php?mode=view&b_code=cc_his_research&b_no=5970">S, se puede</a>!" a phrase that she famously coined during the farmworkers movement. She arroused and inspired the crowd, chanting "who has the power?" with a sea of booming voices shouting in response: "WE have the power!"</p>

<p>Student Angelica Shubbie said she loved how engaging Huerta was during her lecture. "She showed her passion, wisdom, and hope, which was inspiring to witness in person." said Shubbie. "Although her main focus is on Farm Labor Unions, it's amazing to see her work towards human rights for everyone!"</p>

<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/HuertaDialogueSSU/">Join the conversation on Facebook</a></p>

<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/SbkyQSOeOeE" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe><br />
<em><strong>Slideshow by Gabrielle Cordero</strong></em></p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Survival Tips from a Student Teacher by Single Subject Candidate Travis Pappa</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/04/survival-tips-from-a-student-teacher-by-single-subject-candidate-travis-pappa.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17168</id>

    <published>2014-04-08T20:27:27Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-08T23:04:36Z</updated>

    <summary> By Guest Author: Travis Pappa 5 Ways to Make your Student Teaching Effective, Enjoyable and Fulfilling Form a Positive Relationship with Your Mentor Teacher This may come very naturally or it may take some intentional effort on your part....</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byGabrielle Cordero</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Curiculum Studies and Secondary Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<img alt="a picture of Travis Pappa Student Teacher" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/travispappa.jpg" width="150" height="210" class="border right" >
<p>By Guest Author: Travis Pappa</p>

<h4>5 Ways to Make your Student Teaching Effective, Enjoyable and Fulfilling</h4>

<h4>Form a Positive Relationship with Your Mentor Teacher</strong></h4>
<p>This may come very naturally or it may take some intentional effort on your part. Chances are, you probably won't agree with everything your mentor teacher says or does, nevertheless, do your best to understand their point of view and the experiences they have had (namely, their teaching experience that caused them to adapt the procedures or habits they have). While you may find yourself eager for the freedom of your first year of teaching solo, take advantage of the ideas, constructive critique (as humbling as it may be, it will be worth it!), perspective, advice and anecdotes that years of experience have yielded your mentor teacher. Developing a sense of teamwork and camaraderie with your mentor teacher can be of great value to both you and your students.</p>

<h4>Read Articles and Books Related to Education that Interest You</strong></h4>
<p>Teach Like a Champion by Doug Lemov has been one of my favorite reads during my time as a student teacher because of the practical and easily implemented teaching techniques it describes. Ask your mentor teacher for reading recommendations since it is likely they have established a personal library of education-related readings. Books and articles provide a great point of conversation between educated individuals (such as you and your mentor teacher) and are certainly a catalyst for creativity during your lesson planning.</p>

<img alt="a picture of Travis Pappa Student Teacher" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/aaaelblogpic.jpg" height="210" class="border right" >
<h4>Greet the Students Who May Feel Overlooked or Unnoticed in Class</h4>
<p>While student teaching, I was surprised to find that I had at least two students each period who would try to be as unnoticeable (by teachers and/or students) as possible. I challenged myself to greet each of these students personally and consistently at the beginning of each class period - even if it was a simple: "Good morning, Irvin, I'm glad you're here today." Although one of my students wanted to keep their interactions with me limited to this, over the following three weeks, most of these quiet students began to change their classroom behavior. Most of these students who were once shy and quiet began to be more alert and active in class. These students also began to hold conversations with me (during and after class!) and even began smiling more frequently during the period. It was an enjoyable lesson in how intentionality and consistency go a long way for the students who are accustomed to being overlooked.</p>

<h4>Listen More, Talk Less</h4>
<p>The more I teach, the more I am reminded that I become a better teacher by listening: talking with other educators in my content area, formal student feedback, informal student feedback and reading works by published educators. Ironically, the best teachers seem do a great deal of listening.
High school students have an average "lecture attention span" of 14-18 minutes, which means that a teacher should spend most of a class period not addressing the entire class. There are a plethora of ways students can learn content aside from lecture (and a substantial amount of research-based methods and materials to do so). Save your voice for when it's needed and spend time circulating your classroom, talking with students and conducting thoughtful formative assessments on how your students are understanding the material. Often, the less I talk, the more meaningful my words are to my students.</p>

<h4>Remind Yourself of the Reasons You Want to be a Teacher</strong></h4>
<p>No matter how good of an imagination you have, teaching looks, feels and is much different than you ever imagined. Inevitably, there will be days when you will feel you don't have what it takes to be a teacher. After some pizza, chocolate, or a power nap, take some time to remind yourself of why you want to be a teacher. There were likely multiple things that inspired you to pursue this profession and it is important to remind yourself of such inspiration on the days that discourage you. After that, create opportunities that allow you to enjoy your favorite parts of teaching.</p>

<p><em>The Accelerating Academic Achievement for English Learners (AAAEL) Project is a five-year, teacher-centered professional development project funded by the U.S. Department of Education that is focused on improving English Learner (EL) student achievement in mathematics, science and English language arts.</em></p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>SSU discussion commemorates upcoming Brown v. Board of Education 60th anniversary</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/04/brown-v-board-of-ed.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17124</id>

    <published>2014-04-02T22:25:53Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-03T19:53:10Z</updated>

    <summary>May 17, 2014 will mark the 60th anniversary of the historical Brown v. the Board of Education decision. The upcoming anniversary presents the educational community with a moment to re-evaluate race relations today. It is a time to analyze how...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byGabrielle Cordero</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="anniversary" label="anniversary" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="brownvsboardofeducation" label="Brown vs. Board of Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="civilrights" label="civil rights" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="community" label="community" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="dialogue" label="dialogue" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="education" label="Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="equality" label="equality" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="ermajeansims" label="Erma Jean Sims" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="events" label="events" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="history" label="history" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="karenbrodsky" label="Karen Brodsky" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="kimhesterwilliams" label="Kim Hester-Williams" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="lecture" label="lecture" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="librarian" label="librarian" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="multicultural" label="multicultural" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="oncampus" label="on campus" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="race" label="race" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="raceissues" label="race issues" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="sonomastateuniversity" label="sonoma state university" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="ssu" label="ssu" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="steveestes" label="Steve Estes" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<p>May 17, 2014 will mark the 60th anniversary of the historical Brown v. the Board of Education decision. The upcoming anniversary presents the educational community with a moment to re-evaluate race relations today. It is a time to analyze how much education and race in America have transformed since the U.S Supreme Court's decision, as the SSU community joined to discuss on February 19th. </p>

<div class="caption left" style="width:300px;">
<img alt="prof.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/lecturers.jpg" width="300" height=""><p>(From left to right: Professors Erma-Jean Sims, Steve Estes & Kim Hester-Williams</p> </div>

<p>As an institution that recognizes the importance of diversity and education, Sonoma State engaged a panel discussion organized by SSU librarian Karen Brodsky. Speakers included History professor Steve Estes, English and American Multicultural Studies (AMCS) professor Kim Hester-Williams and Erma Jean Sims, professor of Education. Each professor offered insights on the subject through the lens of their professional expertise. </p>


<p>For those who need an update, Brown vs. Board was an important landmark case by the Supreme Court that discontinued the legality of racial segregation in U.S. public schools. </p>


<p>Erma Jean Sims focused on the development and causes of resegregation, explaining how racial issues persist in American society. Along with resegregation, there are economic issues some have to endure, "Resegregation by race usually leads to further segregation by income, which has far-reaching effects on the quality of housing, and quality of education," said Sims, "Racially segregated schools are almost always schools with high concentrations of poverty." </p>


<p>Kim Hester-Williams examined black rights today by prefacing with an excerpt from Toni Morrison's The Dancing Mind, and followed with the powerful painting of Ruby Bridges by Norman Rockwell. Williams added that the incident of Ruby Bridges, entering her first day of first grade, came a mere six years after the Brown v. Board decision. </p>

<div class="caption left" style="width:300px;">
<img alt="ruby bridges" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/rubybridges.jpg" width="300" height="" class="mt-image-right" style="float: left;" /><p>Norman Rockwell's "Ruby Bridges" painting</sup></p></div>


<p>The painting served as an example of how racism prevails in American society. Although America has taken legal matters to protect the rights and education of minorities in America, it seems that diverging interests undermine Brown decisions, as Hester-Williams explained. She pulled into question the extent of progressivism for black rights today and how far American society still has to go. </p>


<p>Steve Estes concluded with his historical knowledge on the matter, detailing how Brown vs. Board inspired movements such as the Grassroots Movement. The audience was given an overview from Plessy to Brown to the 2000's, to help examine issues such as gentrification today. With higher income families migrating back to the cities, audience members learned that segregation is being created within schools. Thus creating an insufficient and inferior education for the Black and Latino youth. </p>

<p>As a conclusion to the discussion, the panel opened to a group discussion. Eager participants from the audience questioned how they could help make changes in the community. From remarks and inputs, the professors and members of the audience offered more active recruitment from the campus.</p> 

<p>The group brought attention to the University and ways the SSU community can be an active part resolving racial issues in education. Fellow participants offered that University, itself, could begin recruiting a more diverse faculty and becoming more involved. The discussion served as a first step to realizing the needs in education in terms of race.</p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Maker Day in Marin Showcases How Teachers and Students Integrate Creativity and Science</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/2014/04/maker-day-in-marin-showcases-how-teachers-and-students-integrate-creativity-and-science.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/education/blog//93.17107</id>

    <published>2014-04-02T16:11:22Z</published>
    <updated>2014-04-03T20:00:46Z</updated>

    <summary><![CDATA[The MAKER Movement has taken hold in many schools around Northern California. Over the last several years interest in the grass roots MAKER Movement&nbsp;has grown. MAKER Fairs around the world have attracted hundreds of thousands of people. Now MAKER is...]]></summary>
    <author>
        <name>Posted byPamela Van Halsema</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Curiculum Studies and Secondary Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="EdTech" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Educational Leadership and Special Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Featured Stories" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Graduate Studies" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Literacy, Elementary, and Early Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="School of Education News" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    <category term="andbayareasciencefestival" label="and Bay Area Science Festival" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="autodesk" label="Autodesk" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="buckinstituteforeducation" label="Buck Institute for Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="edutopia" label="Edutopia" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="intelclubhouse" label="Intel Clubhouse" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="legoplaywell" label="Lego Play-Well" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="maker" label="MAKER" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="marincountybicyclecoalition" label="Marin County Bicycle Coalition" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="marincountyofficeofeducation" label="Marin County Office of Education" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    <category term="microsoft" label="Microsoft" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#tag" />
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en-us" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/education/blog/">
        <![CDATA[<p>The MAKER Movement has taken hold in many schools around Northern California. Over the last several years interest in the grass
roots MAKER Movement<span class="apple-converted-space">&nbsp;</span>has grown.
MAKER Fairs around the world have attracted hundreds of thousands of people.
Now MAKER is beginning to spill into schools and be used by innovative teachers
seeking to provide engaging, hands-on, authentic learning experiences in
Science, Technology, Engineering, the Arts, and Mathematics. &nbsp;</p>

You can find out what MAKER is all about the
1st annual MAKER Day on April 12 at the Marin County Office of Education.See how the future is being imagined,invented, designed, programmed, and manufactured by Marin County students.Meet the MAKERS and have fun with the
hands-on exhibits. Everyone is welcome--teachers, kids, families and more-- and it's free! <a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/marinovators-young-makers-day-tickets-10321747625">HERE</a> to register.</span></p>

<h3><b><span style="color:#007A37">GO Green and ride your bike to MAKER Day on April 12.
Valet bike parking courtesy of the Marin County Bicycle Coalition!</span></b><o:p></o:p></span></p><p class="MsoNormal"></h3>

The Marin County Office of Education
and partners Autodesk,
Microsoft, Edutopia, Intel Clubhouse, Marin County Bicycle Coalition, Lego
Play-Well, Buck Institute for Education, and Bay Area Science Festival are hosting MAKER Day on April 12, from 10:00-4:00 at the Marin County Office of Education, 1111 Las Gallinas Avenue, San Rafael. Experience the excitement,
creativity, genius and the "do it yourself" ingenuity of our students.
More info at <a href="http://make.marinschools.org/">http://make.marinschools.org</a></span><a href="http://make.marinschools.org/"></a>.<br><br>

 The School of Education encourages both pre-service and in-service teachers to take advantage of this opportunity to see how schools are incorporating the MAKER mindset in their classrooms.]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

</feed>
