<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en"
  xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">News</title>
	<subtitle type="text">The University of Texas at Austin</subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-18T15:33:57Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" />
	<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.2.1">WordPress</generator>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jessica Sinn</name>
						<uri>http://www.utexas.edu/cola/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Walking on All Fours Is Not Backward Evolution, Study Shows]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/quadrupedal-humans-shapiro-study/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/</id>
		<updated>2014-07-16T19:25:27Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-16T18:49:56Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="backward evolution" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="College of Liberal Arts" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Department of Anthropology" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="evolution" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Liza Shapiro" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="quadrupedal humans" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="The Family That Walks on All Fours" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Turkish siblings" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Uner Tan" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Contradicting earlier claims, “The Family That Walks on All Fours,” a group of quadrupedal humans made famous by a 2006 BBC documentary, have simply adapted to their inability to walk upright and do not represent an example of backward evolution, according to new research by Liza Shapiro, an anthropologist at The University of Texas at&#8230;&#160;&#160;&#160;<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/quadrupedal-humans-shapiro-study/" class="read-more">&#187;&#160;Continue Reading</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/quadrupedal-humans-shapiro-study/"><![CDATA[<p>Contradicting earlier claims, “The Family That Walks on All Fours,” a group of quadrupedal humans made famous by a 2006 BBC documentary, have simply adapted to their inability to walk upright and do not represent an example of backward evolution, according to new research by <a href="http://uts.cc.utexas.edu/~lshapiro/" target="_blank">Liza Shapiro</a>, an anthropologist at The University of Texas at Austin.<span id="more-46946"></span></p>
<p>Five siblings in the family, who live in a remote corner of Turkey, walk exclusively on their hands and feet. Since they were discovered in 2005, scientists have debated the nature of their disability, with speculation they represent a backward stage of evolution.</p>
<p>Shapiro’s study, published online this month in <em>PLOS One</em>, shows that contrary to previous claims, people with the family members’ condition, called Uner Tan Syndrome (UTS), do not walk in the diagonal pattern characteristic of nonhuman primates such as apes and monkeys.</p>
<div id="attachment_46958" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Jwiz-yhLpT0#t=43m23s"><img src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/familyfours-custom-photo2.jpg" alt="The Family That Walks on All Fours" width="500" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Footage from “The Family That Walks on All Fours,” the 2006 BBC documentary cited in Shapiro&#039;s study.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_46958" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://www.utexas.edu/know/images/2014/TEXAS_PERSPECTIVES/VideoS1.mp4"><img class="size-full wp-image-46979" src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/sample-video-pic.jpg" alt="Sample participant walking on all fours" width="500" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This video is a sample of UTS walking patterns. Video from Shapiro LJ, Cole WG, Young JW, Raichlen DA, Robinson SR, et al. (2014) Human Quadrupeds, Primate Quadrupedalism, and Uner Tan Syndrome. PLoS ONE 9(7): e101758. doi:10.1371/journal.pone.0101758.</p></div>
<p>According to a theory developed by Uner Tan of Cukurova University in Turkey, people with UTS are a human model for reverse evolution, or “devolution,” offering new insights into the human transition from four-legged to two-legged walking. Previous research countering this view has proposed that the quadrupedalism associated with UTS is simply an adaptive response to the impaired ability to walk bipedally in individuals with a genetic mutation, but this is the first study that disproves claims that this form of walking resembles that of nonhuman primates.</p>
<p>The study’s co-authors are Jesse Young of Northeast Ohio Medical University; David Raichlen of the University of Arizona; and Whitney Cole, Scott Robinson and Karen Adolph of New York University.</p>
<p>As part of the study, the researchers analyzed 518 quadrupedal walking strides from several videos of people with various forms of UTS, including footage from the BBC2 documentary of the five Turkish siblings, “The Family That Walks on All Fours.” They compared these walking strides to previous studies of the walking patterns of healthy adults who were asked to move around a laboratory on all fours.</p>
<p>According to the findings, nearly all human subjects (in 98 percent of the total strides) walked in lateral sequences, meaning they placed a foot down and then a hand on the same side and then moved in the same sequence on the other side. Apes and other nonhuman primates, however, walk in a diagonal sequence, in which they put down a foot on one side and then a hand on the other side, continuing that pattern as they move along.</p>
<p>“Although it’s unusual that humans with UTS habitually walk on four limbs, this form of quadrupedalism resembles that of healthy adults and is thus not at all unexpected,” Shapiro says. “As we have shown, quadrupedalism in healthy adults or those with a physical disability can be explained using biomechanical principles rather than evolutionary assumptions.”</p>
<p>The study also shows that Tan and his colleagues appeared to have misidentified the walking patterns among people with UTS as primate-like by confusing diagonal sequence with diagonal couplets. Sequence refers to the order in which the limbs touch the ground, while couplets (independent of sequence) indicate the timing of movement between pairs of limbs. People with UTS more frequently use diagonal couplets than lateral couplets, but the <em>sequence </em>associated with the couplets is almost exclusively lateral.</p>
<p>“Each type of couplet has biomechanical advantages, with lateral couplets serving to avoid limb interference, and diagonal couplets providing stability,” Shapiro says. “The use of diagonal couplets in adult humans walking quadrupedally can thus be explained on the basis of biomechanical considerations, not reverse evolution.”</p>
<div id="attachment_46958" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 727px"><a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/quadrupedal-humans-shapiro-study/fig-1-3/" rel="attachment wp-att-46958" target="_blank"><img class="size-large wp-image-46958 " src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/Fig-12-1024x314.jpg" alt="" width="717" height="220" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Comparison of footfall sequence in primate (baboon, above) and nonprimate (cat, below). Footfall sequence is depicted numerically, beginning with the right hind limb in each animal. The primate is walking in diagonal sequence (RH-LF-LH-RF), and the nonprimate is walking in lateral sequence (RH-RF-LH-LF). Image from Muybridge E (1887) . Animal Locomotion: An Electro-photographic Investigation of Consecutive Phases of Animal Movements, 1872-1885: 112 Plates. Published under the auspices of the University of Pennsylvania.</p></div>
]]></content>
<link href="http://www.utexas.edu/know/images/2014/TEXAS_PERSPECTIVES/VideoS1.mp4" rel="enclosure" length="980962" type="video/mp4" />
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/quadrupedal-humans-shapiro-study/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/quadrupedal-humans-shapiro-study/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Steve Franklin</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Mutation Stops Worms From Getting Drunk]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/mutant-worms-alcohol-neuroscience/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/</id>
		<updated>2014-07-16T12:55:23Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-16T12:55:17Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Research" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="addiction" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="alcohol" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Caenorhabditis elegans" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="College of Natural Sciences" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Department of Neuroscience" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Jon Pierce-Shimomura" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="neurobiology" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="neuroscience" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Scott Davis" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Waggoner Center for Alcohol and Addiction Research" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Neuroscientists at The University of Texas at Austin have generated mutant worms that do not get intoxicated by alcohol, a result that could lead to new drugs to treat the symptoms of people going through alcohol withdrawal. The scientists accomplished this feat by inserting a modified human alcohol target into the worms, as reported this&#8230;&#160;&#160;&#160;<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/mutant-worms-alcohol-neuroscience/" class="read-more">&#187;&#160;Continue Reading</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/mutant-worms-alcohol-neuroscience/"><![CDATA[<p>Neuroscientists at The University of Texas at Austin have generated mutant worms that do not get intoxicated by alcohol, a result that could lead to new drugs to treat the symptoms of people going through alcohol withdrawal.<span id="more-46850"></span></p>
<p>The scientists accomplished this feat by inserting a modified human alcohol target into the worms, as reported this week in <em>The Journal of Neuroscience</em>.</p>
<div id="attachment_46862" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 360px"><a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/mutant-worms-alcohol-neuroscience/drunk-sober-worms-humans-490/" rel="attachment wp-att-46862"><img class="size-full wp-image-46862" src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/drunk-sober-worms-humans-490.jpg" alt="" width="350" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A visual comparison of a sober and an intoxicated worm. Image courtesy of Jon Pierce-Shimomura.</p></div>
<p>“This is the first example of altering a human alcohol target to prevent intoxication in an animal,” says corresponding author <a title="Pierce-Shimomura Lab" href="http://www.utexas.edu/research/wcaar/jps/" target="_blank">Jon Pierce-Shimomura</a>, assistant professor in the university’s <a title="College of Natural Sciences" href="http://cns.utexas.edu/" target="_blank">College of Natural Sciences</a> and <a title="Waggoner Center for Alcohol and Addiction Research" href="http://www.utexas.edu/research/wcaar/" target="_blank">Waggoner Center for Alcohol and Addiction Research</a>.</p>
<p>An alcohol target is any neuronal molecule that binds alcohol, of which there are many.</p>
<p>One important aspect of this modified alcohol target, a neuronal channel called the BK channel, is that the mutation only affects its response to alcohol. The BK channel typically regulates many important functions including activity of neurons, blood vessels, the respiratory tract and bladder. The alcohol-insensitive mutation does not disrupt these functions at all.</p>
<p>“We got pretty lucky and found a way to make the channel insensitive to alcohol without affecting its normal function,” says Pierce-Shimomura.</p>
<p>The scientists believe the research has potential applications for treating people addicted to alcohol.</p>
<p>“Our findings provide exciting evidence that future pharmaceuticals might aim at this portion of the alcohol target to prevent problems in alcohol abuse disorders,” says Pierce-Shimomura. “However, it remains to be seen which aspects of these disorders would benefit.”</p>
<p>Unlike drugs such as cocaine, which has a specific target in the nervous system, the effects of alcohol on the body are complex and have many targets across the brain. The various other aspects of alcohol addiction, such as tolerance, craving and the symptoms of withdrawal, may be influenced by different alcohol targets.</p>
<p>The worms used in the study, <em>Caenorhabditis elegans</em>, model intoxication well. Alcohol causes the worms to slow their crawling and exhibit less wriggling from side to side. The intoxicated worms also stop laying eggs, which build up in their bodies and can be easily counted.</p>
<p>Unfortunately, <em>C. elegans</em> are not as ideal for studying the other areas of alcohol addiction, but mice make an excellent model. The modified human BK channel used in the study, which is based on a mutation discovered by lead author and graduate student <a title="Scott Davis' website" href="http://www.utexas.edu/research/wcaar/jps/davis/" target="_blank">Scott Davis</a>, could be inserted into mice. These modified mice would allow scientists to investigate whether this particular alcohol target also affects tolerance, craving and other symptoms relevant to humans.</p>
<p>Pierce-Shimomura speculated that their research could even be used to develop a “James Bond” drug someday that would enable a spy to drink his opponent under the table without getting drunk himself. Such a drug could potentially be used to treat alcoholics because it would counteract the intoxicating and potentially addicting effects of the alcohol.</p>
<p>Davis and Pierce-Shimomura’s co-authors at The University of Texas at Austin were research associate Luisa Scott and undergraduate student Kevin Hu.</p>
<p>This research was funded by the <a title="ABMRF/The Foundation for Alcohol Research" href="http://www.abmrf.org/" target="_blank">ABMRF/The Foundation for Alcohol Research</a>, the <a title="National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism" href="http://www.niaaa.nih.gov/" target="_blank">National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism</a> and the Waggoner Center for Alcohol and Addiction Research at The University of Texas at Austin.</p>
<p>You can access the original paper in <em>The Journal of Neuroscience</em> <a title="Link to original study in The Journal of Neuroscience" href="http://www.jneurosci.org/content/34/29/9562" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/mutant-worms-alcohol-neuroscience/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/16/mutant-worms-alcohol-neuroscience/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>University Communications</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[University of Texas at Austin President Responds to Court Ruling in Fisher Case]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/fisher-versus-ut-presidentpowers-statement/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/</id>
		<updated>2014-07-16T02:12:41Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-15T20:49:48Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="admissions" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Fisher v. The University of Texas at Austin" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Following is a statement from University of Texas at Austin President Bill Powers regarding today’s court ruling in the case of Fisher versus University of Texas. The ruling relates to the use of ethnicity as one factor in determining college admissions. “We are very pleased with the Court’s ruling recognizing the constitutionality of the University’s&#8230;&#160;&#160;&#160;<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/fisher-versus-ut-presidentpowers-statement/" class="read-more">&#187;&#160;Continue Reading</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/fisher-versus-ut-presidentpowers-statement/"><![CDATA[<p>Following is a statement from University of Texas at Austin President Bill Powers regarding today’s court ruling in the case of Fisher versus University of Texas. The ruling relates to the use of ethnicity as one factor in determining college admissions.<span id="more-46926"></span></p>
<p><em>“We are very pleased with the Court’s ruling recognizing the constitutionality of the University’s admissions policy under the Supreme Court’s recent guidance.</em></p>
<p><em>“We remain committed to assembling a student body at The University of Texas at Austin that brings with it the educational benefits of diversity while respecting the rights of all students. This ruling ensures that our campus, our state and the entire nation will benefit from the exchange of ideas and thoughts that happens when students who are diverse in all regards come together in the classroom, at campus events and in all aspects of campus life.”</em></p>
<hr />
<h3><strong>Media Resources:</strong></h3>
<p><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TQPElTECaXw&amp;hd=1" target="_blank">Video of post-ruling press conference with President Powers<br />
</a></p>
<p>Photos for download</p>
<p><a href="http://www.utexas.edu/know/images/2013/Fisher_Powers/Powers_William_600px_300dpi.jpg">UT Austin President Bill Powers</a> (photo credit: UT Austin)<br />
<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/know/images/2013/Fisher_Powers/UT_Austin_Tower_300dpi.jpg">UT Tower</a> (photo credit: Marsha Miller/UT Austin)<br />
<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/know/images/2013/Fisher_Powers/UT_Austin_Tower.jpg">UT Tower – horizontal </a>(photo credit: Marsha Miller/UT Austin)</p>
<hr />
<h3><strong>Related Resources:</strong></h3>
<p>For more information about the court case, visit <a title="Vice President for Legal Affairs" href="http://www.utexas.edu/vp/irla/Fisher-V-Texas.html" target="_blank">Legal Affairs: Fisher v. Texas.</a></p>
<p>For updates about the University of Texas at Austin admissions process after the <em>Fisher </em>decision, visit <a href="http://bealonghorn.utexas.edu/fisher" target="_blank">Be a Longhorn – Fisher landing page</a>.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.utexas.edu/towertalk/2014/07/15/court-rules-for-ut-austin-in-fisher-case/">Court rules for UT Austin in Fisher case</a> (President Bill Powers’ Tower Talk blog)</p>
<p>Follow <a href="http://www.facebook.com/UTAustinTX">UT Austin’s Facebook page</a>, <a href="http://www.twitter.com/UTAustin">@UTAustin</a> and <a href="http://www.twitter.com/UTAustinNews">@UTAustinNews</a> for the latest updates.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/fisher-versus-ut-presidentpowers-statement/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/fisher-versus-ut-presidentpowers-statement/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Kathryn Wiley</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[School of Nursing Receives Funds to Provide Health Care for Low-Income Central Texans]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/school-of-nursing-wellness-center/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/14/</id>
		<updated>2014-07-15T14:34:18Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-15T14:34:18Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Children&#039;s Wellness Center" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="community health" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Elizabeth Loika" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Family Wellness Center" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="public health" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="St. David&#039;s Foundation" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Underserved population" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="UT School of Nursing" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="UT School of Nursing Wellness Center" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The University of Texas at Austin School of Nursing has received a two-year $703,000 grant from the St. David’s Foundation to fund services at the UT School of Nursing Wellness Center, which provides health care for low-income, uninsured residents of Central Texas. Located at two sites — the Family Wellness Clinic in East Austin and&#8230;&#160;&#160;&#160;<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/school-of-nursing-wellness-center/" class="read-more">&#187;&#160;Continue Reading</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/school-of-nursing-wellness-center/"><![CDATA[<p>The University of Texas at Austin <a href="http://www.utexas.edu/nursing/" target="_blank">School of Nursing</a> has received a two-year $703,000 grant from the St. David’s Foundation to fund services at the <a href="http://www.utexas.edu/nursing/outreach/center.html" target="_blank">UT School of Nursing Wellness Center</a>, which provides health care for low-income, uninsured residents of Central Texas.<span id="more-46839"></span></p>
<p>Located at two sites — the Family Wellness Clinic in East Austin and the Children’s Wellness Clinic in Del Valle — the center also furnishes valuable clinical training programs for nursing graduate students to master skills in management of chronic disease, acute conditions and preventative medicine.</p>
<p>In addition to primary care, the community can obtain a variety of services at both sites that are not available at most other health care facilities, including walk-in immunization clinics, health education classes and community health outreach.</p>
<p>Since 1998, the School of Nursing has received more than $6 million from the St. David’s Foundation to be used for public health services and outreach.</p>
<p>“The generous support from the foundation helps us to provide high-quality, comprehensive health care to thousands of Central Texans without private health insurance,” said Elizabeth Loika, director of the School of Nursing wellness centers. “Our clinics help cut down on expensive, inefficient emergency room visits and improve quality of life for patients and their families. We appreciate the St. David’s Foundation’s ongoing support of our efforts to make health care accessible to so many in our community.”</p>
<p>The Austin-based St. David’s Foundation invests in a healthy community through funding and initiatives to better care for the underserved and uninsured.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/school-of-nursing-wellness-center/#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/15/school-of-nursing-wellness-center/feed/atom/" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Adrienne Lee</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Race is On for Best Solar Car of 2014]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/10/solar-car-race-cockrell/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/10/</id>
		<updated>2014-07-10T17:37:49Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-10T16:23:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Campus" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="american solar challenge" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="circuit of the americas" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Cockrell School of Engineering" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="formula sun grand prix" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Sharon L. Wood" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="solar power" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="The University of Texas at Austin" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="UT Austin" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="ut solar vehicles team" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Cockrell School of Engineering at The University of Texas at Austin will host the nation’s two biggest collegiate solar car races — the Formula Sun Grand Prix and the American Solar Challenge. Student solar car teams from universities around the world, including UT Austin, will be in Austin to compete in the two back-to-back competitions.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/10/solar-car-race-cockrell/"><![CDATA[<p>Beginning Monday, July 14, the <a href="http://www.engr.utexas.edu/" target="_blank">Cockrell School of Engineering</a> at The University of Texas at Austin will host the nation’s two biggest collegiate solar car races — the Formula Sun Grand Prix and the American Solar Challenge.<span id="more-46821"></span></p>
<p>About 20 student solar car teams from universities around the world including UT Austin, the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Stanford University, the Georgia Institute of Technology and the National Kaohsiung University of Applied Sciences will be in Austin to compete in the two back-to-back competitions.</p>
<p>The student teams design solar vehicles that use photovoltaic panels to convert the sun’s energy into electricity. These solar-powered cars can reach speeds of 40-50 miles per hour using only 1,200 watts of power — about two-thirds the amount of power it takes to run a hair dryer.</p>
<p>“We are thrilled to host students and faculty from across the world as they participate in these competitions,” said Sharon L. Wood, interim dean of the Cockrell School of Engineering. “These races reinforce the skills and knowledge our engineering students gain throughout the year and offer them an exciting opportunity to design, build and test their technologies.”</p>
<div id="attachment_46824" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/solar-car-event-2013.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="size-medium wp-image-46824 " src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/solar-car-event-2013-300x200.jpg" alt="solar car team 2013" width="300" height="200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The UT Solar Vehicles Team prepares its TexSun solar car at last year&#039;s Formula Sun Grand Prix at the COTA track.</p></div>
<p>For the second consecutive year, the Cockrell School and its Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering will host the Formula Sun Grand Prix at the Circuit of the Americas (COTA) Formula One racetrack July 14-19. The Formula Sun Grand Prix begins with a series of qualifying events and inspections, called scrutineering. Only teams that successfully pass scrutineering can move forward to compete in a three-day endurance race on the COTA track. The team that logs the most laps after the three-day racing period wins.</p>
<p>In order to qualify for the next competition, teams competing in the Formula Sun event must complete a minimum number of laps at a minimum speed. This is so the team’s solar cars demonstrate that they can safely function on the highway during the American Solar Challenge.</p>
<p>After Formula Sun, the teams will have a one-day break to gear up before embarking on the more than 1,100-mile drive from Austin to St. Paul/Minneapolis, Minnesota, for the American Solar Challenge, July 21-28.</p>
<p>A cross-country road race, the American Solar Challenge is intended to test the reliability and endurance of the solar cars’ systems in real-world driving conditions and weather. The team with the fastest elapsed time for completing the route is the winner.</p>
<p>The UT Solar Vehicles Team sponsors are COTA, Freescale Semiconductor, General Motors, Plantronics, SunPower, Texas Motor Sports, Union Pacific and the University Co-op.</p>
<p>Before the teams begin their journey for the American Solar Challenge, there will be several events open to the public, both at the COTA track and on the UT Austin campus:</p>
<p><strong>July 19</strong>: Formula Sun Grand PrixPublic Day at COTA<br />
The public is invited to COTA to view the race, see sponsor booths and participate in activities for children, including building solar cars, solar radio control car racing and more.<br />
Location: COTA, 9201 Circuit of the Americas Blvd.<br />
Time: 9 a.m.-5 p.m.</p>
<p><strong>July 20</strong>: Public Display Day<br />
The public can view cars up close and talk to teams.<br />
Location: UT Campus Parking Lot 104<br />
Time: noon to 4 p.m.</p>
<p><strong>July 21:</strong> American Solar Challenge Starting Line<br />
The public can watch the beginning of the cross-country race.<br />
Location: UT Campus, outside F. Loren Winship Drama Building, 300 E. 23rd St.<br />
Time: 6-9:30 a.m.</p>
<p>For more information, visit <a href="http://www.ece.utexas.edu/utsvt" target="_blank">ece.utexas.edu/utsvt</a></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/10/solar-car-race-cockrell/#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/10/solar-car-race-cockrell/feed/atom/" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sandra Zaragoza</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers Invent ‘Meta Mirror’ to Help Advance Nonlinear Optical Systems]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/meta-mirror-engineering/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/</id>
		<updated>2014-07-02T19:11:09Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-02T18:58:46Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Research" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="andrea alu" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Cockrell School of Engineering" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="lasers" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="metamaterial" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Mikhail Belkin" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers at the Cockrell School of Engineering at The University of Texas at Austin have created a new nonlinear metasurface, or meta mirror, that could one day enable the miniaturization of laser systems. The invention, called a “nonlinear mirror” by the researchers, could help advance nonlinear laser systems that are used for chemical sensing, explosives&#8230;&#160;&#160;&#160;<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/meta-mirror-engineering/" class="read-more">&#187;&#160;Continue Reading</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/meta-mirror-engineering/"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers at the Cockrell School of Engineering at The University of Texas at Austin have created a new nonlinear metasurface, or meta mirror, that could one day enable the miniaturization of laser systems.<span id="more-46793"></span></p>
<p>The invention, called a “nonlinear mirror” by the researchers, could help advance nonlinear laser systems that are used for chemical sensing, explosives detection, biomedical research and potentially many other applications. The researchers’ study will be published in the July 3 issue of <em>Nature</em>.</p>
<p>The metamaterials were created with nonlinear optical response a million times as strong as traditional nonlinear materials and demonstrated frequency conversion in films 100 times as thin as human hair using light intensity comparable with that of a laser pointer.</p>
<p>Nonlinear optical effects are widely used by engineers and scientists to generate new light frequencies, perform laser diagnostics and advance quantum computing. Due to the small extent of optical nonlinearity in naturally occurring materials, high light intensities and long propagation distances in nonlinear crystals are typically required to produce detectable nonlinear optical effects.</p>
<p>The research team led by UT Austin’s <a href="http://www.engr.utexas.edu/programs/electrical" target="_blank">Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</a> professors Mikhail Belkin and Andrea Alu, in collaboration with colleagues from the Technical University of Munich, has created thin-film nonlinear metamaterials with optical response many orders of magnitude larger than that of traditional nonlinear materials. The scientists demonstrated this functionality by realizing a 400-nanometer-thick nonlinear mirror that reflects radiation at twice the input light frequency. For the given input intensity and structure thickness, the new nonlinear metamaterial produces approximately 1 million times larger frequency-doubled output, compared with similar structures based on conventional materials.</p>
<p>“This work opens a new paradigm in nonlinear optics by exploiting the unique combination of exotic wave interaction in metamaterials and of quantum engineering in semiconductors,” said Professor Andrea Alu.</p>
<p>The metamaterial at the basis of this unusual optical response consists of a sequence of thin layers made of indium, gallium and arsenic on the one hand and aluminum, indium and arsenic on the other. The researchers stacked approximately 100 of these layers, each between 1 nanometer and 12 nanometers thick, and sandwiched them between a layer of gold at the bottom and a pattern of asymmetric gold nanocrosses on top. The thin semiconductor layers confine electrons into desired quantum states, and gold nanocrosses resonate at input and output frequencies to enable the the nonlinear optical response of the mirror.</p>
<p>The realized mirror converts light from a wavelength of 8 micrometers to 4 micrometers; however, the structures can be tailored to work at other wavelengths, from near-infrared to mid-infrared to terahertz.</p>
<p>“Alongside frequency doubling, our structures may be designed for sum- or difference-frequency generation, as well as a variety of four-wave mixing processes,” said UT Austin graduate student Jongwon Lee, the lead author on the paper.</p>
<p>“Our work unveils a pathway towards the development of ultrathin, highly nonlinear optical elements for efficient frequency conversion that will operate without stringent phase-matching constraints of bulk nonlinear crystals,” said Professor Mikhail Belkin.</p>
<p>Belkin and Alu led a team of researchers that included electrical and computer engineering graduate students Jongwon Lee, Mykhailo Tymchenko and Feng Lu. Pai-Yen Chen and Christos Argyropoulos, who graduated from the <a href="http://www.engr.utexas.edu/" target="_blank">Cockrell School</a> in 2013, also contributed to the paper. The semiconductor material was grown at the Walter Schottky Institute, Technical University of Munich.</p>
<p>The research was funded by the National Science Foundation, the Air Force Office of Scientific Research and the Office of Naval Research, as well as the German Research Foundation.</p>
<p>The University of Texas at Austin is committed to transparency and disclosure of all potential conflicts of interest. All UT investigators involved with this research have filed their required financial disclosure forms with the university. Alu and Belkin have both received research funding for other projects from the National Science Foundation and other major public science foundations. Belkin has also received research funding for other projects from the companies Omega Optics, Anasys Instruments and<strong> </strong>Hamamatsu Photonics, and Alu from the AEgis Technologies Group. An alumnus and former doctoral student who worked on the project, Pai-Yen Chen, now works for Intellectual Ventures Inc.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/meta-mirror-engineering/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/meta-mirror-engineering/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>J.B. Bird</name>
						<uri>http://www.utexas.edu</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[New Executive Director Named for Texas Advanced Computing Center]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/tacc-executive-director-dan-stanzione/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/01/</id>
		<updated>2014-07-02T13:57:22Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-02T13:00:09Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Featured News" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="advanced computing" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="big data" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="computation" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="cyberinfrastructure iPlant" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="high-performance computing" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="HPC" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="life sciences" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Lonestar" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="NSF" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Ranger" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="stampede" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="supercomputer" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="supercomputing" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="TACC" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Wrangler" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[AUSTIN, Texas — Dan C. Stanzione Jr. has been named executive director of the Texas Advanced Computing Center (TACC) at The University of Texas at Austin. A nationally recognized leader in high performance computing, Stanzione has served as deputy director since June 2009 and will assume the new post July 1. “The University of Texas at Austin&#8230;&#160;&#160;&#160;<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/tacc-executive-director-dan-stanzione/" class="read-more">&#187;&#160;Continue Reading</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/tacc-executive-director-dan-stanzione/"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_46766" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 257px"><a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/Dan_Stanzione.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="size-large wp-image-46766           " src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/Dan_Stanzione-685x1024.jpg" alt="" width="247" height="368" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dan C. Stanzione Jr., Executive Director, Texas Advanced Computing Center</p></div>
<p>AUSTIN, Texas — Dan C. Stanzione Jr. has been named executive director of the Texas Advanced Computing Center (TACC) at The University of Texas at Austin. A nationally recognized leader in high performance computing, Stanzione has served as deputy director since June 2009 and will assume the new post July 1.<span id="more-46757"></span></p>
<p>“The University of Texas at Austin has become a global leader in supercomputing thanks to TACC and the research it supports,” said UT Austin President Bill Powers. “Under Dan’s leadership, I believe our computers will become even more powerful and our research even more world-changing.”</p>
<p>TACC is a national leader in providing high-end advanced computing resources and services to researchers, conducting leading research and development projects, and providing training and education for the local and national scientific community. The center provides a comprehensive portfolio for virtually every mode of computational research and runs some of the world's largest computing and data systems, with thousands of users from hundreds of institutions investigating such issues as gene sequencing, biofuel production, and weather and climate modeling.</p>
<p>“As deputy director of TACC, Dan has demonstrated his ability to manage the organization and deliver on its commitments to provide world-class computational facilities, research and support to benefit the nation, state and university,” said Juan M. Sanchez, vice president for research at UT Austin. “I am confident that under his new role, TACC will continue to be an internationally recognized center of excellence in advanced computing, offering our faculty, students and researchers the computational tools and technical support needed to sustain our world-class research enterprise.”</p>
<p>Stanzione is the principal investigator (PI) for several leading projects including a multimillion-dollar National Science Foundation (NSF) grant to deploy and support TACC’s Stampede supercomputer over four years. In Stampede’s first year of operation, 3,500 researchers nationwide used it to further their science and engineering research projects. Stanzione is also the PI of TACC’s upcoming Wrangler system, a supercomputer designed specifically for data-focused applications. He served for six years as the co-director of the iPlant Collaborative, a large-scale NSF life sciences cyberinfrastructure in which TACC is a major partner. In addition, Stanzione was a co-principal investigator for TACC’s Ranger and Lonestar supercomputers, large-scale NSF systems previously deployed at UT Austin.</p>
<p>“It is an honor to lead an organization with the tradition of excellence we have at TACC,” Stanzione said. “It’s a fascinating time in supercomputing, with the underlying technology changing rapidly, and the rise of ‘big data’ and cloud computing changing the marketplace. Computing and data are becoming pervasive in many fields of academic inquiry, including medicine. TACC is poised to capitalize on all of these trends and to help even more researchers make new discoveries in the years to come.”</p>
<div id="attachment_46776" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 368px"><a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/Stampede.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-46776   " src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/Stampede.jpg" alt="" width="358" height="150" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Panorama of the Stampede supercomputer, one of the most powerful supercomputers in the U.S. for open research. Able to perform nearly 10 trillion operations per second, Stampede is the most capable of the HPC, visualization and data analysis resources within the NSF Extreme Science and Engineering Discovery Environment (XSEDE).</p></div>
<p>TACC is also preparing a new office facility adjacent to its research complex at the J.J. Pickle Research Campus in North Austin, which will allow TACC to expand its visualization capabilities and provide new spaces for training, collaboration and events for the public.</p>
<p>Stanzione previously served as the founding director of the Fulton High Performance Computing Initiative at Arizona State University and served as an American Association for the Advancement of Science Policy Fellow in the NSF’s Division of Graduate Education. He has served as acting director of TACC since January.</p>
<p>Stanzione received his bachelor’s degree in electrical engineering and his master’s degree and doctorate in computer engineering from Clemson University, where he later directed the supercomputing laboratory and served as an assistant research professor of electrical and computer engineering.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/tacc-executive-director-dan-stanzione/#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/07/02/tacc-executive-director-dan-stanzione/feed/atom/" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Steve Franklin</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Method for Isotope Enrichment Could Secure a Vital Global Commodity]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/30/stable-isotopes-enrichment-method/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/27/</id>
		<updated>2014-06-30T14:05:04Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-30T14:05:55Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Research" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="College of Natural Sciences" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Department of Physics" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="isotope" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="MAGIS" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Mark Raizen" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="national security" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="nuclear medicine" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="nuclear physics" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="nuclear power" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="nuclear reactor" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[AUSTIN, Texas — Researchers at The University of Texas at Austin have devised a new method for enriching a group of the world’s most expensive chemical commodities, stable isotopes, which are vital to medical imaging and nuclear power, as reported this week in the journal Nature Physics. For many isotopes, the new method is cheaper than&#8230;&#160;&#160;&#160;<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/30/stable-isotopes-enrichment-method/" class="read-more">&#187;&#160;Continue Reading</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/30/stable-isotopes-enrichment-method/"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_46733" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 410px"><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zIRi-7AxFAM" target="_blank"><img class="size-full wp-image-46733" src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/MAGIS-700px.jpg" alt="MAGIS Device (magnetically activated and guided isotope separation)." width="400" height="240" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">MAGIS Device (magnetically activated and guided isotope separation). Click on the image to view an animation of the MAGIS device in action and to read more about how it works. Animation by Marianna Grenadier.</p></div>
<p>AUSTIN, Texas — Researchers at The University of Texas at Austin have devised a new method for enriching a group of the world’s most expensive chemical commodities, stable isotopes, which are vital to medical imaging and nuclear power, as reported this week in the journal <em>Nature Physics</em>. For many isotopes, the new method is cheaper than existing methods. For others, it is more environmentally friendly.<span id="more-46724"></span></p>
<p>A less expensive, domestic source of stable isotopes could ensure continuation of current applications while opening up opportunities for new medical therapies and fundamental scientific research.</p>
<p>Chemical elements often exist in nature as a blend of different variants called isotopes. To be useful in most applications, a single isotope has to be enriched, or separated out from the rest.</p>
<p>A combination of factors has created a looming shortage of some of the world’s most expensive but useful stable isotopes.</p>
<p>Last year, <a title="Government Accountability Office report" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/10/09/business/energy-environment/report-says-a-shortage-of-nuclear-fuel-looms.html" target="_blank">the Government Accountability Office released a report</a> warning that there may soon be a shortage of lithium-7, a critical component of many nuclear power reactors. Production of lithium-7 was banned in the U.S. because of environmental concerns, and it's unclear whether the current sources, in China and Russia, will continue meeting global demand.</p>
<p>One of the major sources of molybdenum-99, essential for medical imaging in tens of millions of heart, kidney and breast procedures each year, is an aging nuclear reactor in Canada that's <a title="New York Times article on aging nuclear reactor in Canada" href="http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/07/science/ge-ends-bid-to-create-a-supply-of-technetium-99m.html" target="_blank">expected to cease operations in 2016</a>.Other valuable isotopes are produced by Cold War era machines known as calutrons operating in Russia. Their extreme age, high operating costs and regional concentration further threaten global supply.</p>
<p>“Isotopes are among the most expensive commodities on Earth,” says Mark Raizen, professor of physics in The University of Texas at Austin’s College of Natural Sciences and author on the study. “One ounce of a stable isotope that needs the calutron to separate it can run around $3 million. That’s roughly 2,000 times the price of gold. And that has held back certain medical therapies.”</p>
<p>Unlike the calutron, which requires huge amounts of energy to maintain a magnetic field with electromagnets, the new method for enriching stable isotopes, called MAGIS (magnetically activated and guided isotope separation), needs little energy due to its use of low-powered lasers and permanent magnets. It also has less potential for environmental effects than the chemical process used in producing lithium-7, which has been linked to mercury contamination.</p>
<p>Nuclear medicine in particular could benefit from the new method, the researchers say. Many stable isotopes are precursors to the short-lived radioisotopes used in medical imaging, cancer therapies and nutritional diagnostics.</p>
<p>The new method also has the potential to enhance our national security. The researchers used the method to enrich lithium-7, crucial to the operation of most nuclear reactors. The U.S. depends on the supply of lithium-7 from Russia and China, and a disruption could cause the shutdown of reactors. Other isotopes can be used to detect dangerous nuclear materials arriving at U.S. ports.</p>
<p>Raizen's co-authors on the paper are Tom Mazur, a Ph.D. student at the university; and Bruce Klappauf, a software developer at Enthought and a former senior research scientist at UT Austin.</p>
<p>Now, Raizen's top goal is getting this technology out of the lab and into the world. The MAGIS invention has been issued a U.S. patent, which is owned by The University of Texas at Austin, with Raizen and Klappauf as inventors.</p>
<p>Raizen plans to create a nonprofit foundation to license the technology.</p>
<p>“I believe this is world-changing in a way that is unique among all the projects that I have done. And I do feel passionately about it,” said Raizen. “There are many potential uses of isotopes that we don't even know yet. But they've been held back because the price has been so high, or it's been unavailable. That will be one of the missions of the foundation — to explore and develop isotopes to benefit humanity.”</p>
<p>Some critics have raised concerns about the potential for terrorists or rogue states to use MAGIS to enrich uranium for nuclear weapons. Raizen believes these concerns are unfounded given uranium's unique chemical characteristics. <a title="Read an online debate between Raizen and Francis Slakey" href="http://www.aps.org/publications/apsnews/201301/backpage.cfm" target="_blank">Read an online debate between Raizen and Francis Slakey</a>, a physicist and associate director of public affairs for the American Physical Society.</p>
<p>This research was funded by The University of Texas at Austin.</p>
<p>The University of Texas at Austin is committed to transparency and disclosure of all potential conflicts of interest of its researchers. Dr. Raizen has submitted required financial disclosure forms with the university. He has received research funding for other projects from the Texas Higher Education Coordinating Board, the Welch Foundation, the National Science Foundation and the U.S. Department of Energy. Klappauf and Mazur have no financial ties to the isotope industry or isotope consumers.</p>
<p><strong>More Info</strong></p>
<p>For a global map showing where molybdenum-99 (Mo-99) is enriched, the steps to produce it and the challenges to the global supply, go to: <a title="Global map showing where molybdenum-99 (Mo-99) is enriched" href="http://www.mallinckrodt.com/Nuclear_Imaging/Global_Mo-99_Supply_Chain.aspx" target="_blank">http://www.mallinckrodt.com/Nuclear_Imaging/Global_Mo-99_Supply_Chain.aspx</a></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/30/stable-isotopes-enrichment-method/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/30/stable-isotopes-enrichment-method/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Marc Airhart</name>
						<uri>http://www.cns.utexas.edu/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers Reveal How Electric Fish Evolved Their Shocking Skills Independently at Six Different Times]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/electric-fish-evolution-zakon/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/</id>
		<updated>2014-06-26T19:33:27Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-26T15:40:25Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Research" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="biology" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="College of Natural Sciences" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="fish" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Harold Zakon" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[AUSTIN, Texas — New research demonstrates that the six electric fish lineages, all of which evolved independently, used essentially the same genes and developmental and cellular pathways to make an electricity-generating organ for defense, predation, navigation and communication. The work will be published June 27 in the journal Science. The research was led by Michael Sussman&#8230;&#160;&#160;&#160;<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/electric-fish-evolution-zakon/" class="read-more">&#187;&#160;Continue Reading</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/electric-fish-evolution-zakon/"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_46693" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 310px"><a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/electric-eel-steven-johnson.jpg" target="_blank"><img class="size-medium wp-image-46693 " src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/electric-eel-steven-johnson-300x225.jpg" alt="Electric Eel" width="300" height="225" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">New research demonstrates that the six electric fish lineages, all of which evolved independently, used "genetic toolbox" to make an electricity-generating organ for defense, predation, navigation and communication. This photo of an electric eel is by Steven Johnson.</p></div>
<p>AUSTIN, Texas — New research demonstrates that the six electric fish lineages, all of which evolved independently, used essentially the same genes and developmental and cellular pathways to make an electricity-generating organ for defense, predation, navigation and communication.<span id="more-46691"></span></p>
<p>The work will be published June 27 in the journal <em>Science</em>. The research was led by Michael Sussman of The University of Wisconsin-Madison, <a href="http://cns.utexas.edu/component/cobalt/items/1-directory?Itemid=830" target="_blank">Harold Zakon</a> of The University of Texas at Austin and Manoj Samanta of the Systemix Institute in Redmond, Wash.</p>
<p>Fish evolved an electric organ independently half a dozen times in environments ranging from the flooded forests of the Amazon to murky marine environments. Charles Darwin himself cited electric fish as prime examples of convergent evolution, where unrelated animals independently evolve similar traits to adapt to a particular environment or ecological niche.</p>
<p>“The surprising result of our study is that electric fish seem to use the same ‘genetic toolbox’ to build their electric organ,” despite the fact that they evolved independently, says Jason Gallant, an assistant professor at Michigan State University and co-lead author of the study.</p>
<p>To reach their conclusions, the researchers assembled the complete genome of the most potent electric fish, the electric eel, and the genetic sequences involved in constructing electric organs and skeletal muscles from three fish lineages that have independently evolved electric organs.</p>
<p>Zakon, professor of biology and neuroscience in The University of Texas at Austin’s <a href="http://cns.utexas.edu/" target="_blank">College of Natural Sciences</a>, identified some of the genes that, depending on how they are regulated, can turn simple muscle tissue into an electric organ. Zakon and Gallant also identified some of the key molecular pathways used by multiple electric fish lineages to converge on similar electric organs</p>
<p>"An exciting result of this work is that it pinpoints steps in various cellular pathways that are the most likely to evolve in other animals as well," says Zakon. "For example, the pathways that transmit electrical pulses in the vertebrate heart, including our own heart, derive from muscles. We find that electric organs in fish and these pathways in our hearts share some of the same regulatory genes.”</p>
<p>The electric organ is used by fish in murky environments to communicate with mates, navigate, stun prey and as a shocking defense, probably a reason the muddy Amazon and its tributaries teem with electric fish, including the electric eel. Not really an eel but a fish more closely related to the catfish, the electric eel produces a jolting electric field of up to 600 volts, about 100 volts per foot of fish.</p>
<p>All muscle cells have electrical potential. Simple contraction of a muscle will release a small amount of current. But at least 100 million years ago some fish began to amplify that potential by evolving from muscle cells another type of cell called an electrocyte, larger cells organized in sequence and capable of generating much higher voltages than those used to make muscles work.</p>
<p>The “in-series" alignment of the electrocytes and unique polarity of each cell allow for the “summation of voltages, much like batteries stacked in series in a flashlight,” says Sussman. An electric eel body contains many millions of such “flashlights” working together and firing their electrical discharge simultaneously</p>
<p>“Our study demonstrates nature’s creative powers and its parsimony, using the same genetic and developmental tools to invent an adaptive trait time and again in widely disparate environments," says Susmann, a professor of biochemistry and director of the UW-Madison Biotechnology Center, who first undertook the exploration of the electric organ almost a decade ago. "By learning how nature does this, we may be able to manipulate the process with muscle in other organisms, and in the near future, perhaps use the tools of synthetic biology to create electrocytes for generating electrical power in bionic devices within the human body or for uses we have not thought of yet.”</p>
<p>The study was funded by the National Science Foundation, the W.M. Keck Foundation and the National Institutes of Health.</p>
<p><em>This was adapted from a </em><a href="http://www.wisc.edu/" target="_blank"><em>University of Wisconsin-Madison</em></a><em> press release.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/electric-fish-evolution-zakon/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/electric-fish-evolution-zakon/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Jennifer Tisdale</name>
						<uri>http://www.hrc.utexas.edu/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Texas Collection of Comedias Sueltas and Spanish Theater Available for Research and in Online Database]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/texas-collection-comedias-sueltas/" />
		<id>http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/24/</id>
		<updated>2014-06-26T14:52:19Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-26T14:52:11Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="News Stories" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Cataloging Hidden Special Collections and Archives" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="comedias sueltas" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Council on Library and Information Resources" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Cushing Library at Texas A&amp;M" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="database" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Department of Hispanic Studies at Texas A&amp;M University" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Department of Spanish and Portuguese at The University of Texas at Austin" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Harry Ransom Center" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Leandro Fernández de Moratín" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Lope de Vega" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Manuel Tovar" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Matos Fragoso" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Mildred Boyer" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Mira de Amescua" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Pedro Calderón de la Barca" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Ramón de la Cruz" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Richard Oram" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Rojas Zorilla" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="sueltas" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Texas A&amp;M University" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Texas Collection of Comedias Sueltas and Spanish Theater" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="The State of the Comedia Suelta: Celebrating the Texas Collections" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Tirso de Molina" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="Vélez de Guevara" /><category scheme="http://www.utexas.edu/news/" term="zarauelas" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Texas Collection of Comedias Sueltas and Spanish Theater is available for research at the Harry Ransom Center, a humanities research library and museum at The University of Texas at Austin. Individual records for each suelta are also available in an online database, providing extensive information about the collection. This news is also available in&#8230;&#160;&#160;&#160;<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/texas-collection-comedias-sueltas/" class="read-more">&#187;&#160;Continue Reading</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/texas-collection-comedias-sueltas/"><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.hrc.utexas.edu/collections/books/holdings/sueltas/" target="_blank">Texas Collection of Comedias Sueltas and Spanish Theater</a> is available for research at the Harry Ransom Center, a humanities research library and museum at The University of Texas at Austin. Individual records for each suelta are also available in an online <a href="http://norman.hrc.utexas.edu/sueltas" target="_blank">database</a>, providing extensive information about the collection.<span id="more-46596"></span></p>
<p>This news is also <a href="http://www.hrc.utexas.edu/press/releases/2014/comedias_sueltas.html" target="_blank">available in Spanish</a>.</p>
<div id="attachment_46600" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 514px"><a href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/texas-collection-comedias-sueltas/sueltas_image/" rel="attachment wp-att-46600" target="_blank"><img class="size-full wp-image-46600 " src="http://www.utexas.edu/news/files/Sueltas_Image.jpg" alt="" width="504" height="335" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Comedias sueltas from the Harry Ransom Center&#039;s collection. Photo by Anthony Maddaloni.</p></div>
<p>The collection includes more than 15,000 “comedias sueltas,” a generic term for plays published in small pamphlet format in Spain from the early 17th century through the early 20th century. The materials at the Ransom Center have been described as one of the major collections of Spanish dramatic literature in suelta form in North America.</p>
<p>Within the collection, more than 2,500 authors were identified, publishing sueltas and related works from 1603 to the late 1930s. Nearly 600 sueltas at the Cushing Library at Texas A&amp;M University were also cataloged as part of the project.</p>
<p>The Council on Library and Information Resources (CLIR) funded the cataloging project “Revealing Texas Collections of Comedias Sueltas” under its “Cataloging Hidden Special Collections and Archives” initiative. CLIR is a nonprofit organization that works with libraries, cultural institutions, and communities of higher learning to enhance research and teaching.</p>
<p>The funding allowed for the creation of a database with individual records for each suelta, making extensive information about the collection available on the Ransom Center’s website.</p>
<p>Within the database, works are searchable by author, title, composer, place of publication, publisher, printer, keyword and date. Dimensions of the works, stamps or markings, handwritten notations, added text and the presence of musical and illustrative content are also noted.</p>
<p>Researchers will discover the vast chronological scope and depth of the Texas sueltas holdings. Many provide a glimpse into popular Spanish theatrical and musical entertainment genres, and some of the works overlap with the better known genre of “zarzuela,” a type of Spanish operetta.</p>
<p>The majority of these plays were published after the mid-19<sup>th</sup> century, originating in Madrid or Barcelona. Several hundred were published in smaller cities throughout Spain and Latin America. The collection’s more than 2,000 translations into Spanish originate predominantly from French, Italian and English, with some from German and Catalan.</p>
<p>Within the collection are the 1,119 sueltas described in Mildred Boyer’s bibliography “Texas Collection of Comedias Sueltas” (1978)<em>,</em> covering the second half of the 17<sup>th</sup> century until 1833.</p>
<p>“The collection and database will be excellent resources for scholars interested in the history of the Spanish book,” said Richard Oram, Ransom Center associate director and Hobby Foundation Librarian. “Literary and bibliographical scholars will find scores of unique but previously invisible titles, performing arts historians will discover arcane titles in all manner of theatrical genres, and students of music history will find what are effectively libretti of musical works. Cross-disciplinary projects using the sueltas can certainly be foreseen.”</p>
<p>The cataloging project revealed a previously <a href="http://blogs.utexas.edu/culturalcompass/2014/06/17/cataloging-projects-reveals-unknown-copy-of-a-comedia-suelta/" target="_blank">unknown copy of a comedia suelta</a>, examples of <a href="http://blogs.utexas.edu/culturalcompass/2013/11/05/zarzuelas/" target="_blank">zarzuelas</a>, <a href="http://blogs.utexas.edu/culturalcompass/2013/01/11/cartoons-manuel-tovar/" target="_blank">works by Spanish caricaturist Manuel Tovar</a> and <a href="http://blogs.utexas.edu/culturalcompass/2012/09/13/illustrating-the-sueltas/" target="_blank">illustrated sueltas</a>.</p>
<p>Among the represented dramatists in the earlier sueltas is Pedro Calderón de la Barca, regarded as one of Spain's foremost dramatists and one of the finest playwrights of world literature. The works of Lope de Vega, Matos Fragoso, Mira de Amescua, Rojas Zorilla, Vélez de Guevara, Tirso de Molina, Leandro Fernández de Moratín and Ramón de la Cruz are also in the collection.</p>
<p>Sept. 29-30, the Department of Spanish and Portuguese at The University of Texas at Austin, the Department of Hispanic Studies at Texas A&amp;M University and the Ransom Center will host the conference “<a href="http://www.utexas.edu/cola/depts/spanish/news/Spotlight-news/the-state-of-the-comedia-suelta-celebrating-the-texas-collections.php" target="_blank">The State of the Comedia Suelta: Celebrating the Texas Collections.</a>” Held at the Ransom Center, the conference will highlight writers and/or works represented in the collection. Researchers from a variety of fields — including Hispanic literature and culture, history of the book, music, theater, bibliography, conservation and library science — are expected to attend.</p>
<p>High-resolution press images are available.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/texas-collection-comedias-sueltas/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.utexas.edu/news/2014/06/26/texas-collection-comedias-sueltas/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
<!--This is a cached file, set to expire July 21, 2014 1:56 pm-->