<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en"
  xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Loyola Magazine</title>
	<subtitle type="text">Magazine for Loyola College in Maryland</subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-18T18:31:16Z</updated>
	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="2.6.3">WordPress</generator>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" />
	<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/feed/atom</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/feed/atom" />

			<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[From the Frontlines]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/alumni/7323/from-the-frontlines" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7323</id>
		<updated>2014-07-18T18:31:16Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-18T18:12:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="alumnus" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="author" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="battle of gettysburg" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="book" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="civil war" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Gettysburg" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="literature" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Author John Michael Priest, ’72, tells the stories of Civil War soldiers on the frontlines of the fighting at the Battle of Gettysburg from Cemetery Ridge to Little Round Top on July 2, 1863, through [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/alumni/7323/from-the-frontlines"><![CDATA[<p>Author John Michael Priest, ’72, tells the stories of Civil War soldiers on the frontlines of the fighting at the Battle of Gettysburg from Cemetery Ridge to Little Round Top on July 2, 1863, through letters, memoirs, and diaries in his new book, <em>Stand to It and Give Them Hell</em>.</p>
<p>Priest, who was a history major and secondary education minor at Loyola, spent five years researching and gathering materials for the book to accurately portray the average soldier’s experience in the battle<span>—</span>a perspective that is often missing from the romanticized version of war in history textbooks.</p>
<div id="attachment_7333" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 230px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/priest-mike.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7333  " title="John Michael Priest" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/priest-mike.jpg" alt="John (&quot;Mike&quot;) Priest, '72" width="220" height="330" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">John &quot;Mike&quot; Priest, &#39;72</p></div>
<p>Priest has been a Civil War buff for as long as he can remember. He spent his childhood surrounded by World War II veterans, including his father, which sparked his interest in telling the story from the average soldier’s point of view. Priest saw firsthand how war impacts a man<span>—</span>but these stories are rarely told.</p>
<p>He is a retired high school history teacher who also writes a blog, “<a href="http://johnmpriest.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">Ramblings of a Military Historian</a>.” In his spare time, he is a tour guide at Antietam.</p>
<p>The book is Priest’s fifth battle book told from the perspective of the soldiers on the frontlines. The novel will be available in mid-August. <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Stand-Give-Them-Hell-Experienced/dp/161121176X/ref=la_B001K8JMG4_1_1/178-5624977-2035511?s=books&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1405601916&amp;sr=1-1" target="_blank">Readers can pre-order the book on Amazon</a>.</p>
<p><em>Loyola</em> magazine invited Priest to chat about his new book and discuss why telling the stories of the average soldier is important.</p>
<h2>What interested you in creating a Civil War book from firsthand perspectives? Why did you choose to focus on this particular battle?</h2>
<p>I started writing about Civil War history in the 1980s. All my books are told from the perspective of people getting shot at, not the generals. The average guy gets overlooked and left out of the picture in the big history books.</p>
<p>The Civil War is the first war in which the solider wrote extensively about it. The average solider in writing what they saw, not how important it was, has nothing to lose by telling the truth. He has no reputation to save. He has his own life to worry about.</p>
<p>For me, writing the book was like being a forensic scientist at a crime scene. You have the pieces but you need to put them together, and the picture doesn&#8217;t really come out the way the pieces have fit before.</p>
<p>I don’t think anyone has written about the average solider at this level. What the men remember are the intimate things: kneeling down to a friend and kissing him on the field before he dies, twin brothers getting hit together and one brother watching the other fall. These are the little things men just didn&#8217;t expect when they went to battle. These memories changed those men. It probably haunted them. It’s not pleasant. That’s the human element<span>—</span>and it often gets left out. It’s brutal.</p>
<p>I was raised around World War II veterans. None of them came home the same. The Civil War veteran was the same way. There’s nothing grandiose about war. No soldier intentionally did something heroic in battle. They did it because they had to for survival. Battle is like a brawl: everyone gets pulled into it. There’s no rhyme or reason, it’s chaotic<span>—</span>and that’s how I portray it.</p>
<p>I wrote it like a novel, which irritates people. But it is a novel. It’s a never ending story. Someone had to understand what these guys went through. It’s a shame that wars don’t end when the shootings stop.</p>
<div id="attachment_7336" class="wp-caption alignleft" style="width: 230px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/stand-to-it-give-them-hell.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7336" title="stand-to-it-give-them-hell" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/stand-to-it-give-them-hell.jpg" alt="" width="220" height="330" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Priest&#39;s book, available in August 2014.</p></div>
<h2>You’ve been interested in the Civil War since an early age. Why?</h2>
<p>I was raised in Virginia for a few years and we always went to Gettysburg out of Fairfax when I was a boy. We were always around it. I grew up on the literature and went to the historical places. It fascinated me. I&#8217;ve always been interested in the Civil War, since I can remember. I still play with toy soldiers.</p>
<h2>What is it about the Civil War that so many people find so compelling?</h2>
<p>A lot of people have blood ties to it. That’s what draws people. It’s sacred to make contact where their relatives were.</p>
<h2>How long was the gathering process<span>—</span>finding all the letters, memoirs, and diaries? Was the process different from working on the other books you&#8217;ve written?</h2>
<p>It took about five years to gather the research and about five years to find publisher, a total of 10 years; it’s been a while. Five years is the average time for research.</p>
<h2>How did you decide the title of the book?</h2>
<p>It’s a quote from a colonel giving what I call a “brave up talk” to his men. To paraphrase, he told them if anyone runs, I’m going to shoot him. I’m going to stand and give them hell. And if I run, you shoot me. He is encouraging the men to stand their ground during the battle.</p>
<h2>Any plans for your next book?</h2>
<p>I’m working on series of three books on The Battle of Spotsylvania Court House.</p>
<h2>Did you have a faculty member at Loyola who was particularly influential on your experience? If so, who and how?</h2>
<p>My three favorite professors were Nick Varga, Stuart Rochester, and Hans Mair. Varga taught history and had been in the Battle of the Bulge in World War II, but he wouldn&#8217;t talk about it. Stuart Rochester taught American intellectual history, which involved literature, history, and lifestyles. We looked at how Americans see themselves and how they think.</p>
<h2>How did your Loyola experience influence what you&#8217;ve accomplished today?</h2>
<p>You can’t beat a good Jesuit education. The academics are superb. For a guy like me who doesn&#8217;t do sports, I could be a bookworm and no one bothered me. I loved it.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/alumni/7323/from-the-frontlines#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/alumni/7323/from-the-frontlines/feed/atom" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Loyola adds color to Baltimore’s artscape]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7301/loyola-adds-color-to-baltimore%e2%80%99s-artscape" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7301</id>
		<updated>2014-07-18T17:43:13Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-18T17:43:13Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Beyond Loyola" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="art" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="artwork" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="baltimore" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="festival" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="music" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="summer" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Loyola adds color to Baltimore’s growing artscape]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7301/loyola-adds-color-to-baltimore%e2%80%99s-artscape"><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Starting today through Sunday evening, more than 300,000 lovers of the visionary and performing arts (not to mention snowballs and funnel cake) will flock to Charm City to explore the country’s largest free arts festival, which takes place in Baltimore every year during the third weekend of July.</p>
<div id="attachment_7304" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/artscape-artists-market-edwin-remsberg-photography1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7304" title="artscape-artists-market-edwin-remsberg-photography1" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/artscape-artists-market-edwin-remsberg-photography1.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="332" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Edwin Remsberg</p></div>
<p class="MsoNormal">Artscape features more than 150 fine artists and craftspeople, fashion designers, photographers, actors, musicians, performers, puppeteers<span>—</span><span>you name it: If it has to do with art, there&#8217;s a good chance it has a place at Artscape.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;"><span>From the famous “art cars,” automobiles that have been transformed into fantastic, eye-popping works of art by their owners to metal works and ceramics&#8230; lovers of the weird and wonderful, of all ages and all levels of appreciation for the arts, are sure to find something that speaks to them at Artscape. </span>Festival</span><span style="font-size: 13px;"> goers can buy paintings or sculpture, participate in hands-on activities with vendors, and catch a variety of live music from varying genres at any of the festival’s three main stages.</span></p>
<div id="attachment_7305" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/artscape-main-stage-edwin-remsberg-photography.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7305" title="artscape-main-stage-edwin-remsberg-photography" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/artscape-main-stage-edwin-remsberg-photography.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Edwin Remsberg</p></div>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">The festival is open to the public and takes place outdoors in tents that line Mount Royal Avenue, Cathedral Street, and Charles Street, and inside exhibition spaces and performing arts venues surrounding the Maryland Institute College of Art and University of Baltimore campuses and the Station North Arts and Entertainment District.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: left;"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/artscape-jpg.jpg"></a></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<p class="MsoNormal">In addition to the outdoor installations and performances, Artscape provides a stage for the finalists, semi-finalists, and grand prize winner of the Janet &amp; Walter Sondheim Prize, a $25,000 fellowship awarded each year to a visual artist living and working in the Baltimore area.</p>
<h2>A Touch of Green and Grey</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">Loyola&#8217;s own <a href="http://www.jonmalis.com/">Jon Malis</a>, professor of photography in the fine arts department, was selected as a semi-finalist for the prestigious and highly-coveted 2014 Sondheim Prize. Malis&#8217;<span style="font-size: 13px;"> work will be on display in an exhibition of the semifinalists’ work at MICA’s Decker and Meyerhoff galleries at 1303 West Mount Royal Avenue for the duration of Artscape.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">(And this isn&#8217;t Loyola&#8217;s first representation in the top tier of the Sondheim Prize entries: <a href="http://www.sarahmcneil.com/">Sarah McNeil</a>, an <span>affiliate faculty member in Loyola&#8217;s fine arts department</span><span>, was named a semi-finalist for the award in 2012.)</span></p>
<div id="attachment_7309" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/artscape-jpg1.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7309" title="artscape-jpg1" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/artscape-jpg1.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="309" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Brigid Hamilton</p></div>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: 13px;">While </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">Artscape is perhaps the largest and most apparent compilation of Baltimore’s art scene, it is only one of dozens of the &#8220;art-thusiastic&#8221; projects popping up in Charm City, adding to Baltimore’s growing, colorful art scene.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<p class="MsoNormal"><a href="http://www.janetmaher.com/">Janet Maher</a>, professor of studio arts at Loyola, has exhibited at the Artscapes of years past—in 1999, 2000, and 2001, including juried exhibits in several of the area galleries <span style="font-size: 13px;">and a site-specific installation during the festival called <em>V</em></span><em>iewing Station: Martyrology, </em>for which a dozen artists were given a box the size of a phone booth to put their work in.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">“I love everything at Artscape,&#8221; Maher says. &#8220;I have always been someone who loves to go listen to outdoor music and go look at everything that is going on. I love that kind of mass of humanity. Even in the early years of Artscape, the heat didn&#8217;t really bother me because I just love it so much!&#8221;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">“When I first moved to Baltimore years ago, I was missing New Mexico. I loved it there. I&#8217;m still very attached to the people and the place, but coming to a place like Baltimore, where things like this happen I&#8217;ve always been a huge fan of the art scene here, from my first year in this city.”</p>
<h2>The Spirit of It All</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">Although Maher won&#8217;t be showing at Artscape this year, she will be among the thousands in attendance, checking out her colleague&#8217;s work and taking in &#8220;the spirit of it all.&#8221; <span style="font-size: 13px;">It is a spirit that extends to many of Baltimore City&#8217;s galleries and shows that take place not just on a hot July weekend, but throughout the year.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">“<a href="http://www.creativealliance.org/">The Creative Alliance</a> is part of that spirit, too,&#8221; Maher explains. &#8220;They&#8217;ve been part of that funky, wonderful thing from the beginning, and the organization has evolved along with Artscape. I always encourage my students become members of the Creative Alliance if they are staying in Baltimore after graduation, and to try to exhibit in as many different kinds of galleries and shows as possible.”</span></p>
<p><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-7310" title="33-2" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/33-2-270x202.jpg" alt="" width="270" height="202" /></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">For years, Maher&#8217;s students have been displaying their artwork in an annual exhibit at <a href="http://www.mdartplace.org/home">Maryland Art Place</a> called <em>Out of Order</em>, during which the artists actually go to the space and hang their own work on the walls in any order they choose.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;<em>Out of Order</em> is neat because the artists are also the curators in a way,&#8221; she said.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Maher&#8217;s own work is currently on display at the School 33&#8217;s Art Center in Federal Hill as part of an exhibit called <em>3</em></span><em>5-33-35</em><span style="font-size: 13px;">, a celebration of School 33&#8217;s 35th anniversary, featuring 35 artists who have made an impact with their support and dedication of the school over the years.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;School 33 was originally established as a neighborhood art center in South Baltimore. When I first moved to Baltimore, my studio was in School 33. That little back corner of the main room where the <em>35-33-35</em> exhibit is now? That was my whole world.&#8221; Maher remembers.</p>
<h2>Writing the Book on Art</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Maher, who considers herself a mixed media artist, teaches 2-D design, drawing, digital design, and printmaking at Loyola, as well as a form of art that is growing ever more popular among visual artists called &#8220;book art&#8221; and &#8220;the artist&#8217;s book.&#8221; </span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Book art calls for a</span><span style="font-size: 13px;"> physical manipulation and an intimate contact with the artwork on the part of the viewer, much in the way we interact with common books. </span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">&#8220;</span><span>You’re playing with the form of a book and the idea of reading, but it’s all visual and tactile,&#8221; Maher explained. &#8220;It&#8217;s not something you put on the wall, but it&#8217;s not a sculpture because it&#8217;s interactive; you don’t just walk around it and admire it.&#8221;</span></p>
<div id="attachment_7312" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/33-31.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7312" title="33-31" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/33-31.jpeg" alt="" width="500" height="666" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Maher&#39;s mixed-media assemblages are pictured on the bottom row, from left to right: &quot;Computation,&quot; &quot;Moment&quot;, and &quot;Perijud 12.&quot; | Photo by Brigid Hamilton. </p></div>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: 13px;">&#8220;It’s a broad, open category</span><span style="font-size: 13px;">—</span><span style="font-size: 13px;">which is why I like it so much! </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">Artists&#8217; books tend to be adventurous as artworks. They may involve painting, drawing, printmaking, collage, and aspects of sculpture. They may be fine or crude. They may be made of materials other than paper. Their form grows from the inside out such that the materials and the overall look of the work reflects the content.&#8221; </span></p>
<div id="attachment_7313" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 410px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/33-4.jpeg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7313" title="33-4" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/33-4.jpeg" alt="" width="400" height="566" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Closeup of Maher&#39;s work entitled &quot;Computation,&quot; a mixed-media assemblage made with papers and boards, plastic, acrylic paint. | Photo by Brigid Hamilton</p></div>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: left;"><span style="font-size: 13px;">&#8220;This kind of art</span><span style="font-size: 13px;">—and art in general</span><span style="font-size: 13px;">—is always evolving. That&#8217;s probably why Artscape and the Baltimore art scene is always growing, always changing. It&#8217;s just thrilling.&#8221;</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: left;">Learn more about <a href="http://www.artscape.org/">Artscape</a> and <a style="font-style: italic;" href="http://www.school33.org/index.cfm?page=exhibits&amp;section=current&amp;exhibitID=89">35-33-35</a><em>, </em>open now through August 21.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: left;">Get your culture fix this summer while supporting the talented artists who teach, learn, and create at Loyola.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7301/loyola-adds-color-to-baltimore%e2%80%99s-artscape#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7301/loyola-adds-color-to-baltimore%e2%80%99s-artscape/feed/atom" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[12 ways you can help your child learn to read]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7280/12-ways-you-can-help-your-child-learn-to-read" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7280</id>
		<updated>2014-07-16T14:49:58Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-16T14:46:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Beyond Loyola" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Default" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="graduate programs" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="literacy" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Loyola Clinical Centers" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="speech-pathology/audiology" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="summer" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="summer reading" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tignor and Reinhardt, creators and directors of the Ready, Set, Read! program at the Loyola Clinical Centers, shared with Loyola magazine 12 tips for reading at home with your child.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7280/12-ways-you-can-help-your-child-learn-to-read"><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">Whether during car rides to soccer camp, a walk on the boardwalk, or over a Popsicle, the summer months provide extra time for parents and family members to read to and discuss books with their children.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span>Kara Tignor is the division director of speech-language pathology and audiology at the Loyola Clinical Centers (LCC). She and </span><span>Dana Reinhardt, division director of LCC’s literacy clinic, have created </span><span>an interdisciplinary reading readiness program for children ages 4-6 called Ready, Set, Read!</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Tignor and </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">Reinhardt</span><span style="font-size: 13px;"> </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">shared with </span><em>Loyola </em><span style="font-size: 13px;">magazine 12 tips for encouraging reading at home during the summer months</span><span style="font-size: 13px;">—and throughout the year.</span></p>
<h2>1. Make reading a special time.</h2>
<p>Reading is a way of bonding with your child over a book; you get quality time together <em>and</em> they are learning through the experience.</p>
<p>Share your favorite stories as a child. Make a special trip to the library or book store. Have a favorite place to read books together.</p>
<p><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_96311.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7293" title="img_96311" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_96311.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<h2>2. Model reading and identify parts of a book.</h2>
<p>Start by pointing to the title and author and read them aloud. Use your finger to track the words on each page. Even if the child is too young to read, he or she is learning the proper left-to-right reading pattern.</p>
<h2>3. Read aloud to your child, no matter his or her age.</h2>
<p>It is always beneficial for a child to listen to a fluent reader model reading for them. This is especially true if the level of reading of the book is above your child&#8217;s level. Children should listen to stories that are rich in language, as they are still learning to read the words.</p>
<h2>4. Talk about the book.</h2>
<p>Talk about the book before, during, and after reading. Children should be <em>thinking</em> about the story/topic in order to understand what they are reading. Encourage them to ask questions, summarize what they have read, and make connections to other stories or experiences that relate to the book. Ask a lot of &#8220;Why?&#8221; and &#8220;How?&#8221; questions. Have the child describe the pictures in the book and make predictions about what might happen next.</p>
<div id="attachment_7289" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_9597-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7289" title="img_9597-2" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_9597-2.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tara McGarvey, a graduate student in Loyola University Maryland&#39;s reading specialist master&#39;s program, leads a discussion with children enrolled in Ready, Set, Read! at the Loyola Clinical Centers.</p></div>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<h2>5. Read for a purpose.</h2>
<p>Demonstrate how many times a day you have to read. Begin to ask your child to read the &#8220;everyday reading&#8221; to you: recipes, signs, directions, text messages to mom or dad.</p>
<h2>6. Choose &#8220;just right&#8221; books.</h2>
<p>When selecting books for your child to read, keep in mind they should be able to read <em>most </em>of the words on the page without any help. This way, they are concentrating on meaning, rather than what the words are. Use the &#8220;Five Finger Rule&#8221;: If the child is unable to identify more than five words on a page, the book is too difficult to read independently.</p>
<h2>7. Interest is key!</h2>
<p>Let your child read what they are interested in! It doesn&#8217;t matter if they are reading magazine articles or award-winning books&#8230; <span style="text-decoration: underline;">It matters that they read.</span> The more they read, the better readers they will become.</p>
<h2>8. Write, draw, write.</h2>
<p>Encourage your child to write as much as they are willing to. Reading and writing develop simultaneously.  Your child can write emails, texts, letters, grocery lists, thank you notes, or even keep a journal or diary&#8230; If your child cannot spell words, help them hear the sounds in the word and write down what they hear.</p>
<p>If they are too young to write, have them draw a picture of their favorite part of the book, and let them dictate a sentence or two to you.</p>
<p><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_9663.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7290" title="img_9663" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_9663.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<h2>9. &#8220;What does that mean?&#8221;</h2>
<p>Children are curious about language and their world.</p>
<p>Explain new vocabulary and words they are unsure of. This will build their oral language and reading vocabulary. Make a list of new words that they learn, and talk about the words at different times.</p>
<h2>10. Share the story.</h2>
<p>Have your child tell another person—a sibling, a parent, a grandparent—about the story you just read.  Guide their summaries as needed by asking questions about specific parts. Soon their ability to retell stories will improve.</p>
<h2>11. Mix it up!</h2>
<p>Read a variety of genres with your child, including non-fiction. Children need exposure and familiarity with all genres: fiction and non-fiction, such as fairy tales, realistic fiction, poetry, fantasy; non-fiction, biographies, and informational text, to name a few.</p>
<h2>12. Play games with words.</h2>
<p>Try to come up with as many words that rhyme with a selected word as possible. Go around the dinner table and everyone can take a turn. Pick a sound/letter (e.g. &#8216;b&#8217;), and come up with as many words that start with that sound.</p>
<p>Clap out the beats or syllables in words. Start with family members&#8217; names, and model how to clap out the syllables.</p>
<p><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_9646.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7291" title="img_9646" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_9646.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;"><br />
Ready, Set, Read! kicked off on July 1 with 22 students enrolled in sessions at LCC’s headquarters in Belvedere Square in north Baltimore. </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">LCC hopes to expand the program next year to serve more students. </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">Read more about Ready, Set, Read! </span><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://www.loyola.edu/news/2014/0711-ready-set-read">here.</a></p>
<p>Looking for more tips from our experts? <span style="font-size: 13px;">Check out </span><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7216/6-ways-to-help-your-child-learn-this-summer%E2%80%94while-having-fun">this article</a><span style="font-size: 13px;"> on six ways to help your child learn this summer—</span><span style="font-size: 13px;">while having fun.</span></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7280/12-ways-you-can-help-your-child-learn-to-read#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7280/12-ways-you-can-help-your-child-learn-to-read/feed/atom" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Five-Point Heart]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/alumni/7269/the-five-point-heart" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7269</id>
		<updated>2014-07-15T17:31:45Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-15T16:08:32Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Opinion" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="reflection" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="service" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tom Butler, '95, is a professor of English at Eastern Kentucky University. He shares his experience as a hospice volunteer.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/alumni/7269/the-five-point-heart"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_7270" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 160px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/coffee.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7270 " title="coffee" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/coffee.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="200" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Brigid Hamilton</p></div>
<p class="MsoNormal">When the volunteer coordinator from the local hospice called me, she said that she&#8217;d had a hard time finding someone to visit Lester because he was a heavy smoker.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Lester&#8217;s wife had asked the coordinator if someone could spend a few hours with Lester so she could drive to Eastern Kentucky to pay her respects at a family member&#8217;s grave.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Once I agreed to take this assignment, I called Phyllis, Lester&#8217;s wife, and set up a time for my visit to their home. She thanked me for offering to help her and then admitted that she&#8217;d planned not to pay respects at a grave but, instead, to visit a shooting range.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Explaining this confusion, she said, &#8220;Lester wants me to be safe once he passes.&#8221; <span style="font-size: 13px;">I said I&#8217;d be there at 10:45 on Monday morning.</span></p>
<p>Phyllis led me into the living room, which was dark and cluttered with sheets of piano music and old books primarily about World War II, gardening, and cooking. I sat on the sofa and immediately felt the years of cigarette smoke seep into my clothes.</p>
<p>After a few moments, Phyllis pulled Lester in his wheelchair backward into the living room. &#8220;It&#8217;s easier to get him around everything this way,&#8221; she said with a smile. As she maneuvered the chair toward me, I stood up, and Lester&#8217;s entrance felt oddly ceremonial, since he neither spoke nor turned toward me until Phyllis had finished her maneuvering.</p>
<p>I held out my hand, and Lester&#8217;s scabby, trembling hand slowly took hold of it as I introduced myself. He looked up from his hunched posture and nodded.</p>
<h2>A hole in the heart</h2>
<p>Phyllis left us with two pots of coffee, some of which she kept in a couple of fastened Mason jars on the kitchen counter. I poured cups for Lester and me once I found cups hidden amid an array of bills, advertisements, and medicine bottles on the kitchen table.</p>
<p>&#8220;Care for anything in your coffee, Lester?&#8221; I shouted into the living room. &#8220;Just my sweetener; that&#8217;s here,&#8221; he responded.</p>
<p>I placed Lester&#8217;s cup next to his cigarettes and a heap of blue packets of artificial sweetener. I admired Lester&#8217;s illogical insistence in choosing<span lang="EN-AU">—</span>despite his terminal condition and steady intake of nicotine<span lang="EN-AU">—</span>a (supposedly) healthy alternative to sugar.</p>
<p>Through a steady dosage of cigarettes (at one point, he had two lit at once), Lester told me about his life.</p>
<p>He grew up in poverty-ravaged Eastern Kentucky, went into the Marine Corps, got married, divorced, married again, and held many jobs in several states.</p>
<p>He was proudest of the vegetable gardens he created in his small backyard. He expressed disappointment when I told him that I planted my tomato plants about two feet apart in my own haphazard backyard garden. He shook his head: &#8220;That&#8217;s nowhere near enough.&#8221;</p>
<p>He looked up and admitted he has double-vision. He chuckled, &#8220;It&#8217;s the darnedest thing: There&#8217;s two of you there.&#8221; I told him that a lamp was next to me, not another me. A flash of mischief appeared in his eye: &#8220;And if I may say so, the lamp is better looking than you.&#8221;</p>
<p>Lester said that his problem was simple: a hole in the heart. He had luck with treatments and managed to land a spot on a list for an experimental procedure. According to Lester&#8217;s explanation, doctors fastened a tiny clamp around the hole. Unfortunately, the clamp did not fit properly, and the doctors had no other recourse. For now, the clamp was precariously holding Lester&#8217;s heart together, and it would snap someday. &#8220;Then I became a short-timer,&#8221; Lester quipped.</p>
<p>&#8220;How do you feel about that?&#8221; I asked clumsily.</p>
<p>&#8220;Well, I&#8217;m not sorry for anything.&#8221;</p>
<p>Silences regularly punctuated his speech, and a long one came between us now. Then he let his ash fall onto his lap and continued, &#8220;I had some luck with the stock market, and Phyllis should be OK.&#8221;</p>
<p>The backdoor opened, and Phyllis returned earlier than we had expected. She came into the living room holding a rolled-up poster as if it were a precious scroll. She stood before us and unfurled it, revealing its depiction of a human upper body. The sketch divided the body into several sections with a number between 0 and 5 in the center of each. Each arm had a 1 on it, each of the torso&#8217;s shirtsleeves was marked with a 0, and the head and heart each had a 5, making them the real prize.</p>
<p>Phyllis stretched out the paper and proudly pointed out the holes, reflecting the success of her first time ever shooting a gun.</p>
<p>She craned her neck toward the far side of the paper. &#8220;Those shots there were my first, but I got the hang of it pretty quick.&#8221;</p>
<p>Sure enough, the entire torso was peppered with holes. Lester, the Marine vet, beamed and took hold of the side of the target, making the entire paper tremble.</p>
<p>She then nodded toward the 5-point circle at the center of the torso. It was dotted by several holes, some overlapping with others.</p>
<p>&#8220;See that, I&#8217;m real proud of that there. You won&#8217;t have to worry about me, baby.&#8221;</p>
<div id="attachment_7271" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 509px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/tom-on-germ-ave.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7271" title="tom-on-germ-ave" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/tom-on-germ-ave.jpg" alt="Photo submitted by Tom Butler, '95" width="499" height="333" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo submitted by Tom Butler, &#39;95.</p></div>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span><em>Originally from Philadelphia, Tom Butler graduated from Loyola in 1995 with degrees in English and philosophy. Tom studied in Leuven, Belgium, during his junior year, and following his graduation from Loyola, he returned to Leuven for an M.A. in philosophy (and, it’s true, plentiful good beer). He went on to earn a Ph.D. in English from the University of Notre Dame. </em></span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span><em>Today Tom teaches English at Eastern Kentucky University and, f</em></span><em>or the past two years, he has served as a hospice volunteer in Lexington, Kentucky. </em><em>In his free time, Tom likes to run marathons.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/alumni/7269/the-five-point-heart#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/alumni/7269/the-five-point-heart/feed/atom" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembering Frank Cashen]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7236/remembering-frank-cashen" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7236</id>
		<updated>2014-07-03T03:43:06Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-02T18:01:11Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Default" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="baltimore" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="baltimore stories" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="baseball" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="reflection" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The sports world lost one of its most respected figures on Monday when Frank Cashen, '45, the famed baseball executive, died at a hospital near his Easton, Md., home. He was 88 years old.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7236/remembering-frank-cashen"><![CDATA[<p>The sports world lost one of its most respected figures on Monday when famed baseball executive Frank Cashen, &#8216;45, died at a hospital near his Easton, Md., home. He <span style="font-size: 13px;">was 88 years old.</span></p>
<p>Cashen, who became the Baltimore Orioles&#8217; general manager in 1966, is best known for helping build a team that went to four World Series—winning in 1966 and 1970—and later <span style="font-size: 13px;">completely transforming a losing New York Mets team </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">to become the World Series champions of 1986.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">Born in Baltimore, John Francis &#8220;Frank&#8221; Cashen studied English at Loyola, where he played second base for the Greyhounds baseball team. </span>Cashen later earned a law degree from the University of Maryland.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">Cashen worked as a sportswriter and columnist for t</span>he <em>Baltimore News-American </em><em>for nearly two decades.</em> It was during this time that he began regularly wearing what would become his &#8220;signature bow tie&#8221; as a way to avoid dragging a long tie through the ink of hot-off-the-press editions.</p>
<p>Cashen&#8217;s vast experience in journalism, advertising, and law no doubt contributed to his success as a sports executive and general manager.</p>
<p>But a<span style="font-size: 13px;">s he told </span><em>Loyola </em><span style="font-size: 13px;">magazine during an interview in 2011, “I was a writer by choice, a lawyer by education, a horseman by heritage, a brewery worker by necessity, and a baseball executive by good fortune.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">You can read that interview in full </span><a style="font-size: 13px;" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/alumni/2210/legendary-leap/all/1">here.</a></p>
<p>Brian Oakes, &#8216;99, MBA &#8216;10, director of development for Loyola&#8217;s College of Arts and Sciences<span style="font-size: 13px;">, spent many hours with Cashen in both of his homes on the Eastern Shore of Maryland and </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">in Port St. Lucie, Fla. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">Oakes shared with </span><em>Loyola</em><span style="font-size: 13px;"> magazine some of his fondest memories of these visits&#8230;</span></p>
<h2>Stories, Sports Banter, and a Signing</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;At that time, I was working as the director of alumni relations. The director of planned giving and I would fly to Florida and then rent a car and drive to Port St. Lucie,&#8221; Oakes recalled.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;Mr. Cashen would always greet us at and invite us into his home. He was a very unassuming person. <span style="font-size: 13px;">He would ask us to lunch, and he often would bring a friend, many times another Loyola guy. </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">Our conversations would always begin with an update on Loyola, and then Mr. Cashen would tell us stories. He was a great storyteller, and he had a lot of stories,&#8221; Oakes said.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">&#8220;We would sit in his home and he&#8217;d tell us all these stories about his family</span><span style="font-size: 13px;">—he doted on his children and grandchildren, his family was very important to him; about golfing in Ireland and in Florida</span>—he loved to golf;<span style="font-size: 13px;"> </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">about Baltimore and what being a student at Loyola was like in the 1940s, what his colleagues were doing at the time,&#8221; said Oakes. </span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">&#8220;And then the conversation would inevitably turn to baseball&#8230;&#8221;</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Cashen showed Oakes and his colleague his World Series Champions trophy one afternoon. </span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">It was on a shelf with other objects, like any other knickknack. </span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">&#8220;He had great insight. He would tell us about what he called &#8216;his Orioles&#8217; of today, and of the &#8217;60s. He still listened to all the games on the radio,&#8221; Oakes said.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">During one of his last visits to Cashen&#8217;s Florida home, Oakes and his colleague decided to take a chance and ask Cashen to sign two baseballs.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;We were afraid that it might be misconstrued as inappropriate, but at the end of our time with him, we presented the baseballs to Mr. Cashen with this sort of sheepish look—we were fans, too—and he thought nothing of it. He just motioned with his hand for us to bring them to him,&#8221; Oakes remembered.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Cashen opened a desk drawer and pulled out what was his signing pen from a special case, and he signed the baseballs for Oakes and his colleague, who noticed that the drawer was <em>also</em> full of autographed Topps baseball cards from Cashen&#8217;s days with the Mets.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">Cashen saw the men eyeing up the cards, and gave them each one to take home.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;<span style="font-size: 13px;">I’ve worked at Loyola for ten years, and one of my greatest memories is spending time with Mr. Cashen and the day he signed the ball and gave us those baseball cards,&#8221; said Oakes.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_3204.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7245" title="img_3204" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_3204.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">Cashen was inducted into the Mets Hall of Fame in 2010, along with other players from the 1986 World Series team, including Dwight Gooden and Darryl Strawberry, and </span><span style="font-size: 13px;">Davey Johnson. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">Many baseball executives consider Cashen the finest front-office man of his generation to this day. </span></p>
<p>Cashen is survived by his wife, Jean; five sons, Timothy, Brian, Sean, Gregory, and Terrance; two daughters, Stacy and Blaise; and nine grandchildren.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">He will certainly be missed by his family and friends, and by the world of baseball.</span></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7236/remembering-frank-cashen#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7236/remembering-frank-cashen/feed/atom" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[What your friends think when you forgive a romantic partner]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/academics/7231/what-your-friends-think-when-you-forgive-a-romantic-partner" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7231</id>
		<updated>2014-07-02T18:12:09Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-02T16:04:22Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Academics" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="forgiveness" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="psychology" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="relationships" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="research" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="theresa didonato" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Do your friends judge you for the decisions you make? They just might if you forgive a romantic partner, no matter the severity of his or her indiscretions.
Call it a “spillover effect.”
Theresa DiDonato, Ph.D., assistant [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/academics/7231/what-your-friends-think-when-you-forgive-a-romantic-partner"><![CDATA[<p>Do your friends judge you for the decisions you make? They just might if you forgive a romantic partner, no matter the severity of his or her indiscretions.</p>
<p>Call it a “spillover effect.”</p>
<p>Theresa DiDonato, Ph.D., assistant professor of psychology at Loyola University Maryland, explores this issue in “<a href="http://spr.sagepub.com/content/early/2014/05/23/0265407514536291.abstract" target="_blank">The Fallout of Forgiveness</a>,” research published online in the <em>Journal of Social and Personal Relationships</em> in May 2014 and conducted with collaborators Marianna Carlucci, Ph.D., assistant professor of psychology, and Laurette McIlwee, ’13.</p>
<p>Loyola magazine sat down with DiDonato to discuss the key takeaways from what she discovered.</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s the ‘fallout of forgiveness’?</h2>
<p>The ‘fallout of forgiveness’ refers to the unintended consequences of forgiving a romantic partner for committing a relational offense. A relational offense can be anything from an annoying irritation (e.g., forgot to take out the trash) to something much more serious (e.g., had an affair).</p>
<p>In our research, we learned that decisions to forgive or not forgive a romantic partner have a spillover effect: friends hear about or observe these events happening and use this information to form impressions. For example, if Sally experiences a relational offense and forgives her partner, Sally’s friends are likely to assume that Sally is happy in her relationship and committed to her partner. If she forgives a serious offense, they are apt to see her as incompetent, but warm.</p>
<p>These relationship and person judgments are what’s so exciting about this research: it helps us appreciate that relationships don’t happen in isolation, they happen in a very alive and perceptive social context.</p>
<h2>What surprised you most?</h2>
<div id="attachment_7237" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 234px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/theresa-didonato.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7237 " title="theresa-didonato" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/theresa-didonato.jpg" alt="Theresa DiDonato, Ph.D." width="224" height="337" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Theresa DiDonato, Ph.D.</p></div>
<p>We were impressed by how much friends know about other peoples’ relationship troubles. People definitely talk to their friends, for support and comfort, but friends are also highly observant and are aware of a lot. They also use this information to color their views of their friends, which is so interesting. We think our friends see us in a certain light, but our own relationship experiences can change their impressions of us.</p>
<p>We were also surprised by the dramatic way in which friends penalized their friends for forgiving severe offenses (e.g., cheating). When friends forgave cheating partners, people were apt to see them as less competent, which is associated with friendship behaviors like distancing and other negative social perceptions. In other words, if someone is in an abusive relationship and forgives his/her partner, that person’s friends might actually treat them differently and not provide the support they need. Such conclusions underscore how much our relationships occur within a social context.</p>
<h2>Why do people forgive their romantic partners for indiscretions?</h2>
<p>Relationships are complex and no partner is perfect. Conflict, offenses, and irritations are normal aspects of a healthy relationship, and forgiveness is a way to promote commitment. Many people forgive their partners for mild or even serious offenses because they are highly invested in the relationship, their partner has apologized, they believe it was a one-time offense, or because they are committed to the relationship’s future.</p>
<p>Whether it was a forgotten anniversary, a physical confrontation, a miscommunication, or an affair, offenses can be complex and challenging to navigate. Forgiveness is generally a process that helps sustain a romantic partnership.</p>
<h2>How does forgiving a romantic partner&#8217;s transgressions affect relationship quality?</h2>
<p>Forgiveness is generally viewed as a positive factor in relationships, promoting commitment and satisfaction. In our research, however, we found that forgiveness is not universally positive. In the same way that repeated forgiveness of a serious offense can hurt someone’s own sense of self respect, forgiveness of a serious offense has broader consequences, predicting negative judgments from others.</p>
<h2>What advice do you have for someone whose friend forgives a romantic partner for a relational offense?</h2>
<p>Friends play an important role in the health and wellbeing of others’ relationships. Friends can offer support, help, and advice. When we know someone who is navigating a relational offense and deciding whether to forgive or not to forgive, as friends we can do our best to provide support and stay engaged in the friendship, regardless of their relationship decisions.</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s the focus of your research, in general, and what got you interested in it?</h2>
<p>I’m an experimental social psychologist whose work focuses on the intersection of self and other, so I spend a lot of time thinking deeply about interpersonal relationships. My research tends to focus on romantic relationships, be they just forming, ongoing, or in the process of falling apart. I ask questions like, “How does humor affect romantic attraction? How do our romantic partners influence our sense of self? What factors predict hook-up regret?”</p>
<p>Close, intimate relationships are so important to psychological wellbeing that I can’t help but be fascinated by the dynamics of romantic relationships. Plus, I usually don’t have too much trouble recruiting students to help with my work – most people want to know more about how to find and maintain healthy relationships.</p>
<h2>What&#8217;s next for you?</h2>
<p>My current research could be fodder for future, related research. At present, we can only marginally disentangle the chicken or egg question when it comes to friends’ perceptions and their knowledge of relational transgressions. Are the relational transgressions changing people’s impressions? We think so, but it may be the case that peoples’ impressions color the lenses through which they interpret their friends’ relationship events and decisions.</p>
<p>Big picture, I tend to juggle a number of projects at the same time, but they all tend to ask compelling questions about romantic relationships. Next up, I’m looking at romantic relationship attraction and how the simple decisions that potential partners make, like choosing to purchase a luxury item (like a BMW) or an eco-friendly item (like a Prius) can predict an array of impressions that might in turn predict romantic attraction. I love my work because I can add new understanding to questions that matter in individuals’ everyday lives.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/academics/7231/what-your-friends-think-when-you-forgive-a-romantic-partner#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/academics/7231/what-your-friends-think-when-you-forgive-a-romantic-partner/feed/atom" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[6 ways to help your child learn this summer—while having fun]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7216/6-ways-to-help-your-child-learn-this-summer%e2%80%94while-having-fun" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7216</id>
		<updated>2014-06-23T13:42:24Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-23T13:36:59Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Beyond Loyola" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="children" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="education" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="learning" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="make learning fun" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="school of education" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="summer" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="summer reading" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As summer vacation begins, students are sent home with summer reading lists and instructions to keep children’s minds active over the summer. How do you balance trips to the playground and pool with cultivating academic excellence?]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7216/6-ways-to-help-your-child-learn-this-summer%e2%80%94while-having-fun"><![CDATA[<p class="MsoNormal">As summer vacation begins, students are sent home with summer reading lists and instructions to keep children’s minds active over the summer.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">How do you balance trips to the playground and pool with cultivating academic excellence?</p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><em>Loyola </em>magazine asked <a href="http://www.loyola.edu/soe/faculty/w-smith" target="_blank">Wendy Smith, Ph.D., associate professor of teacher education</a> in Loyola’s School of Education, to offer advice to parents on how to keep their children learning through the summer.</p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpFirst"><!--[if !supportLists]-->1.<span> </span><!--[endif]--><strong>Focus on your children’s interests.</strong> “Summer is a more relaxed time. Spend some time talking with your children, and find out what they are interested in. Maybe your child likes dogs or nature or space exploration. Maybe they studied about the Holocaust this year, and your child was intrigued by that. Figure out what your child is really interested in and you can do all kinds of things. You could join a nature museum or take them to some places in D.C., like the Holocaust museum. Ask yourself, &#8216;What kind of day trips could we take as a family that might enhance what my child loves?&#8217;” Smith suggests.</p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/100_4913.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7217" title="100_4913" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/100_4913.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">2.<span> </span><strong>Read books aloud together. </strong>“You can do this any time of the year, but summer lends itself to more reading when people seem to have a little more time as a family,&#8221; Smith says. &#8220;When my children were young, my husband read the Hobbit books to them<span>—</span>even when they were teenagers<span>—</span>in the evening. It was a really special time. Then you can talk about the issues you find in the books. A lot of the time people say, ‘They’re 8 years old. They can read themselves,’ and there’s nothing wrong with that. But older kids still do like to be read to.</p>
<p>When you’re picking a book to fit a wide variety of ages, look at Newberry award winners. The winners this year cover a wide variety of issues, and they can give you some things to talk about as a family.”</p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">3.<span> </span><strong>Avoid formal, structured learning. </strong>“I definitely wouldn&#8217;t recommend workbooks or formal education, unless the child is behind and needs a tutor. Children need this opportunity to think about their learning and not in a formal way.”</p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_0948.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7220" title="img_0948" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/img_0948.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">4.<span> </span><strong>Incorporate fun learning into a family trip.</strong> “You don’t want to make anything you do too much like schoolwork, but if you’re planning a trip, you could have your child help plan how many miles is it and how much gas will you use. They can use some math skills, but they’re not really thinking about math<span>—a</span>nd you can tell them your goal for the day and let them follow the map along the way.”</p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">5.<span> </span><strong>Sign up for your library’s summer reading program. </strong>“Find out what kinds of books your child likes to read so you can help find them at the library. Sometimes we just assume our child is going to love this book because we loved it,&#8221; Smith explains. &#8220;My daughter loved nonfiction, and I didn&#8217;t realize that for a while. The city libraries and the county libraries have these wonderful children’s librarians helping children find out what’s best for them.”</p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">6.<span> </span><strong>Don’t put pressure on yourself or your child.</strong> <strong>Enjoy the summer.</strong> “Summer is a time when you can focus on who they are and what they like and help them pursue that.”</p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/100_2608.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7218" title="100_2608" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/100_2608.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="375" /></a></p>
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpMiddle">
<p class="MsoListParagraphCxSpLast">
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7216/6-ways-to-help-your-child-learn-this-summer%e2%80%94while-having-fun#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7216/6-ways-to-help-your-child-learn-this-summer%e2%80%94while-having-fun/feed/atom" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The rapid growth of Christianity in China]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/academics/7202/the-rapid-growth-of-christianity-in-china" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7202</id>
		<updated>2014-06-16T19:37:19Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-16T17:08:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Academics" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="china" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="chinese government" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="christianity" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="communist party" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Religious freedom in China has progressed substantially over the last three decades, and with it has come a record growth of Christianity and increased suspicion from the Chinese government. But China’s booming population of practicing [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/academics/7202/the-rapid-growth-of-christianity-in-china"><![CDATA[<p>Religious freedom in China has progressed substantially over the last three decades, and with it has come a record growth of Christianity and increased suspicion from the Chinese government. But China’s booming population of practicing Christians is flourishing despite the ruling Communist Party’s continued efforts to tamp down on church activities.</p>
<p>On June 3, 2014, the Brookings Institution hosted a public panel of experts to explore the topic. Among the experts at “Christianity in China: Force for Change?” was Carsten Vala, Ph.D., assistant professor of political science at Loyola University Maryland, who studies the dynamic between China’s government and Christianity in the country.</p>
<p><em>Loyola</em> magazine asked Dr. Vala to discuss what he’s learned from his research, and what the future might look like for Christians in China.</p>
<h2>What’s the focus of your research related to Christianity in China?</h2>
<p>My research investigates the interactions between the Chinese Communist Party-state and Protestant Christianity, specifically understanding how the Party aims to influence Christians in official churches and in unregistered &#8220;house&#8221; churches to support its rule.</p>
<h2>Describe the state of Christianity in China today and give us some historical background.</h2>
<p>Christianity has a long history in China, with the earliest presence being Nestorian Christians in the 7th century. Protestants really came in the 1800s, arriving in great numbers after Great Britain defeated the Qing dynasty forces in the Opium Wars.</p>
<p>Because the British forced China to buy opium, open ports for trade with the outside world, and allow missionaries to enter the country, the association of the &#8220;Bible and gun&#8221; in the popular imagination helped Communist historians attack Protestant missionaries as Western imperialists. Today, after Communists expelled all missionaries (Catholics, too), Protestant Christianity has flourished and become the fastest growing religion in a time of religious revival. Although some claim that there are as many as 100 million or more Christians in China, better estimates say there are 40 to 60 million Protestants and another 10-13 million Catholics. Protestants have grown at least 10-fold in 30 years, one of the fastest growth rates in world history!</p>
<div id="attachment_7210" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/carsten-vala.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7210 " title="Carsten Vala" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/carsten-vala.jpg" alt="Carsten Vala in China." width="500" height="409" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Carsten Vala on Nanluoguxiang Lane in Beijing, China.</p></div>
<h2>How have the policies of China’s government influenced the growth of Christianity? Is religion in general growing in China?</h2>
<p>The policies of the Chinese Communist Party-state have benefited Christianity in surprising ways. The attempts to eradicate all religion in the Mao Zedong period from 1949 to 1976 sparked lay believers to spread the faith, strengthening a &#8220;house church&#8221; movement that began in the pre-1949 era. The PRC government reopened official churches in the early 1980s as part of a promise to U.S. President Jimmy Carter, and tens of millions of Christians worship in Protestant and Catholic churches. Scholars generally agree that more Christians worship outside the official churches recognized by the government, however.</p>
<p>Religion as a whole is booming. Buddhists number in the hundreds of millions and are the largest group, but they lack the clear membership rituals that Christians have in baptism, so many people participate in Buddhist rituals without being regular believers. Also, Buddhists lack the social structures of small groups for prayer and Bible study that both strengthen faith and hold believers accountable to making changes in their lives.</p>
<p>Government officials see religion in a more positive light these days because it attracts investment from overseas Chinese believers, draws tourists to local religious sites, and religious believers operate a range of social welfare activities like nursing homes, orphanages, poverty alleviation, and disaster relief.</p>
<h2>What does it mean to be a Christian in China? Is it different than in other countries?</h2>
<p>Being a Christian in China presents difficulties that believers in the U.S. and countries in Western Europe do not face. Although citizens often respect Christians as good people, some government officials view Christians with suspicion, linked to the role of Christianity in the downfall of Eastern European regimes and the strong support by democratic countries such as the U.S. and South Korea for Chinese Christians.</p>
<p>Also, universities, for example, are still run by Communist Party officials, and so some professors face pressure and discrimination for their beliefs, leading to some Chinese calling themselves &#8220;cultural Christians&#8221; who appreciate the values and beliefs without joining a church and getting baptized. There still can be a cost to declaring one&#8217;s faith openly.</p>
<h2>What have you discovered in your research that has surprised you most?</h2>
<p>Most surprising has been the rise of a new type of &#8220;urban church&#8221; that rejects subordination under Communist Party authority and also rejects being a small, hidden church like the traditional &#8220;house&#8221; churches. Leaders of these churches have forged a third way, welcoming interested newcomers as well as Communist Party officials and police to attend their congregations. They seek to be a more open and visible component of society, not under control of the Party-state.</p>
<h2>What does the future look like for Christianity in China?</h2>
<p>Christianity is a diverse religion in China. Some say there are &#8220;Christianities,&#8221; because there are many different theologies, attitudes toward the state, and populations that range from intellectual, high-status Chinese churches to migrant worker churches to rural churches. Because Christian doctrines include the expectation of persecution, pressure from authorities helps spur growth as fleeing believers find new areas in which to spread the faith.</p>
<p>At the same time, the gravest challenges come from a lack of trained pastors and from a materialist culture focused on success. These factors lead to weak believers and a variety of heretical sects.</p>
<p>Overall, Protestants in China are growing at such a rapid rate that some experts suggest China will become the largest Christian country in less than 20 years. In any case, two recent events suggest a nervousness on the part of the Chinese Communist Party towards Christians:</p>
<p>First, the Chinese Communist Party&#8217;s detained leading lawyers and constitutional scholars – many of whom are Chinese Christians – before the 25th anniversary of the June 4, 1989 crackdown on Tiananmen Square movement. Several top Tiananmen leaders now in exile have also become Christian.  Second, a provincial leader in the southeastern coastal region has started a campaign to topple crosses and raze official Christian churches because they are too prominent.</p>
<p><em>A wrap up story of the “Christianity in China” panel discussion featuring Dr. Vala is available at <a href="http://www.brookings.edu/blogs/brookings-now/posts/2014/06/tiananmen-square-leader-and-other-experts-describe-growth-of-christianity-in-china" target="_blank">brookings.edu</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/academics/7202/the-rapid-growth-of-christianity-in-china#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/academics/7202/the-rapid-growth-of-christianity-in-china/feed/atom" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on the life of Maya Angelou]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7179/reflecting-on-the-life-of-maya-angelou" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7179</id>
		<updated>2014-05-29T01:40:36Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-28T16:39:12Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Beyond Loyola" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="african american history" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="maya angelou" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="poet" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="poet laureate" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="still i rise" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Poet and author Maya Angelou, who delivered the Eighth Annual Sr. Cleophas Costello Lecture at Loyola in 1990, touched many lives throughout her life. Loyola magazine invited members of the Loyola community to celebrate her life and reflect on her impact.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7179/reflecting-on-the-life-of-maya-angelou"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_7187" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/se9-a.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7187" title="se9-a" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/se9-a.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="351" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Maya Angelou during a visit to Loyola in 1990.</p></div>
<p>Poet and author Maya Angelou, who delivered the Eighth Annual Sr. Cleophas Costello Lecture at Loyola in 1990, touched many lives throughout her life.</p>
<p><em>Loyola </em>magazine invited members of the Loyola community to celebrate her life and reflect on her impact.</p>
<h2>Opening Unusual Doors</h2>
<p><a href="http://www.loyola.edu/academic/english/faculty/norman">Brian Norman, Ph.D.,</a> is director of African and African American studies at Loyola. His courses focus largely on civil rights literature, a time in American history during which Angelou played a major role.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">Norman pointed out that while Angelou is mainly known for her work as an autobiographer and poet, she was a woman of many talents who got her start as dancer and singer. She went on to tour Europe; she performed on Broadway; she recorded several albums. Angelou taught classes at Wake Forest University and even authored cookbooks.</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">“She had a pretty impressive resume for a young girl who grew up in segregated Arkansas. And we have to remember that she came of age during the height of the Civil Rights movement. There was great responsibility that came with being a Civil Rights artist and a black artist. Angelou gave a heart to the movement—not just to protest injustices, but to celebrate and revel in the beauty and in the lives of everyday black folks.”</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Norman explained people connect with Angelou because she spoke from her own experience as a black woman: “Folks even beyond her own specific identify found themselves represented in her, in the way that she found out of her own history of pain, both personal and political, a sense of beauty, grace, and integrity that came from her growing up in the Jim Crow South and then as a celebrated artist on the world stage.”</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<p class="MsoNormal"><span style="font-size: 13px;">Just yesterday, Norman said he was reading Angelou’s eulogy of her friend, James Baldwin, at whose funeral she spoke in 1987. She closed in saying, “His love opened the unusual door for me, and I am blessed that James Baldwin was my brother.”</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">“That’s what Angelou did for many. She opened &#8216;unusual doors&#8217; from her own pain and isolation… to beauty and fellowship,” Norman reflected.</p>
<div id="attachment_7188" class="wp-caption aligncenter" style="width: 510px"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/se9-b.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-7188" title="se9-b" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/se9-b.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="342" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Maya Angelou addressed a sellout crowd in McGuire Hall during her visit.</p></div>
<p><span style="font-weight: normal;"><br />
</span></p>
<h2>My Heart Has Stopped</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;For just a moment, my heart has stopped. The same way that it stopped when my Nana passed away, when Toni Cade Bambara passed away, when Tata Madiba passed away. I met Auntie Maya Angelou when I lived in New York. It was in 1999 and I had just won The Langston Hughes, David Diop, Etheridge Knight Poetry Award from The Gwendolyn Brooks Creative Writing Center. She came over to me after I received myAward, grabbed my hand and gave me a hug. She then said, &#8216;Keep writing baby, the world needs your words so that we can become a little bit better.&#8217; To this day, I write these words in the front of every journal that I have and I have them hanging in my bedroom to remind myself to keep writing, to keep going, and to keep doing my part to make the word better. Today, just for a moment, when a friend called to give me the news, my heart stopped.</p>
<p class="MsoNormal">I met Auntie Maya Angelou again in 2002. At that time, I was a young mother, pregnant with my second son, and had just received a New York Emmy-nomination for my documentary &#8216;Twin Towers: A History.&#8217; I asked her for some advice on how to ke<span class="textexposedshow">ep going everyday because I was exhausted. She then took my copy of her book, wrote something down, gave it back to me, and said do everything with Joy! She then hugged me and moved on to the next person.&#8221;</span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: right;">—<em>Kaye Whitehead, Ph.D., assistant professor of communication and African &amp; African American Studies and author of <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Notes-Colored-Girl-Diaries-Frances/dp/1611173523/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1401298787&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=notes+from+a+colored+girl" target="_blank">Notes from a Colored Girl: The Civil War Pocket Diaries of Emilie Frances Davis</a></em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/whiteheadbook.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7197" title="whiteheadbook" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/whiteheadbook.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="666" /></a></p>
<h2>A Great Loss to Humankind</h2>
<p>&#8220;The death of Maya Angelou is a great loss to humankind.  She was a steady backbone for a people grappling with issues of diversity. <span style="font-size: 13px;">She inspired me as a woman and as an educator to  dare to think big thoughts, to dare to love, and to dare to create change where needed.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 13px;">This is one of my favorite quotes of hers: &#8216;</span><span style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal;">The desire t</span><span style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal;">o reach the stars is ambitious. The desire to reach hearts is wise and most possible.&#8217;&#8221;</span></p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>—Kari O&#8217;Grady, Ph.D., assistant professor in the pastoral counseling department</em></p>
<h2>An Evergreen Memory</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;As part of the Evergreen Players, I often got to meet celebrities who came to Loyola&#8217;s campus to speak. In 1990, I had the pleasure of listening to and meeting Maya Angelou. I can close my eyes and still hear her captivating voice and amazing words. She was quite the inspiration and will be missed.&#8221;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: right;"><em>—Michele Wojciechowski, &#8216;90, writer and president of Wojo Enterprises</em></p>
<h2>What a Gift</h2>
<p>&#8220;I remember reading &#8216;Still I Rise&#8217; for the first time in high school, feeling power bestowed on me through Angelou&#8217;s voice, spirit, and strength.  I go back to those words again and again, gaining more with each read.  What a gift that her presence will always BE there to carry me through life&#8217;s constant trials.&#8221;</p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>—Erin O&#8217;Keefe, &#8216;03, director of the York Road Initiative</em></p>
<h2>She Spoke to Me</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;Although Maya Angelou was a black woman and was very proud of her color, she did not seem to operate from a place that focused on gender, race, sexuality, or culture. Her words, delivered in various forms&#8230;poetry, speeches, conversations, advice&#8230;spoke to everyone. I remember reading her books and being amazed by how she seemed to know me and be speaking to me directly even though we seemingly had nothing in common. Her work transcended all of those potential barriers without effort. I think that was part of her broad and long lasting appeal. I was also always struck by the positivity of all of her messages and by her constant message to embrace life joyfully and passionately.&#8221;</p>
<p class="MsoNormal" style="text-align: right;"><em><span>—</span>Janet Simon Schreck, Ph.D., CCC-SLP, executive director, Loyola Clinical Centers</em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<p class="MsoNormal">
<p class="MsoNormal">
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7179/reflecting-on-the-life-of-maya-angelou#comments" thr:count="2"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/beyond-loyola/7179/reflecting-on-the-life-of-maya-angelou/feed/atom" thr:count="2"/>
		<thr:total>2</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>editor</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Senior BBQ&#038;A]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7150/senior-bbqa" />
		<id>http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/?p=7150</id>
		<updated>2014-05-22T16:59:57Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-22T16:59:57Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Default" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Graduating Greyhounds" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="Opinion" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="commencement" /><category scheme="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue" term="undergraduate" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Loyola magazine picked Loyola seniors' brains on an array of topics, from what kind of sandwich they would have named after them to what they will miss most about college after they walk across the stage at Baltimore Arena on May 17.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7150/senior-bbqa"><![CDATA[<p>Bean bags, grilled kabobs, and Nantucket red shorts were all featured at the annual Senior BBQ that took place on the Arminger House lawn last week, two days before Loyola&#8217;s 162nd Commencement Exercises.</p>
<p><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7151" title="picnic1" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic1.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7152" title="picnic2" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic2.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="333" /></a></p>
<p>Hosted by Loyola&#8217;s president, Rev. Brian F. Linnane, S.J., and the Loyola Alumni Association, the event gives seniors a chance to gather one last time for food, fun, and words of farewell and congratulations.</p>
<p>Senior class president Kim Porfido had the opportunity to speak to her classmates and to present Fr. Linnane with the class gift: a check for $19,929.59.</p>
<p>The Class of 2014 boasts an impressive 50% participation rate for their giving, a goal that was reached at the event as seniors made last-minute gifts in between taking photos with friends and enjoying slices of watermelon.</p>
<p><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/senior-class-gift.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7153" title="senior-class-gift" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/senior-class-gift.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="440" /></a></p>
<p>You can <a href="https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10152463694011563.1073741832.77371871562&amp;type=3">view more photos of the event here.</a></p>
<p><em>Loyola </em><span style="font-size: 13px;">magazine had the pleasure of picking our graduating seniors&#8217; brains on an array of topics, from what kind of sandwich they would have named after them to what they will miss most about college after they walk across the Baltimore Arena stage on May 17.</span></p>
<p>The participants pulled questions from our BBQ&amp;A basket and took a break between bites to share their responses with us&#8230;</p>
<h2>You can have a ticket to travel anywhere in the world. Where would you go?</h2>
<p>&#8220;I would travel to Ireland.&#8221;<em>—<span style="font-size: 13px;">Sarah Ismail</span><span style="font-size: 13px;"> received her degree in speech-language pathology</span></em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;Definitely Bora Bora.&#8221;<em>—<span style="font-size: 13px;">Erin Thompson received her degree in mechanical engineering </span></em></p>
<h2>Now that you don&#8217;t have studying to do or papers to write, what will you do in your downtime?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;I will look for a job.&#8221;<em>—Samantha Seib received her bachelor&#8217;s in business administration in international business and marketing</em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;Now that I will have downtime, and especially on Sundays, I want to focus on working out, being in shape, and being more of a productive person.&#8221;<em>—</em><em>Christopher Musarra received his B.B.A. in finance</em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;I will be going to the gym.&#8221;<em>—Alex Namin received his degree in communications</em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<p><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic-5.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7154" title="picnic-5" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic-5.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="315" /></a></p>
<h2>What will you miss most about dorm life?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;Living with and right next-door to my friends. I can’t just walk around the corner and talk to them anytime I want to.&#8221;<em>—Julia O’Connell <span style="font-size: 13px;">received her B.A. in communication</span></em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;I’ll miss being able to socialize and go right next door whenever I want to talk to my buddies and hang out… I’ll probably never have that experience again in my life.&#8221;<em>—Richard Carrara graduated from Loyola with a degree in communication</em></p>
<h2>What is your favorite memory from a Greyhound athletics event?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;When Loyola won the national championship in men’s lacrosse. It was unbelievable.&#8221;<em>—</em><em>Evan Yulo received his degree in accounting</em></p>
<h2>Which classmate who is most likely to succeed and why?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;Thomas Marcotte. I think he’s going to be the president of the United States one day, because he just wants it. He’s a motivated individual. And he’s driven.&#8221;<em>—Ben Nicholson received his B.A. in marketing</em></p>
<p>&#8220;Steve Celano. He is someone who’s really ambitious, and he has a good head on his shoulders.&#8221;<em>—Charles Cuthrell received his B.A. in communication</em></p>
<p><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic3.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7155" title="picnic3" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic3.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="308" /></a></p>
<h2>What will you be doing professionally when you return for Milestone Reunion in 2019?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;Well I&#8217;ll be 27 then, so I&#8217;ll probably be looking for health insurance policies&#8230; I hope to be working at Ernst &amp; Young, hopefully being a manager and living in New York City and not being evicted because I have a job and can make rent.&#8221;-<em>Mike Pirozzi received his bachelor&#8217;s degree in business administration in accounting</em></p>
<p>&#8220;I hope to be a physician assistant when I return to our Milestone Reunion in 2019.&#8221;—<em>Emily Smith received her B.S. in biology</em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<h2>How many free Loyola t-shirts are you leaving college with?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;An excessive number… but my favorite is the long-sleeved one that we got freshman year for Battle of the Hounds. I don’t even know what it says on it but I’ve lived in it. I can’t wear it anymore because it shrunk so much from many washes.&#8221; <em>—</em><em>Johnathan Raffensperger graduated with a degree in finance</em></p>
<p>&#8220;Probably 25!&#8221;<em><em>—</em><span style="font-size: 13px;">Kelly Gajdzisz received</span><span style="font-size: 13px;"> her degree in business economics</span></em></p>
<h2>What was your favorite place on campus to take a nap between classes?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;Sellinger, on the fourth floor&#8230; there’s a good room there for naps.&#8221;<em>—Caitlyn Conlin graduated with a B.A. in marketing </em></p>
<p class="MsoNormal"><a href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic4.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-7156" title="picnic4" src="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/wp-content/uploads/picnic4.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="473" /></a></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<h2>If Loyola would name a building, sandwich, or spot on campus after you, which one would you pick—and why?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;I would want the bench near Donnelly Science Center to be named after me, because it&#8217;s a beautiful spot to sit, its very tranquil.&#8221;<em>—Joe Lomuti received his B.S. in biology</em></p>
<h2>If you could take a piece of Loyola’s campus with you after graduation, what would it be?</h2>
<p class="MsoNormal">&#8220;The Fitness and Aquatic Center, and more specifically, the pool.&#8221;<span style="font-size: 13px;"><em>—Bryan Bedacht received his bachelor&#8217;s in business administration and was a member of the Loyola men&#8217;s swimming &amp; diving team</em></span></p>
<p class="MsoNormal">
<p class="MsoNormal">
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7150/senior-bbqa#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.loyola.edu/issue/default/7150/senior-bbqa/feed/atom" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
