<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">NC State News :: NC State News and Information</title>
	<subtitle type="text">NC State News and Information Website</subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-21T16:48:30Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu" />
	<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.7.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mick Kulikowski</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[New Residential Living Options Available On Centennial Campus]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/new-residential-living-options-available-on-centennial-campus/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=133991</id>
		<updated>2014-07-16T15:49:23Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-16T15:49:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Campus News" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Centennial Campus" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Finance &amp; Business" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Releases" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[White Oak Properties, local Raleigh real estate developer, and NC State University announced today the resumption of development and the start of pre-construction sales for North Shore Condominiums, overlooking Lake Raleigh on NC State’s Centennial Campus near the new James [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/new-residential-living-options-available-on-centennial-campus/"><![CDATA[<p>White Oak Properties, local Raleigh real estate developer, and NC State University announced today the resumption of development and the start of pre-construction sales for North Shore Condominiums, overlooking Lake Raleigh on NC State’s Centennial Campus near the new James B. Hunt Jr. Library. Located at water’s edge, North Shore will be built on Campus Shore Drive and Capability Drive. Groundbreaking is planned for late summer 2014.</p>
<p>The project resumes development of the North Shore property of approximately 15 acres and consists exclusively of ownership “for-sale” homes. Home styles will be a mix of multi-story townhomes and single-level flats. Initial development will include townhomes plus a community pool with a large outdoor patio and shelter available for the enjoyment of the current owners as well as new purchasers.</p>
<p>“North Shore offers the best of urban living in a relaxed lakeside outdoor residential neighborhood,” said Roland Gammon, president of White Oak Properties. “It is conveniently located within minutes of downtown Raleigh attractions while offering a true residential atmosphere of tree-lined streets, courtyards, walking trails, greenways and the Lake Raleigh view.”</p>
<p>The complex sits in the heart of NC State’s Centennial Campus, world renowned for its innovative mix of academic, office, lab and residential living in an amenity-rich environment.</p>
<p>&#8220;At NC State, our extensive partnerships with business, industry and government help generate a unique culture of collaboration focused on addressing the grand challenges of society,&#8221; said NC State Chancellor Randy Woodson. “The North Shore development adds a vibrant around-the-clock element that enhances the unique learning-and-living environment on campus.”</p>
<p>Jeff Davis of JDavis Architects, project architect, said, “We studied elements of the existing topography as well as the surrounding architecture to incorporate the design to be aesthetically pleasing and blend into what is becoming an amazing neighborhood. The result is to give the sense of place and connectivity with nature. Our goal is that property owners will feel a part of their surrounds and invited to participate in the opportunities that are at their doorstep.”</p>
<p>&#8220;North Shore’s views, unique design and neighborhood feel blend nicely into the natural surroundings with a world-class research university and its many private partners next door,” said Ann-Cabell Baum Andersen, marketing and sales representative with The Glenwood Agency Real Estate. “We have found many people are searching for more convenient access to outdoor activities offered via the greenways and the lake and new Lonnie Poole Golf Course, but they don’t want to give up the feel of living in a real urban neighborhood. We are offering both at North Shore.”</p>
<p><a href="http://centennial.ncsu.edu/" target="_blank">Centennial Campus</a> is home to the university&#8217;s Colleges of Engineering, Education, Textiles and Veterinary Medicine, many interdisciplinary centers and institutes, more than 60 corporate, government and non-profit partners and 75 NC State research and academic units – along with thousands of students, faculty and staff. A magnet middle school, residential housing, planned executive conference center, 18-hole championship golf course, restored watershed and recreational amenities weave the 1,334-acre campus into a true community.</p>
<p>For over thirty years White Oak Properties has been a developer of for-sale housing throughout the Triangle. In particular White Oak Properties has been a pioneer in housing opportunities in downtown Raleigh with The Cotton Mill, Park Devereux and Palladium Plaza. Several of its projects have been honored by the Raleigh Appearance Commission with the Sir Walter Raleigh Award.</p>
<p><a href="http://northshoreraleigh.com/" target="_blank">Full details</a> of the development can be viewed online.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">- 30 -</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/new-residential-living-options-available-on-centennial-campus/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/new-residential-living-options-available-on-centennial-campus/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mick Kulikowski</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[NC State Designated ‘Innovation &amp; Economic Prosperity University’ by APLU]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/nc-state-designated-innovation-economic-prosperity-university-by-aplu/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=132721</id>
		<updated>2014-07-10T14:18:01Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-10T14:04:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Administration" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Awards &amp; Recognition" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Campus News" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Chancellor" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Economic Development" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Releases" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In recognition of a strong commitment to economic engagement, the Association of Public and Land-grant Universities (APLU) today designated North Carolina State University as an Innovation &#38; Economic Prosperity University. The designation acknowledges universities working with public and private sector [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/nc-state-designated-innovation-economic-prosperity-university-by-aplu/"><![CDATA[<p>In recognition of a strong commitment to economic engagement, the Association of Public and Land-grant Universities (APLU) today designated North Carolina State University as an Innovation &amp; Economic Prosperity University. The designation acknowledges universities working with public and private sector partners in their states and regions to support economic development through a variety of activities, including innovation and entrepreneurship, technology transfer, talent and workforce development, and community development.</p>
<p>NC State received the designation after conducting a thorough self-review with outside stakeholder input and subsequently submitting an application that went through a rigorous independent review process.</p>
<p>NC State and 13 other public institutions comprise the second annual class of Innovation &amp; Economic Prosperity Universities: Georgia Institute of Technology, Indiana University, The Pennsylvania State University, Purdue University, South Dakota State University, Texas Tech University, the University of Houston, the University of Illinois, the University of Massachusetts Boston, the University of Massachusetts Lowell, the University of Pittsburgh, Virginia Tech and Wayne State University.</p>
<p>“Public universities serve as economic engines for their local communities and states by conducting cutting-edge research to reach new breakthroughs, and by developing the talent to help existing businesses grow stronger and enabling new ones to develop and thrive,” APLU President Peter McPherson said. “The 14 institutions receiving the 2014 Innovation &amp; Economic Prosperity University designation serve as models. They demonstrate how public research universities extend beyond their campuses to engage their communities in economic development that creates jobs and improves lives.”</p>
<p>“NC State is proud to be recognized by the APLU for our impact on economic development and fostering a culture of innovation that drives economic, societal and intellectual prosperity across North Carolina,” Chancellor Randy Woodson said. “Public land-grant universities are uniquely positioned to play vital roles in the growth and development of local communities. This prestigious designation opens up opportunities that will enable NC State to further strengthen our impact across the state.&#8221;</p>
<p>Innovation &amp; Economic Prosperity University designees conducted an institutional self-study and solicited input from external stakeholders. Each university designee identified three areas of institutional strength in economic engagement, and described programs in these areas. Designees also identified areas for growth and improvement for their university’s economic engagement enterprise, and developed an improvement plan. This work demonstrated a commitment to continuous learning and improvement in this kind of engagement vital to universities and their regional partners.</p>
<p>NC State now qualifies to submit an application for APLU’s 2014 Innovation &amp; Economic Prosperity University Awards, which will be given out at the association’s annual meeting in November.</p>
<p>APLU is a research, policy and advocacy organization representing 234 public research universities, land-grant institutions, state university systems and affiliated organizations.  Founded in 1887, APLU is North America&#8217;s oldest higher education association with member institutions in all 50 U.S. states, the District of Columbia, four U.S. territories, Canada and Mexico. Annually, APLU member campuses enroll 4.7 million undergraduates and 1.3 million graduate students, award 1.1 million degrees, employ 1.3 million faculty and staff, and conduct $41 billion in university-based research.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">- 30 -</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/nc-state-designated-innovation-economic-prosperity-university-by-aplu/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/nc-state-designated-innovation-economic-prosperity-university-by-aplu/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mick Kulikowski</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Hotel Planned for NC State’s Centennial Campus]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/hotel-planned-for-centennial-campus/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=132461</id>
		<updated>2014-07-09T14:00:28Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-09T14:00:28Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Campus News" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Centennial Campus" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Releases" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[NC State University today announced plans for the development of a privately managed hotel and conference facility on Centennial Campus that will operate under the Marriott Autograph Collection franchise. The new facility is expected to open with 155 rooms and [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/hotel-planned-for-centennial-campus/"><![CDATA[<p>NC State University today announced plans for the development of a privately managed hotel and conference facility on Centennial Campus that will operate under the Marriott Autograph Collection franchise.</p>
<p>The new facility is expected to open with 155 rooms and 7,500 square feet of meeting space with potential expansion of up to an additional 75 rooms and 7,500 square feet of meeting space.</p>
<p>Opening is targeted for 2016, although final plans are still in development. The hotel will overlook Lake Raleigh and sit adjacent to the current Park Alumni Center, with conference facility space complementary to the center.</p>
<p>“This hotel is the latest exciting addition to Centennial Campus. Not only will it be a place of learning and collaboration but it will also serve as an important amenity for the campus,” said Chancellor Randy Woodson.</p>
<p>The university envisions using the hotel to attract regional, national and international conferences, particularly related to education, science and technology. The new facility will also serve as a resource to help enhance the development of industry, government and academic partnerships that foster the unique learning and living environment on Centennial Campus.</p>
<p>Operating under the Marriott Autograph Collection, a group of independently designed, high-personality boutique hotels, the university and the developers will have the flexibility to design a property that reflects the NC State spirit while leveraging the Marriott brand and reservation system.</p>
<p>The $28 million project will be privately funded and developed by NF II/CEI Raleigh, LLC, a partnership of Concord Eastridge Inc. and Noble Investment Group. NC State will lease the land to the developer, who will build, own and operate the facility.  BB&amp;T will provide the debt funding for the project.</p>
<p>NC State’s Centennial Campus is renowned globally for its mix of academics, technology, research and partnerships in an amenity-rich environment. The campus is home to the university’s Colleges of Engineering, Education, Textiles and Veterinary Medicine, many interdisciplinary centers and institutes, more than 60 corporate, government and non-profit partners and 75 NC State research and academic units – along with thousands of students, faculty and staff. A magnet middle school, residential housing, 18-hole championship golf course, restored watersheds, recreational amenities and this hotel and conference center weave the 1,334-acre campus into a true community. Go to the <a href="http://centennial.ncsu.edu/" target="_blank">Centennial Campus website</a> for more information.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">- 30 -</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/hotel-planned-for-centennial-campus/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/hotel-planned-for-centennial-campus/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Matt Shipman</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[When Faced With Some Sugars, Bacteria Can Be Picky Eaters]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/beisel-sugars-2014/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=131691</id>
		<updated>2014-07-07T18:21:32Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-08T10:15:37Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Engineering" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Research News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers from North Carolina State University and the University of Minnesota have found for the first time that genetically identical strains of bacteria can respond very differently to the presence of sugars and other organic molecules in the environment, with [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/beisel-sugars-2014/"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers from North Carolina State University and the University of Minnesota have found for the first time that genetically identical strains of bacteria can respond very differently to the presence of sugars and other organic molecules in the environment, with some individual bacteria devouring the sugars and others ignoring it.<span id="more-131691"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_131701" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Beisel-sugar-image.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-131701 " alt="Individual bacteria within a uniform population display different responses depending on the selected sugar. In this illustration, blue bacteria are consuming the sugar, whereas white bacteria are not. Image credit: Chase Beisel. Click to enlarge." src="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Beisel-sugar-image-225.jpg" width="225" height="142" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Individual bacteria within a uniform population display different responses depending on the selected sugar. In this illustration, blue bacteria are consuming the sugar, whereas white bacteria are not. Image credit: Chase Beisel. Click to enlarge.</p></div>
<p>“This highlights the complexity of bacterial behaviors and their response to environmental conditions, and how much we still need to learn,” says Dr. Chase Beisel, an assistant professor of chemical and biomolecular engineering at NC State and senior author of a paper describing the work. “This is one additional piece of the puzzle that could help us understand the behaviors of bacterial pathogens or the population dynamics of the micro-organisms that live in our guts.”</p>
<p>The researchers grew a non-pathogenic strain of <em>E. coli</em> in liquid culture, with each culture rich in a different type of sugar. Bacteria produce different protein pumps and enzymes that are dedicated to taking in and breaking down specific types of sugar, but only when the relevant sugar is present.</p>
<p>To explore how individual bacteria respond to different sugars, the research team genetically modified the bacteria to create fluorescent proteins whenever they produced the pumps or enzymes. These fluorescent proteins acted as visual cues that the researchers could use to see how individual bacteria responded to the presence of a particular sugar.</p>
<p>The researchers tested the <em>E. coli</em>’s responses to eight different sugars. For four of those sugars, all of the bacteria responded identically, increasing consumption in response to greater concentrations of sugar molecules in the culture.</p>
<p>But the bacteria responded differently to the other four molecules, exhibiting a wide range of behaviors.</p>
<p>“The behaviors were all over the place,” Beisel says.</p>
<p>“While this is the first time we’ve seen such divergent behavior from bacteria regarding sugars, it’s consistent with ‘bet-hedging’ behaviors that have been reported for bacteria in other contexts,” he adds. “Bet hedging means that at least some of the bacteria will survive when faced with new environments.”</p>
<p>The researchers also performed mathematical modeling, which found that the bacteria’s diverse behaviors could be traced to the production of pumps and enzymes in the presence of sugar.</p>
<p>One question this study raises is whether this bet-hedging behavior is exhibited by bacteria used to convert sugars into biofuels. If it is, that would mean that a percentage of the bacteria aren’t converting the sugar – which would mean the system wasn’t working at peak efficiency.</p>
<p>“But this work raises a lot of other questions as well,” Beisel says. Why does this happen in the presence of some sugars but not others? What are the circumstances in which this bet-hedging behavior actually helps the bacteria? What happens in the presence of multiple sugars? And what does this mean for bacteria in real-world conditions? For example, how would this behavior impact the introduction of probiotics – or pathogens – into the human gut?</p>
<p>“These are all questions we’d love to answer,” Beisel says.</p>
<p>The paper, “<a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/mmi.12695/abstract" target="_blank">Bacterial sugar utilization gives rise to distinct single-cell behaviors</a>,” is published online in the journal <em>Molecular Microbiology</em>. Lead author of the paper is Taliman Afroz, a Ph.D. student at NC State. The paper was co-authored by Drs. Konstantinos Biliouris and Yiannis Kaznessis of the University of Minnesota. The research was supported by the National Institutes of Health under grant GM086865; the National Science Foundation, under grants CBET-0425882 and CBET-0644792, and the National Computational Science Alliance under grant TG-MCA04N033.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">-shipman-</p>
<p><strong>Note to Editors:</strong> The study abstract follows.</p>
<p><strong>“Bacterial sugar utilization gives rise to distinct single-cell behaviors”</strong></p>
<p><em>Authors</em>: Taliman Afroz and Chase L. Beisel, North Carolina State University; Konstantinos Biliouris and Yiannis Kaznessis, University of Minnesota</p>
<p><em>Published</em>: online July 2014 in <em>Molecular Microbiology</em></p>
<p><em>DOI</em>: 10.1111/mmi.12695</p>
<p><strong>Abstract:</strong> Inducible utilization pathways reflect widespread microbial strategies to uptake and consume sugars from the environment. Despite their broad importance and extensive characterization, little is known how these pathways naturally respond to their inducing sugar in individual cells. Here, we performed single-cell analyses to probe the behavior of representative pathways in the model bacterium <em>Escherichia coli</em>. We observed diverse single-cell behaviors, including uniform responses (D-lactose, D-galactose, N-acetylglucosamine, N-acetylneuraminic acid), “all-or-none” responses (D-xylose, L-rhamnose), and complex combinations thereof (L-arabinose, D-gluconate). Mathematical modeling and probing of genetically modified pathways revealed that the simple framework underlying these pathways—inducible transport and inducible catabolism—could give rise to most of these behaviors. Sugar catabolism was also an important feature, as disruption of catabolism eliminated tunable induction as well as enhanced memory of previous conditions. For instance, disruption of catabolism in pathways that respond to endogenously synthesized sugars led to full pathway induction even in the absence of exogenous sugar. Our findings demonstrate the remarkable flexibility of this simple biological framework, with direct implications for environmental adaptation and the engineering of synthetic utilization pathways as titratable expression systems and for metabolic engineering.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/beisel-sugars-2014/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/beisel-sugars-2014/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Matt Shipman</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Science and Cookies: Researchers Tap Into Citizen Science To Shed Light on Ant Diversity]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/savage-ant-school-2014/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=131261</id>
		<updated>2014-07-07T16:52:49Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-07T12:07:01Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="College of Sciences" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Research News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Scientists from North Carolina State University and the University of Florida have combined cookies, citizen science and robust research methods to track the diversity of ant species across the United States, and are now collaborating with international partners to get [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/savage-ant-school-2014/"><![CDATA[<p>Scientists from North Carolina State University and the University of Florida have combined cookies, citizen science and robust research methods to track the diversity of ant species across the United States, and are now collaborating with international partners to get a global perspective on how ants are moving and surviving in the modern world.<span id="more-131261"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_131271" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/School-of-Ants-Ant-Photo-Lauren-Nichols.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-131271 " alt="A winter ant. Photo credit: Lauren Nichols. Click to enlarge." src="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/School-of-Ants-A.jpg" width="225" height="148" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A winter ant. Photo credit: Lauren Nichols. Click to enlarge.</p></div>
<p>“We think our School of Ants project serves as a good model for how citizen science can be used to collect more data, more quickly, from more places than a research team could do otherwise,” says Dr. Andrea Lucky, a researcher at the University of Florida who started work on the School of Ants while a postdoctoral researcher at NC State and now heads the project. Lucky is co-lead author of a paper describing the work and its early findings. “And our protocols help ensure that the data we are collecting are high quality.”</p>
<p>The School of Ants project was developed at NC State to help researchers get a handle on the diversity of ant species across the United States, with a particular focus on Chicago, Raleigh and New York City. In short, to discover which ant species are living where.</p>
<p>“But we also wanted to launch a citizen science project that both increased the public’s ecological literacy and addressed criticisms that public involvement made citizen science data unreliable,” says Dr. Amy Savage , a postdoctoral biological sciences researcher at NC State and the other co-lead author of the paper.</p>
<p>The researchers developed a simple protocol involving Pecan Sandies cookies and sealable plastic bags, detailing precisely how the public should collect and label ant samples before shipping them to NC State or UF. This process was designed to engage the public in the aspect of the research that was easiest for non-scientists to enjoy and participate in, while also limiting the chances that the public could make mistakes that would skew the findings.</p>
<div id="attachment_131291" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/School-of-Ants-Rob-Dunn-photo-Lauren-Nichols.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-131291 " alt="Rob Dunn and a young citizen scientist. Photo credit: Lauren Nichols. Click to enlarge." src="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/School-of-Ants-B.jpg" width="225" height="281" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Rob Dunn and a young citizen scientist. Photo credit: Lauren Nichols. Click to enlarge.</p></div>
<p>Once the samples arrive at NC State or UF, they are sorted, identified by a team of national experts and entered into a database. That information is then made publicly available in a user-friendly format on the project’s <a href="http://schoolofants.org/" target="_blank">schoolofants.org</a> site, allowing study participants to track the survey.</p>
<p>“This information is helping us tackle a variety of ecological and evolutionary questions, such as how ants may be evolving in urban environments, and how invasive species are spreading in the U.S.,” Savage says.</p>
<p>More than 1,000 participants, with samples from all 50 states, have taken part in the project since its 2011 launch – and there have already been some surprising findings.</p>
<p>For example, the researchers learned that a venomous invasive species, the Asian needle ant (Pachycondyla chinensis), had spread thousands of miles farther than anyone expected. Researchers knew the species had established itself in the Southeast, but study participants sent in Asian needle ant samples from as far afield as Wisconsin and Washington state.</p>
<p>To build on the School of Ants model, the researchers have launched collaborations with counterparts in <a href="http://www.schoolofants.it/" target="_blank">Italy</a> and <a href="http://schoolofants.net.au/" target="_blank">Australia</a>.</p>
<p>“We’re optimistic that this project will give us a broader view of ant diversity and how these species intersect with us, where we live and work around the world,” Lucky says.</p>
<p>The researchers are also working with teachers to incorporate the project into K-12 instruction modules that incorporate key elements of common core education standards. One early teacher collaboration has led to <a href="http://www.yourwildlife.org/2014/06/kids-do-real-science-the-ant-project/" target="_blank">a research paper co-written by 4th and 5th graders</a>.</p>
<p>“We also collaborated with a science writer to produce <a href="http://ants.yourwildlife.org/dr-eleanors-book-of-common-ants/" target="_blank">a free series of iBooks</a> featuring natural history stories about the most common ants that our citizen science partners are collecting in their backyards and sidewalks,” Savage says.</p>
<p>“One of our big goals now is to move from collecting data and finding patterns to identifying ways that we can work with the public to figure out what is driving those patterns,” says Dr. Rob Dunn, an associate professor of biological sciences at NC State and co-author of the paper.</p>
<p>The paper, “<a href="http://www.esajournals.org/doi/pdf/10.1890/ES13-00364.1" target="_blank">Ecologists, educators, and writers collaborate with the public to assess backyard diversity in The School of Ants Project</a>,” was published online July 7 in the open-access journal <em>Ecosphere</em>. Co-authors include Lauren Nichols and Leonora Shell of NC State; and Drs. Cristina Castracani, Donato Grasso and Alessandra Mori of the Università degli Studi di Parma. The research was funded National Science Foundation grant 551819-0654, with support from the Burroughs Wellcome Fund.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">-shipman-</p>
<p><strong>Note to Editors:</strong> The study abstract follows.</p>
<p><strong>“Ecologists, educators, and writers collaborate with the public to assess backyard diversity in The School of Ants Project”</strong></p>
<p><em>Authors</em>: Andrea Lucky, University of Florida and North Carolina State University; Amy M. Savage, Lauren M. Nichols, Leonora Shell, and Robert R. Dunn, North Carolina State University; Cristina Castracani, Donato A. Grasso, and Alessandra Mori, Università degli Studi di Parma</p>
<p><em>Published</em>: online July 7, 2014, <em>Ecosphere</em></p>
<p><strong>Abstract:</strong> Citizen science can generate data that would not exist otherwise while increasing public scientific literacy. However, the quality and use of citizen science data have been criticized in the recent ecological literature. We need an approach that advances eco-evolutionary understanding, achieves education goals and incorporates public participation into as many aspects of the scientific process as possible. We collaborated with public participants to make new discoveries about the distribution and ecology of ants while informing the next studies that participants and scientists might perform together. We implemented the School of Ants (SoA) program in which participants sample ants that are identified by taxonomic experts. Using a comprehensive framework that meets the needs of multiple agents, we also developed outreach materials about ant biology, collaborated with educators to incorporate SoA into classroom science, and launched an international SoA module in Italy. In the first 17 months, SoA volunteers collected ants at 500 unique sites across the USA-including all 50 states and Washington, D.C. To address concerns about the validity of citizen scientist-derived data, we conducted a ground trothing trial that confirmed that trained and untrained volunteers were equally effective at collecting ants. Data from SoA samples indicate that ant diversity varies across wide geographic scales and that there can be high levels of native ant diversity where people live. SoA volunteers collected 7 exotic and 107 native ant species. Although exotic ants were common, ants native to North America occurred in ~70% of all sites. Many of the ants common in backyards were species that tend to be very poorly studied. For example, citizen scientists documented a range extension of more than 2000 miles for the Asian Needle Ant, Pachycondyla chinensis. Using SoA data as a starting point, we collaborated with a science writer to produce a free, interactive iBook about the common ants in North America; the book included distribution maps such as that for P. chinensis informed by participant collections. Moving forward, we plan to leverage this existing framework to address more complex ecological and evolutionary questions in partnership with our public participants.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/savage-ant-school-2014/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/savage-ant-school-2014/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Tracey Peake</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[NC State Experts Can Discuss Hurricane, Disaster Issues]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/hurricane2014tip/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=131241</id>
		<updated>2014-07-03T18:34:23Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-03T18:34:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Faculty/Staff" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Tips" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[As hurricane Arthur moves up the coast this weekend, media looking for information on a variety of hurricane topics can contact the following North Carolina State University experts: Storm Surge and Flood Prediction Marine meteorologist Dr. Lian Xie can discuss [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/hurricane2014tip/"><![CDATA[<p>As hurricane Arthur moves up the coast this weekend, media looking for information on a variety of hurricane topics can contact the following North Carolina State University experts:</p>
<p><strong>Storm Surge and Flood Prediction</strong></p>
<p>Marine meteorologist Dr. Lian Xie can discuss research on hurricane formation. Specifically, Xie can talk about hurricane climatology and seasonal prediction; storm surge and coastal flooding forecasting; and ocean-hurricane interaction. He is at 919/515-1435 or <a href="mailto:lian_xie@ncsu.edu">lian_xie@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Hurricanes in North Carolina</strong></p>
<p>State Climatologist Ryan Boyles is a weather and climate specialist who can talk about hurricane history and impacts in North Carolina. He can be reached at 919/513-2816 or <a href="mailto:ryan_boyles@ncsu.edu">ryan_boyles@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Care for Pets and Animals During and After Disasters</strong></p>
<p>Dr. Kelli Ferris, assistant professor of clinical sciences, has been instrumental in saving animals during natural disasters. Dr. Ferris directs the College of Veterinary Medicine’s Community-Campus Partnership, which provides a range of veterinary services to communities across the state. Dr. Ferris is no stranger to disaster relief: Utilizing a mobile veterinary hospital, she cared for hundreds of animals in the aftermaths of Hurricane Floyd in 1999, Hurricane Katrina in 2005 and Hurricane Irene in 2011. She can be reached at 919/606-2752 or <a href="mailto:kelli_ferris@ncsu.edu">kelli_ferris@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p>Dr. Dianne Dunning is the director of NC State’s Animal Welfare, Ethics and Public Service Program. She can discuss these efforts and can talk about how to care for animals and animal survival during disasters. She can be reached at 919/513-6267 or <a href="mailto:dianne_dunning@ncsu.edu">dianne_dunning@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p>Dr. David Eggleston, director of the Center for Marine Sciences and Technology, can speak about the impact that hurricanes can have on crab and fisheries populations along the eastern seaboard. He can be reached at 919/515-7840 or 252/222-6301, or at <a href="mailto:eggleston@ncsu.edu">eggleston@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p>Dr. Barrett Slenning, College of Veterinary Medicine director of agrosecurity and biopreparedness, can speak to large-animal care, emergency needs and biosecurity issues. He can be reached at 919/513-6324 or <a href="mailto:barrett_slenning@ncsu.edu">barrett_slenning@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Water Quality</strong></p>
<p>Dr. David Eggleston, director of the Center for Marine Sciences and Technology, can discuss a hurricane’s effects on ocean salinity and dissolved oxygen levels. He can be reached at 919/515-7840 or 252/222-6301, or at <a href="mailto:eggleston@ncsu.edu">eggleston@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p><b>Food Safety</b></p>
<p>Dr. Ben Chapman, a food-safety specialist and assistant professor of family and consumer sciences, can discuss food safety issues related to post-hurricane power outages. He can be reached at 919/515-8099 or <a href="mailto:benjamin_chapman@ncsu.edu">benjamin_chapman@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Effects on Children and Parents</strong></p>
<p>Dr. Kimberly Allen, parenting and youth development specialist, can discuss the effects of disasters – like hurricanes – on children and parents, and how to help parents assist their children in preparing for and recovering from a disaster. She can be reached at 919/515-9139 or <a href="mailto:kimberly_allen@ncsu.edu">kimberly_allen@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Home Cleanup and Restoration</strong></p>
<p>Dr. Sarah Kirby can talk about a variety of topics on storm damage to homes, including cleaning and minor structural repairs. She can be reached at 919/515-9154 or <a href="mailto:sarah_kirby@ncsu.edu">sarah_kirby@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Effect on Trees and Timber Resources</strong></p>
<p>Forestry and Environmental Resources extension leader Dr. Robert Bardon can discuss the economic damage to the timber industry and how any salvage operations might be conducted.<strong> </strong>Bardon can be reached at 919/515-5575 or <a href="mailto:rebardon@ncsu.edu">rebardon@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Impact on Local Wildlife</strong></p>
<p>Dr. Chris DePerno, professor of forestry and environmental resources, is an expert in wildlife and fisheries who can discuss the hurricane’s impact on wild animals. DePerno is at 919/513-7559 or <a href="mailto:chris_deperno@ncsu.edu">chris_deperno@ncsu.edu</a>.</p>
<p><strong>On the Web</strong></p>
<p>A list of N.C. Cooperative Extension personnel with expertise in disaster-related issues can be accessed at: <a href="http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/disaster/media/experts.html" target="_blank">http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/disaster/media/experts.html</a>.</p>
<p>Information and materials on tree-related damage after natural disasters can be accessed on Extension Forestry’s website: <a href="http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/forestry/programs/disaster.php">http://www.ces.ncsu.edu/forestry/programs/disaster.php</a>.</p>
<p>A State Climate Office website with real-time access to weather information collected from hundreds of weather stations around the state and bordering regions can be accessed here: <a href="http://www.nc-climate.ncsu.edu/" target="_blank">http://www.nc-climate.ncsu.edu/</a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/hurricane2014tip/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/hurricane2014tip/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Matt Shipman</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Inspired by Nature, Researchers Create Tougher Metal Materials]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/zhu-gradient-structure-2014/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=130651</id>
		<updated>2014-07-02T13:53:41Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-02T13:53:41Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Engineering" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Research News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Drawing inspiration from the structure of bones and bamboo, researchers have found that by gradually changing the internal structure of metals they can make stronger, tougher materials that can be customized for a wide variety of applications – from body [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/zhu-gradient-structure-2014/"><![CDATA[<p>Drawing inspiration from the structure of bones and bamboo, researchers have found that by gradually changing the internal structure of metals they can make stronger, tougher materials that can be customized for a wide variety of applications – from body armor to automobile parts.<span id="more-130651"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_130661" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Yuntian-Zhu-gradient-structure-image.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-130661 " alt="This image illustrates the gradient structure concept. Click to enlarge. Image credit: Yuntian Zhu." src="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Yuntian-Zhu-gradient-structure-image-225.jpg" width="225" height="107" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">This image illustrates the gradient structure concept. Click to enlarge. Image credit: Yuntian Zhu.</p></div>
<p>“If you looked at metal under a microscope you’d see that it is composed of millions of closely-packed grains,” says Yuntian Zhu, a professor of materials science and engineering at NC State and senior author of two papers on the new work. “The size and disposition of those grains affect the metal’s physical characteristics.”</p>
<p>“Having small grains on the surface makes the metal harder, but also makes it less ductile – meaning it can’t be stretched very far without breaking,” says Xiaolei Wu, a professor of materials science at the Chinese Academy of Sciences’ Institute of Mechanics, and lead author of the two papers. “But if we gradually increase the size of the grains lower down in the material, we can make the metal more ductile. You see similar variation in the size and distribution of structures in a cross-section of bone or a bamboo stalk. In short, the gradual interface of the large and small grains makes the overall material stronger and more ductile, which is a combination of characteristics that is unattainable in conventional materials.</p>
<p>“We call this a ‘gradient structure,’ and you can use this technique to customize a metal’s characteristics,” Wu adds.</p>
<p>Wu and Zhu collaborated on research that tested the gradient structure concept in a variety of metals, including copper, iron, nickel and stainless steel. The technique improved the metal’s properties in all of them.</p>
<p>The research team also tested the new approach in interstitial free (IF) steel, which is used in some industrial applications.</p>
<p>If conventional IF steel is made strong enough to withstand 450 megapascals (MPa) of stress, it has very low ductility – the steel can only be stretched to less than 5 percent of its length without breaking. That makes it unsafe. Low ductility means a material is susceptible to catastrophic failure, such as suddenly snapping in half. Highly ductile materials can stretch, meaning they’re more likely to give people time to respond to a problem before total failure.</p>
<p>By comparison, the researchers created an IF steel with a gradient structure; it was strong enough to handle 500 MPa and ductile enough to stretch to 20 percent of its length before failing.</p>
<p>The researchers are also interested in using the gradient structure approach to make materials more resistant to corrosion, wear and fatigue.</p>
<p>“We think this is an exciting new area for materials research because it has a host of applications and it can be easily and inexpensively incorporated into industrial processes,” Wu says.</p>
<p>The work is described in two recently published papers: “<a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/21663831.2014.935821#.U7P1fvldVik" target="_blank">Synergetic Strengthening by Gradient Structure</a>,” which was published online July 2 in <em>Materials Research Letters</em>, and “<a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/early/2014/04/30/1324069111.abstract" target="_blank">Extraordinary strain hardening by gradient structure</a>,” which is published in <em>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</em>. The work was supported by the U.S. Army Research Office under grants W911NF-09-1-0427 and W911QX-08-C-0083.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">-shipman-</p>
<p><strong>Note to Editors:</strong> The study abstracts follow.</p>
<p><strong>“Synergetic Strengthening by Gradient Structure”</strong></p>
<p><em>Authors</em>: X.L. Wu, P. Jiang, L. Chen, J.F. Zhang and F.P. Yuan, Chinese Academy of Sciences; Y.T. Zhu, North Carolina State University</p>
<p><em>Published</em>: online July 2, <em>Materials Research Letters</em></p>
<p><em>DOI</em>: 10.1080/21663831.2014.935821</p>
<p><strong>Abstract:</strong> Gradient structures are characterized with a systematic change in microstructures on a macroscopic scale. Here we report that gradient structures in engineering materials such as metals produce an intrinsic synergetic strengthening, which is much higher than the sum of separate gradient layers. This is caused by macroscopic stress gradient and the bi-axial stress generated by mechanical incompatibility between different layers. This finding represents a new mechanism for strengthening that exploits the principles of both mechanics and materials science. It may provide for a new strategy for designing material structures with superior properties.</p>
<p><strong>“Extraordinary strain hardening by gradient structure”</strong></p>
<p><em>Authors</em>: X.L. Wu, P. Jiang, L. Chen and F.P. Yuan, Chinese Academy of Sciences; Y.T. Zhu, North Carolina State University</p>
<p><em>Published</em>: online May 5, <em>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences</em></p>
<p><em>DOI</em>: 10.1073/pnas.1324069111</p>
<p><strong>Abstract:</strong> Gradient structures have evolved over millions of years through natural selection and optimization in many biological systems such as bones and plant stems, where the structures gradually change from the surface to interior. The advantage of gradient structures is their maximization of physical and mechanical performance while minimizing material cost. Here we report that the gradient structure in engineering materials such as metals renders a unique extra strain hardening, which leads to high ductility. The grain size gradient under uniaxial tension induces a macroscopic strain gradient and converts the applied uniaxial stress to multi-axial stresses due to the evolution of incompatible deformation along the gradient depth. Thereby accumulation and interaction of dislocations are promoted, resulting in an extra hardening and an obvious strain hardening rate up-turn. Such extraordinary strain hardening, which is inherent to gradient structures and does not exist in homogeneous materials, provides a novel strategy to develop strong and ductile materials by architecting heterogeneous nanostructures.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/zhu-gradient-structure-2014/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/zhu-gradient-structure-2014/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Matt Shipman</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[‘Sensing Skin’ Quickly Detects Cracks, Damage in Concrete Structures]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/pour-ghaz-skin-2014/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=128281</id>
		<updated>2014-06-23T14:52:56Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-23T11:40:22Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Engineering" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Research News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers from North Carolina State University and the University of Eastern Finland have developed new “sensing skin” technology designed to serve as an early warning system for concrete structures, allowing authorities to respond quickly to damage in everything from nuclear [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/pour-ghaz-skin-2014/"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers from North Carolina State University and the University of Eastern Finland have developed new “sensing skin” technology designed to serve as an early warning system for concrete structures, allowing authorities to respond quickly to damage in everything from nuclear facilities to bridges.<span id="more-128281"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_128331" style="width: 260px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Beam-Combo-Image.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-128331 " alt="The &quot;sensing skin&quot; technology detects cracks in concrete (as in top image) and reports when and where the damage took place (as in bottom image). Click to enlarge. Image credit: Aku Seppänen." src="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Beam-Combo-Image-250.jpg" width="250" height="131" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">The &#8220;sensing skin&#8221; technology detects cracks in concrete (as in top image) and reports when and where the damage took place (as in bottom image). Click to enlarge. Image credit: Aku Seppänen.</p></div>
<p>“The sensing skin could be used for a wide range of structures, but the impetus for the work was to help ensure the integrity of critical infrastructure such as nuclear waste storage facilities,” says Dr. Mohammad Pour-Ghaz, an assistant professor of civil, construction and environmental engineering at NC State and co-author of a paper describing the work.</p>
<p>“The idea is to identify problems quickly so that they can be addressed before they become big problems and – in the case of some critical infrastructure – so that public safety measures can be implemented,” Pour-Ghaz says.</p>
<p>The skin is an electrically conductive coat of paint that can be applied to new or existing structures. The paint can incorporate any number of conductive materials, such as copper, making it relatively inexpensive.</p>
<p>Electrodes are applied around the perimeter of a structure. The sensing skin is then painted onto the structure, over the electrodes. A computer program then runs a small current between two of the electrodes at a time, cycling through a number of possible electrode combinations.</p>
<p>Every time the current runs between two electrodes, a computer monitors and records the electrical potential at all of the electrodes on the structure. This data is then used to calculate the sensing skin’s spatially distributed electrical conductivity. If the skin’s conductivity decreases, that means the structure has cracked or been otherwise damaged.</p>
<p>The researchers have developed a suite of algorithms that allow them to both register damage and to determine where the damage has taken place.</p>
<p>“Determining the location of the damage based on the measured electrode potentials is a challenging mathematical problem,” says Dr. Aku Seppänen, an Academy Research Fellow in the Department of Applied Physics at the University of Eastern Finland and co-author of the paper. “We had to develop new computational methods to more reliably determine where the damage is. Ultimately, I think our work represents an advance over previous algorithms in terms of accuracy.”</p>
<p>The researchers have demonstrated the effectiveness and accuracy of the sensing skin on a small scale, using concrete beams less than a meter wide.</p>
<p>“Our next step is to extend this to large geometries,” Pour-Ghaz says. “We want to show that this will work on real-world structures.”</p>
<p>The paper, “<a href="http://iopscience.iop.org/0964-1726/23/8/085001/article" target="_blank">Electrical impedance tomography-based sensing skin for quantitative imaging of damage in concrete</a>,” was published online June 18 in the journal <em>Smart Materials and Structures</em>. The research was supported in part by the Academy of Finland.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">-shipman-</p>
<p><strong>Note to Editors:</strong> The study abstract follows.</p>
<p><strong>“Electrical impedance tomography-based sensing skin for quantitative imaging of damage in concrete”</strong></p>
<p><em>Authors</em>: Milad Hallaji and Mohammad Pour-Ghaz, North Carolina State University; Aku Seppänen, University of Eastern Finland</p>
<p><em>Published</em>: online June 18, in <em>Smart Materials and Structures</em></p>
<p><em>DOI</em>: 10.1088/0964-1726/23/8/085001</p>
<p><strong>Abstract:</strong> In this paper, a large-area sensing skin for damage detection in concrete structures is developed. The developed sensing skin consists of a thin layer of electrically conductive copper paint that is applied to the surface of the concrete. Cracking of the concrete substrate results in the rupture of the sensing skin, decreasing the electrical conductivity of the sensing skin locally. The decrease of the conductivity is detected with Electrical Impedance Tomography (EIT) imaging. In previous works, electrically-based sensing skins have provided only qualitative information on the damage on the substrate surface. In this paper, we study whether quantitative imaging of the damage is possible. We utilize application-specific models and computational methods in the image reconstruction, including Total Variation (TV) prior model for the damage and an approximate correction of the modeling errors caused by the inhomogeneity of the painted sensing skin. The developed damage detection method is tested experimentally by applying the sensing skin to polymeric substrates and a reinforced concrete beam under four-point bending. In all test cases, the EIT-based sensing skin provides quantitative information on cracks/other damages on the substrate surface – featuring a very low conductivity in the locations of the damages, and indicating the lengths and shapes of the cracks reliably. The results strongly support the applicability of the painted EIT-based sensing skin for damage detection in reinforced concrete elements and other substrates.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/pour-ghaz-skin-2014/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/pour-ghaz-skin-2014/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mick Kulikowski</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers Develop Genetic Control Mechanism for Major Livestock Pest]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/genetic-control-sheep-blowlfy/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=127441</id>
		<updated>2014-06-19T13:35:06Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-19T13:35:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Agriculture &amp; Life Sciences" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Biotechnology" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Research News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Researchers from North Carolina State University have developed a technique to control populations of the Australian sheep blowfly – a major livestock pest in Australia and New Zealand – by making female flies dependent upon a common antibiotic to survive. [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/genetic-control-sheep-blowlfy/"><![CDATA[<p>Researchers from North Carolina State University have developed a technique to control populations of the Australian sheep blowfly – a major livestock pest in Australia and New Zealand – by making female flies dependent upon a common antibiotic to survive.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.cals.ncsu.edu/entomology/scott" target="_blank">Dr. Max Scott</a>, professor of entomology at NC State, and his research team genetically modified lines of female Australian sheep blowflies (<em>Lucilia cuprina</em>) so that they required doses of tetracycline in order to live. Female blowflies that did not receive the antibiotic died in the late larval or pupal stages, before reaching adulthood. Several genetically modified lines lacking tetracycline showed 100 percent female deaths.</p>
<p>Scott says that the gene construct responsible for lethality in antibiotic-free diets is female-specific. Interestingly and unexpectedly, the genetically modified female larvae containing the tetracycline lethality genes also took on a crimson color due to overexpression of the linked red fluorescent protein “marker gene.” This allows scientists to tell which larvae will be females and which will be males.</p>
<p>“Overexpression of the gene responsible for the reliance on tetracycline also seems to overexpress this marker gene,” Scott says.</p>
<p>Since the females will die when not provided tetracycline in their diets, the males can be separated out in the larval stage. This is essential for a “male-only” genetic control program to reduce blowfly populations, Scott says, as fertile males would pass the lethality construct on to female offspring, which would die in the absence of tetracycline. Male larval offspring, however, would still be dangerous to livestock.</p>
<p>In the <a href="http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0965174814000952" target="_blank">study</a>, the researchers showed that the tetracycline gene construct also works in <em>Drosophila</em>, the fruit fly “lab rat” of the insect world that is a distant cousin of the sheep blowfly. This holds promise that the genetic system will function in the New World and Old World screwworm, two major livestock pests that are close relatives of the sheep blowfly. Scott is working with the U.S. Department of Agriculture to make “male-only” strains of the New World screwworm (<em>Cochliomyia hominivorax</em>).</p>
<p>“The New World screwworm is a devastating pest of livestock that was eradicated from North and Central America by releasing sterilized male and female flies,” Scott says. However, a male-only strain offers several advantages, including potentially more efficient population suppression for the ongoing program. “Efficient genetic control systems have the potential to help eradicate some of the biggest problem pests across the globe,” he said.</p>
<p>The research is funded by the U.S. Department of Agriculture, National Institute of Food and Agriculture and NC State.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">- kulikowski -</p>
<p><strong>Note to editors</strong>: An abstract of the paper follows.</p>
<p><strong>“Transgenic sexing system for genetic control of the Australian sheep blow fly <em>Lucilia cuprina</em>”</strong></p>
<p><strong>Authors</strong>: Fang Li, Holly Wantuch, Rebecca Linger, Esther Belikoff and Max Scott, North Carolina State University</p>
<p><strong>Published</strong>: June 2014 online in <em>Insect Biochemistry and Molecular Biology</em></p>
<p><strong>DOI</strong>: 10.1016/j.ibmb.2014.06.001</p>
<p><strong>Abstract</strong>: The New World screwworm and the Australian sheep blow fly <em>Lucilia cuprina</em> are devastating pests of livestock. The larvae of these species feed on the tissue of the living animal and can cause death if untreated. The sterile insect technique or SIT was used to eradicate screwworm from North and Central America. This inspired efforts to develop strains containing complex chromosomal rearrangements for genetic control of <em>L. cuprina</em> in Australia. Although one field trial was promising, the approach was abandoned due to costs and difficulties in mass rearing the strain. As the efficiency of SIT can be significantly increased if only sterile males are released, we have developed transgenic strains of <em>L. cuprina</em> that carry a dominant tetracycline repressible female lethal genetic system. Lethality is due to overexpression of an auto-regulated tetracycline repressible transactivator (tTA) gene and occurs mostly at the pupal stage. Dominant female lethality was achieved by replacing the <em>Drosophila</em> hsp70 core promoter with a <em>Lucilia</em> hsp70 core promoter-5/UTR for tTA overexpression. The strains carry a dominant strongly expressed marker that will facilitate identification in the field. Interestingly, the sexes could be reliably sorted by fluorescence or color from the early first instar larval stage as females that overexpress tTA also overexpress the linked marker gene. Male-only strains of <em>L. cuprina</em> developed in this study could form the basis for a future genetic control program. Moreover, the system developed for <em>L. cuprina</em> should be readily transferrable to other major calliphorid livestock pests including the New and Old World screwworm.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/genetic-control-sheep-blowlfy/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/genetic-control-sheep-blowlfy/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Matt Shipman</name>
						<uri>http://</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Trap-Jaw Ants Spreading in Southeastern United States]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/sorger-trap-jaw-2014/" />
		<id>http://news.ncsu.edu/?p=127101</id>
		<updated>2014-06-18T10:44:38Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-18T10:44:38Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="College of Sciences" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="News Releases" /><category scheme="http://news.ncsu.edu" term="Research News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Trap-jaw ant species are active hunters with venomous stings and jaws powerful enough to fling themselves through the air. According to new research, they are also spreading into new territory in the southeastern United States. The research was done by [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/sorger-trap-jaw-2014/"><![CDATA[<p>Trap-jaw ant species are active hunters with venomous stings and jaws powerful enough to fling themselves through the air. According to new research, they are also spreading into new territory in the southeastern United States. The research was done by scientists at North Carolina State University, the Mississippi Entomological Museum, the University of California, Davis and Archbold Biological Station.<span id="more-127101"></span></p>
<div id="attachment_127111" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Magda-11.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-127111 " alt="Odontomachus relictus. Click to enlarge. Image may be used by news media. Photo credit: Magdalena Sorger." src="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Magda-1-225.jpg" width="225" height="175" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Odontomachus relictus. Click to enlarge. Image may be used by news media. Photo credit: Magdalena Sorger.</p></div>
<p>“The fact that some of these species are spreading is interesting, in part, because these giant ants have managed to expand their territory without anyone noticing,” says Magdalena Sorger, a Ph.D. candidate at NC State and co-author of a paper describing the ant species. “We know very little about these ants, including how they interact with native ant species in the areas they’re invading.”</p>
<p>The new paper offers a broad overview of trap-jaw ant species – all of which are in the genus <em>Odontomachus</em> – in the United States. The paper is designed to help scientists identify which species of trap-jaw ants they’re dealing with. While the paper draws on previously published research, it also includes new findings.</p>
<p>The paper is the first scientific article establishing the presence of the species <em>O. haematodus</em> in the United States. Native to South America, haematodus was first unofficially recorded in Alabama in 1956. But the researchers found that the species has now spread across the Gulf Coast, at least as far east as Pensacola, Florida.</p>
<p>“<em>Haemotodus</em> is particularly interesting because it is larger and more aggressive than other trap-jaw ants in the United States,” Sorger says.</p>
<p>The researchers also found that <em>O. ruginodis</em> has been expanding its territory.</p>
<p>As recently as a few years ago, <em>ruginodis</em> was thought to be confined to the Orlando region, and points south. “I found <em>ruginodis</em> in landscaped areas near buildings – outside a mall, outside my hotel – usually in the mulch underneath hedges,” Sorger says. But now Sorger has confirmed a record of <em>ruginodis</em> more than a hundred miles north of Orlando, in Gainesville. “The species could have traveled even farther than Gainesville, but no one has looked for it.”</p>
<div id="attachment_127121" style="width: 235px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Magda-2.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-127121 " alt="Odontomachus relictus. Click to enlarge. Image may be used by news media. Photo credit: Magdalena Sorger." src="http://v3prod.news.ncsu.edu/wp/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Magda-2-225.jpg" width="225" height="112" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Odontomachus relictus. Click to enlarge. Image may be used by news media. Photo credit: Magdalena Sorger.</p></div>
<p>But not all of the trap-jaw species are on the move. Sorger also studies <em>O. relictus</em>, a species that is found only in endangered scrub habitat on central Florida’s ancient sand ridges.</p>
<p>Sorger found that <em>relictus</em> ants on separate ridges displayed different behaviors and had distinct genetic profiles – indicating that they may have evolved into separate species.</p>
<p>“If these two <em>O. relictus</em> populations are, in fact, distinct species, it would make them the rarest ants in North America,” Sorger says. “I’m hoping to resolve this question soon, via more genetic analyses.”</p>
<p>The paper, “<a href="http://biotaxa.org/Zootaxa/article/view/zootaxa.3802.4.7" target="_blank">A review of the Nearctic <em>Odontomachus</em> (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Ponerinae) with a treatment of the males</a>,” was published online May 28 in <em>Zootaxa</em>. Lead author of the paper is Joe MacGown of the Mississippi Entomological Museum. Co-authors include Brendon Boudinot of UC Davis and Mark Deyrup of Archbold Biological Station. The research was supported, in part, by the U.S. Department of Agriculture under project MIS-012040.</p>
<p style="text-align: center;">-shipman-</p>
<p><strong>Note to Editors:</strong> The study abstract follows.</p>
<p><strong>“A review of the Nearctic <em>Odontomachus</em> (Hymenoptera: Formicidae: Ponerinae) with a treatment of the males”</strong></p>
<p><em>Authors</em>: Joe A. MacGown, Mississippi Entomological Museum; Brendon Boudinot, University of California, Davis; Mark Deyrup, Archbold Biological Station; D. Magdalena Sorger, North Carolina State University</p>
<p><em>Published</em>: May 28, 2014, <em>Zootaxa</em></p>
<p><em>DOI</em>: http://dx.doi.org/10.11646/zootaxa.3802.4.7</p>
<p><strong>Abstract:</strong> The ant genus <em>Odontomachus</em> Latreille in the United States is reviewed. Six species are treated: <em>O. brunneus</em> (Patton), <em>O. clarus</em> Roger, <em>O. desertorum</em> Wheeler stat. nov., <em>O. relictus</em> Deyrup and Cover, <em>O. ruginodis</em> M.R. Smith, and <em>O. haematodus</em> (Linnaeus), a new record for North America. The spread of <em>O. haematodus</em> is documented, and its identity is clarified. The genus is diagnosed for species in the Nearctic region for all castes, and worker- and male-based keys are presented. The workers and males of all six species are described and figured, including the first male descriptions for <em>O. haematodus</em> and <em>O. desertorum</em>. This represents the first study of species-level variation in <em>Odontomachus</em> male genitalia, and one of the first of such studies of the Ponerinae for any biogeographic region. A discussion of the utility of the male sex for <em>Odontomachus</em> taxonomy is provided.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/sorger-trap-jaw-2014/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news.ncsu.edu/releases/sorger-trap-jaw-2014/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

 Served from: news.ncsu.edu @ 2014-07-21 13:56:50 by W3 Total Cache -->