<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">WCU News</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-21T15:21:41Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" />
	<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.9.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Dance program director wins national teaching award]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/dance-program-director-wins-national-teaching-award/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27065</id>
		<updated>2014-07-21T13:41:30Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-18T20:11:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Faculty and Staff Awards and Accolades" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Fine &amp; Performing Arts" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Stage &amp; Screen" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Karyn Tomczak, director of the WCU dance program, will receive the 2014 Dance Teacher Award for Higher Education at the Dance Teacher Summit to be held in New York City in August.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/dance-program-director-wins-national-teaching-award/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WCU_Karyn-Tomczak.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-27067" src="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WCU_Karyn-Tomczak.jpg" alt="WCU_Karyn Tomczak" width="375" height="266" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/FPA/schools-departments-and-centers/stagescreen/stage-screen-faculty/karyn-tomczak.asp"><strong>Karyn Tomczak</strong></a>, director of the Western Carolina University dance program, will receive the 2014 Dance Teacher Award for Higher Education at the Dance Teacher Summit to be held in New York City in August.</p>
<p>Dance Teacher magazine published<a href="http://www.dance-teacher.com/2014/07/the-2014-dance-teacher-awards/" target="_blank"><strong> a feature in July about Tomczak and three other award winners</strong></a> recognized for offering students top-notch training, real-world performing experiences, financial support and an emphasis on academic success.</p>
<p>Tomczak began teaching dance at age 14, when she ran her own dance studio, and taught at three others in the Buffalo, New York, area.</p>
<p>After college, she gained experience working as a professional dancer for more than 15 years. She not only was a Rockette but also performed in the United States and abroad in shows such as “42nd Street,” “Sophisticated Ladies,” “Will Rogers Follies” and “Funny Girl.”</p>
<p>“My performing experience enhanced the teaching package I am now able to offer students,” said Tomczak, who joined the WCU faculty in 2009. “I loved performing and miss it sometimes, but when I see my students on stage, I feel like part of me is still performing.”</p>
<p>Tomczak teaches a full course load in addition to choreographing a range of shows at WCU. For the past two years, she has secured grants and raised money through teaching master classes to take dance students during spring break to New York City. There, they took dance classes, toured theaters, attended shows and performed in The Ziegfield Society’s shows saluting the history of the Rockettes. As part of the experience, Tomczak also arranged for musical theatre students to be able to perform before agents and in a cabaret.</p>
<p>Tomczak said working as a dance teacher sometimes requires long hours but the work is tremendously fulfilling.</p>
<p>“I learn new things about dance every day from my students and through ongoing professional development about my craft,” said Tomczak. “I get to do what I love to do, make a living doing it and share it with my students, all of which makes teaching dance the best job in the world.”</p>
<p>For more information, visit <a href="http://dance.wcu.edu"><strong>dance.wcu.edu</strong></a> online or contact Tomczak at 828-227-3672 or <strong><a href="mailto:ktomczak@wcu.edu">ktomczak@wcu.edu</a></strong>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/dance-program-director-wins-national-teaching-award/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/dance-program-director-wins-national-teaching-award/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Unawarewulves to perform Tuesday]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/unawarewulves-to-perform-july-22/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27052</id>
		<updated>2014-07-21T12:56:11Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-17T15:23:21Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Events" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="HomepageTwo" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[WCU's annual Summer Concert Series will conclude with a free show at 7 p.m. in the Central Plaza featuring the Franklin-based sextet offering a blend of several genres of music.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/unawarewulves-to-perform-july-22/"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_27053" style="width: 385px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Unawarewulves_375.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-27053" src="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Unawarewulves_375.jpg" alt="Unawarewulves" width="375" height="248" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Unawarewulves</p></div>
<p>Western Carolina University’s annual Summer Concert Series will conclude Tuesday, July 22, with a free show featuring Unawarewulves in the Central Plaza on campus at 7 p.m.</p>
<p>The Franklin-based sextet offers a blend of rockabilly, dance, jazz, funk and pop music.</p>
<p>For more information, contact Michael J. Corelli, an associate director at A.K. Hinds University Center, at <a href="mailto:corelli@wcu.edu">corelli@wcu.edu</a> or 828-227-3618.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/unawarewulves-to-perform-july-22/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/unawarewulves-to-perform-july-22/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Budding Broadway stars to perform Sunday]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/budding-broadway-stars-to-strut-their-stuff-in-sunday-performance/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27047</id>
		<updated>2014-07-21T12:44:29Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-16T18:46:30Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Events" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Fine &amp; Performing Arts" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A troupe of budding Broadway stars from around the world will hit the stage at WCU this weekend to cap the 2014 Triple Arts intensive musical theatre summer camp.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/budding-broadway-stars-to-strut-their-stuff-in-sunday-performance/"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_27057" style="width: 385px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WCU_Triple-Arts_375.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-27057" src="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WCU_Triple-Arts_375.jpg" alt="Participants in the WCU Triple Arts intensive musical theatre summer camp rehearse for a show on Sunday, July 20." width="375" height="238" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Participants in the WCU Triple Arts intensive musical theatre summer camp rehearse for a show on Sunday, July 20.</p></div>
<p>A troupe of budding Broadway stars from around the world will hit the stage at Western Carolina University’s John W. Bardo Fine and Performing Arts Center this weekend to cap the 2014 Triple Arts intensive musical theatre summer camp.</p>
<p>The students, ranging in age from 15 to 22 and hailing from as far away as Switzerland, will give a free performance at 3 p.m. Sunday, July 20. The performance will consist of a selection of songs and scenes from Broadway shows.</p>
<p>Broadway veterans <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/FPA/schools-departments-and-centers/stagescreen/stage-screen-faculty/terrence-mann.asp"><strong>Terrence Mann</strong></a> and Charlotte d’Amboise have been guiding participants through a two-week workshop in which skills in auditioning, dancing, singing and scene interpretation are developed and honed.</p>
<p>A staff of expert choreographers, vocal teachers and directors – several with extensive Broadway backgrounds – are assisting in the program.</p>
<p>“The goal is to let these young people feel what it is like to work as a professional while they are still in school, and to experience what it takes to compete with the best musical performers on the Broadway stage today,” said Mann, the Phillips Distinguished Professor of Musical Theatre at WCU.</p>
<p>The Triple Arts summer camp is sponsored by <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/FPA/schools-departments-and-centers/stagescreen/stage-screen-academic-programs/musthea/index.asp"><strong>WCU’s Musical Theatre Program</strong></a> and the <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/edoutreach/"><strong>Division of Educational Outreach</strong></a>.</p>
<p>For more information, visit <a href="http://triplearts.wcu.edu"><strong>triplearts.wcu.edu</strong></a> or call 828-227-7397.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/budding-broadway-stars-to-strut-their-stuff-in-sunday-performance/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/budding-broadway-stars-to-strut-their-stuff-in-sunday-performance/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Students produce campus walking trail brochure]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/students-produce-walking-trail-brochure/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27034</id>
		<updated>2014-07-21T12:48:03Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-15T14:34:09Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="HomepageLinks" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="125th Anniversary" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Students in Jessie Swigger’s “Introduction to Public History” class produced a historic walking trail and map of Western Carolina University points of interest as part of the university’s 125th anniversary celebration.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/students-produce-walking-trail-brochure/"><![CDATA[<p>Students in Jessie Swigger’s “Introduction to Public History” class produced <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/celebrate125/images/pdfs/HistoricWalkingTour_map.pdf"><strong>a historic walking trail and map</strong></a> of Western Carolina University points of interest as part of the university’s 125th anniversary celebration.</p>
<p>“The class started the project by taking a tour of campus with George Frizzell from <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/hunter-library/collections/special-collections/index.asp"><strong>Special Collections</strong></a>,” said Swigger, assistant professor in the <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/cas/casdepts/history/index.asp"><strong>Department of History</strong></a> at WCU. “As a class, we selected what we thought were the most important historic sites on campus,” she said.</p>
<p>The landmarks on the trail are:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Highway 106 </strong>– The first paved road in Cullowhee allowed students, faculty and staff to travel to and from campus more easily than the old dirt roads allowed.</li>
<li><strong>Mount Zion AME Zion Church</strong> – A Methodist church established by 11 former slaves was built on the hill where Robertson Hall now stands.</li>
<li><strong>Moore Building</strong> – The oldest building still standing on campus, Moore served as a dining hall, an academic building and a home to the health sciences programs.</li>
<li><strong>Madison Memorial</strong> – The memorial, located on the site of the original Cullowhee Academy, honors WCU’s founder, Robert Lee Madison.</li>
<li><strong>Memorial Stadium</strong> – Situated where Hunter Library and the Natural Sciences Building now stand, the football stadium was built to honor students, faculty and staff who served in the U.S. military during World War II.</li>
<li><strong>Breese Gymnasium </strong>– The building, funded by New Deal emergency relief projects, included a basketball arena and an indoor swimming pool and served as a nuclear fallout shelter. Today, Breese is home to the physical education and dance programs.</li>
<li><strong>McKee Building </strong>– Once home to a training school for teachers, the building now houses several programs in the College of Arts and Sciences.</li>
<li><strong>Cherokee Mound </strong>– The mound, which was located where the Killian Building now stands, was central to the Cherokee village in Cullowhee until the mid-17th century.</li>
<li><strong>Haywood Field </strong>– WCU’s original baseball diamond, the field was located where A.K. Hinds University Center and the Coulter Building now stand.</li>
<li><strong>A.K. Hinds University Center</strong> – Built in 1968, the UC created a new social center for campus, providing places to congregate, multipurpose rooms for university events, mail services and dining services.</li>
<li><strong>Alumni Tower </strong>– At 66 feet tall, the tower is a gathering place for students in the Central Plaza and a symbol of the role that alumni play in shaping WCU.</li>
<li><strong>The Catafount</strong> – In 2011, the fountain became an epicenter for social activities such as Valley Ballyhoo, Greek life ceremonies, concerts and impromptu gatherings.</li>
<li><strong>Reid Gymnasium</strong> – WCU’s original spot for collegiate basketball, the gym witnessed many historical events, including the NCAA’s first three-point shot.</li>
<li><strong>E.J. Whitmire Stadium – </strong>The stadium became the new home for Catamount football in 1973.</li>
<li><strong>Ramsey Regional Activity Center –</strong> Built in 1986, the Ramsey Center became the primary venue for Catamount basketball and volleyball, graduation ceremonies and concerts.</li>
<li><strong>Childress Field at Hennon Stadium </strong>– Catamount baseball moved to the stadium at the south end of campus in 1978.</li>
<li><strong>Catamount Statue</strong> – Built in 2000, the bronze statue of WCU’s mascot stands at the university’s entrance and was a gift from Charlotte businessman Irwin Belk.</li>
<li><strong>Highway 107 </strong>– The highway serves as campus’ main entrance, and it represents WCU’s continually expanding student and faculty population.</li>
</ul>
<p>Students who worked on the project will give tours of the walking trail at the Big Birthday Bash, an event celebrating 125 years of history at WCU. The event will be held on Tuesday, Aug. 26, on the A.K. Hinds University Center lawn and adjoining Central Plaza from 4 to 7 p.m.</p>
<p>For more information, visit <strong><a href="http://www.wcu.edu/celebrate125/history.html">www.wcu.edu/celebrate125/history.html</a></strong>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/students-produce-walking-trail-brochure/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/students-produce-walking-trail-brochure/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[WCU Bass Cats qualify for nationals]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-bass-cats-qualify-for-bassmaster-college-nationals-at-lake-chatuge/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27030</id>
		<updated>2014-07-16T13:02:10Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-15T14:28:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Students representing WCU's bass fishing club team recently placed third at the Bassmaster College Eastern Regional tournament to advance to a national competition later this summer.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-bass-cats-qualify-for-bassmaster-college-nationals-at-lake-chatuge/"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_27031" style="width: 385px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WCU_Bass-Fishing2_375.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-27031" src="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WCU_Bass-Fishing2_375.jpg" alt="From left, Austin Neary and Zachary Hicks of the Western Carolina University bass fishing club team get in some practice casts at Lake Chatuge in advance of a national competition to be held there later this summer. (Photo by Mark Haskett)" width="375" height="245" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">From left, Austin Neary and Zachary Hicks of the Western Carolina University bass fishing club team get in some practice casts at Lake Chatuge in advance of a national competition to be held there later this summer. (Photo by Mark Haskett)</p></div>
<p>Students representing Western Carolina University’s bass fishing club team recently placed third at the Bassmaster College Eastern Regional tournament to advance to a national competition later this summer.</p>
<p>Bass Cats, a team from WCU that includes male students, traveled to Dayton, Tennessee, to compete in the June 12-13 regional tournament. The team went up against 55 other collegiate fishing teams from the eastern region of the country. Placing third in the tournament, Bass Cats qualified for the Bassmaster College Nationals on Lake Chatuge, which is to be held July 31 through Aug. 2. Team members Austin Neary and Zachary Hicks, who currently are ranked 14th in the country as a fishing team, will compete against the best two-person fishing teams from across the U.S.</p>
<p>“We set goals that may seem farfetched for a first-year program, but we know we can do it with the right attitude,” said Neary, the club’s president. “Fishing is all about being positive and having confidence. We have had a string of great finishes this year, and the tournament can’t get here soon enough,” said Neary, who currently is ranked among the top 35 collegiate anglers in the country.</p>
<p>The WCU fishing team, founded in the spring of 2013, competes in a variety of fishing series and trails, including the Forrest L. Wood Southeastern College Series. Team members, in addition to Neary and Hicks, are WCU students Ethan Pace, Chandler Todd, Brad Hart and Daniel Ratliff.</p>
<p>For more information about the Bass Cats, contact Neary at <a href="mailto:amneary1@catamount.wcu.edu">amneary1@catamount.wcu.edu</a> or visit the team’s website at <a href="http://wcubasscats.wcubasscats.com"><strong>wcubasscats.wcubasscats.com</strong></a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-bass-cats-qualify-for-bassmaster-college-nationals-at-lake-chatuge/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-bass-cats-qualify-for-bassmaster-college-nationals-at-lake-chatuge/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Instructor honored for swiftwater rescue initiative]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-instructor-honored-internationally-for-swiftwater-rescue-training-initiative/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27023</id>
		<updated>2014-07-21T12:47:07Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-14T13:39:21Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="HomepageLinks" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Education" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Faculty and Staff Awards and Accolades" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sam Fowlkes, who teaches paddlesports and rescue at WCU, accepted an award considered among the most prestigious in the field of technical swiftwater rescue for an American Canoe Association conference he helped coordinate.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-instructor-honored-internationally-for-swiftwater-rescue-training-initiative/"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_27024" style="width: 385px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WhitwaterSam_375.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-27024" src="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WhitwaterSam_375.jpg" alt="Sam Fowlkes" width="375" height="281" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sam Fowlkes</p></div>
<p>Sam Fowlkes, who teaches paddlesports and rescue at Western Carolina University, recently accepted an award considered among the most prestigious in the field of technical swiftwater rescue for an American Canoe Association conference he helped coordinate.</p>
<p>Fowlkes, chair of the ACA’s safety and rescue committee, co-chaired the association’s landmark 2013 Swiftwater Rescue Conference, which was held in October in Western North Carolina. The event featured seminars from the leading water rescue educators in the nation, including people who developed techniques and wrote the first instructional materials in the field. Participants included more than 100 recreational paddlers, certified paddlesport instructors and emergency responders from 22 states and three foreign countries.</p>
<div id="attachment_27025" style="width: 285px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Sam-Fowlkes-Jim-Coffey_Webnews.jpg"><img class="wp-image-27025" src="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Sam-Fowlkes-Jim-Coffey_Webnews.jpg" alt="From left, Jim Coffey presents a Higgins and Langley award to Sam Fowlkes, an adjunct parks and recreation management instructor at WCU and chair of the American Canoe Association's safety and rescue committee. (Photo by and courtesy Ryan Maxwell)" width="275" height="227" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">From left, Jim Coffey presents a Higgins and Langley award to Sam Fowlkes, an adjunct parks and recreation management instructor at WCU and chair of the American Canoe Association&#8217;s safety and rescue committee. (Photo by and courtesy Ryan Maxwell)</p></div>
<p>The Higgins and Langley Memorial and Education Fund, which is the water rescue division of the National Association of Search and Rescue, bestowed one of the international Higgins and Langley Awards for special commendation to ACA for the initiative in June. In accepting the award at an event held in Woodcliff Lake, New Jersey, Fowlkes said ACA has been promoting safety in paddlesports since 1880 and was one of the pioneering forces in the field.</p>
<p>Fowlkes has served as an adjunct <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/CEAP/ceap-depts/humanserv/prm/"><strong>parks and recreation management</strong></a> instructor at WCU for 16 years.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-instructor-honored-internationally-for-swiftwater-rescue-training-initiative/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-instructor-honored-internationally-for-swiftwater-rescue-training-initiative/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Business faculty member honored at international symposium]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/paper-co-authored-by-faculty-member-wins-award-at-international-symposium/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27001</id>
		<updated>2014-07-17T14:58:47Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-11T19:21:12Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Business" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Faculty and Staff Awards and Accolades" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[A paper co-authored by Jon Marvel, associate professor of management, and presented at the 2014 International Supply Chain Symposium held in Edmonton, Alberta, in June received the symposium’s Best Paper Award. ]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/paper-co-authored-by-faculty-member-wins-award-at-international-symposium/"><![CDATA[<p>A paper co-authored by <strong><a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/COB/college-of-business-departments/gms/mgmt-faculty-and-staff/jon-marvel.asp">Jon Marvel</a></strong>, associate professor of management, and presented at the 2014 International Supply Chain Symposium held in Edmonton, Alberta, in June received the symposium’s <strong><a href="http://www.scmanational.ca/en/events/international-symposium-on-scm/2014-symposium/winning-papers">Best Paper Award.</a></strong> The paper was titled “<strong><a href="http://www.scmanational.ca/images/stories/events_pdf/2014Symposium/J26-Lean-Green-or-Resilient-An-Explorative-Study-of-Manufacturing-Firms.pdf">Lean, Green, or Resilient? An Explorative Study of Manufacturing Firms</a></strong>.”<span id="more-29130"></span></p>
<p>Supply chains adopt a variety of strategies to respond to market changes and increased environmental turbulence. The research team investigated how the level of integration of the strategies typically adopted by manufacturing companies to improve competitiveness impacts the performance of the firms.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/paper-co-authored-by-faculty-member-wins-award-at-international-symposium/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/paper-co-authored-by-faculty-member-wins-award-at-international-symposium/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[WCU Best of Controlled Chaos Film Festival to be held Aug. 17 in Cashiers]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-best-of-controlled-chaos-film-festival-to-be-held-aug-17-in-cashiers/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27015</id>
		<updated>2014-07-11T19:08:58Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-11T19:04:26Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Events" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Fine &amp; Performing Arts" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Some of the most riveting and moving student-created films from Western Carolina University’s annual Controlled Chaos Film Festivals will be shared at the inaugural Best of Controlled Chaos Film Festival in Cashiers on Sunday, Aug. 17.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-best-of-controlled-chaos-film-festival-to-be-held-aug-17-in-cashiers/"><![CDATA[<p>Some of the most riveting and moving student-created films from Western Carolina University’s annual Controlled Chaos Film Festivals will be shared at the inaugural Best of Controlled Chaos Film Festival in Cashiers on Sunday, Aug. 17.</p>
<div id="attachment_27016" style="width: 285px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Radical-Notion3.jpg"><img class="wp-image-27016" src="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Radical-Notion3.jpg" alt="As students in Western Carolina University’s Film and Television Production Program, Grant Gilliard and Samantha Hunt worked with classmates on “The Radical Notion of Gene Mutation,” which was screened at the 2014 Controlled Chaos Film Festival. A Best of the Controlled Chaos Film Festival event will be held at The Country Club of Sapphire Valley on Sunday, Aug. 17." width="275" height="359" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">As students in Western Carolina University’s Film and Television Production Program, Grant Gilliard and Samantha Hunt worked with classmates on “The Radical Notion of Gene Mutation,” which was screened at the 2014 Controlled Chaos Film Festival. A Best of the Controlled Chaos Film Festival event will be held at The Country Club of Sapphire Valley on Sunday, Aug. 17.</p></div>
<p>The event will be held at The Country Club of Sapphire Valley and will open with a reception at 6 p.m., followed by the screening of an hour-and-a-half of the most entertaining student films from the past five years. The line-up will include two longer senior project films and shorter films ranging from 15 seconds to four minutes.</p>
<p>In addition, attendees will have the chance to bid on the opportunity to have students and faculty in <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/FPA/schools-departments-and-centers/stagescreen/stage-screen-academic-programs/ftp/http://"><strong>WCU’s Film and Television Production Program</strong></a> create a short custom-made film, either a promotional short film or family documentary.</p>
<p>Adair Simon, event co-chair and an award-winning producer from Cashiers with more than 35 years of industry experience, has attended WCU’s Controlled Chaos Film Festival and said she looks forward to sharing the work of WCU student filmmakers with a broader audience.</p>
<p>“The quality, the variety and visual excitement of the films in the festival impressed me, and I encourage everyone who has not had the opportunity to attend before to join us for what promises to be an entertaining – and perhaps inspiring – evening,” said Simon, CEO of Video Progressions. “We are fortunate to have such a high-quality film school in Western North Carolina that is not only providing a top-notch education to students, but also helping capture the stories, the beauty and the imagination of our mountains.”</p>
<p>Simon and Susan Belcher, wife of WCU Chancellor David O. Belcher, are members of the <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/friendsofthearts/index.asp"><strong>WCU Friends of the Arts</strong> </a>Advancement Council. Both stepped forward to co-chair the festival after Marcia Shawler inquired about the possibility of sharing student films with the Cashiers community. Shawler, president of Mountain Youth Charities in Cashiers, was involved with a fundraiser last summer for which a WCU team from the Film and Television Production Program created a 4-minute, documentary-style film centered on the organization and needs of at-risk youth.</p>
<p>“Each time I viewed the video, I kept thinking about what an excellent group effort this project was,” said Shawler, honorary chair for the Best of the Controlled Chaos Film Festival event.</p>
<p>WCU established the Film and TV Production Program in 2006 and launched the festival in 2009 as a way to celebrate student work throughout the year. The event was named “controlled chaos” – the phrase Jack Sholder, director of the program, uses to describe the process of filmmaking.</p>
<p>An award-winning Hollywood director and screenwriter at the helm since the inception of the WCU program, Sholder served as an editor on the documentary “King: From Montgomery to Memphis,” which was nominated for an Academy Award; won an Emmy for his editing work on “3-2-1- Contact,” and directed such blockbusters as “Nightmare on Elm Street II” and “The Hidden.”</p>
<p>Other faculty who work with students in the program include Arledge Armenaki, a cinematographer with more than 30 feature film and documentary credits including “South of Hell,” “Club Fed,” “Howling V,” “Dennis the Menace,” “Focus on Africa” and “Wesley”; screenwriter and producer Terry Curtis Fox, whose credits include “Hill Street Blues,” “JAG,” “The Hunger” and “Stargate SG-1”; and Brenda Lilly, who worked as a writer on series including “Big,” “Shades of L.A.,” “Parker Lewis Can’t Lose,” “L.A. Law,” “Christy,” “Walker: Texas Ranger,” “Xena: Warrior Princess,” “Bobby’s World,” “Second Noah,” “Fame L.A.,” “Honey I Shrunk the Kids” and “State of Grace.”</p>
<p>Almost 90 percent of the program’s graduates go on to work in the industry, and the films they create as students win awards. Most recently, “Jerry,” a senior project film from the 2012-13 academic year, was honored with the jury award for the best student film at the 2013 Asheville Cinema Festival.</p>
<p>“When you see our students’ films in relation to other work, the technical skills are at least as high if not higher than other films but where they really shine is with the storytelling skills,” said Sholder. “Their films are really well done, entertaining and thought-provoking. When people come to our festival for the first time, they say, ‘Wow, I can’t believe how good these films are.’”</p>
<p>Belcher said the creativity and energy of the students and quality of their work brings her back to the festival year after year. She enjoys everything from the 15-second short films that center on topics such as lost keys to documentaries on subjects ranging from a Vietnam War memorial to a local weaver who raises animals, shears them and prepares her own wool. She said the longer senior-project films are unforgettable and diverse, including “Strigoii,” a horror movie about a town terrorized nightly by a mysterious creature; “Black, White and Blue,” a film about a girl overcoming depression that incorporated underwater sequences; and “Jerry,” an off-kilter black comedy about a homeless man who comes back to haunt the local politician who ran him over.</p>
<p>“I have watched these films many times for my own enjoyment,” she said. “What impresses me about the program and the festival are that the films are written, produced, directed, edited and performed all by students. That, to me, is the most impressive part, and that’s what makes it so exciting. You see the progress and the promise inside what these students are doing.”</p>
<p>Students in WCU’s School of Stage and Screen write, direct, perform, film, edit and produce the films and incorporate musical compositions created by students in the Commercial and Electronic Music Program and title sequences developed in the School of Art and Design.</p>
<p>Meg White, director of development at WCU, said the festival will demonstrate the quality instruction that students are receiving from WCU faculty who are trained professionals from the film industry.</p>
<p>“It’s been my experience that when any audience has the opportunity to see WCU students in action, they are entertained and impressed,” said White.</p>
<p>Belcher said the response so far to hosting the Best of the Controlled Chaos Film Festival in Cashiers has been overwhelming.</p>
<p>“Every person we have asked to be involved has said ‘yes,’ immediately,” said Belcher.</p>
<p>More than two dozen people, many of whom are Cashiers and Highlands residents, have volunteered time to assist on the events’ committees. In addition to Belcher, Shawler, Sholder, Simon and White, assisting with the event are Ann McKee Austin, Grace Battle, Bob Bryan, Sandra Davis, Andrew Dyson, Stephanie Edwards, Steve Johanessen, Pat Kaemmerling, Kathy Kaye, Kay Keller, Mary Adair Leslie, Penny Pollock Mawyer, Anne McKee, Ginger Mead, Cindy Moore, Jack Morse, Brien Peterkin, Chuck Self, Marilyn Staats, Irv Welling, Meg White and Wes Wofford.</p>
<p>Tickets to the Best of the Controlled Chaos Film Festival are $75. The money raised will be used to assist students with making senior project films, which typically cost upward of $5,000 to create, and acquire much needed equipment for the program.</p>
<p>For more information, contact the<a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/FPA/"><strong> WCU College of Fine and Performing Arts</strong></a> at 828-227-7028.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-best-of-controlled-chaos-film-festival-to-be-held-aug-17-in-cashiers/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-best-of-controlled-chaos-film-festival-to-be-held-aug-17-in-cashiers/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[WCU ASP Day of Service set for July 19 at Sylva&#8217;s Bridge Park]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-asp-day-of-service-set-for-july-19-at-sylvas-bridge-park/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27013</id>
		<updated>2014-07-21T12:47:20Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-11T18:58:08Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Students in WCU's Academic Success Program are collaborating with the town of Sylva, Wal-Mart of Sylva, Lowe’s of Sylva, Sylva Rotary Club and several area businesses and nonprofit agencies to host the fourth annual Day of Service on Saturday July 19, at Bridge Park.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-asp-day-of-service-set-for-july-19-at-sylvas-bridge-park/"><![CDATA[<p>Students in Western Carolina University’s <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/about-wcu/leadership/office-of-the-provost/ugstudies/academic-success-program/index.asp"><strong>Academic Success Program</strong></a> are collaborating with the town of Sylva, Wal-Mart of Sylva, Lowe’s of Sylva, Sylva Rotary Club and several area businesses and nonprofit agencies to host the fourth annual Day of Service on Saturday July 19, at Bridge Park.</p>
<p>The festival in the park will include games, food and music from 9 a.m. until 1 p.m. Lowe’s will sponsor a booth where children can make a creation of their own. Local nonprofits and local emergency agencies, including Sparky the Dog, will be at the festival to provide information about their services. Proceeds from this event directly benefit Jackson Neighbors in Need, Communities in Schools of the Great Smoky Mountains and The Community Table.</p>
<p>Throughout the day, ASP students will be volunteering in a variety of service projects throughout Jackson County. The service project sites include Catman2, Cullowhee Community Garden, Habitat Thrift Store, Library Thrift Store, Pathways Thrift Store, Sylva Rotary traffic islands, Teen Challenge Thrift Store, Watershed Association of the Tuckasegee River creek cleanup, and roadside cleanup along N.C. Highway 107.</p>
<p>Donations, volunteers and support from local businesses have helped to make this event possible, said Janina DeHart, WCU assistant director of academic transition and success. Wal-Mart of Sylva is providing food, and Soul Infusion Tea House and Bistro is providing the entertainment.</p>
<p>Other local sponsors – including Perk and Pastry, City Lights Café, The River Jordan Christian Store, In Your Ear Music Emporium, Mad Batter Food &amp; Film, Lulu’s On Main, Heinzelmachenn Brewery, Survival Pride Clothing, Jack The Dipper, Friends of the Jackson County Public Library and Catamount Athletics – also are making contributions to the Day of Service. Those businesses and organizations are providing prizes for a raffle sponsored by the town of Sylva, hosting donation jars and making monetary contributions to local nonprofits.</p>
<p>A new component to the ASP Day of Service this year is Desserts Downtown, to be held Friday, July 18, in conjunction with Concerts on the Creek. The purchase of a $5 ticket will allow the bearer to get three sample desserts from any of the participating restaurants between 6:30 and 9:30 p.m. Tickets for Desserts Downtown can be purchased through Lori Overstreet in the <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/about-wcu/leadership/office-of-the-provost/ugstudies/first-year-experience/index.asp"><strong>Office of First Year Experience</strong></a> at Western Carolina University, Soul Infusion, or any of the participating restaurants – Lulu’s on Main, City Lights Cafe, Mad Batter Food and Film, and Perk and Pastry.</p>
<p>For more information about ASP Day of Service or Desserts Downtown, contact Lori Overstreet by email at <a href="mailto:looverstreet1@catamount.wcu.edu"><strong>looverstreet1@catamount.wcu.edu</strong></a> or by phone at 828-227-3017.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-asp-day-of-service-set-for-july-19-at-sylvas-bridge-park/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-asp-day-of-service-set-for-july-19-at-sylvas-bridge-park/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>killian</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[WCU hosts natural products seminar to launch new chemistry degree concentration]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-hosts-natural-products-seminar-to-launch-new-chemistry-degree-concentration/" />
		<id>http://news-prod.wcu.edu/?p=27009</id>
		<updated>2014-07-11T18:54:47Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-11T18:54:47Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="News" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Arts &amp; Sciences" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Chemistry &amp; Physics" /><category scheme="http://news-prod.wcu.edu" term="Graduate" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[WCU recently hosted a half-day event focusing on the emerging natural products industry of the Western North Carolina region. The event also served as an official launch for WCU’s newest graduate program, which leads to a master’s degree in chemistry with a professional science concentration in natural products.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-hosts-natural-products-seminar-to-launch-new-chemistry-degree-concentration/"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_27010" style="width: 385px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WCU_Natural-Products_375.jpg"><img class="size-full wp-image-27010" src="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WCU_Natural-Products_375.jpg" alt="Matt Raker of AdvantageWest, the economic development agency for Western North Carolina, makes a point during a panel discussion about the emerging natural products industry hosted recently by Western Carolina University, which is launching a new master’s degree in chemistry with a professional science concentration in natural products." width="375" height="250" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Matt Raker of AdvantageWest, the economic development agency for Western North Carolina, makes a point during a panel discussion about the emerging natural products industry hosted recently by Western Carolina University, which is launching a new master’s degree in chemistry with a professional science concentration in natural products.</p></div>
<p>Western Carolina University recently hosted a half-day event focusing on the emerging natural products industry of the Western North Carolina region. The event also served as an official launch for WCU’s newest graduate program, which leads to a master’s degree in chemistry with a <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/cas/casdepts/chemphys/academic-programs/chem/mschem/psm/index.asp"><strong>professional science concentration in natural products</strong></a>.</p>
<p>The “WCU Summit on Natural Products: Education, Innovation and Vision,” held in Cullowhee on June 10, invited local natural products businesses to cultivate relationships with WCU faculty and university leaders.</p>
<p>The summit kicked off with remarks from Mimi Fenton, dean of the <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/wcu-graduate-school/index.asp"><strong>Graduate School</strong></a> and <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/research/"><strong>Research</strong></a>; Richard Starnes, dean of the <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/cas/"><strong>College of Arts and Sciences</strong></a>; and Arthur Salido, graduate program director for <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/departments-schools-colleges/cas/casdepts/chemphys/"><strong>chemistry and physics</strong></a>.</p>
<p>WCU alumnus Floyd “Ski” Chilton, professor of physiology and pharmacology at the Wake Forest School of Medicine and author of “Inflammation Nation,” delivered the keynote address. The talk, titled “A Vision for Changing the World from Western (North) Carolina,” highlighted the special opportunities that are available for university and industry partnerships in the region.</p>
<p>Representatives from organizations and businesses – Annice Brown (Small Business and Technology Development Center), Greg Cumberford (Bent Creek Institute), Frank King (KingBio), Sarah Schober (BioNetwork) and Matt Raker (AdvantageWest) – conducted a panel discussion and answered questions from the more than 50 people in attendance.</p>
<p>Local and regional businesses involved in the natural products industry offered sample products, including Jeanine and Jeff Buscher (Buchi), Frank and Suzie King (King Bio) and Jennifer Flynn (Blue Ridge Naturally).</p>
<p>During luncheon remarks, WCU Chancellor David O. Belcher stressed WCU’s commitment to cooperation and collaboration with the local natural products industry. Following the luncheon and remarks, attendees toured WCU’s West Campus with Tony Johnson, director of <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/about-wcu/millennial-initiative/index.asp"><strong>millennial initiatives</strong></a>.</p>
<p>Organizers of the summit deemed it a success, said Laura Cruz, executive director of WCU’s <a href="http://www.wcu.edu/academics/faculty/coulter-faculty-commons/"><strong>Coulter Faculty Commons</strong></a>, which organized and hosted the event along with the WCU Graduate School and WCU’s Millennial Initiatives.</p>
<p>“Feedback from the summit has been very positive, indicating a high degree of sustained interest in new natural products-based educational, research and economic development opportunities in WNC,” said Salido.</p>
<p>For more information about the new master’s degree program in chemistry and the concentration in natural products, visit the website <a href="http://chemistry.wcu.edu"><strong>chemistry.wcu.edu</strong></a>.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-hosts-natural-products-seminar-to-launch-new-chemistry-degree-concentration/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://news-prod.wcu.edu/2014/07/wcu-hosts-natural-products-seminar-to-launch-new-chemistry-degree-concentration/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.336 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2014-07-21 13:37:12 -->
