<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>SSU NewsCenter</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/atom.xml" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2010-06-04:/newscenter//77</id>
    <updated>2014-07-17T21:30:23Z</updated>
    
    <generator uri="http://www.sixapart.com/movabletype/">Movable Type 4.26</generator>

<entry>
    <title>OLLI Celebrates &quot;Place&quot; in Sonoma County </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/07/place-matters-at-olli-ssu.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17563</id>

    <published>2014-07-16T16:13:47Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-17T21:30:23Z</updated>

    <summary>Wallace Stegner writes &quot;...the knowledge of place comes from working in it in all weathers, making a living from it, suffering from its catastrophes...&quot; In her meditations on the Poetics of Place, Eudora Welty adds &quot;...feelings are bound up in...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="olliplace.jpeg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/olliplace.jpeg" width="350" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span>Wallace Stegner writes "...the knowledge of place comes from working in it in all weathers, making a living from it, suffering from its catastrophes..." </p>

<p>In her meditations on the Poetics of Place, Eudora Welty adds "...feelings are bound up in place, and in art, from time to time, place undoubtedly works upon genius..." </p>

<p>From architectural regionalism to the notion of terroir, many human values and cultural identities are rooted in the idea of "place."  </p>

<p>This summer, the Osher Lifelong Learning Institute (OLLI) at SSU has been exploring "place" in Sonoma County through its art, history, landscape, food and wine as curators, writers, vintners, naturalists, scholars, artists, chefs and historians led talks and tours both on the SSU campus and in the surrounding communities. More than 200 have joined in the experience with 20 percent new to OLLI.<br />
</p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p>The 2014 Place Project culminates with <em><strong>Place Matters</strong></em> from 10 a.m. to 1:30 p.m. on Tuesday, July 29 in the new Student Center. This free celebration features opening remarks by regional historian Gaye LeBaron. </p>

<p><br />
The event also includes OLLI students reflecting on their own sense of place, SSU faculty speakers, an art exhibition, catered lunch, entertainment from Broadway Under the Stars performers, and SSU student musicians. </p>

<p><br />
<em>Senses of Place</em>, a commemorative anthology will be given to everyone who attends. Essays and poetry in the anthology treat subjects of love, solace, nature, lifecycles, escape, community, seasons, sensory experience, and loss.</p>

<p><br />
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="socobarn.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/socobarn.jpg" width="300" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span><em>Senses of Place</em> weaves together OLLI student writings with place-inspired images, reproduced from original art work in the exhibition of the same name at THE HUB in the Student Center through July 31. </p>

<p> <br />
The musings on place began off-campus, with a series of June explorations to art museums, historic sites and nature preserves, immersing students in the natural and cultural history of Sonoma County. </p>

<p><br />
Each thread (art, history and science) had three destinations where scholars, curators and researchers welcomed OLLI students with a lecture and a tour.</p>

<p> <br />
Throughout the month of July, speakers from the worlds of food and wine, including producers, purveyors, chefs and culinary historians regaled OLLI students with gastronomic tales of Sonoma County. James Beard award winners and masters of terroir came together in <em>Taste Matters,</em> the OLLI version of food and wine pairings, held at the new SSU Student Center. </p>

<p> <br />
Sociologist Ray Oldenburg, in his work <em>The Great Good Place: Cafes, Coffee Shops, Bookstores, Bars, Hair Salons, and Other Hangouts at the Heart of a Community</em>, shares the concept of "third places" (in contrast to first and second places of home and work).  </p>

<p><br />
These sites of social activity, where adults gather on a regular basis, triangulate the social, behavioral and cognitive aspects of contemporary culture. "In its purest form, OLLI provides a third place for older adults while providing quality pathways for lifelong learning in the context of campus life," says Director Carin Jacobs.   </p>

<p> <br />
<em>OLLI Off Campus</em> and <em>Taste Matters</em> are generously supported by Connie Codding.<br />
Place Matters is generously supported by a grant from the Bernard Osher Foundation.<br />
 </p>

<p>To learn more or inquire about joining the "Place Project," contact<br />
Carin Jacobs, OLLI Director, at <a href="mailto:carin.jacobs@sonoma.edu">carin.jacobs@sonoma.edu</a> or 707-664-3927.<br />
  <br />
 <br />
<em>Above, OLLI students visit historical museum in Sonoma Valley. (Photo by Lindajoy Fenley)</em><br />
 <br />
<em> Middle "Sonoma Country Barn" by Marcia Fosberg</em><br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
 <br />
  </p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Lake County&apos;s High Schoolers Get to College Thanks to Upward Bound </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/07/post-242.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17538</id>

    <published>2014-07-07T21:41:45Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-17T21:48:56Z</updated>

    <summary>The entire Upward Bound senior class, from both Upper Lake and Lower Lake High Schools, have worked a long, hard four years of high school to achieve their goal of graduating and enrolling in college. While the Lake County Upward...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="llcupwardbound.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/llcupwardbound.jpg" width="540" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></span>The entire Upward Bound senior class, from both Upper Lake and Lower Lake High Schools, have worked a long, hard four years of high school to achieve their goal of graduating and enrolling in college. While the Lake County Upward Bound program celebrates its sixth year of success, the nation celebrates the program's 50th anniversary. </p>

<p> "Achieving educational equity in this country is still worth fighting for," said program director Shannon Smith. "There is no other social program I can think of that can pull a family out of poverty in one generation, the way that helping a young person get a college degree can do."  </p>

<p>Upward Bound students are required to maintain a 3.0 GPA, and cannot to receive less than a C in any core class. They are also encouraged to take Honors and Advanced Placement classes, perform community service, join clubs and sports, and serve as leaders in their school.    <br />
       </p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p>With the use of program funds, these Upward Bound seniors visited more than 30 college campuses in California, Oregon, and Nevada to help make an intelligent decision about what college is best for them. </p>

<p><br />
Of the 22 seniors, 14 will attend a four-year university in the fall. The other eight will attend community colleges.This year's class also has the first Upward Bound student to go to school in Oregon, attending Southern Oregon University. </p>

<p><br />
The other seniors will attend UC Berkley, UC Davis, CSU Monterey Bay, CSU Humboldt, CSU East Bay, CSU Chico, Sacramento State, San Diego State, as well as several community colleges. </p>

<p><br />
These students received more than $ 250,000 in scholarships, grants, and financial aid awards. Jordin Simons, Upward Bound student from Upper Lake High School, received the Buick Achievers Scholarship for up to $20,000 a year for four years. This is a highly competitive national scholarship program.</p>

<p>           <br />
Upward Bound is an education focused support program that assists low income, first generation students prepare for a successful college education. Funding from the U.S. Department of Education is awarded to SSU, who partners with Lake County schools to deliver services to selected students. </p>

<p><br />
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="ulupwardbound.jpeg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/ulupwardbound.jpeg" width="540" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></span>Statistics show that students from underrepresented groups, including low-income families, have more barriers to college enrollment and success. Upward Bound is designed to address these barriers and give students an opportunity to succeed. The Upward Bound program was born in 1964, as part of the "war on poverty" and is celebrating its 50th Anniversary this year. </p>

<p><br />
"In just six years of offering Upward Bound in Lake County, we have made a tremendous impact on the lives of the students served and expect to have our first college graduates in the coming year," said Smith. </p>

<p><br />
"But the goal is also to change the culture of this community and give people hope that a better life can be achieved through education, for individuals and their families."<br />
  <br />
For more information about the program, visit <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/trio/ubl">http://www.sonoma.edu/trio/ubl</a> or contact Shannon Smith at (707) 994-6471 ext. 2777 or shannon.smith@sonoma.edu.<a href="mailto:shannon.smith@sonoma.edu"></a></p>

<p> <br />
<em>- Tietta Mitchell, Upward Bound Student, Lower Lake High School</em></p>

<p><br />
<em>Lake County high school seniors achieved much thanks to the Upward Bound program. Top is Lower Lake class and middle is Upper Lake class.</em></p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Grand Weekend Staged for Opening of 250-Seat Schroeder Hall at SSU&apos;s Green Music Center</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/07/post-241.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17531</id>

    <published>2014-07-03T16:21:46Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-03T18:50:06Z</updated>

    <summary> Cathedral-Inspired Architecture Highlighted By 1,248-Pipe Brombaugh Opus 9 Organ Inaugural Concert with Pianist David Benoit Honors Jean Schulz, Aug. 22 Two Days of Free Community Concerts, Aug. 23, 24 Features Jeffrey Kahane Concert, Christening of the Organ by James...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><br />
<strong>Cathedral-Inspired Architecture Highlighted By 1,248-Pipe Brombaugh Opus 9 Organ </p>

<p>Inaugural Concert with Pianist David Benoit Honors Jean Schulz, Aug. 22</p>

<p>Two Days of Free Community Concerts, Aug. 23, 24 Features Jeffrey Kahane Concert, Christening of the Organ by James David Christie (Boston Symphony Orchestra) and Soprano Ruth Ann Swenson <br />
 <br />
"Sundays at Schroeder" Concert Series To Begin in September Featuring Celebrated Guest Artists in an Intimate Setting</p>

<p>SSU Music Department Year-Round Classes and Concerts Set in Schroeder Hall</strong></p>

<p><br />
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="schroeder.jpeg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/schroeder.jpeg" width="350" class="mt-image-left" style="float: right; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span>The much-anticipated opening of Schroeder Hall at the Green Music Center at Sonoma State University has been announced with a grand weekend of events in late August. </p>

<p>The venue, a 250-seat cathedral-like recital hall, has been designed to specifically accentuate instruments, organ, and voice in a small, intimate setting. The hall will also house a 1,248-pipe Brombaugh Opus 9 organ.</p>

<p>The opening weekend includes a private inaugural concert by pianist David Benoit honoring Schroeder's main philanthropist Jean Schulz on Aug. 22. Free community concerts are scheduled on Aug. 23 and 24 featuring Jeffery Kahane and Ruth Ann Swenson.</p>

<p>"Championed for nearly 20 years by donors far and wide -- including Donald and Maureen Green, Jean Schulz, and Joan and Sanford Weill -- the opening of Schroeder Hall represents a 'coming full circle' for  the Green Music Center," said SSU President Ruben Armiñana. "We are all tremendously pleased that the dream of this recital hall is at long last becoming reality."</p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p>"To step through the doors of Schroeder Hall is to embark on an exploration of the arts<br />
-- a musical journey," said Green Music Center Co-Executive Director Zarin Mehta.</p>

<p><br />
"This hall will be the epicenter of music education on a daily basis, and a place to<br />
showcase the diverse talents of Sonoma State University's exceptional students and<br />
faculty, in addition to beloved artists from a wide range of genres. The importance of<br />
Schroeder Hall to our campus and community cannot be overstated."</p>

<p><br />
Schroeder Hall's gently-curved stone exterior and distinctive, swooping roofline<br />
punctuate the south perimeter of the Green Music Center (GMC) grounds. Thousands of<br />
concertgoers have dined and danced in its shadow since the opening of Joan and<br />
Sanford I. Weill Hall and Lawn in 2012, and students have strode past its doors to<br />
classes in the Music Education Hall. </p>

<p><br />
For nearly 20 years, a dedicated group of founding donors and visionaries has championed the conception, construction and completion of this landmark building for SSU.</p>

<p><br />
<strong>Opening Weekend</strong></p>

<p><br />
The inaugural performance in Schroeder Hall will take place Friday, Aug. 22 <br />
with a private concert by pianist David Benoit to honor Jean Schulz. Schulz is a chief<br />
philanthropist and local leader who, in 2007, named the building in recognition of her late<br />
husband, cartoonist Charles Schulz, known for his piano-playing Peanuts character,<br />
Schroeder. The leadership and support of  Schulz is celebrated by Benoit's program<br />
for the evening, "Tribute to Charlie Brown."</p>

<p><br />
The Grand Opening festivities continue throughout the weekend, with nearly a dozen<br />
free concerts on Saturday, Aug. 23 and Sunday, Aug. 24 which will<br />
showcase Schroeder Hall's many acoustical attributes, as well as talent from the<br />
campus, community and beyond.</p>

<p><br />
Focal points of the weekend include a concert by pianist Jeffrey Kahane, Santa Rosa<br />
Symphony (SRS) Conductor Laureate and current Artistic Director of the Los Angeles<br />
Chamber Orchestra; recitals by SSU students and faculty; and a christening of the hall's<br />
Brombaugh Opus 9 organ by James David Christie of the Boston Symphony Orchestra,<br />
joined by soprano Ruth Ann Swenson, conductor Julian Wachner, and members of the<br />
SRS.</p>

<p></p>

<p><br />
<strong>"Sundays at Schroeder" Concert Series</strong></p>

<p><br />
Beginning in September 2014, the hall will feature presentations by up-and-coming<br />
musicians and celebrated guest artists through an ongoing series entitled, "Sundays at<br />
Schroeder." An exploration of musical genres, the concert series will launch with a<br />
performance by pianist Juho Pohjonen, and continue through May 2015. The 11-concert<br />
lineup will include intimate performances by singer Storm Large, of Pink Martini fame;<br />
Galician bagpiper Cristina Pato; jazz vocalist Mary Stallings; and violinist Ray Chen.</p>

<p></p>

<p><br />
<strong>Sonoma State University Music Department</strong></p>

<p><br />
Throughout the year, Schroeder Hall will be home to the students and faculty of the SSU<br />
Music Department, who will utilize the space for classes, rehearsals, recitals and<br />
performances.</p>

<p><br />
The hall will also be used as an expanded classroom for the 9000-student university,<br />
becoming one of the largest academic spaces on the 269-acre campus. Additionally,<br />
Schroeder Hall will be another venue for student life and co-curricular programming on<br />
the campus, serving as an additional space for meetings, presentations, and workshops<br />
organized annually by student groups.</p>

<p></p>

<p><br />
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="organ.png" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/organ.png" width="200" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span><strong>Brombaugh Opus 9 organ</strong></p>

<p><br />
Designed by BAR Architects of San Francisco, the 3,420 square-foot Schroeder Hall is notable for its curved architecture, soaring ceilings, and dedicated organ balcony where a 1,248-pipe Brombaugh Opus 9 organ will live. Constructed of red oak, with accents of<br />
rare woods, the organ's metal pipes range in size from 16 feet long to some smaller than<br />
a pencil.</p>

<p><br />
The organ --a gift to the University by donors BJ and Bebe Cassin in 2005-- has been<br />
temporarily housed at Saint Michael's Cathedral in Rochester, New York. There, students and faculty of the nearby Eastman School of Music organ department have kept the instrument in use.</p>

<p></p>

<p>  <br />
<strong>Ticket and Box Office Information</strong></p>

<p><br />
Ticket information and additional programming details for the grand opening weekend of<br />
Schroeder Hall can be found at gmc.sonoma.edu for more details. Tickets to the "Sundays at Schroeder" concert series will be available on Tuesday, July 15 in conjunction with the single ticket on-sale for the 2014-15 MasterCard Performance Series in Weill Hall.</p>

<p></p>

<p></p>

<p><br />
<strong>MEDIA CONTACTS</strong></p>

<p><strong>Melissa Sanders</strong><br />
Senior Director, Communications<br />
Green Music Center<br />
melissa.sanders@sonoma.edu<br />
404.909.6726</p>

<p><br />
<strong>Jessica Anderson</strong><br />
Associate Director, Communications<br />
Green Music Center<br />
jessica.anderson@sonoma.edu<br />
707.664.4122</p>

<p><br />
<strong>Eric Latzky</strong><br />
Eric Latzky Culture | Communications NY<br />
eric@elccny.com<br />
212.358.0223<br />
 <br />
  </p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Chancellor Timothy P. White Comments on State Budget News</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/06/chancellor-timothy-p-white-comments-on-state-budget-news.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17518</id>

    <published>2014-06-25T20:01:12Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-25T20:51:20Z</updated>

    <summary> &quot;Tuition fees will remain stable for our students for the fourth consecutive year. The allocation will also enable us to begin to address a backlog of deferred maintenance projects.&quot; CSU Chancellor Timothy P. White made the following announcement to...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><br />
<em><strong>"Tuition fees will remain stable for our students for the fourth consecutive year. The allocation will also enable us to begin to address a backlog of deferred maintenance projects."</strong></em></p>

<p><br />
<em>CSU Chancellor Timothy P. White made the following announcement to the SSU campus community today regarding the passage of the 2014-15 California State Budget.</em><br />
 <br />
 <br />
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="timothywhite.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/timothywhite.jpg" width="250" class="mt-image-right" style="float: right; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span>"The Governor has signed the 2014-15 state budget that includes an increase of $142.2 million in base funding for the CSU. The budget increase will enable the CSU to maintain existing programs and services. </p>

<p>Moreover, tuition fees will remain stable for our students for the fourth consecutive year. The allocation will also enable us to begin to address a backlog of deferred maintenance projects.</p>

<p>This increase in our budget is welcome and reflects the tremendous grassroots advocacy work of the CSU family--students, faculty, staff, alumni, labor leaders and community supporters--who were in the trenches meeting with lawmakers about California's need to reinvest in the CSU. </p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p>As you are likely aware, the Trustees' budget request was $95 million more than what was ultimately signed into law. I am grateful to all of you who advocated tirelessly on the CSU's behalf. </p>

<p><br />
Your efforts resulted in more than 80 lawmakers committing to "Stand with the CSU" in the budget negotiations, which led to both houses recommending increases to the system's funding allocation to match the Trustees' request. </p>

<p><br />
While the final result fell short of our request, it does not diminish the power of our collective voice and our steadfast commitment to student success, nor does it diminish our resolve going forward.</p>

<p><br />
The CSU continues to offer students an excellent education, but in this budgetary climate we will not be able to serve all of the eligible students who want to attend the university. Indeed, over the last two years, the CSU has experienced a 12 percent increase in applications and turned away more than 25,000 California students.</p>

<p><br />
For California to succeed at the level we expect, its climate of innovation and economic growth must be fueled by an educated citizenry. The CSU is doing its part, graduating more than 100,000 students into the workforce annually, and we stand ready to do more. </p>

<p><br />
But we can only increase the number of graduates with the adequate, sustained funding needed to hire more faculty and staff to serve our students, to increase employee compensation in order to recruit and retain the best individuals, and to address facility and infrastructure needs.</p>

<p><br />
Our story is compelling, and we must continue to come together and raise the profile of the CSU's impact and importance to the state's economy, businesses and industries, and social fabric. </p>

<p><br />
I seek your ongoing assistance sharing the CSU's remarkable story. The vital work you do in the classroom and on campus helps our students become engaged and productive members of society."<br />
 </p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>The Roth Family Donation Sparks a Legacy of Environmental Education and Research  </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/06/post-239.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17512</id>

    <published>2014-06-23T22:18:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-02T18:09:20Z</updated>

    <summary> William and Joan Roth (far right) with their children (left to right) Maggie, SSU Preserves Director Claudia Luke, Jessica, Grandson Willem Vorster and his mother Ana Roth. Less than a year before his death this May, William Matson Roth...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="rothfamily.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/rothfamily.jpg" width="560" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></span></p>

<p></p>

<p><em>William and Joan Roth (far right) with their children (left to right) Maggie, SSU Preserves Director Claudia Luke, Jessica, Grandson Willem Vorster and his mother Ana Roth.</em></p>

<p><br />
Less than a year before his death this May, <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2014/06/16/business/william-m-roth-shipping-heir-who-became-lifelong-public-servant-dies-at-97.html?_r=0">William Matson Roth</a> was thinking of Sonoma State University (SSU) and the nature preserve that he and his family's philanthropy had created in the hills above the campus.  <br />
 <br />
In their most recent "gift of generosity," William and Joan Roth, and their children Jessica, Maggie, and Ana, donated a 40-acre parcel at the top of Sonoma Mountain to cement the future of the 450-acre Fairfield Osborn Preserve they had helped create.<br />
 <br />
"At SSU, we teach students of all ages and from all disciplines about the importance of their connections to local environments - something that they can carry with them throughout their careers," says SSU Preserves Director Claudia Luke. <br />
 <br />
"The Roth family's generous donation and history of giving has created a legacy of learning for generations." </p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p>The property carries a "forever wild" conservation easement with the Sonoma County Agricultural Preservation and Open Space District that blocks any future development or access roads through the Preserve.  <br />
 <br />
 </p>

<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="fairfieldosborn.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/fairfieldosborn.jpg" width="150" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span>The Roth's initial land donation of 221 acres in 1972 to the Nature Conservancy was made in honor of Joan Roth's father, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_Fairfield_Osborn">Fairfield Osborn</a>. Osborn was a well-known naturalist, writer, and conservation advisor to several U.S. presidential administrations.  </p>

<p> <br />
In 1948, his book "Our Plundered Planet" was published, a prophetic work in which he warned that the earth's resources were not inexhaustible and that the ecological web connecting all life could be broken by thoughtless, irreparable action.</p>

<p> <br />
His family has taken that to heart. Osborn Preserve has become a symbol of a family's hopes, generosity and love of the land.</p>

<p> <br />
In 1997 when the property transferred to SSU, the Roth family expanded their initial gift by adding 190 adjacent acres with education in mind. It doubled the size of the Osborn Preserve to 411 acres. </p>

<p> <br />
Since the University took ownership and management of the land, programs at the Preserve have expanded to create transformational environmental and research experiences for students in all disciplines. These run the gamut from performing arts, engineering, biology and environmental studies to anthropology, social sciences, and business.</p>

<p> <br />
One of these is the Osborn Environmental Sensor Network, a sensor-to-screen network built by students for students in engineering science, computer science and environmental disciplines. <br />
 <br />
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="preservesfieldwork.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/preservesfieldwork.jpg" width="400" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span>For the past 32 years, Fairfield Osborn Preserve has also provided natural history education and land management programs for university students, elementary school children, and the public.</p>

<p> <br />
Hundreds of 3rd-5th graders annually visit the Preserve where they interact with plants, soil, water, rocks, insects and animals in ways that help them understand their interconnectedness with and relationship to our planet.</p>

<p> <br />
The Osborn Preserve also hosts research projects from many academic institutions and environmentally focused non-profits, the most significant of which concerns the continued study of the spread and the impacts of Sudden Oak Death Syndrome. </p>

<p> <br />
SSU now owns a total of 450 acres of property on Sonoma Mountain that includes its 2,300-foot high northern ridgeline. </p>

<p> <br />
Luke says the new donation is also a crucial component of a regional habitat corridor that connects the Blue Ridge and Mayacama Mountains to Point Reyes National Seashore.</p>

<p> <br />
The corridor allows animals with long-ranging roaming needs like the mountain lion to move freely throughout the region.  </p>

<p> <br />
"The Roth's dreams have been heard, they are in safe hands, and are on a trajectory to change the world." Luke says.</p>

<p></p>

<p><br />
<em>ABOVE:  SSU biology class with Preserve educator Suzanne DeCoursey studies watershed issues.</em><br />
 </p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>With State Budget Support Coming, SSU To Increase Faculty Hiring to Better Serve Students</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/06/with-state-budget-support-coming-ssu-to-increase-faculty-hiring-to-better-serve-students.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17500</id>

    <published>2014-06-12T18:56:50Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-17T17:49:27Z</updated>

    <summary> SSU IN THE NEWS - Press Democrat, June 16, 2014 Sonoma State University expects $3.3 million budget hike SSU President Ruben Armiñana has announced that with the Governor&apos;s final budget offer to the California State University system of $142...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<div class="notice-30 alert">

<p><br />
<strong>SSU IN THE NEWS - Press Democrat, June 16, 2014</strong></p>

<p><a href="http://www.pressdemocrat.com/article/20140615/articles/140619680">Sonoma State University expects $3.3 million budget hike</a></p>

</div>

<p>SSU President Ruben Armiñana has announced that with the Governor's final budget offer to the California State University system of $142 million holds, the campus will hire a minimum of 45 new permanent faculty over the next three academic years.</p>

<p>The hiring of 15 new faculty each academic year in 2015-16, 2016-17 and 2017-18 will help SSU meet Arminana's first priority of better serving students by keeping them on track to a timely graduation.<br />
</p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p>"The addition of more faculty will provide more class sections, particularly in bottleneck courses," says Arminana. The process began on a smaller scale for this coming academic year as nine new permanent faculty have been hired for 2014-15.</p>

<p> <br />
Arminana says he looks forward to continued state-wide economic growth and a new positive beginning for the campus with an updated University strategic plan now under development. </p>

<p><br />
The plan includes a goal of offering all undergraduate students the opportunity to engage in a hands-on scholarly activity (e.g. a research project, internship or a work of art project as determined by the academic departments) as part of the educational "tattoo" of SSU. </p>

<p><br />
These activities would be phased in by providing increasing amounts of faculty professional development each year to mentor students in these activities.<br />
 </p>

<p>Also under review is a goal to permanently close the ongoing $1.7 million deficit in the Academic Affairs Division.</p>

<p><br />
These new strategies are in line with Chancellor Timothy White's priority goals for the CSU which are:</p>

<p><br />
 •   Increased numbers of tenure-track faculty</p>

<p>•   Enhanced advising</p>

<p>•   Solutions for bottleneck courses</p>

<p>•   Better first-year student preparation</p>

<p>•   High-impact practices for student achievement</p>

<p>•   Expand data-driven decision-making</p>

<p>•   Bolster transfer degree completion rates</p>

<p><br />
Over the past several years, Sonoma State University, like it sister California State University campuses, suffered the loss of almost 30% of its budget resulting in prolonging students' progress toward graduation.  </p>

<p><br />
"The State of California appears to be turning a positive financial corner which directly affects the campuses of the CSU," says Arminana. "Governor Brown strongly supports higher education as a means to keep the state on par with what a 21st century workforce needs to be." </p>

<p> <br />
For more budget news from the CSU, visit <a href="http://blogs.calstate.edu/budgetcentral/?p=1927">http://blogs.calstate.edu/budgetcentral/?p=1927</a>.</p>

<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Thaine Stearns Named Dean of School of Arts and Humanities</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/thaine-stearns-named-dean-of-arts-and-humanities.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17454</id>

    <published>2014-05-28T17:48:59Z</published>
    <updated>2014-06-02T17:54:58Z</updated>

    <summary>Dr. Thaine Stearns has been selected as Dean of the School of Arts and Humanities, effective July 1, 2014. Dr. Stearns has served as interim dean in the School for the last three years. Under his leadership, the School has...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="stearns.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/stearns.jpg" width="147" height="274" class="mt-image-right" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 20px 20px;" /></span>Dr. Thaine Stearns has been selected as Dean of the School of Arts and Humanities, effective July 1, 2014.</p>

<p>Dr. Stearns has served as interim dean in the School for the last three years. Under his leadership, the School has developed and implemented several major initiatives, including the Humanities Learning Communities; the Center for Ethics, Law, and Society; the Weill Hall Artists in Residence; the Arts & Humanities "First-Stop" Advising Center. Beginning in Fall 2014, the Sophomore Year Research and Creative Experience courses will be launched. <br />
</p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p>In addition, he steered successful efforts to renovate Person Theater and the Walford Sound Recording Studio. </p>

<p><br />
Dr. Stearns received his Ph.D. in English from the University of Washington in 1999. After holding teaching positions at the Pacific Northwest College of Art and the University of Wisconsin, he began at SSU as an Assistant Professor in the English Department. </p>

<p><br />
His scholarly and teaching interests are in twentieth-century British, U.S. and European literatures, visual culture, literary theory, and the novel. </p>

<p><br />
An active scholar, he has published several reviews and articles on Virginia Woolf, James Joyce and Dora Marsden; Rebecca West and T.S. Eliot; and on Wyndham Lewis, Vladimir Nabokov, and William Carlos Williams.<br />
 </p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Financial Yoga for College Grads: Get Over Your Fears, Increase Your Tech Skills </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/money-advice-for-college-graduates.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17452</id>

    <published>2014-05-28T17:16:56Z</published>
    <updated>2014-07-08T16:12:47Z</updated>

    <summary>A blogger from US News and World reports asked for some advice from a wise financial soul to help college grads who are looking for work or just landed their first job. Economics professor Robert Eyler had some compelling thoughts...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="roberteyler.png" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/roberteyler.png" width="100" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span>A blogger from <a href="http://news.yahoo.com/smartest-post-college-money-plan-starting-budgeting-now-185227515.html;_ylt=AwrTWf3oMatTQiUA97fQtDMD">US News and World reports</a> asked for some advice from a wise financial soul to help college grads who are looking for work or just landed their first job. </p>

<p>Economics professor Robert Eyler had some compelling thoughts about living without a paycheck or on a pretty slim one for those first entering the world of work.</p>

<p>Think about it all as financial yoga; hurts now, helps later.</p>

<p><strong>1.  Increase your ability to use new and difficult technology tools.</strong></p>

<p>For recent graduates who have the latest smartphone and tablets, the market will pay a premium for folks that utilize these tech tools well in traditional markets.  For example, bring ideas to markets like finance, accounting, traditional sales, and other services that are potentially slow movers on technology may help you land a job more quickly.  Develop knowledge of a statistical package (SPSS, STATA, SAS) and Excel for sure; if you have these abilities, bring that up immediately in an interview.  If you can use Prezi for presentations, say it also.</p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p><strong>2.  Get over your fears of public speaking through practice.</strong></p>

<p><br />
One thing texting has done is make people more reluctant to have face-to-face conversations.  Do not lose your ability (or start developing the ability) to command a conversation in person or a room if asked to present to a crowd.  </p>

<p><br />
Because the tide is turning more to informal communications as a norm, there is a niche market in speaking in front of people well. Future jobs are going to be about sales, specifically selling yourself and experiences, so bring passion to your speaking.  Conquering fears and developing good speaking techniques will help long-term.</p>

<p><br />
<strong>3.  Live a going-to-die-at-100 lifestyle</strong></p>

<p><br />
Don't act like a psycho with money if you do not land a job soon. The more you spend, the more you will need to dig out of debt.  One way to control your spending, if you know it may be a while before you get a job is to go to a local community college and take some courses on the above skills.  </p>

<p><br />
That will keep you focused, out of the bars, and (hopefully) out of debt.  A lot of people I know that have struggled in the job market struggle in real life because they lived check to check. Build a mentality around war chests and you will be happier later if the job market is fickle. Think about it as financial yoga; hurts now, helps later.<br />
 <br />
</p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Becoming an SSU Homestay Family is a Special Experience</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/becoming-an-ssu-homestay-family-is-a-special-experience.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17012</id>

    <published>2014-05-16T22:28:57Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-16T19:35:52Z</updated>

    <summary>Since 1979, the Sonoma State American Language Institute (SSALI) has provided international students with a chance to learn the English language as well as to absorb American culture. However, it has become increasingly difficult to offer this experience, as there...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="homestayfamilya.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/homestayfamilya.jpg" width="350" class="mt-image-right" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 20px 20px;" /></span>Since 1979, the Sonoma State American Language Institute (SSALI) has provided international students with a chance to learn the English language as well as to absorb American culture. </p>

<p>However, it has become increasingly difficult to offer this experience, as there are fewer and fewer places to house students involved in the SSALI program.<br />
 <br />
For years the SSALI program has relied upon a core group of homestays, local families who have voluntarily opened their doors and allowed a student, or several, to stay with them during a SSALI semester. </p>

<p>Unfortunately the pool of acceptable homes has shrunk tremendously, leaving many students' housing situation uncertain. However, when a student and a homestay family come together, results can often be wondrous.</p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p>Lupita Barragan recently opened her home for a SSALI student. She and her family are new to the SSALI program but have experienced great results while involved. The student she was placed with is 19 year old Rowena Wu from China. </p>

<p><br />
"She has actually brought us together as a family and has reminded us it's important to have time and conversations together at least once a day," Barragan said  Her family is now having more family dinners consistently throughout the week.</p>

<p><br />
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="homestaylupita.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/homestaylupita.jpg" width="250" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span>Barragan added "We are glad to have her and a SSALI program that includes my family and gives us an opportunity to share our home with someone who could've been alone. I'm happy to have her home. It's a nice match." </p>

<p> <br />
In order to become a homestay, a family must meet certain criteria such as distance to campus, access to public transportation, and ability to provide for the student during their stay. Once deemed an appropriate place to house a student a homestay then may designate preferences they would prefer in a student. The challenge resides in the attempt to match an established home with a particular student while a student hopes for a place to call home.</p>

<p> <br />
With limited housing options and nonexistent alternatives SSALI administrators have been forced to explore other options. Currently, they are exploring the brokering of reserved on-campus housing units strictly for SSALI students as well as surveying other lodging possibilities in the community.</p>

<p> <br />
As a component of the Extended Education Department the SSALI program has been in operation since 1979. Generally the program attracts 40 to 50 students per semester who are gathered via third party placement agencies. Students in the program come from across the globe, stretching from South America, Asia and the Middle East.</p>

<p> <br />
While enrolled, students receive rigorous instruction in English composition, reading, and grammar, as well as classes revolving around American culture and conversation.</p>

<p><br />
Students also have the option to contribute to the <em>Scoop</em> Newsletter, a publication produced by SSALI students used to facilitate the improvement of written communication skills. Students may also enroll in courses designed for TOEFL preparation, an English proficiency test used for college admissions. </p>

<p> <br />
For more information on the <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/exed/ssali">SSALI program</a> please contact Debra Crow at 707-664-2742 or at <a href="mailto:debra.crow@sonoma.edu">debra.crow@sonoma.edu</a>.</p>

<p><br />
<em>-Doug Arias</em></p>

<p></p>

<p><br />
<em>ABOVE; Lupita Barragan and Armando Franco have hosted SSALI student Rowena Wu in their home and find it very rewarding. The family has included trips to see the sights of San Francisco.</em></p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>First Multi-Cultural Reception Goes Beyond Expectations</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/post-237.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17420</id>

    <published>2014-05-16T17:24:55Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-16T17:33:36Z</updated>

    <summary>The first multi-cultural graduation reception held in the Student Center grand ballroom on the Friday before Commencement was a beautiful, multi-generational success. &quot;The students, led by Kelly Hodgins, did an excellent job putting together an event that far exceeded expectations,&quot;...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="blackgradscelebrate.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/blackgradscelebrate.jpg" width="560" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></span>The first multi-cultural graduation reception held in the Student Center grand ballroom on the Friday before Commencement was a beautiful, multi-generational success. "The students, led by Kelly Hodgins, did an excellent job putting together an event that far exceeded expectations," said HUB director Mark Fabionar. "Students, faculty, administrators and community members deeply appreciated the opportunity to celebrate our students and communities." <br />
 </p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="culturalgrads.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/culturalgrads.jpg" width="560" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></span></p>

<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="culturalgradsevent.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/culturalgradsevent.jpg" width="560" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></span></p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>SSU Library Aids in PBS Documentary &quot;Ruben Salazar: Man in the Middle&quot; </title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/ssu-library-aids-in-pbs-documentary-ruben-salazar-man-in-the-middle.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17418</id>

    <published>2014-05-15T17:47:10Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-15T18:44:29Z</updated>

    <summary> The recently broadcast PBS documentary &quot;Ruben Salazar: Man in the Middle&quot; was supported by the SSU Special Collections Dept. which contributed research and film footage for this production and received a closing credit. It can be viewed online at...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p> <span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="rubensalazar.png" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/rubensalazar.png" width="250" class="mt-image-right" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 20px 20px;" /></span></p>

<p>The recently broadcast PBS documentary "Ruben Salazar: Man in the Middle" was supported by the SSU Special Collections Dept. which contributed research and film footage for this production and received a closing credit. It can be viewed online at <a href="http://video.pbs.org/video/2365231799/">http://video.pbs.org/video/2365231799/</a><br />
 <br />
Ruben Salazar Hall, which was originally the location of the SSU University Library, is named after the famous Latino journalist who worked for a time at the <em>Press Democrat </em>in the late 1950s. He later moved to the <em>Los Angeles Times</em>. </p>

<p>The University Library is also the curator of the <strong><a href="http://library.sonoma.edu/regional/notables/salazar.php">Ruben Salazar Collection</a></strong> which is comprised of clippings of Salazar's news stories and includes articles about him, bibliographies, photocopies of photographs, documents, and ephemera.<br />
 </p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p><em>Ruben Salazar: Man in the Middle</em> examines the life and mysterious death of this pioneering  journalist. At the heart of the story is Salazar's transformation from a mainstream, establishment reporter to primary chronicler and supporter of the radical Chicano Movement of the late 1960s. </p>

<p><br />
Killed under mysterious circumstances by a law enforcement officer in 1970, Salazar became an instant martyr to Latinos -- many of whom had criticized his reporting during his lifetime. Adding to the Salazar mystique is that the details of how he was killed have been obscured in the ensuing four decades since his death.</p>

<p><br />
Featuring material from recently released files obtained by the filmmaker, <em>Ruben Salazar: Man in the Middle</em> "removes Salazar from the glare of myth and martyrdom and offers a clear-eyed look at the man and his times." The film, produced and directed by Phillip Rodriguez, includes interviews with Salazar's friends, colleagues and family members, and Salazar's own words culled from personal writings.</p>

<p><br />
More information about the documentary can be found at <a href="http://rubensalazarpbs.org">http://rubensalazarpbs.org</a>. </p>

<p> </p>

<p>The DVD can also be checked out from the University Library at <a href="http://iii.sonoma.edu/record=b3587594~S10">http://iii.sonoma.edu/record=b3587594~S10</a>.</p>

<p><br />
In addition to the documentary, the University Library has these related resources about Salazar and the Chicano Moratorium, as well as books.</p>

<p> <br />
<strong>Ruben Salazar Collection</strong>            <a href="http://library.sonoma.edu/regional/notables/salazar.php">http://library.sonoma.edu/regional/notables/salazar.php</a><br />
<strong>Requiem 29 (film)   </strong>                       <a href="http://iii.sonoma.edu/record=b1609317~S10">http://iii.sonoma.edu/record=b1609317~S10</a><br />
<strong>Latino USA  (radio show)  </strong>          <a href="http://iii.sonoma.edu/record=b1398151~S10">http://iii.sonoma.edu/record=b1398151~S10</a>  <br />
 <br />
For further information, contact Dayle Reilly, Coordinator, North Bay Regional & Special Collections, 707-664-2510.</p>

<p><br />
 </p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>From a Fraternity Dragfest to a CD of Children&apos;s Songs, Work on Mental Illness Awareness Pushes Forward</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/from-an-ssu-fraternity-drag-fest-to-a-cd-of-childrens-songs-work-on-mental-illness-awareness-pushes.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17345</id>

    <published>2014-05-13T21:18:06Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-20T23:46:49Z</updated>

    <summary>A fraternity drag fest and a CD full of comforting songs are part of recent efforts at SSU to raise awareness about the stigma of mental illness in the community. Having seen students, faculty, staff, administrators, friends and family affected...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="denybozeman.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/denybozeman.jpg" width="300" class="mt-image-left" style="float: left; margin: 0 20px 20px 0;" /></span>A fraternity drag fest and a CD full of comforting songs are part of recent efforts at SSU to raise awareness about the stigma of mental illness in the community.<br />
 <br />
Having seen students, faculty, staff, administrators, friends and family affected by depression, anxiety, PTSD, bipolar and other mental illness, combined with a passion for educating others, inspired two SSU faculty recently to team up to produce a children's CD in hopes of comforting families and individuals affected by mental illness. Donations for the CD have already raised more than $6,500 for the non-profit agency. </p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p>The CD is part of the fundraising efforts of the local <a href="http://www.namisonomacounty.org">Sonoma County based chapter of the National Alliance for Mental Illness (NAMI)</a>. Entitled "Songs for Children and Families," it was produced by retired SSU Music and English lecturer <a href="http://sarahbakerstudios.com">Sarah Baker</a> (who performs blues and jazz in the North Bay and beyond) and English and Philosophy lecturer Denny Bozman-Moss, who also teaches English at SRJC.  It has songs for all ages from children's classics to older favorites.</p>

<p> <br />
Bozman-Moss, who received SSU's "Outstanding Faculty Award" for "promoting academic excellence, supporting students outside of class and encouraging students achievement" is also passionate about the cause NAMI works to advocate for because of many students, staff, faculty, administrators, friends and family he has witnessed struggling with depression and other mental illness and the stigma attached to it by law enforcement and social agencies.</p>

<p> <br />
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="sarahbaker.jpeg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/sarahbaker.jpeg" width="200" class="mt-image-right" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 20px 20px;" /></span>"NAMI has been there like a life raft for my students and so many other people," said Bozman-Moss. "Knowing that one out of four families are affected by mental illness makes me want to put the word out there that we have a resource like NAMI. It can help all of us start to understand and educate people, including law enforcement and social agencies, to work together to provide a society where we can work safely with people suffering from it."</p>

<p> <br />
"Songs for Families and Children" not only raises money for the local non-profit but it is also meant to provide comfort and peace to individuals affected by mental illness. The songs, recorded in both English and Spanish, are not just about mental illness. Rather, they are upbeat and positive and meant to bring happiness to families and children, whether affected by mental health issues or not.</p>

<p> <br />
Some of the music includes: "Riding in My Car" by Woody Guthrie, "De Colores" the ever popular migrant workers song, "What Did You Learn in School Today" by Tom Paxton and Kate Wolf's "Give Yourself Love". </p>

<p><br />
There are a total of 23 songs on the CD, all sung and recorded by Baker and Bozman-Moss. The CD comes with a songbook with words to all 23 songs. There is no set cost for the CD; people donate what they want. Some donations have been $3, and one was a high as $1,000.</p>

<p><br />
<div class="notice-50 alert"></p>

<p><br />
<span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="bozmancdcvr.jpeg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/bozmancdcvr.jpeg" width="200" class="mt-image-center" style="text-align: center; display: block; margin: 0 auto 20px;" /></span><br />
<strong>Songs for Children and Families</strong><br />
<em>(Selections from the NAMI CD)</em></p>

<p><br />
<embed src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/songinmyheart.aiff"" width="200" height="32" autoplay="false"></embed><br /></p>

<p><embed src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/mockingbird.aiff" width="200" height="32" autoplay="false"></embed><br /></p>

<p><embed src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/wholewideworld.aiff" width="200" height="32" autoplay="false"></embed><br /></p>

<p></p>

<p><br />
</div><br />
 </p>

<p>Founded in 1979, the NAMI works to advocate for the rights and needs of community members who live with mental illness. NAMI Sonoma County located in Santa Rosa, works on expanding knowledge of mental illness throughout the community, as well as giving support to individuals who suffer with mental illness, through programs like "Peer to Peer" and for families with loved ones struggling with mental health issues there is "Family to Family."<br />
 <br />
Former NAMI board member and SSU Professor of Nursing Dr. Deb Kindy works with the non-profit organization because of her motivation to educate and inform students and the community about mental illness.<br />
 <br />
"I like tackling the stigma (surrounding mental illness). It is the drive to create more balance in the world in terms of allowing people to live up to their potential," said Kindy<br />
 <br />
In Kindy's Psychiatric and Mental Health Nursing course, NAMI spokespeople from "In their Own Voice" program visit her class to speak about the messages the organization works to promote and advocate. NAMI looks to not only educate about mental illness but also be a resource for people who suffer from mental illness and their families.<br />
 <br />
The non-profit organization is now looking to raise money and promote the CD further in the community. NAMI Executive Director Rosemary Milbrath can be reached at 707-527-6655 or at <a href="http://www.namisoco.org">www.namisoco.org</a> for those who would like to assist, or who have a loved one with a mental health issue and do not know where to turn.<br />
 <br />
Earlier this year, NAMI and the Alpha Psi fraternity at SSU held a campus fundraising event that promoted the mission of the organization and advocacy efforts for mental illness. Sonoma State student, Alpha Psi fraternity member and friend of the Bozman-Moss family, Elijah Stephenson, organized the fundraising event.<br />
 <br />
The self-titled "Alpha Psi Cutie Pie Drag Show," raised nearly $500 for NAMI along with successfully advocating what the organization does for the community. The campus event featured fraternity members dressed in drag wear who competed in dance and singing competition along with performing short comedic skits.<br />
 <br />
"We wanted to raise money for NAMI and wanted to do something really out of the ordinary and the drag just fell into place. I don't think anyone really knew anything about drag," said Stephenson. </p>

<p>"There was really an impressive outcome and so we want the Green Music Center next time. We definitely can't wait to do it again. Next year we want to include as many organizations as we can; not just Greek organizations. It was definitely a great opportunity."</p>

<p><br />
<em>- Kayla Galloway</em></p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>SSU&apos;s Super Kids Camp Offers Ten Weeks of Fun</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/ssus-super-kids-camp-offers-ten-weeks-of-fun.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17414</id>

    <published>2014-05-13T18:24:12Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-13T18:26:20Z</updated>

    <summary>Super Kids Camp provides a fun, recreational, educational, and motivational experience for campers, ages 5-11, this summer at Sonoma State University. Registration is now open and the first week of camp starts Monday, June 2. Each weekly Super Kids Camp...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p>Super Kids Camp provides a fun, recreational, educational, and motivational experience for campers, ages 5-11, this summer at Sonoma State University. Registration is now open and the first week of camp starts Monday, June 2.</p>

<p>Each weekly Super Kids Camp session will include a fun theme, local field trip, special events, pool time, and rock wall climbing. Other camp activities include arts & crafts, sports, science, and group play. All are held in the Student Recreation Center.</p>

<p>"Our low camper to counselor ratio makes it possible to promote a non-competitive environment in all camp activities," says Mike Dominguez, Kids Camp Coordinator. "Our Super Kids Camp counselors are CPR and first aid certified. They are high energy and active SSU students who are enthusiastic about working with children."</p>]]>
        
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Guzmán Earns Mario Savio Student Activist Award From ACLU</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/ssu-junior-jesus-guzman-has.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17413</id>

    <published>2014-05-12T23:29:06Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-13T20:03:28Z</updated>

    <summary>SSU Junior Jesús Guzmán has received the ACLU of Sonoma County&apos;s 2014 Mario Savio Student Activist Award at ceremonies recently. Guzmán is an accomplished student and a dedicated social justice activist. He is currently serving as the lead organizer and...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Achievements" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p><span class="mt-enclosure mt-enclosure-image" style="display: inline;"><img alt="jesusguzman.jpg" src="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/jesusguzman.jpg" width="100" height="100" class="mt-image-right" style="float: right; margin: 0 0 20px 20px;" /></span>SSU Junior <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/jesusguzman07">Jesús Guzmán</a> has received the ACLU of Sonoma County's 2014 <a href="http://aclusonoma.org/mario-savio-award">Mario Savio Student Activist Award</a> at ceremonies recently. Guzmán is an accomplished student and a dedicated social justice activist. He is currently serving as the lead organizer and program manager for the Graton Day Labor Center.</p>

<p>Born in Mexico, he arrived in the United States as a one-year-old and grew up on a small dairy farm in Sonoma County, as the son of a domestic worker and dairyman.  </p>

<p>Over the last few years, he founded the DREAM Alliance of Sonoma County and has been organizing with other immigrant youth to increase access to financial aid, DACA (Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals) and fighting to end deportations.  <br />
</p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p> The Mario Savio Student Activist Award was established to recognize a Sonoma County student who has shown a personal commitment to civil liberties, human rights and social justice. The recipient receives $500 from the chapter with the award. </p>

<p><br />
Successful candidates for this award have demonstrated leadership ability, creativity, and integrity in their activism. The recipient should possess the core spirit of moral courage that Mario Savio exemplifies.<br />
 </p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

<entry>
    <title>Workshop Highlights SSU Research on Under-represented Student Groups</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/the-academic-advising-sub-committee-is.html" />
    <id>tag:www.sonoma.edu,2014:/newscenter//77.17412</id>

    <published>2014-05-12T22:57:00Z</published>
    <updated>2014-05-12T23:28:25Z</updated>

    <summary>The Academic Advising Sub-Committee is hosting a workshop featuring SSU research on under-represented student groups with a discussion about how the campus can better support those students in various campus roles. The workshop will be on Thursday, May 15 from...</summary>
    <author>
        <name>Jean Wasp</name>
        
    </author>
    
        <category term="Homepage" scheme="http://www.sixapart.com/ns/types#category" />
    
    
    <content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/">
        <![CDATA[<p>The Academic Advising Sub-Committee is hosting a workshop featuring SSU research on under-represented student groups with a discussion about how the campus can better support those students in various campus roles. </p>

<p>The workshop will be on Thursday, May 15 from 1-2:30 p.m in Darwin 30. </p>

<p>Included are three 10-minute research talks, a discussion of student stigma on campus by Dr. Leslie Shelton, Director of Academic Support Service, and discussion of the topics and ideas for improving the retention, experience, and graduation of underrepresented students. <br />
</p>]]>
        <![CDATA[<p><strong>Research presentations will be presented by: </strong></p>

<p><br />
<strong>Kristal Raheem, Sociology graduating senior,</strong> will present <strong>"The Experience: An Analysis of the Retention and Graduation Rate of Black Students at Sonoma State University."</strong> Raheem recently presented her paper at the Pacific Sociological Association meetings in Portland, Oregon. She also recently won the <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/sociology-senior-wins-csu-student-research-competition-for-black-student-experience-at-ssu.html">CSU Student Research Competition</a> in the undergraduate Behavioral and Social Sciences session for this research. </p>

<p><br />
<strong>Beni Merlin, Sociology graduating senior</strong>, will present his research <strong>"Dreams Unfulfilled- An Analysis of Undocumented Students at SSU and SRJC." </strong> Merlin also competed in the <a href="http://www.sonoma.edu/newscenter/2014/05/sociology-senior-wins-csu-student-research-competition-for-black-student-experience-at-ssu.html">CSU Student Research Competition</a> with this paper and will be presenting his research this summer at the American Sociological Association annual meetings in San Francisco. </p>

<p><br />
<strong>Sheila Katz, Assistant Professor of Sociology, with Holly Phillips, a Human Development graduating senior and Sociology minor</strong>, will present <strong>"Student Parents' Experiences and Challenges at Sonoma State University." </strong></p>

<p><br />
Their information is the result  of the student parent survey they conducted this spring on campus. This research will also be presented at Ohio State University at the end of May at the National Student Parent Support Symposium. <br />
 <br />
 </p>]]>
    </content>
</entry>

</feed>
