<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">WIT Magazine</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2014-05-15T18:42:44Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" />
	<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.8.2">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Sang</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Boston as a Lab]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/15/boston-as-a-lab/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3617</id>
		<updated>2014-05-15T17:57:11Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-15T17:56:09Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[New curriculum emphasizes location]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/15/boston-as-a-lab/"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 1.5em;">ON A WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON LAST FALL, a group of first-year architecture students stood in the middle of Summer Street in Downtown Crossing, pencils and paper in hand, sketching their surroundings while trying to find the horizon line in the distance. As the students worked, Robert Trumbour, assistant professor in the College of Architecture, Design, and Construction Management, offered suggestions on how to properly view the space they occupied, while also offering insight into the architectural features of the historic area.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-BostonLab.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-3552" alt="web-BostonLab" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-BostonLab-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a></p>
<p>Wentworth students have long known the close proximity of famous Boston sites to campus, but thanks to a focus on hands-on, project-based learning at the school, they are able to use the city for real-world learning.</p>
<p>“There is really a focus on locations, and we’re looking more at experiential learning, as opposed to abstraction,” Trumbour explained. “We think by showing actual examples up close, we’re providing a more well-rounded learning experience.”</p>
<p>Last fall, the aforementioned class—Studio 1—enrolled 195 first-year students split into 13 different sections. Around a dozen students per group traveled with their professors to various Boston sites via the Orange and Green MBTA lines. Once a week, students and faculty met in Blount Auditorium to share their findings from the field. Classes continued this spring and included visits to the Museum of Fine Arts and the Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, among other destinations.<br />
“The site visits have really helped me understand certain concepts better,” said Allison Reynolds, ’18. “Having real-world examples really connects you to what you’re studying.”</p>
<p>For Glenn Wiggins, dean of the College of Architecture, Design, and Construction Management, the class allows students to explore “one of the greatest urban spaces in the United States” and take a hands-on approach to studying projects.<br />
“Compare this experience with that of students from schools that may be as close as 100 miles. At best, once a semester they board a bus, travel to Boston, spend an afternoon studying, and travel back,” said Wiggins. “The rest of the semester they study pictures, videos, drawings, and so forth. It’s not the same as living in the laboratory, and it directly impacts the character of a student’s education.”</p>
<p>–<em>Greg Abazorius</em></p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/FVKoapc75qs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/15/boston-as-a-lab/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/15/boston-as-a-lab/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>abazoriusg</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Honor Roll]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/15/honor-roll-2/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3589</id>
		<updated>2014-05-15T18:42:44Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-15T13:22:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Honor Roll" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Recent student, faculty, and staff awards and achievements]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/15/honor-roll-2/"><![CDATA[<p><b>FACULTY</b> Associate Professor of Architecture <b>Robert Cowherd</b> has been named to the board of directors for the Global Architecture History Teaching Collaborative (GAHTC). The group was created after a</p>
<div id="attachment_3592" style="width: 187px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-cowherd.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3592" alt="Robert Cowherd" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-cowherd-177x300.jpg" width="177" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Robert Cowherd</p></div>
<p>$1 million grant delivered by the Andrew W. Mellon Foundation to MIT’s School of Architecture and Planning. Aimed at expanding the consciousness and reach of global architectural history, GAHTC will support scholars working together to produce classroom materials that will allow teachers to cover topics otherwise inaccessible to them.   Professor <b>George Katsiaficas</b> of the College of Arts and Sciences published the book <i>Asia’s Unknown Uprisings: Vol. 2 People Power in the Philippines</i>. The work was published through Oakland: PM Press.   Associate Professor <b>James Lambrechts</b> of the College of Engineering and Technology was awarded the Presidential Citation by the Association of Environmental and Engineering Geologists. Lambrechts earned the achievement through his work as chairman of the Boston Society of Civil Engineers Editorial Board for the journal <i>Civil Engineering Practice</i>, through which he sponsored, guided, and produced a discourse on the geology of Boston.   <b>Marilyn Stern</b>, professor in the College of Arts and Sciences, presented at the National Popular Culture/American Culture Association Conference in Washington, D.C.  Stern’s presentation was entitled “Suzanne Collins World Without Triumph: The <i>Hunger Games</i> Trilogy and the Metaphors of War.” <b> </b> <b>STUDENTS</b> <b>Benjamin Franco, BSEE ’16</b>, recently received a scholarship as part of the IEEE Power and Energy Society Scholarship Plus Initiative. The scholarship recognizes undergraduate students who have declared a major in Electrical and Computer Engineering and are high achievers with strong GPAs who have committed themselves to distinctive extracurricular activities and to exploring the power and energy field.</p>
<div id="attachment_3593" style="width: 224px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-mallory_lindsey.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3593" alt="Mallory Hudak (right) and Lindsay Mehaylo " src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-mallory_lindsey-214x300.jpg" width="214" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Mallory Hudak (right) and Lindsay Mehaylo</p></div>
<p><b>Jacob Pfahl, BSA ’17</b>, was named a finalist in the December 2013 PINarchitecture competition. Pfahl focused on sound when answering the question, “What if a window didn’t let light transfer through it, and was instead used to transfer something else?” Pfahl designed a concrete dome with steel apertures of varying sizes along the exterior. Each size produces a different sound as the wind passes—the thinner ones creating a higher sound, and the wider ones a lower sound. Pfahl earned a top-nine finish in the international competition.   Wentworth’s <b>Mechanical Contractors Association student chapter</b> received the Mechanical Contracting Education and Research Foundation Chapter of Excellence Grant for the 2012-2013 school year. The $7,500 grant is awarded to honor chapters across the country that display exemplary performance throughout the year and to promote the further expansion of the chapter. Pictured are <b>Jessica Mendez, BCMT ’15; Wesley Tagget, BCMT ’14</b>; and <b>Logen Johnson, BELM ’14.</b>   Interior Design students <b>Mallory Hudak ’15</b> <b>and Lindsay Mehaylo ’15</b> were recently given a classroom assignment of hypothetically redesigning Wentworth’s Alumni Library. The two entered their respective designs into the Interior Design Career Day (IDCD) 2013 competition where they captured two of the top three spots. <b> </b> <b>STAFF</b> The Division of Student Affairs awarded Wentworth staff members for work that exemplifies the guiding principles of the division. Earning the Inspire Award were <b>Jennifer Cheng</b>, program coordinator, and <b>Jennifer Casavant</b>, associate director of housing and residential life; the Empower Award was given to <b>Heather Miller</b>, director of new student programs; the Innovate Award was bestowed upon <b>Steve Rossi</b>, assistant director of campus life; and the Collaboration Award was given to the Weekends@WIT committee.</p>
<div id="attachment_3594" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-collaborative_group_2.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-3594 " alt="Heather Miller, Jennifer Chang, Steve Rossi, and Jennifer Casavant" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-collaborative_group_2-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Heather Miller, Jennifer Chang, Steve Rossi, and Jennifer Casavant</p></div>
<p><b>Chris Haigh</b>, director of diversity programs, received the Access and Inclusion Award from the Massachusetts College Personnel Association.  The award serves as a way to recognize excellence in higher education, and recognize individuals who are best upholding the organization’s mantra of anti-discrimination.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/15/honor-roll-2/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/15/honor-roll-2/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cochranc</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Boston as a Lab]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/architecture-students-using-boston-as-a-lab/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3443</id>
		<updated>2014-05-15T17:45:22Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-14T14:31:02Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Featured WITNews" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Homepage-Feature-News" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Video" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="WITNews" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[New curriculum emphasizes location]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/architecture-students-using-boston-as-a-lab/"><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 14px; line-height: 1.5em;">ON A WEDNESDAY AFTERNOON LAST FALL, a group of first-year architecture students stood in the middle of Summer Street in Downtown Crossing, pencils and paper in hand, sketching their surroundings while trying to find the horizon line in the distance. As the students worked, Robert Trumbour, assistant professor in the College of Architecture, Design, and Construction Management, offered suggestions on how to properly view the space they occupied, while also offering insight into the architectural features of the historic area.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-BostonLab.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-3552" alt="web-BostonLab" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-BostonLab-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a></p>
<p>Wentworth students have long known the close proximity of famous Boston sites to campus, but thanks to a focus on hands-on, project-based learning at the school, they are able to use the city for real-world learning.</p>
<p>“There is really a focus on locations, and we’re looking more at experiential learning, as opposed to abstraction,” Trumbour explained. “We think by showing actual examples up close, we’re providing a more well-rounded learning experience.”</p>
<p>Last fall, the aforementioned class—Studio 1—enrolled 195 first-year students split into 13 different sections. Around a dozen students per group traveled with their professors to various Boston sites via the Orange and Green MBTA lines. Once a week, students and faculty met in Blount Auditorium to share their findings from the field. Classes continued this spring and included visits to the Museum of Fine Arts and the Isabella Stewart Gardner Museum, among other destinations.<br />
“The site visits have really helped me understand certain concepts better,” said Allison Reynolds, ’18. “Having real-world examples really connects you to what you’re studying.”</p>
<p>For Glenn Wiggins, dean of the College of Architecture, Design, and Construction Management, the class allows students to explore “one of the greatest urban spaces in the United States” and take a hands-on approach to studying projects.<br />
“Compare this experience with that of students from schools that may be as close as 100 miles. At best, once a semester they board a bus, travel to Boston, spend an afternoon studying, and travel back,” said Wiggins. “The rest of the semester they study pictures, videos, drawings, and so forth. It’s not the same as living in the laboratory, and it directly impacts the character of a student’s education.”</p>
<p>–<em>Greg Abazorius</em></p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/FVKoapc75qs?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/architecture-students-using-boston-as-a-lab/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/architecture-students-using-boston-as-a-lab/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cochranc</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Sitting Pretty]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/sitting-pretty/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3486</id>
		<updated>2014-05-15T13:32:59Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-14T13:34:21Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Portfolio" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Victor Zhu '15 found inspiration for his stool project in an unlikely spot]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/sitting-pretty/"><![CDATA[<p>When Victor Zhu ’15 started to design a studio stool for an industrial design assignment last fall, inspiration came from an unlikely source.</p>
<p>“In terms of form and color, I chose industrial assembly robots as the basis of my inspiration,” explains Zhu. Favorite artists, including Scott Robertson and Thomas Pringle, also provided creative spark.</p>
<p>With comfort and portability atop his priority list, Zhu spent six weeks refining his design in the studio. The final product, which includes bolt footrests, an angled square seatpan, and a bright orange finish, was a showstopper at the Industrial Design Junior Studio Project Presentation in December.</p>
<p><em>–Caleb Cochran</em></p>
<p style="text-align: center"><a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web2-Portfolio_Zhu1-2.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-3522" alt="web2-Portfolio_Zhu1-(2)" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web2-Portfolio_Zhu1-2-231x300.jpg" width="231" height="300" /></a><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-3523" alt="web3-StoolRendering" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web3-StoolRendering-231x300.jpg" width="231" height="300" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/sitting-pretty/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/sitting-pretty/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cochranc</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[We Remember: Ted Hood, BC &#8217;50]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/we-remember-ted-hood-bc-50/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3488</id>
		<updated>2014-05-15T17:51:27Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-14T13:33:52Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Uncategorized" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Renowned sailor and  sailmaker]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/we-remember-ted-hood-bc-50/"><![CDATA[<p>Frederick Emmart “Ted” Hood, BC ’50, renowned sailmaker and founder of Hood Sail, died on June 28, 2013. He was 86.</p>
<p>Hood was known as unique in seafaring circles for his ability to excel not only as a sailor, but also as a designer and builder of both yachts and sails. His company, Hood Sailmakers, was the world’s largest manufacturer of sails during the 1960s and 70s, and he would count such magnates as Ted Turner as friends during his life on the seas.</p>
<p>“Ted was a standout graduate and an innovative pioneer in his industry—he is the epitome of Wentworth’s innovation and entrepreneurship spirit,” said Wentworth President Zorica Pantić. “Ted led by example and became one of the most influential and revered names in the boating world. From his success here at Wentworth to his achievements on the water and in the business world, Ted was one of a kind and will be greatly missed.”<a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-TedHood.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-3516" alt="Ted Hood" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-TedHood-300x276.jpg" width="300" height="276" /></a></p>
<p>A native of Marblehead, Mass., Hood built his first boat at the age of 13, triggering a lifelong passion. He originally attended New England College in New Hampshire before transferring to Wentworth to study building construction. After serving in the U.S. Navy during World War II, Hood graduated from Wentworth and founded Hood Sailmakers in 1955. Hood was the first sail maker to weave his own sail, and is credited with early designs for grooved head stays and other breakthroughs.</p>
<p>When Hood Sailmakers grew to a worldwide level, Hood found an unprecedented string of success as his company supplied the sails to every one of the America’s Cup winners between 1958 and 1977. Hood was also known to take to the water himself, winning the Mallory Cup in 1956, the Newport-to-Bermuda race in 1968, and the Marblehead-to-Halifax race in both 1961 and 1971. It was during Hood’s tenure as a member of the New York Yacht Club, though, that he found the most success, winning the 1974 America’s Cup by guiding his boat, Courageous, to a 4-0 triumph over Australia. Ted Turner would later skipper the Courageous in the 1977 America’s Cup race.</p>
<p>Hood would later turn his attention away from sail-making and onto the design and construction of boats, specifically sailboats and yachts. Hood sold his business in 1999, but remained active in design work helping to create a series of catamarans and heavy offshore yachts. In 2006, the “serious-minded, better than average student” (as he was described in the 1950 Wentworth yearbook) released his autobiography,<em> Ted Hood: </em><em>Through Hand and Eye</em>, published through Mystic Seaport. He is a member of the America’s Cup Hall of Fame, as well as the National Sailing Hall of Fame. Hood is survived by his wife Susan; sons Ted, Richard, and Robert; daughter Nancy; and eight grandchildren.</p>
<p><em>—Greg Abazorius</em></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/we-remember-ted-hood-bc-50/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/we-remember-ted-hood-bc-50/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cochranc</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Profiles in Giving: Sam Altschuler, Hon. &#8217;08]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/profiles-in-giving-sam-altschuler-hon-08/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3483</id>
		<updated>2014-05-15T13:39:27Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-14T13:33:24Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Alumni News" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="WITNews" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[$1 million gift helps fund new computer center]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/profiles-in-giving-sam-altschuler-hon-08/"><![CDATA[<p>About two years ago, when Sam Altschuler, Hon. ’08, began considering a gift to assist Wentworth’s Department of Computer Science and Networking, he made it clear that he wanted to think big. Already a supporter of the department through the funding of scholarships, Altschuler was interested in making an even broader impact on the lives of Wentworth students.</p>
<p>The result is a state-of-the-art classroom and networking laboratory—the Altschuler Computer Center—funded in large part by a $1 million gift from Altschuler and his wife, Nancy.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-Altschuler.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-3525" alt="Sam Altschuler" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-Altschuler-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a>“When we started to talk about renovating a major new space and adding classroom space, we became very excited about how that’s going to improve the chances for students in their careers,” Altschuler says. A 50-year veteran of the electronics industry, Altschuler founded Wilmington, Mass.-based Altron Incorporated, a leading manufacturer of electronics equipment—primarily surface-mount assemblies, custom-designed backplanes, and circuit boards—in 1970. He retired in 1999. The Altschulers’ son, Jeff, is a 1984 graduate (Manufacturing Engineering Technology) and founder of New Hampshire-based electronics manufacturing company Altronics. Grandson David is a current Wentworth student (Computer Networking) who will benefit directly when he works in the center this summer.</p>
<p>“In order to have a successful career in the high-tech industry, it’s extremely important to have a solid education as provided here at Wentworth,” Sam Altschuler says. “David has really benefitted from the co-op experience. Wentworth students are ready to hit the ground running and do real work rather than going through a transition period from school to work. As a result, Wentworth students are prized employees for many companies in the United States.”</p>
<p>Thanks to Altschuler family’s generosity, Wentworth students now have a computer networking facility that ranks among the very best in the country.</p>
<p><em>—Caleb Cochran</em></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/profiles-in-giving-sam-altschuler-hon-08/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/profiles-in-giving-sam-altschuler-hon-08/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cochranc</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Bottle Bill]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/bottle-bill/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3478</id>
		<updated>2014-05-14T13:39:42Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-14T13:33:12Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Features" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For Bill Eaton, BCMT '90, success is a package deal]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/bottle-bill/"><![CDATA[<p>When you pop the top and take a sip of your favorite soft drink, how much time do you spend thinking about the bottle you’re holding? Do you consider the weight of the container? The way it feels in your hand? The designs integrated into the plastic and what they might signify? What about the height of the cap?</p>
<p>For Bill Eaton, BCMT ’90, director of R&amp;D packaging engineering and innovation in the Global Beverages Group at PepsiCo, these are just a few of the things he examines when designing and developing a new polyethylene terephthalate (PET) bottle for Pepsi, Mountain Dew, and the many varieties of these well-known drinks. In addition to the 20-ounce PET bottles that are the top focus for many beverage manufacturers, Eaton oversees anything that Pepsi beverage products are “put in, shipped in, and displayed in,” as he puts it.</p>
<p>An expert with more than 20 years of beverage and consumer goods packaging development experience, Eaton got into the packaging field more or less by chance. After graduating from <a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web_DSC2418.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-3528" alt="web_DSC2418" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web_DSC2418-214x300.jpg" width="214" height="300" /></a>Wentworth, the construction management major entered a bleak job market in the early 1990s. He nearly accepted a project management position in Kuwait before starting his own business remodeling kitchens and bathrooms in his native Connecticut. A client happened to be a human resources officer at Cadbury Schweppes.</p>
<p>“She mentioned a job in their packaging lab,” Eaton says. “She said, ‘it’s kind of technical—you might be interested.” At his interview, Eaton was introduced to workers who were measuring and testing bottles and thinking, “This is probably not for me.” But he was quickly offered a position with the company with the possibility of long-term growth opportunities. He took it.</p>
<p><strong>‘MINUTE’ MAN</strong><br />
“One of the first projects I worked on was called Mott’s in a Minute,” Eaton recalls. “It was a shelf-stable juice concentrate in a can—the first of its kind. We spent a lot of time in our pilot plant running these cans and testing them. You have to ‘hot-fill’ the can with 185-degree juice concentrate, and then cool it down, and the can has to perform in different ways. I learned how to tear down and rebuild the can-seamer, which puts the top on the can. All that technical detail was really interesting to me.”</p>
<p>After 15 years with Cadbury Schweppes, Eaton moved to Pepsico in 2007. His first project was one that had challenged colleagues for years—designing a one-gallon PET bottle for Lipton tea with an integrated snap-on handle.</p>
<p>“My boss said, ‘I know you can do it. Go figure it out,’” Eaton says. “I used a lot of the knowledge I retained from school to design the structural elements that were hidden inside the handle. I recalled bridge theory to design the handle so it wouldn’t bend, and worked with designers to integrate the handle design.” The end product—including the handle and cap—was lighter than the competition’s bottle alone. It was a hit.</p>
<p><strong>CREATING CONNECTION</strong><br />
Today, Eaton leads a group that works with marketing teams and design agencies to take bottles and other packaging innovations from concept to development. His latest project involved moving Pepsi—which had been in the same bottle for nearly 16 years—and other core brands into new bottle designs. Pepsi and Mountain Dew each received a unique design, while a third bottle was designed for all other brands.</p>
<p>After an eight-month period in which Eaton and his team completed design, development, validation, and production trials of more than 750,000 bottles, the new designs were approved, triggering a two-year conversion process to the new bottles.</p>
<p>“It’s really about keeping the brand fresh and connected with the consumer,” Eaton says. The latest 20-ounce Mountain Dew bottle, he explains, “is kind of edgy. It fits with the consumer who drinks Mountain Dew—the gamer, the skateboarder. The package has design elements that specifically point out those attributes, and consumers really pick up on them.”</p>
<p>The research and testing involved in the production of a typical PET bottle today is staggering. Eaton estimates that the Mountain Dew bottle went through 70 to 80 design revisions, in addition to 10 to 15 computer-model finite element analyses (FEAs) to gauge how the bottle would react under pressure when filled. A bottle sold in India, for example, requires a slightly different design from bottles sold in the U.S. and Europe to accommodate high temperatures that can flatten some of the raised “grip features” of the bottle.</p>
<p>Looking toward the future of packaging innovation, Eaton mentions two keys: materials and speed. When he first started in the industry, blow molders—machines that produce hollow plastic objects—ran at speeds of 12,000 to 15,000 bottles per hour. Today, 50,000 bottles per hour is becoming the standard.</p>
<p>“Every year there is something new in equipment or technology that allows you to do something unique from a labeling or bottling perspective,” he says. “On the packaging side, materials development is going to be the game-changer. The challenge in any industry is marrying up the new innovation with something that fits your cost structure that you can sell and that consumers want. That’s what makes this job really cool and interesting.”</p>
<p><em>-Caleb Cochran</em></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/bottle-bill/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/bottle-bill/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cochranc</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[High-Tech Highway]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/high-tech-highway/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3476</id>
		<updated>2014-05-14T13:40:33Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-14T13:32:56Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Features" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Revamped academic corridor nears completion]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/high-tech-highway/"><![CDATA[<p>UNTIL RECENTLY, walking through the ground-floor corridor of Wentworth Hall was almost like taking a step back in time. Pedestrians were greeted by a painted concrete floor, high-school style lockers, and in some cases, lab equipment that dated to the middle of last century.</p>
<p>Today, construction is underway on two major renovations that will transform this hallway into a modern thoroughfare featuring state-of-the-art laboratories and classrooms. The Altschuler Computer Center will open this spring, and new strength of materials, nanotechnology, and materials science laboratories will be completed over the summer. The architect for the renovations is Allegro. Columbia is the construction management firm.</p>
<p>Along with the Manufacturing Center, completed in 2011, these new projects complete Wentworth’s “High-Tech Highway,” a central artery through Williston, Wentworth, and Dobbs Halls.</p>
<p>“It’s going to be a showpiece,” says David Wahlstrom, AET ’80, vice president of business. “These updates bring everything up to today’s standards.”</p>
<p>Samuel Altschuler, Hon. ’08—father of Jeff Altschuler, MET ’84, and grandfather of current computer networking student David Altschuler—was eager to provide an environment that would help Wentworth students gain a clear advantage as they prepare to enter the work force. Industry-standard networking equipment, servers, and data-storage equipment will allow students to practice tackling the same issues faced by giants of the technology world.</p>
<p>“We’re very enthusiastic about what will be one of the finest networking laboratories in the United States,” says Altschuler, who, with his wife Nancy, donated $1 million toward the new facility. “This computer center will be an important part of improving the educational opportunities for students in the computer networking area.”</p>
<div id="attachment_3532" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-Altschuler-classroom-hallway.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3532" alt="A rendering of a classroom area in the Altschuler Center" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-Altschuler-classroom-hallway-300x168.jpg" width="300" height="168" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A rendering of a classroom area in the Altschuler Computer Center</p></div>
<p>“Amazon, Facebook, and Google all run data centers with hundreds of thousands of servers, and they spend a lot of time architecting these systems to make sure they function,” explains Charlie Wiseman, assistant professor of computer science and computer networking, who worked closely with the Altschulers and others on the project. “Now our students can build their own miniature versions of these systems. If you look at other programs around the country, the lab we’re going to have will enable us to teach things to undergraduates that nobody teaches.”</p>
<p>Down the hall, construction is in progress on the multi-phase lab project. Funded in part by a $1 million gift from the Gelfand Family Charitable Trust, led by Wentworth friends and supporters Mark Gelfand and Cynthia Calabrese, the space includes a new strength of materials lab—which will triple the size of the current lab—as well as complete overhauls of the materials science and nanotechnology labs.</p>
<p>“Having a gift like this moves us from the 1960s to today,” says Michael Jackson, chair of the Department of Mechanical Engineering and Technology. “The principles haven’t changes, but the equipment changes, and we have to keep up with it.”</p>
<p>In the strength of materials lab, new equipment tests tensile strength, torsion, structural behavior, and more on smaller, more streamlined packages that use modern software. In some cases, giant freestanding machines are being replaced with tabletop models.</p>
<p>“Bringing in the modern equipment and the modern technology is incredible for our students,” Jackson adds. “I think it motivates them to know that we are trying to make them better at what they’re going to be doing out in the real world.”</p>
<p>-<em>Caleb Cochran</em></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/high-tech-highway/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/high-tech-highway/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cochranc</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Making the Grade Abroad]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/making-the-grade-abroad/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3472</id>
		<updated>2014-05-14T13:41:01Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-14T13:32:42Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Features" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Students making the most of overseas opportunities]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/making-the-grade-abroad/"><![CDATA[<p>FOR MORE THAN A DECADE, Wentworth architecture students have traded Boston for Berlin for a semester. Each year, nearly 100 Wentworth students travel to the German capital for a full semester of design studio, two architecture electives, and one humanities elective—the same curriculum as their peers in Boston. Students also travel elsewhere in Europe to visit sites that relate to their work. Previous trips have included Prague, Rome, Venice, and Hamburg.</p>
<div id="attachment_3534" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-Holland-Bauhaus_higher-res.jpg"><img class="size-medium wp-image-3534" alt="Wentworth students pose outside of the site of the former Bauhaus art school in Germany" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web-Holland-Bauhaus_higher-res-300x199.jpg" width="300" height="199" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Wentworth students pose outside of the site of the former Bauhaus art school in Germany</p></div>
<p>Wentworth’s first architecture study-abroad programs were hatched decades ago. Travel concerns after September 11, 2001, led to a wane in student interest, but the Berlin semester-abroad program was re-launched in 2002.</p>
<p>“Many [Wentworth students] who travel to Berlin have never left the U.S., and when they go home, they return with broader horizons,” says program director Rolf Backmann.</p>
<p>“The three-month program gave me a chance to live what I had previously only seen in slide presentations during lecture class,” says Alex Cabral, BSA ’10, MARC ’11. “It provided energy to think bigger, produce better and work harder.”</p>
<p>The Berlin program has proven a massive success for Wentworth, leading to the development of several other international initiatives, including an option for architecture students to study in Montpellier, France, as well a program for industrial design and interior design students in Berlin. This summer, the Institute plans to launch a program for construction management students, also in Berlin.</p>
<p>Susan Paris, associate provost for academic operations, and other administrators are speaking with the various colleges about adding more study-abroad options. Paris notes that when she came to Wentworth four years ago, the Institute had the lowest enrollment of study-abroad students in the Colleges of the Fenway; today Wentworth boasts the highest.</p>
<p>“[The engineering program] has had the most recent growth,” she says, “and they have built programs to specifically create room for study abroad within the curriculum.”</p>
<p>Fred Driscoll, dean of the College of Engineering and Technology, says that there has always been a strong desire among his students to study internationally, but that course requirements have made it difficult for students to leave campus. Today, students in the interdisciplinary engineering program have some leeway in regard to how and when they complete their major course work. Engineering students have already taken classes in Kingston University in London and at Lucerne University of Applied Sciences in Switzerland.</p>
<p>“For our graduates to be the next generation of leaders, supervisors, and project managers—in global companies—they really need the international experience,” says Driscoll. “And it allows students from different majors and different countries to develop a mindset for collaboration.”</p>
<p>-<em>Greg Abazorius</em></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/making-the-grade-abroad/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/making-the-grade-abroad/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cochranc</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[5 Questions for Russ Pinizzotto]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/5-questions-for-russ-pinizzotto/" />
		<id>http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/?p=3456</id>
		<updated>2014-05-15T15:04:05Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-14T13:32:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="5 Questions" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Spring 2014" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="Video" /><category scheme="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine" term="WITNews" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The senior VP for Academic Affairs and provost discusses EPIC Learning, how Wentworth has changed, and more]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/5-questions-for-russ-pinizzotto/"><![CDATA[<p>Russ Pinizzotto arrived at Wentworth in 2009 with big ideas and energy to match. He recently sat down with <i>WIT </i>to reflect on five years of change in academics at the Institute.</p>
<p><b>1. In an article that appeared in the Spring 2009 issue of <i>Wentworth </i>magazine shortly after you were hired, you called yourself a “change agent.” What did you mean by that?<br />
</b>A change agent to me means someone who comes in, sees what’s going on, and then sees where the future might be and makes changes to enable the institution to achieve those goals. I think anyone who is a change agent sees what could be, instead of what is.</p>
<p><b>2. How has Wentworth changed over the past five years?<br />
</b>We’ve changed just about everything. When it comes to academic programs, we’ve changed the structure—we now have colleges and departments. We’ve made the College of Professional and Continuing Education more of its own independent operation. We’ve started online programs and added graduate programs. We now graduate close to 125 master’s students a year, and that number will be growing. We’ve increased the average SAT scores of the incoming class by almost 50 points, which is unbelievable. We’ve started to get national rankings as an engineering school. When people ask what has changed, it’s really been almost everything, as far as academics are concerned.</p>
<p><b>3. How has your experience as a professor influenced your work as a provost?<br />
</b>I think it’s very, very important to understand your students. At many institutions, once you get to a certain level, you don’t teach anymore, and I think you lose contact with the students. The students as they are now are not the students as they were 20 years ago. So if I had not been in a classroom watching these changes in student expectations, behaviors, and preparation, it would all be second-hand. I’m an experimental scientist, not a theoretician, so to me, talking about what the students are like is nothing like being in a classroom and teaching. I still teach every year, because I think it’s important to have direct contact with the students.</p>
<p><b>4. What is “EPIC learning?”<a href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web2-Pinizzotto-8713.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-3515" alt="Russ Pinizzotto" src="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/files/2014/05/web2-Pinizzotto-8713-199x300.jpg" width="199" height="300" /></a><br />
</b>EPIC [<b>E</b>xternally collaborative, <b>P</b>roject-based, <b>I</b>nterdisciplinary <b>C</b>urricula for learning] really characterizes a lot of things. We want our students to have experience in the real world. We want them to work on projects that are meaningful, not just theoretical, so we stay true to the basic values of the institution. Interdisciplinary work is something they’re going to have to do when they get out into the workplace. You work in interdisciplinary teams—you don’t work by yourself, in general. We want to make sure our curricula reflect that.</p>
<p><b>5. You’re a musician (vibraphone and drums), an astronomy buff, and a sailor. If you were forced to choose just one of these pursuits, which would it be?<br />
</b>This is a really tough question. I don’t know how I would give up one of these things. If I could only do one, it’s a close call between music and astronomy. My mother says that before I was a year old, I used to sit on the back step on my father’s lap pointing up at the sky saying, “What’s that?” And I started playing music when I was four years old. I guess I would have to choose music over astronomy, but that’s tough. And giving up the sailboat—I don’t know about that, either!</p>
<p>&#8211;<i>Caleb Cochran</i></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><iframe width="500" height="281" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/HHavIJt3ZGw?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/5-questions-for-russ-pinizzotto/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.wit.edu/magazine/2014/05/14/5-questions-for-russ-pinizzotto/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
