<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Giving to Fielding: Stock Donations, Real Estate Donations, Nonprofit Donations</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-07T22:39:19Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu" />
	<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.8.3">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/current-drive/403/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=403</id>
		<updated>2014-06-26T17:00:41Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-25T22:54:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="Current Drive" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re raising donations to rebuild scholarship funds in our schools.

You can help …
<ul>
	<li>Provide access</li>
	<li>Advance academic and professional goals</li>
	<li>Change lives</li>
</ul>
Scholarships make it possible for many of our students to attend Fielding.

<a title="Make a gift today" href="https://www.applyweb.com/public/contribute?s=FIELDOGF" target="">Make a gift today</a> and make a difference for our students.
Thank you!]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/current-drive/403/"><![CDATA[]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/current-drive/403/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/current-drive/403/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Karlene Ferron &#8211; ELC Doctoral Student and Recipient of the Fielding Graduate University Scholarship]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/gifts-make-a-difference/karlene-ferron-elc-doctoral-student-and-recipient-of-the-fielding-graduate-university-scholarship/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=395</id>
		<updated>2014-06-25T23:05:09Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-23T20:21:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="Gifts make a difference" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<i>“Thank you Fielding donors for supporting my academic progress and affirming my important appointment to serve those in need.”</i><a href="http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=395"> Karlene Ferron, ELC doctoral student and scholarship recipient. Read more...</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/gifts-make-a-difference/karlene-ferron-elc-doctoral-student-and-recipient-of-the-fielding-graduate-university-scholarship/"><![CDATA[<p>My dissertation aims to improve support for frontline workers who help vulnerable populations of youth. To achieve <a href="http://giving.fielding.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Karlene-Ferron_1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-405" alt="Karlene Ferron_1" src="http://giving.fielding.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Karlene-Ferron_1.jpg" width="120" height="150" /></a>this goal, I am working collaboratively in an appreciative inquiry model to help frontline workers become more effective in their profession. I have conducted interviews to inquire about the kinds of supports they think improve their efforts to help troubled youth. I also hope to understand the strategies frontline workers use to sustain themselves and what supports they need to provide optimum care to their clients. I am using auto ethnography as a secondary method to relate my personal journey to my passion for assisting troubled youth.</p>
<p>A Fielding scholarship is affirming of my efforts towards improving the work frontline workers do for these young people. It is also a testament to my intention to tell a liberating story about my life and the virtues of resilience. Being a recipient of a Fielding Graduate University Scholarship is a powerful reminder that my vision to help improve the lives of these vulnerable and important individuals is also significant to others. <strong>Thank you Fielding donors for supporting my academic progress and affirming my important appointment to serve those in need.</strong></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/gifts-make-a-difference/karlene-ferron-elc-doctoral-student-and-recipient-of-the-fielding-graduate-university-scholarship/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/gifts-make-a-difference/karlene-ferron-elc-doctoral-student-and-recipient-of-the-fielding-graduate-university-scholarship/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Margaret Rudolf Endowed Scholarship Created]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/margaret-rudolf-endowed-scholarship-created/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=388</id>
		<updated>2014-06-24T22:03:15Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-27T23:59:52Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alumna Margaret Rudolf and her husband Dana Vanier, PhD, have established an endowed scholarship for international students at Fielding. The Margaret Rudolf International Scholarship Endowment Fund is created in honor of Margaret’s beloved grandfather Victor, “who always encouraged learning and intellectual development,” she said. Rudolf is a 2009 graduate of the doctoral program in the [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/margaret-rudolf-endowed-scholarship-created/"><![CDATA[<p>Alumna Margaret Rudolf and her husband Dana Vanier, PhD, have established an endowed scholarship for international students at Fielding. The Margaret Rudolf International Scholarship Endowment Fund is created in honor of Margaret’s beloved grandfather Victor, “who always encouraged learning and intellectual development,” she said. Rudolf is a 2009 graduate of the doctoral program in the School of Human &amp; Organizational Development.</p>
<p>The scholarships will be awarded to international Fielding students who reside outside of North America. Rudolf is a resident of British Columbia, Canada, and was a co-chair of the university’s Internationalization Task Force.</p>
<p>The Margaret Rudolf International Scholarship will support Fielding’s international growth and will, according to Rudolf’s goals, assist international students in ways that are most needed.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/margaret-rudolf-endowed-scholarship-created/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/margaret-rudolf-endowed-scholarship-created/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[LGBTQ/Allies Canadian Scholarship is second fund for HOD grad]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/lgbtqallies-canadian-scholarship-is-second-fund-for-hod-grad/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=389</id>
		<updated>2014-03-31T18:59:32Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-27T23:45:37Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just one year after alumna Laura (Lolly) de Jonge and her husband Mike established the Laura and Mike de Jonge Scholarship Fund, the couple has created another targeted fund for Fielding students: the LGBTQ/Allies Canadian Scholarship. Lolly is a 2012 graduate of the Human &#38; Organizational Development doctoral program. “The award is intended to recognize [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/lgbtqallies-canadian-scholarship-is-second-fund-for-hod-grad/"><![CDATA[<p>Just one year after alumna Laura (Lolly) de Jonge and her husband Mike established the Laura and Mike de Jonge Scholarship Fund, the couple has created another targeted fund for Fielding students: the LGBTQ/Allies Canadian Scholarship. Lolly is a 2012 graduate of the Human &amp; Organizational Development doctoral program.</p>
<p>“The award is intended to recognize the growing importance of research on LGBTQ/ Allies issues and offers concrete support and encouragement to emerging scholars in this field,” Lolly said.  The award will be given for research that addresses issues related to the lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer community and their allies, and is open to anyone conducting research involving LGBTQ/allies participants or studying issues affecting LGBTQ/allies and communities.</p>
<p>This will be an annual award to a continuing Canadian student in support of meritorious work and / or their academic progress at Fielding. The de Jonge LGBTQ / Allies Canadian Scholarship Fund is endowed at The Winnipeg Foundation.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/lgbtqallies-canadian-scholarship-is-second-fund-for-hod-grad/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/lgbtqallies-canadian-scholarship-is-second-fund-for-hod-grad/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Major SB Foundation grant for Nonprofit Leadership scholarships]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/major-sb-foundation-grant-for-nonprofit-leadership-scholarships/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=390</id>
		<updated>2014-03-27T23:24:38Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-27T23:24:38Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Santa Barbara Foundation has provided a grant of $35,000 to Fielding Graduate University. The grant provides scholarships to students in the first cohort of Fielding’s new Nonprofit Leadership Certificate Program. The Santa Barbara Foundation seeks to facilitate the building of philanthropy and strengthen the nonprofit sector within the Santa Barbara community.  It has identified [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/major-sb-foundation-grant-for-nonprofit-leadership-scholarships/"><![CDATA[<p>The Santa Barbara Foundation has provided a grant of $35,000 to Fielding Graduate University. The grant provides scholarships to students in the first cohort of Fielding’s new Nonprofit Leadership Certificate Program.</p>
<p>The Santa Barbara Foundation seeks to facilitate the building of philanthropy and strengthen the nonprofit sector within the Santa Barbara community.  It has identified Fielding&#8217;s Nonprofit Leadership Certificate as a significant opportunity to further this mission.</p>
<p>The scholarship is intended to create greater access to Fielding&#8217;s Nonprofit Leadership Certificate program for individuals working in the nonprofit sector.  Through practical applications and a project-driven curriculum, the program focuses on board and executive leadership, strategic planning, fundraising, talent management, evaluation, and marketing—skills that will create impact<strong> </strong>in nonprofit organizations.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/major-sb-foundation-grant-for-nonprofit-leadership-scholarships/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/major-sb-foundation-grant-for-nonprofit-leadership-scholarships/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Hector De Jesus &#8211; Scholarship Winner and ELC Doctoral Student]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/gifts-make-a-difference/hector-de-jesus-scholarship-recipient/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=381</id>
		<updated>2014-03-18T20:50:51Z</updated>
		<published>2014-03-18T19:27:16Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="Gifts make a difference" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[<i>“With hard work, and the education and support I receive from Fielding, I hope to make a positive change in my community, challenge ‘the system,’ and ...”</i><a href="http://giving.fielding.edu/gifts-make-a-difference/hector-de-jesus-scholarship-recipient/"> Scholarship recipient Hector De Jesus is investigating lack of recidivism among former inmates.</a>]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/gifts-make-a-difference/hector-de-jesus-scholarship-recipient/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://giving.fielding.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Hector-deJesus.jpg"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-382" title="Hector De Jesus" alt="Hector De Jesus" src="http://giving.fielding.edu/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/Hector-deJesus.jpg" width="120" height="150" /></a></p>
<p>Hector De Jesus is investigating novel approaches to understanding recidivism.  “The aim of my dissertation research is to determine, through interviews with successful former inmates and related data sources, what they say accounts for their lack of recidivism,” he explains. “The goal is to identify the factors that are associated with successful return to society and use the study results to influence the practices of advocates and professionals like myself who work with ex-offenders seeking to reduce, if not eliminate, the terror and tragedy of recidivism.”</p>
<p>De Jesus is currently a program coordinator for a non-profit organization that provides behavioral health services for adults, children and families. “Pursuing a doctoral degree at 47 years old was not an easy decision to make,” de Jesus says. “However, having reached a level of conscientiousness and maturity, and embracing my own personal struggles in life as learning lessons, I strongly believe that it was by far the best decision I have made. I anticipate that with hard work, my continued pursuit of a brighter future, coupled with the education and support I receive from Fielding Graduate University, I will be able to effectively make a positive change in my community, challenge ‘the system’, and perhaps inspire others. <b>I want to thank Fielding donors for making these scholarships possible and investing in my future.</b>”</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/gifts-make-a-difference/hector-de-jesus-scholarship-recipient/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/gifts-make-a-difference/hector-de-jesus-scholarship-recipient/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/current-drive/125/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=125</id>
		<updated>2013-07-08T15:49:55Z</updated>
		<published>2013-07-08T15:49:05Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="Current Drive" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Board of Trustees re-named its scholarship to The Michael Goldstein Endowed Board Scholarship  in honor of Immediate Past Chair Goldstein and his many contributions to Fielding.  ]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/current-drive/125/"><![CDATA[<p>The Board of Trustees re-named its scholarship to The Michael Goldstein Endowed Board Scholarship  in honor of Immediate Past Chair Goldstein and his many contributions to Fielding.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/current-drive/125/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/current-drive/125/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Gary Wagenheim Endows International Scholarship]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/gary-wagenheim-endows-international-scholarship/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=122</id>
		<updated>2013-07-03T18:32:47Z</updated>
		<published>2013-07-03T18:24:06Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Board member and HOD alumnus Gary Wagenheim has endowed a new scholarship to support international students attending Fielding. His generous lead pledge creates the endowment which will provide interest income for the annual scholarship for years into the future. The Wagenheim Endowed Scholarship for International Students is available to qualifying master’s and doctoral students from [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/gary-wagenheim-endows-international-scholarship/"><![CDATA[<p>Board member and HOD alumnus Gary Wagenheim has endowed a new scholarship to support international students attending Fielding. His generous lead pledge creates the endowment which will provide interest income for the annual scholarship for years into the future.</p>
<p>The Wagenheim Endowed Scholarship for International Students is available to qualifying master’s and doctoral students from countries outside the United States, whether they are continuing or just entering Fielding.</p>
<p>The scholarship will aid Fielding’s internationalization efforts and expand the university’s global community of scholar-practitioners. Nearly 10% of Fielding students are from countries outside of the US, the majority from Canada and as many as 25 other countries.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/gary-wagenheim-endows-international-scholarship/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/gary-wagenheim-endows-international-scholarship/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Meyers Human Rights Scholarship Established]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/meyers-human-rights-scholarship-established/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=121</id>
		<updated>2013-07-03T18:33:09Z</updated>
		<published>2013-07-03T18:21:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fielding President Richard Meyers and his wife Yakko have established an endowment for scholarships dedicated to global human rights.  The Meyers Human Rights Scholarship Fund will support students who have personally experienced hardship, or whose family has experienced hardship, resulting from human rights violations, yet continue to grow and flourish as a Fielding Graduate University [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/meyers-human-rights-scholarship-established/"><![CDATA[<p>Fielding President Richard Meyers and his wife Yakko have established an endowment for scholarships dedicated to global human rights.  The Meyers Human Rights Scholarship Fund will support students who have personally experienced hardship, or whose family has experienced hardship, resulting from human rights violations, yet continue to grow and flourish as a Fielding Graduate University student.</p>
<p>President Meyers, who will retire from Fielding at the end of 2013, said of the fund, “It is important to Yakko and I that our legacy at Fielding reflect the values we hold close, including our concern for human rights.”</p>
<p>The fund may also support entrepreneurial ventures that support the university’s mission in the areas of human rights and social justice.  Scholarship awards may be made to one student annually. The first award is expected to be made in the fall 2013 term.</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/meyers-human-rights-scholarship-established/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/meyers-human-rights-scholarship-established/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>cbillings</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Scholarship Created in Memory of Charlie and Edie Seashore]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/scholarship-created-in-memory-of-charlie-and-edie-seashore/" />
		<id>http://giving.fielding.edu/?p=120</id>
		<updated>2013-07-03T18:24:50Z</updated>
		<published>2013-07-03T18:21:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://giving.fielding.edu" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The passing of beloved faculty member Charlie Seashore, and soon after the passing of his equally esteemed wife Edie, created a spontaneous drive to fund a scholarship in their name. The Charlie and Edie Seashore Scholarship was established in their memory in the spring of 2013 through donations from students, alumni, faculty, and staff. The [&#8230;]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/scholarship-created-in-memory-of-charlie-and-edie-seashore/"><![CDATA[<p>The passing of beloved faculty member Charlie Seashore, and soon after the passing of his equally esteemed wife Edie, created a spontaneous drive to fund a scholarship in their name. The Charlie and Edie Seashore Scholarship was established in their memory in the spring of 2013 through donations from students, alumni, faculty, and staff. The new scholarship will support students in the School of Human &amp; Organizational Development, where Charlie was faculty for 28 years.</p>
<p>The much loved, admired, and respected Edie Seashore has been called the most significant woman in the field of organizational development. Charlie’s professional distinctions in the field were exceptional and numerous, and he was a sought-after and beloved mentor to his students at Fielding. Together, Edie and Charlie touched many people with their warmth, sense of humor, and ability to create community wherever they went. Edie and Charlie will forever be a treasured part of Fielding Graduate University and its history.</p>
<p>Gifts to the Charlie and Edie Seashore Scholarship insure that their legacy will continue to reach Fielding students for years to come.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/scholarship-created-in-memory-of-charlie-and-edie-seashore/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://giving.fielding.edu/news/scholarship-created-in-memory-of-charlie-and-edie-seashore/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>

<!-- Performance optimized by W3 Total Cache. Learn more: http://www.w3-edge.com/wordpress-plugins/

Page Caching using disk: enhanced

 Served from: giving.fielding.edu @ 2014-07-21 17:40:16 by W3 Total Cache -->