<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en"
  xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Messiah College Homepage Features</title>
	<subtitle type="text">An archive of feature stories from Messiah\&#039;s homepage</subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-21T14:17:50Z</updated>
	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="2.9.1">WordPress</generator>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" />
	<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/feed/atom/" />

			<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alumna follows passion for language overseas to teach English in South Korea]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/07/21/abby_long/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1221</id>
		<updated>2014-07-21T14:17:50Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-21T14:17:50Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="International experience" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[For Abby Long ’12, following her dreams meant going far – all the way from Waynesboro, Pa., to Deokso, South Korea.
Long, who graduated with a degree in English, started learning Korean as a hobby after graduation, simply because she had an interest in Korean pop culture. During the same period, she took an online course [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/07/21/abby_long/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1222" style="margin: 5px" title="Abby Long" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/07/Abby_Long.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="171" />For Abby Long ’12, following her dreams meant going far – all the way from Waynesboro, Pa., to Deokso, South Korea.</p>
<p>Long, who graduated with a degree in English, started learning Korean as a hobby after graduation, simply because she had an interest in Korean pop culture. During the same period, she took an online course to earn Teaching English as a Foreign Language (TEFL) certification.</p>
<p>“I realized I could learn Korean and teach English by finding a teaching job in South Korea,” said Long, who applied at the Connexus Language Institute, a school associated with the Korean Anabaptist Center. <span id="more-1221"></span></p>
<p>Long landed the job in April and arrived in South Korea a month later, after having applied for an e-2 visa to teach abroad and researching the learning process for Korean speakers learning English. “I had some idea of where to start because I had been studying Korean before, so I knew where Korean and English grammar really differed,” she said.</p>
<p>She says she found it humbling to live in a country where she was unable to communicate very well. “At the same time, the willingness of every Korean I’ve met to use any bit of English they knew to try facilitate communication has been so touching,” said Long, “and makes me feel welcome and at home.”</p>
<p>At Connexus, she teaches several courses, including phonics and conversational English. Her role as a teacher goes beyond linguistics, however: “There is a big focus not just on teaching English but also on living in community and trying to minister to the students holistically,” said Long. “Because of that, we spend a lot of time working on conflict resolution and restorative justice.”</p>
<p>Long says her English courses at Messiah and her education abroad experience as a student served as catalysts for her desire to teach English overseas. Now able to combine her skills in English with her passion for other cultures, Long says that her job in Korea is the perfect opportunity for her.</p>
<p><em>Story by  Rose Talbot ’16.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/07/21/abby_long/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/07/21/abby_long/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Alumni show their love for their alma mater &#8230; 520 times!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/07/03/development_goal/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1212</id>
		<updated>2014-07-03T20:16:18Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-03T17:16:10Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Campaign" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[We ♥ Messiah is more than a slogan! It represents a deep affection our alumni feel for their experiences at Messiah College. We often hear how much their time at Messiah meant and how profoundly it impacted their spiritual and intellectual development. We hear the friendships they made at Messiah remain some of the most meaningful [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/07/03/development_goal/"><![CDATA[<p><strong><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1219" style="margin: 5px" title="Heart" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/07/Heart.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="171" />We</strong> ♥ <strong>Messiah</strong> is more than a slogan! It represents a deep affection our alumni feel for their experiences at Messiah College. We often hear how much their time at Messiah meant and how profoundly it impacted their spiritual and intellectual development. We hear the friendships they made at Messiah remain some of the most meaningful relationships in their lives and many have been sustained long past their Messiah days. We hear how much they care that Messiah remains true to its Christian roots and firm in its theological traditions. We know how much they love Messiah because they tell us.</p>
<p>The <strong>We</strong> ♥ <strong>Messiah </strong>appeal echoes alumni sentiments about their Messiah experience.  Understanding the life-changing opportunities a Messiah education offers, two generous alumni, Steve Rice ’80 and Todd Witmer ’91, graciously offered a challenge gift of $20,000. They and the College challenged 500 alumni to renew their annual financial support by June 30.  In turn, their $20,000 challenge gift would be given to the Messiah Annual Fund, which supports student scholarship aid.  Although a lofty goal for a short appeal, our alumni enthusiastically accepted the challenge and not only achieved the goal, but exceeded it with a final count of 520 new* alumni donors!</p>
<p>We are beyond grateful for the love alumni showed their alma mater by supporting Messiah College during the last days of our fiscal year. Their gifts continue our ongoing tradition of providing scholarship aid for students and making it possible for us to offer a high quality Christian education to students who may otherwise not have the means to afford it. Part of the legacy of Messiah College is our alumni, employees, parents and friends who have sacrificially given financial support from the first days of Messiah through today. Without the investment of these people, Messiah would not be the College our alums have grown to love.  <strong>We</strong> ♥ <strong>our Alumni </strong>and their commitment to continue the traditions of their alma mater!</p>
<p><em>*refers to those who have not given July 1, 2013 – June 30, 2014</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/07/03/development_goal/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/07/03/development_goal/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Student film illuminates challenges experienced by people with disabilities in Ghana]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/06/24/esch_ghana/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1207</id>
		<updated>2014-06-24T18:51:49Z</updated>
		<published>2014-06-24T18:51:49Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Academics" /><category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Collaboratory" /><category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Students" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[People with disabilities are often overlooked or left behind in discussions about global humanitarian relief aid and advocacy. But the number of vulnerable disabled people living in poverty and suffering in poor health is staggering in many communities. Eighty-two percent of people with disabilities live in poverty and more than 90% of children with disabilities [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/06/24/esch_ghana/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1210" style="margin: 5px" title="Derick Esch" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/06/Esch_w.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="171" />People with disabilities are often overlooked or left behind in discussions about global humanitarian relief aid and advocacy. But the number of vulnerable disabled people living in poverty and suffering in poor health is staggering in many communities. Eighty-two percent of people with disabilities live in poverty and more than 90% of children with disabilities do not receive education.</p>
<p>A new, short documentary film, <a href="http://vimeo.com/93334624">Beyond the Margins</a>, tells the stories of several unlikely heroes in Ghana—people with disabilities. Behind the cameras was Messiah College senior Derick Esch ‘14 who undertook the film as part of a graduation project. <span id="more-1207"></span></p>
<p>The film shows the difference that inclusion makes in the lives of people with disabilities and in their communities, and it was intended to challenge viewers to consider their own perceptions and responses to people with disabilities.</p>
<p>Esch says of the experience: “I think the biggest thing I learned through making the film was just how resilient the people we interviewed are, and how they did not wait for assistance from non-governmental organizations, but took the initiative themselves to better their situation.”</p>
<p>The individuals featured in the film are working to ensure all people in their community can experience the transformation that comes with clean, accessible and inclusive water, sanitation and hygiene. When persons with disabilities cannot meet their basic needs, their challenges are compounded. Too often, children with disabilities are kept at home, unable to access education or participate in development.</p>
<p>Rodney Green, executive producer of the video and program manager of the <a href="http://www.messiah.edu/collaboratory/">Collaboratory for Strategic Partnership and Applied Research</a>, spent two weeks in Ghana with Esch. Green recalls, “I was inspired by the fierce passion of people with disabilities to empower themselves and those around them to do what they might have thought was once impossible. I was excited to see how they are volunteering in their communities or pursuing their dreams. It felt like a force that will not be stopped.”</p>
<p>The film was a collaborative effort between the Collaboratory, Messiah&#8217;s film department and World Vision, who are partnering in several countries to find simple, affordable and locally producible ways to make clean water and sanitation accessible for people with disabilities.</p>
<p>“I hope that this film influences the audience to reflect on how they view people with disabilities, prioritize access issues with people with disabilities to promote equality and to open their minds and imaginations on how people with disabilities contribute to the overall well-being of society,” said Green. “I also hope that these stories can inspire other people with disabilities to pursue their dreams and to overcome their challenges in reaching their full potential.”</p>
<p><em>Story adapted with permission from <a href="http://www.wvi.org/">World Vision International</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/06/24/esch_ghana/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/06/24/esch_ghana/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Kay Boyer’s memoir remembers faith, family and public service of Ernest L. Boyer ‘48]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/30/boyer_memoir/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1193</id>
		<updated>2014-05-30T19:39:26Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-30T15:29:40Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Boyer Center" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The life of Ernest L. Boyer ‘48, a man whose career in public service has had a profound effect on quality education in America at every level, is now honored in his wife’s memoir, “Many Mansions: Lessons of Faith, Family, and Public Service.” Kathyrn Boyer’s memoir was released May 29 at a private reception attended [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/30/boyer_memoir/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1203" style="margin: 5px" title="Kay Boyer and Kim Phipps" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/05/BoyerKim_w.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" />The life of <a href="http://www.messiah.edu/info/200835/about_ernest_l_boyer">Ernest L. Boyer ‘48</a>, a man whose career in public service has had a profound effect on quality education in America at every level, is now honored in his wife’s memoir, “Many Mansions: Lessons of Faith, Family, and Public Service.” Kathyrn Boyer’s memoir was released May 29 at a private reception attended by the Boyer family and hosted at Messiah College by President Kim Phipps and the <a href="http://www.messiah.edu/boyer_center/">Ernest L. Boyer Center</a>.</p>
<p>“Ernie’s dedication and accomplishments on behalf of the education of our world’s children was enriched by Kay’s significant influence and imprint,” said President Phipps. <span id="more-1193"></span></p>
<p>The Boyers, who met as students at Messiah Bible School, traveled extensively and moved 20 times to fulfill Ernie’s roles as Chancellor of the State University of New York, United States Commissioner of Education and President of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching. In her memoir, Kay details the challenges and joys that came with the balancing act of faith, family and public service.</p>
<p>“This personal story of the family life of Ernest Boyer will be very valuable to all Americans who are interested in quality education in our country,” said Jimmy Carter, 39<span style="font-size: 11px">th</span> president of the United States and 2002 Nobel Peace Prize winner. “His extraordinary contributions in the highest levels of government and academic service have been a blessing to millions of students and other educators.” <img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-1195" style="margin: 5px" title="Kay Boyer" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/05/Boyer-300x200.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="200" /></p>
<p>Kay, a certified midwife and past president of the American College of Nurse-Midwives Foundation (1984-89) writes in the memoir, “I was called to be an advocate on behalf of children preparing to enter the world. Ernie was called to provide those children with ways by which they could take their place as rightful leaders in society.”</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bible.acu.edu/acupress/pg.asp?ID=124">“Many Mansions: Lessons of Faith, Family, and Public Service”</a> is published by Abilene Christian University Press. Judith and Bill Moyers of Public Affairs Television wrote, “More than a memoir, her story of the life and work they shared during a dynamic period in the shaping of American public education is an invaluable contribution to our understanding of the times. Together they created a partnership of faithful living and service that inspires to this day.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/30/boyer_memoir/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/30/boyer_memoir/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Ian Gallo ’14 will spend summer as fellow at Au Sable Institute of Environmental Studies]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/27/ian_gallo/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1188</id>
		<updated>2014-06-09T15:41:54Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-27T18:45:43Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Sustainability" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Sometimes, it takes a natural disaster to find one’s calling. After Haiti’s devastating earthquake in 2010, Ian Gallo ’14 traveled to the ravaged country on a medical mission trip. “That was my first time out of the country,” said Gallo, “and it was a little bit of a shock from my white, suburban upbringing. After [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/27/ian_gallo/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-1190" style="margin: 5px" title="Ian Gallo" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/05/Gallo_w-140x150.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="150" />Sometimes, it takes a natural disaster to find one’s calling. After Haiti’s devastating earthquake in 2010, Ian Gallo ’14 traveled to the ravaged country on a medical mission trip. “That was my first time out of the country,” said Gallo, “and it was a little bit of a shock from my white, suburban upbringing. After seeing the great disparity between the life I was accustomed to and what I saw in Haiti, I began to question many of the systems that enabled my life to be different from those in Haiti.”</p>
<p>Messiah College provided the environment in which he could explore exactly those questions he brought back from Haiti. As a sustainability studies major with a minor in peace and conflict studies, he signed up for the first-year seminar course, “In the Pursuit of Green,” an examination of issues that result from an insatiable consumerist culture and how Christians are called to respond to them. “The class was a wonderful and entirely overwhelming critique of the state of creation care,” said Gallo. “The social and environmental destruction that came about as a result of the exploitation of our neighbors around the world deeply inspired me to change part of the systems that enabled these crimes against God and humanity.” <span id="more-1188"></span></p>
<p>So, Gallo got busy. Working with the Office of Sustainability, he developed a comprehensive plan to capture and compost almost 100 percent of biodegradable waste on campus. The effort, collaborating with the grounds department, dining, housing and campus events, involved converting all to-go ware to compostable, post-consumer products.</p>
<p>“Through his position as the student compost intern, Ian is personally responsible for ensuring the compositing of all 30,000 pounds of our campus food waste,” said David Foster, professor of biology and environmental science.</p>
<p>Gallo also managed the Grantham Community Garden, redesigning it from a hobby plot to a production-oriented garden that sells produce to students, staff and the community at weekly farm stands. Unsold vegetables are purchased by Lottie Nelson Dining Hall. Anything left over is composted, in a continuation of the nutrient cycle.</p>
<p>“It is our responsibility to ourselves, our neighbor and to God to sustain the earth that we have been entrusted with. The biblical command to love your neighbor as you love yourself is most powerful in my care for creation,” said Gallo. “Creation is also beautiful, every part of it. I love it all and want my children to be able to experience that same appreciation.”<img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-1191" style="margin: 5px" title="Ian Gallo" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/05/Gallo2-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" /></p>
<p>Craig Dalen, director of the Office of Sustainability, said, “In his search to respond with responsible love to the pressing issues of our day, Ian combines an insatiable curiosity, selfless compassion and a rigorous work ethic to challenge and support himself and those around him to imagine a better world.”</p>
<p>Gallo will spend the summer pursuing his passion for sustainable agriculture at <a href="http://ausable.org/">Au Sable Institute of Environmental Studies</a> as the recipient of the $5,400 <a href="http://ausable.org/news_and_resources/news/a_passion_for_transforming_agriculture_motivates_2014_calvin_dewitt_leaders#.U4TdGHJdVOI">Calvin B. DeWitt Leadership Fellowship scholarship</a>. He will take several summer classes at Au Sable and then move to Pittsburgh with his family.</p>
<p>“I am very excited to continue my learning in an area that is facing major challenges and fostering really exciting innovation in the areas of urban agriculture and sustainable community and economic development,” said Gallo. “It seems as if I have a hippie on one shoulder and an industrialist on the other. The both want to make the world a better place but have, sometimes, drastically different ways of doing it. The next few years will be a time of exploration and learning that will help me to better understand my place in promoting a better world.”</p>
<p><em>Story by Adela Antal ’16. Photographs by Joanna Benner `17.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/27/ian_gallo/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/27/ian_gallo/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Messiah College celebrates Commencement with 734 undergraduate and graduate students]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/17/14commencement/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1176</id>
		<updated>2014-05-22T13:33:02Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-17T17:18:07Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Commencement" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[More than 5,000 people gathered May 17 to celebrate the 72 graduate students and 662 undergraduate students receiving their diplomas at Messiah College’s 105th annual Commencement ceremony. In his Commencement address, Richard Mouw, former president of Fuller Theological Seminary, challenged the graduates, “When it’s all said and done, it’s all about Jesus. So my charge [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/17/14commencement/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-1178" style="margin: 5px" title="2014 Commencement" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/05/comm_web-140x150.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="150" />More than 5,000 people gathered May 17 to celebrate the 72 graduate students and 662 undergraduate students receiving their diplomas at Messiah College’s 105<sup>th</sup> annual Commencement ceremony. In his<a href="http://www.messiah.edu/documents/commencement/2014-commencement-address.pdf"> Commencement address</a>, Richard Mouw, former president of Fuller Theological Seminary, challenged the graduates, “When it’s all said and done, it’s all about Jesus. So my charge to you is simply this: Be faithful to Jesus.”</p>
<p>A highlight of the ceremony was the presentation of the Donald and Anna Zook Alumni Merit Award to senior Hope Johnson. Johnson, an English major and Messiah’s first non-verbal, non-ambulatory graduate, was nominated for her “diligence, perseverance, fortitude and sheer determination” as an excellent writer and scholar. Johnson was lauded by English department chair Matthew Roth for her “hardworking big toe,” which, because of her cerebral palsy, she used to type her drama, memoir, fiction and literary analysis assignments.</p>
<p>Other recognitions included the presentation of the Dr. Robert and Marilyn Smith Awards for Outstanding Teaching and the Class of 2014 Senior Gift.</p>
<p>Provost Randy Basinger recognized Sharon Baker Putt, assistant professor of theology, and Richard Schaeffer ’83, professor of chemistry, as this year’s outstanding teachers, a recognition based on the nominations of senior students.</p>
<p>Julie Fenton, senior class president, presented President Kim Phipps with a $6,421 check for the expansion of the Grantham Community Garden to an acre-lot across the railroad tracks.</p>
<p>Congratulations, Class of 2014!</p>
<p>UPDATE 5/19: Enjoy this <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pe_ExQRx8w0&amp;list=UUFxu7dyMRgxCAr20e29KO8Q">brief video recap</a> of today&#8217;s ceremony. Watch the full-length <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=evRpbhqbbzY&amp;list=UUFxu7dyMRgxCAr20e29KO8Q">video</a>.</p>
<p>UPDATE 5/19: <a href="http://www.messiah.edu/baccalaureate-photos">Baccalaureate</a> photo gallery and <a href="http://www.messiah.edu/galleries/gallery/5/2014_commencement_gallery?currentPage=1&amp;itemsPerPage=12">Commencement</a> photo gallery</p>
<p>UPDATE 5/21: Harrisburg Patriot-News <a href="http://www.pennlive.com/midstate/index.ssf/2014/05/messiah_college_1.html">photo gallery</a></p>
<p><em>See an album of photos on our <a href="https://www.facebook.com/media/set/?set=a.10152053593246456.1073741863.79563991455&amp;type=1">Facebook page</a> or peruse the fun content on Twitter, Facebook and Instagram using #mcgrad14.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/17/14commencement/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/17/14commencement/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Night Razors “scooter gang” hopes to break a world record]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/13/night_razors/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1172</id>
		<updated>2014-05-13T12:59:23Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-13T12:59:23Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Students" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[They ride by night. They are lightning fast and throw caution to the wind with every 1 a.m. trip to Sheetz they brave. They are selflessly using their new-found passion to raise money for an incredible organization. They are the Night Razors.
The Night Razors is a group of 25 first-year students who turned a moment [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/13/night_razors/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-1173" style="margin: 5px" title="Night Razors" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/05/Razors_w-140x150.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="150" />They ride by night. They are lightning fast and throw caution to the wind with every 1 a.m. trip to Sheetz they brave. They are selflessly using their new-found passion to raise money for an incredible organization. They are the Night Razors.</p>
<p>The Night Razors is a group of 25 first-year students who turned a moment of childhood nostalgia at Walmart into a successful fundraising cause for a worthy organization close to their hearts. <span id="more-1172"></span></p>
<p>First-year students Ben Baker, Jason Yoder, Forrest Evans, Shaun Egolf, Kyle Talbert and Jeremy White started a trend amongst their friends after buying Razor scooters at Walmart and flaunting them around campus. The six founders, now called the OG6, accrued quite a following and soon formed a “scooter gang,” the Night Razors. Co-founder Yoder says, “The idea to ride scooters around campus occurred in a state of childish nostalgia. In its beginning, we just wanted a cathartic release from stress in the form of goofing off, and scooters just so happen to fit the criteria. We were blind to the fact that it could progress as far as it has.”</p>
<p>After daring middle-of-the-night adventures to Sheetz and Walmart, the Night Razors decided to pursue a more “epic” adventure, finally deciding on the most epic adventure of all—the pursuit of a world record. In the words of Baker, “We decided to go for it. Why not try to break a world record for the longest scooter ride and have some fun, just to try it!” The Guinness World Records accepted their endeavor and informed the Night Razors that a group of Australian farmers currently held the world record for scooting 336.11 miles in 1980.</p>
<p>After the Night Razors tweeted about the record, Razor scooter saw the tweet and contacted them directly, asking if they could do anything to help. The boys now have new Razor scooters and will be receiving jerseys for their ride.</p>
<p>The Guinness World Record’s application asks if the attempt is for charity, which sparked the Night Razor’s to use the record as a fundraising platform. The boys chose the <a href="http://www.thellf.org/">Living Legacy of Maryland Foundation</a>, an organization that helps people who are undergoing organ and tissue transplants and counsels families of both patients and donors. Baker received a liver transplant from Johns Hopkins Hospital two years ago and the Living Legacy Foundation reached out to him following his surgery, offering funds and counseling to him and his family.</p>
<p>The Living Legacy Foundation also invited Baker to their annual 5K Fun Run last year, where he met his donor’s family. Baker says, “Attending the 5K and seeing all the families the Living Legacy affected made it clear to me that if we were going to support any foundation for our ride, this was <em>the</em> one.”</p>
<p>The Night Razors will attempt to break the world record between 10 a.m. May 17 and 10 a.m. May 18 at the nearby Yellow Breeches Sports Center in New Cumberland. They’ll strive to scoot more than 336.11 miles in 24 hours.</p>
<p>The group has raised $4,300 (as of April 23), with donors such as Messiah College alumni and people from the community. Baker says, “It will be really neat when we send the money to the foundation … People need to know that it’s not all about us breaking the record. What truly matters at the end of the day is that we raised money for a really great cause and that it will help someone.”</p>
<p><em>Story by Katie Johnston &#8216;15. Photograph courtesy of the Carlisle Sentinel.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/13/night_razors/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/13/night_razors/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Messiah alum pursues professional Ultimate Frisbee career]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/06/schulze_ultfrisbee/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1162</id>
		<updated>2014-05-06T18:34:41Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-06T18:34:41Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Alumni" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many people think Frisbee is only a leisurely game to be played outside among friends but for some, Frisbee is a lifelong passion. In the case of Messiah alumnus Chris Schulze ’07, that passion netted him a position as a professional Ultimate Frisbee player for the Philadelphia Phoenix.
Schulze grew up near Amherst, Mass. a place [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/06/schulze_ultfrisbee/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-1166" style="margin: 5px" title="Chris Schulze '07" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/05/Schulze_w-140x150.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="150" />Many people think Frisbee is only a leisurely game to be played outside among friends but for some, Frisbee is a lifelong passion. In the case of Messiah alumnus Chris Schulze ’07, that passion netted him a position as a professional Ultimate Frisbee player for the <a href="http://phlphoenix.com/">Philadelphia Phoenix</a>.</p>
<p>Schulze grew up near Amherst, Mass. a place where Ultimate Frisbee is beloved by many people.  Ultimate is fast-paced and dynamic.  The disc can float, providing players with opportunities for diving plays. For Schulze, “Ultimate gives me a chance to fly. There’s nothing quite like chasing down a disc, laying out completely and grabbing it just before it hits the grass.” Another feature which drew Schulze to Ultimate was something called “spirit of the game,” meaning that the game is self-officiated and requires players to be of the highest integrity. <span id="more-1162"></span></p>
<p>When Schulze, a sports and exercise science major, first came to Messiah, he was surprised to find that the College had no official Ultimate Frisbee team.  He had started playing with his church’s youth group at the age of 14 and played on a varsity team in high school, so naturally he “was disappointed to realize that the extent of the Ultimate scene [at Messiah] was a few people who got together sporadically to play around campus and intramurals in the spring.” Schulze set out to start the first Ultimate team at Messiah and eventually formed a group of 15 people.  This young team traveled to Dickinson College to participate in a 12-team tournament. The Messiah team won and, more importantly, the players enjoyed the experience. With growing support from classmates, Schulze officially started the Messiah Ultimate team in 2004 and the Ultimate group grew from just one co-ed team into men’s A and B teams and a women’s team.</p>
<p>Schulze hasn’t forgotten his Messiah Ultimate “family.” In June 2010, he married Andrea (Peters) ’09, who he met through playing Messiah Ultimate.  They weren&#8217;t the only teammates to marry. “There have been many other marriages to which Messiah Ultimate has been a catalyst,” Schulze says.</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-1165" style="margin: 5px" title="Chris Schulze" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/05/Schulze2-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" />The time Schulze spent at Messiah was instrumental in preparing him for the future. Schulze said, “At Messiah I learned how to be a leader and learned the importance of engaging in activities that make me feel whole. When I play Ultimate I feel like I am doing what God created me to do.”  These lessons were helpful when, more recently, Schulze was given the opportunity to pursue his passion for Ultimate even further.  He was contracted by the Philadelphia Phoenix to play on their professional Ultimate team. The experience has been a unique challenge. Schulze mentioned, “The personal and team training that goes along with playing professionally is certainly intense.”  But Schulze is not alone at the Philadelphia Phoenix. He has reconnected with several teammates from the Messiah Ultimate team including Jordan Winey ’07, now a professional teammate, and Charlie Hoppes, coach of Messiah’s men’s Ultimate team and assistant coach of the Phoenix.</p>
<p>For Schulze, Ultimate has become a lifelong passion which he hopes to enjoy many years from now. “I’ve always wanted to be that old guy who looks like he doesn&#8217;t belong on the field, but can still school the young guys.  I plan to keep playing until I’m unable to move faster than a walk.”</p>
<p><em>Story by Jeremy Ross ‘15. Photographs courtesy of Chris Schulze.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/06/schulze_ultfrisbee/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/05/06/schulze_ultfrisbee/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Exposing injustice—Messiah College professor to film documentary in Uganda]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/04/21/imbesi/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1156</id>
		<updated>2014-04-21T19:39:34Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-21T19:38:24Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Alumni" /><category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Faculty" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[With a heart for social justice and peace, professor and filmmaker Krista Imbesi ‘09 will collaborate with Phil Wilmot ’12 to voice a story of injustice and hopeful reconciliation in the documentary, &#8220;Our Feet are Rooted,&#8221; exposing the illegal land grabbing crisis in Northern Uganda.
This June, Imbesi and her husband Christian ’09 will partner with [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/04/21/imbesi/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="size-thumbnail wp-image-1158 alignleft" style="margin: 5px" title="Krista Imbesi" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/04/Krista_W-140x150.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="150" />With a heart for social justice and peace, professor and filmmaker Krista Imbesi ‘09 will collaborate with Phil Wilmot ’12 to voice a story of injustice and hopeful reconciliation in the documentary, <a href="http://solidarityuganda.wordpress.com/2014/03/04/how-a-documentary-film-will-protect-land-in-uganda/">&#8220;Our Feet are Rooted,&#8221;</a> exposing the illegal land grabbing crisis in Northern Uganda.</p>
<p>This June, Imbesi and her husband Christian ’09 will partner with Wilmot and his wife, Suzan, founders of the non-profit organization, Solidarity Uganda to tell the story of the Amuru District residents and their struggle against the corporate government violently stealing their land and selling it to multinational oil and sugarcane companies. <span id="more-1156"></span></p>
<p>Solidarity Uganda endeavors to train the district in non-violent protesting and spread awareness of this conflict. In hopes of raising consciousness and creating support for the community, the team will submit “Our Feet are Rooted” to social justice themed film festivals and tour the film in Uganda and the United States after its completion next spring. Wilmot says, “This film will bring national and international attention to the conflict.  It will serve as an advocacy tool to affect social and political change both near and far from Amuru.”<em></em></p>
<p>Imbesi entered this project with a pre-existing passion for Uganda cultivated during a summer service trip to Ugandan orphanages.  Her experiences in Uganda prompted her to create the documentary, <a href="http://www.kristaimbesi.com/#!where-we-belong/cyuu">&#8220;Where We Belong&#8221;</a>, explaining the implications of Westerners’ running Ugandan orphanages. This documentary screened at Messiah College&#8217;s Humanities Symposium last year and won the Jury Award at the DIY Film Festival in Los Angeles. After seeing “Where We Belong,” filmmaker Wilmot expressed interest in collaborating with the Imbesis to produce a film about the Amuru District community. The implications for the recent collaboration will be far-reaching. Wilmot says, “There is an empowering element to telling one’s story.  Film is an effective platform for articulating human identity.”</p>
<p><img class="alignright size-thumbnail wp-image-1157" style="margin: 5px" title="Krista Imbesi" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/04/Krista_films-150x150.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="150" />Imbesi’s ultimate goal in filming this documentary is to give a voice to the voiceless in the most ethical and accurate way possible; she wants to gain information directly from the local residents to best portray their struggle. Imbesi says, “What I would like to achieve is forming a collaborative project in which the subjects have a voice in the making of and interpretation of the film. We will be working with the community in finding out how they want this story told, and using our expertise in equipment and visual aesthetics to assist in the creation of the film.” She continues, “I happen to have the expertise and resources for filmmaking, but only the Ugandan people in the film will understand the nuances of their culture, what is or isn&#8217;t important to their story, and how they want that story to be told … and storytelling should always trump aesthetics in priority.” <em></em></p>
<p>The residents of the Amuru District are excited to take part in the film’s creation. They are working to choreograph a dance displaying their frustration and struggle in this land conflict. The documentary will shed light on the crisis as it is shared throughout Uganda, even in unaffected areas. Imbesi says, “Outside of the community that is involved, it will be great to show Ugandans in other parts of the country what is happening. The conflict has been kept relatively quiet and many people in other parts of the country are unaware of it.”</p>
<p>Imbesi’s time at Messiah College served as inspiration for her post-graduate projects. She says, “My education at Messiah affected my perception of filmmaking through the idea that we are to be servants in our vocations. The film industry is full of people who are taught to emphasize their pride and their artistic integrity above all else … Putting aside pride in order to prioritize ethics in filmmaking practices is definitely something I learned at Messiah.”</p>
<p><em>Story by Katie Johnston &#8216;15. Photos courtesy of Krista Imbsei.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/04/21/imbesi/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/04/21/imbesi/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>blorow</name>
						<uri>http://www.messiah.edu/offices/pr/</uri>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[From shining in the spotlight to shining the spotlight on social issues: Theatre and Social Change at Messiah]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/04/14/tasc/" />
		<id>http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/?p=1153</id>
		<updated>2014-04-14T20:30:38Z</updated>
		<published>2014-04-14T20:30:38Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Faculty" /><category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Students" /><category scheme="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features" term="Theatre" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[In “The Real Thing: a Play,” Czechoslovakian producer and writer Tom Stoppard wrote, “Words are sacred … If you get the right ones, in the right order, you can nudge the world a little.” Nudging the world toward social change has been the goal of Messiah College’s Theatre and Social Change course since its introduction [...]]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/04/14/tasc/"><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-1154" style="margin: 5px" title="Theatre" src="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/files/2014/04/Theatre_w-140x150.jpg" alt="" width="140" height="150" />In “The Real Thing: a Play,” Czechoslovakian producer and writer Tom Stoppard wrote, “Words are sacred … If you get the right ones, in the right order, you can nudge the world a little.” Nudging the world toward social change has been the goal of Messiah College’s Theatre and Social Change course since its introduction to the theatre curriculum in 2002. The impetus behind Theatre and Social Change (TASC) came after Messiah College professor Valerie Rae Smith facilitated the student-writing of an original production, “E.D. &amp; Ana,” which studied eating disorders among college students.<em> </em>Smith says, “Students were so responsive to the play and the conversations surrounding “E.D. &amp; Ana” that a general education course was created. By 2002 Theatre and Social Change was a term students used across campus, in the residence halls and in the classrooms.” <span id="more-1153"></span></p>
<p>Creative outlets like theatre are typically considered pure entertainment, but TASC poses a novel question: what if theatre could shine the spotlight on stories that illuminate social issues? Through TASC Smith hopes “to disturb our notion of what theatre is, what it can be and how much potential theatre has to join our desires to heal a world in pain … at its best, TASC can be a part of God’s ongoing work of reconciliation.”   In selecting topics for class discussion and dramatization, Smith chooses social justice issues that students consider “taboo” or problematic, such as minimum wage reform, the death penalty, cancer, organ donation, medical ethics and human trafficking. Sophomore Courtney Chase says, “This is a different kind of theatre that discusses serious issues and helps me to understand a bit better the struggles people go through that I have not experienced.”</p>
<p>In class, students begin the semester studying parables, learning the power of words to “nudge the world” from the greatest storyteller of all times, Jesus. Students then study writings from 20th century authors and activists who applied Christian liberation theology to their theoretical development, such as  Paulo Freire’s “Pedagogy of the Oppressed” and Augusto Boal’s “Theatre of the Oppressed.” Smith says, “Boal voiced my hopes when he said that ‘when we look beyond appearances, we see oppressors and oppressed people, in all societies, ethnic groups, genders and social classes … We have to create another world because we know it is possible. But it is up to us to build this other world with our hands and by acting on the stage and in our own life.’”</p>
<p>Senior theatre major Christie Heimbach says, “In last spring’s Theatre and Social Change class, we learned that an effective way to touch the audience is to reveal a performance which inspires questioning … I’ve always been extremely passionate about resolving injustices, and it’s exciting to think that you can create awareness with art.” This fall, Heimbach produced her senior show, “Beyond the Rain,” drawing from experiences of social injustice she saw while doing mission work in Africa. This moving show premiered in the Black Box theatre in the college’s new, state-of-the-art Calvin and Janet High Center for Worship and Performing Arts, a magnificent facility for theatre, dance, worship and music. Heimbach’s show will next be performed in Scotland at the Edinburg Fringe Festival in August.</p>
<p>Theatre and Social Change ultimately uses theatre as a venue for raising social consciousness and creating civic dialogue. Smith says, “TASC invites us to live in the tension, a place of both energy and, yes, enervation. When we give ourselves to the work we move from ignorance to knowledge, from defensiveness to vulnerability, from the despair that comes with the nightly news to the hope that comes in the morning when we dare to hope that we can change ourselves and our world for the better.”</p>
<p><em>By Katie Johnston ‘15. This story is part of the Mennonite World Review <a href="http://mennoworld.org/2014/04/14/class-uses-stage-to-shine-a-spotlight-on-social-issues/">annual college issue</a>.</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/04/14/tasc/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://blogs.messiah.edu/features/2014/04/14/tasc/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
