<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:/news</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://research.nd.edu/news.atom"/>
  <title>Research at Notre Dame // Research at Notre Dame</title>
  <updated>2014-07-21T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/49463</id>
    <published>2014-07-21T08:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-21T08:44:57-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/49463-thomson-reuters-names-three-notre-dame-faculty-among-the-worlds-most-influential-scientific-minds/"/>
    <title>Thomson Reuters names three Notre Dame faculty among the world’s most influential scientific minds</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136893/reuters_300.jpg" title="Thomson Reuters The World’s Most Influential Scientific Minds: 2014" alt="Thomson Reuters The World’s Most Influential Scientific Minds: 2014" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Notre Dame faculty members &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/for-the-media/nd-experts/faculty/joan-brennecke/"&gt;Joan Brennecke&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/bhochwald"&gt;Bertrand Hochwald&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www3.nd.edu/~pkamat/"&gt;Prashant Kamat&lt;/a&gt; have been named to Thomson Reuters&amp;#8217; list of &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://thomsonreuters.com/articles/2014/worlds-most-influential-scientific-minds-2014"&gt;The World’s Most Influential Scientific Minds: 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list includes more than 3,200 scientists around the world who have published the highest number of articles that are cited the most frequently by other researchers. The list was compiled from two separate Thomson Reuters studies analyzed for publication and citation data from 21 broad fields of study, ranging from chemistry to social sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A faculty member since 1989, Brennecke is the Keating-Crawford Professor of &lt;a href="https://cbe.nd.edu/"&gt;Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering&lt;/a&gt; and served as founding director of the University of Notre Dame Energy Center. She is internationally known for her research in the development of solvents, specifically supercritical fluids and ionic liquids. Her research interests include supercritical fluid technology, ionic liquids, thermodynamics, environmentally benign chemical processing and carbon dioxide separation, storage and usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136888/brennecke_200.jpg" title="Joan Brennecke" alt="Joan Brennecke" /&gt; Joan Brennecke&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brennecke most recently received the E.V. Murphree Award in Industrial and Engineering Chemistry from the American Chemical Society (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACS&lt;/span&gt;). She also received the 2009 Ernest Orlando Lawrence Award from the United States Department of Energy, the 2008 Julius Stieglitz Lecturer Award from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACS&lt;/span&gt; and the 2007 John M. Prausnitz Award for outstanding achievement in applied chemical thermodynamics from the Conference on Properties and Phase Equilibria for Product and Process Design. Other honors she has received include the 2006 Professional Progress Award from the American Institute of Chemical Engineers and the 2001 Ipatieff Prize from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACS&lt;/span&gt; in recognition of her high-pressure studies of the local structure of supercritical fluid solutions and the effect of this local structure on the rates of homogeneous reactions. In 1991, the National Science Foundation presented her with the Presidential Young Investigator Award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A member of the National Academy of Engineering, Brennecke is past chair of the Council for Chemical Research and currently serves as editor-in-chief of the Journal of Chemical and Engineering Data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136889/200x/hochwald_300.jpg" title="Bertrand Hochwald" alt="Bertrand Hochwald" /&gt; Bertrand Hochwald&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 26 patents in the field of wireless communications, Hochwald has experienced and led the practice of wireless communications from a variety of angles in his roles at the Department of Defense, as a Distinguished Member of the Technical Staff at Bell Laboratories and as vice president of Systems Engineering at Beceem Communications. He has invented technologies and published research articles that are the mainstays of communication theory and practice, including several multiple-antenna technologies, such as a differential method, linear dispersion codes and multi-user methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hochwald joined the University faculty in 2011 and serves as the Frank M. Freimann Professor of &lt;a href="http://ee.nd.edu"&gt;Electrical Engineering&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to the many plenary talks he has given and awards he has received, such as the 2006 Stephen O. Rice Best Paper in the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IEEE&lt;/span&gt; Transactions on Communications, he is a fellow of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers and has served as editor on several industry journals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136890/kamat_200.jpg" title="Prashant Kamat" alt="Prashant Kamat" /&gt; Prashant Kamat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kamat, who also was selected as a Thomson Reuters &lt;a href="http://highlycited.com/"&gt;Highly Cited Researcher&lt;/a&gt;, is the Rev. John A. Zahm, C.S.C., Professor of Science in the &lt;a href="http://chemistry.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://www.rad.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Radiation Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;, as well as concurrent professor of the Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A leader in the field of converting solar to electricity and chemical energy, he has published more than 400 peer-reviewed publications, edited three books, is a contributor to 14 books and monographs and serves as the deputy editor of the Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. In addition to the recognition from Tomson Reuters, in 2011 Times Higher Education Group ranked him among the top 100 chemists of the previous decade based on citations per paper. The h-index measure of his research impact surpassed 100 this year, a distinction achieved by only the world’s most elite scientists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Kamat, the goal of his research is to build bridges between physical chemistry and material science in order to improve energy conversion efficiencies. His most recent work focuses on nanotechnology and material chemistry, solar energy conversion, chemical processes in heterogeneous media and solar fuels. He joined the University faculty in 1983.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kamat recently won the CS’s Langmuir Leadership Award. He also is a fellow of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACS&lt;/span&gt;, American Association for the Advancement of Science and the Electrochemical Society. His international honors include the Chemical Research Society of India Medal and the Honda-Fujishima Lectureship Award from the Japanese Photochemistry Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;: Nina Welding, College of Engineering, 574-631-4397, &lt;a href="mailto:nwelding@nd.edu"&gt;nwelding@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Nina Welding&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49437-thomson-reuters-names-three-notre-dame-faculty-among-the-worlds-most-influential-scientific-minds/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 18, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Nina Welding</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/49439</id>
    <published>2014-07-18T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-18T13:34:19-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/49439-notre-dame-energy-frontier-research-center-receives-further-doe-funding/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame Energy Frontier Research Center receives further DOE funding</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;Graduate engineering research in Peter Burns’ lab in Stinson-Remick Hall&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="burns_lab_full" src="http://energy.nd.edu/assets/136067/burns_lab_full.jpg" title="burns_lab_full"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A University of Notre Dame research center has once again been designated an &lt;a href="http://science.energy.gov/bes/efrc/"&gt;Energy Frontier Research Center&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) by the U.S. Department of Energy (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;) and will receive funding to help accelerate the scientific breakthroughs needed to build the 21st-century energy economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://science.energy.gov/bes/efrc/"&gt;Notre Dame &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, titled “Materials Science of Actinides,” was first &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/11640-doe-to-establish-energy-frontier-research-center-at-notre-dame/"&gt;designated as an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in 2009&lt;/a&gt; along with 45 other centers. This year, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; awarded $100 million in funding to 32 projects. Ten of this year’s projects are new, while the rest received their funding based on both their achievements to date and the quality of their proposals. The 32 projects receiving funding were selected from more than 200 proposals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Notre Dame &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, which is directed by &lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/pburns"&gt;Peter Burns&lt;/a&gt;, Henry J. Massman Chair and Professor of Civil Engineering and Geological Sciences and concurrent professor of chemistry and biochemistry, received a $12 million, four-year grant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“With this renewed funding, we will continue to focus the efforts of a team of gifted scholars on issues related to nuclear energy that are of great importance to the nation,” Burns said. “The center structure allows us to unite experts from several disciplines to address scientific challenges that would be intractable with smaller, discipline-specific funding models. Continuation of the center also permits us to provide the best possible education to students at all levels who are involved in our research program.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus of the center, which includes participants from several other universities and a national laboratory, is the elements that are the basis of nuclear energy — uranium, plutonium and other actinides. Research in the center will seek to understand and control materials that contain actinides at the nanoscale, which is about one-millionth of the size of the tip of a ball-point pen. This research is intended to lay the scientific foundation for advanced nuclear energy systems that may provide much more energy while creating less nuclear waste.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are mobilizing some of our most talented scientists to join forces and purse the discoveries and breakthroughs that will lay the foundation for our nation’s energy future,” U.S. Energy Secretary Ernest Moniz said in announcing the centers. “The funding we’re announcing today will help fuel scientific and technological innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A National Research Council report, titled “Assuring a Future U.S.-Based Nuclear and Radiochemistry Expertise,” stated: “The growing use of nuclear medicine, the potential expansion of nuclear power generation, and the urgent needs to protect the nation against external nuclear threats, to maintain our nuclear weapons stockpile, and to manage the nuclear wastes generated in past decades, require a substantial, highly trained, and exceptionally talented workforce.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since its establishment in 2009, Notre Dame’s Materials Science of Actinides &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; has supported 32 graduate students, including 16 women, in actinide sciences, eight of whom have graduated; 28 post-doctoral researchers; 53 undergraduate researchers, including 29 women; and it has hosted 19 visiting scholars. The center has organized and taught three short courses with 172 total participants, and organized five sessions at national and international conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame’s &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;EFRC&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; partners include Stanford University, The University of California-Davis, the University of Minnesota, Oregon State University, the University of Tennessee, George Washington University, the University of Akron and Los Alamos National Laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;: Peter Burns, 574-631-7582, &lt;a href="mailto:pburns@nd.edu"&gt;pburns@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;William G. Gilroy&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49160-notre-dame-energy-frontier-research-center-receives-further-doe-funding/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 03, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>William G. Gilroy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/49333</id>
    <published>2014-07-14T09:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-14T09:45:44-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/49333-notre-dame-to-receive-father-badins-bible/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame to receive Father Badin’s Bible</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rev. Stephen Badin" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/136450/father_stephen_theodore_badin_224.jpg" title="Rev. Stephen Badin"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame has acquired a Bible once owned by Rev. Stephen Badin, the pioneer priest on whose mission grounds Notre Dame’s founder, Rev. Edward Sorin, C.S.C., began to build the University 172 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Father Badin’s Bible was purchased from the Sisters of Loretto of Nerinx, Kentucky, and a delegation of sisters is coming to Notre Dame on Monday (July 14) to deliver it by hand during a Mass that will be celebrated in the Log Chapel where Father Badin is buried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first Catholic priest ordained in the United States, Father Badin served as a missionary on the Kentucky, Indiana and Illinois frontiers. In 1831, he built the Log Chapel for his mission headquarters on the site where its replica stands today, the original having burned down in 1858. The 542 acres around that site, of which much of the campus (including a student residence hall named after him) is now comprised, Father Badin donated to Bishop Celestine de la Hailandiere of Vincennes, Indiana, who subsequently gave the land to Father Sorin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Badin Bible is a rare book. A three-volume edition of the Douay-Rheims version published by Mathew Carey in 1790, it was the first “Catholic” Bible for sale in the United States. Carey, an expatriate Irish journalist, printer and publisher in Philadelphia, issued and sold fewer than 500 copies at a time when Catholics were an extremely small minority (some 35,000 of 4 million, or roughly 1 percent) of the nation’s population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding to this book’s distinction and historical significance is that it was given to Father Badin at his ordination in 1793, the gift of Bishop John Carroll of Baltimore, himself the first Catholic bishop of the United States. The Bible is inscribed to Father Badin by Bishop Carroll, who ordained him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Notre Dame’s acquisition of the Badin Bible will link Father Badin’s Kentucky home with his Indiana one, and his early ministry as a priest with his final resting place,” said &lt;a href="http://cushwa.nd.edu/about/cushwa-center-staff/kathleen-sprows-cummings/"&gt;Kathleen Sprows Cummings&lt;/a&gt;, director of the &lt;a href="http://cushwa.nd.edu/"&gt;Cushwa Center for the Study of American Catholicism&lt;/a&gt;. “Far beyond the campus connection, however, Badin’s Bible represents a number of historic firsts in American Catholicism. This is a real treasure that will benefit the teaching and research of historians and Bible scholars at Notre Dame and beyond.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bible will be on display in the &lt;a href="http://rarebooks.library.nd.edu/"&gt;Rare Books and Special Collections Room&lt;/a&gt; on the main floor of the Hesburgh Library during the fall semester. “The Badin Bible will be one of the most significant additions to the collection of Catholic Americana held in the Rare Books and Special Collections department of the Hesburgh Libraries,” said Catholic Studies librarian Jean McManus. “The later work of Stephen Badin, as a missionary to the Middle West, connects this Bible to the University of Notre Dame.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Heather Grennan Gary, Cushwa Center for the Study of American Catholicism, 574-631-4696&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49291-notre-dame-to-receive-father-badins-bible/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;July 10, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/49175</id>
    <published>2014-07-03T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-03T13:12:46-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/49175-trophy-wife-stereotype-is-largely-a-myth-new-study-shows/"/>
    <title>'Trophy wife' stereotype is largely a myth, new study shows</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135196/trump_300.jpg" title="Melania Knauss-Trump" alt="Melania Knauss-Trump" /&gt; Melania Knauss-Trump&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t be so quick to judge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are familiar with the “trophy wife” stereotype that attractive women marry rich men, placing little importance on their other traits, including physical appearance, and that men look for pretty wives but don’t care about their education or earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New research, however, by University of Notre Dame sociologist &lt;a href="http://sociology.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-by-alpha/elizabeth-mcclintock/"&gt;Elizabeth McClintock&lt;/a&gt; shows the trophy wife stereotype is largely a myth fueled by selective observation that reinforces sexist stereotypes and trivializes women’s careers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &amp;#8220;&lt;a href="http://asr.sagepub.com/content/early/2014/05/29/0003122414536391.abstract"&gt;Beauty and Status: The Illusion of Exchange in Partner Selection?&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8221; forthcoming in American Sociological Review, McClintock resolves the paradox between the trophy wife stereotype and the evidence that couples match on both physical attractiveness and socioeconomic status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using, for the first time, a nationally representative sample of young couples in which both partners were interviewed and rated for physical attractiveness, McClintock was able to control for matching on attractiveness. She says prior research in this area has ignored two important factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I find that handsome men partner with pretty women and successful men partner with successful women,” says McClintock, who specializes in inequality within romantic partnerships. “So, on average, high-status men do have better-looking wives, but this is because they themselves are considered better looking &amp;#8212; perhaps because they are less likely to be overweight and more likely to afford braces, nice clothes and trips to the dermatologist, etc. Secondly, the strongest force by far in partner selection is similarity &amp;#8212; in education, race, religion and physical attractiveness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McClintock’s research shows that there is not, in fact, a general tendency for women to trade beauty for money. That is not to say trophy wife marriages never happen, just that they are very rare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Donald Trump and his third wife, Melania Knauss-Trump, may very well exemplify the trophy wife stereotype,” McClintock says. “But, there are many examples of rich men who partner with successful women rather than ‘buying’ a supermodel wife. The two men who founded Google (Larry Page and Sergey Brin) both married highly accomplished women &amp;#8212; one has a Ph.D. and the other is a wealthy entrepreneur.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/92629/elizabeth_mcclintock_200x.jpg" title="Elizabeth McClintock" alt="Elizabeth McClintock" /&gt; Elizabeth McClintock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McClintock says the trophy wife stereotype is most often wrongly applied among non-celebrities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I’ve heard doctors’ wives referred to as trophy wives by observers who only notice her looks and his status and fail to realize that he is good-looking too and that she is also a successful professional &amp;#8212; or was before she had kids and left her job,” McClintock says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McClintock’s research also indicates that, contrary to the trophy wife stereotype, social class barriers in the marriage market are relatively impermeable. Beautiful women are unlikely to leverage their looks to secure upward mobility by marriage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;: Elizabeth McClintock, 574-631-5218, &lt;a href="mailto:emcclint@nd.edu"&gt;emcclint@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Shannon Chapla&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/48903-trophy-wife-stereotype-is-largely-a-myth-new-study-shows/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 17, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Shannon Chapla</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/49101</id>
    <published>2014-06-26T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-30T09:02:52-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/49101-notre-dame-turbomachinery-facility/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame collaborating with five partners to build nation’s top turbine engine component research and testing facility</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/135586/300x/turbomachinery_news.jpg" title="Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility" alt="Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame and five public and private partners announced today Thursday (June 26) a &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/turbomachinery/"&gt;$36 million project&lt;/a&gt; that will be the nation’s foremost research and test facility for advancing the technology used in the massive gas turbine engines used by commercial and military aircraft, power plants, and the oil and gas industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Construction in South Bend’s &lt;a href="http://www.ignitionpark.com/"&gt;Ignition Park&lt;/a&gt; on a 43,000-square-foot building &amp;#8212; of which 25,000 square feet will be for the &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/turbomachinery/"&gt;Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8212; will begin this summer and be completed by March. The facility will be fully operational in July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This venture will be a cutting-edge research and testing facility for the turbine engine industry as well as a tremendous economic driver for our region,” said Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C., the University’s president. “Notre Dame is grateful to our partners for their support of this project and excited about all that it will mean to our University, the city and state, the industry as a whole and our nation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame will contribute $7.5 million to the project. Other partners are the General Electric Co., which has committed $13.5 million to fund research and testing for five years; the city of South Bend, which is contributing $4.4 million inclusive of equipment, land for a new power substation and tax abatements; the state of Indiana, through the Indiana Economic Development Corp., which is providing up to $600,000 in training grants and up to $2 million in infrastructure assistance; Great Lakes Capital, which is providing upfront capital of approximately $6 million to construct the facility; and Indiana Michigan Power, which will be investing $2 million in a new substation to provide the considerable power needed to operate the facility’s multiple test cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The center will allow GE’s industrial businesses to simulate full-scale engine operating environments,” said Rick Stanley, vice president and chief technologist for GE’s Power and Water business and a Notre Dame graduate. “The important rig testing we will do at the center builds upon GE’s already strong and long-standing technical relationship with the University. For years, GE has turned to Notre Dame for top technical talent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When fully operational, the Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility will provide about 60 new jobs to directly operate the center, with an average salary and benefits package of about $79,000. An additional 60 jobs are expected through the growth of local suppliers to support the facility’s need for precision manufactured components. At full operation, research expenditures generated through work conducted at the facility are expected to exceed $15 million annually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The aerospace industry is reaching new heights in Indiana,” said Gov. Mike Pence. “Universities like Notre Dame and others across the state are providing avenues for discovery, proving that the sky is the limit in Indiana when it comes to bringing a big vision to life. The next great technological innovation could come from the mind of a Hoosier, highlighting for the world the full range of possibilities when investing in a state that works.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Neal, deputy mayor of South Bend, added: “Attracting such major investment speaks to South Bend’s economic future and its capacity to attract high-tech businesses. This project continues our city’s history of innovation and is more evidence of the benefits that South Bend’s economic and geographic advantages offer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame’s current Turbomachinery Laboratory has worked with industry and government partners to advance gas turbine engine technologies since 2003. Center researchers focus on the design and operation of test facilities that simulate full-scale engine operating environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new facility, which will feature five test bays for compressor and turbine rig testing, will take previous work to new heights by testing engine components at pressures and temperatures higher than any that exist at current U.S. university facilities. It also will be used to advance current working relationships with both government sponsors and all manufacturers of gas turbine engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are very excited to be launching the Notre Dame Turbomachinery Facility,” said Robert J. Bernhard, the University’s vice president for research. “It will be a significant combination of world class research, building on an outstanding program, and local economic development. We are very grateful to our collaborating organizations, who have been outstanding partners in putting this project together.”&lt;br /&gt;
In addition to the industry and government partnerships, Notre Dame plans to collaborate with researchers and staff at local and state colleges and universities in order to widen the educational mission of the new facility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information is available at http://www.nd.edu/turbomachinery/.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Dennis Brown&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/49032-notre-dame-turbomachinery-facility/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;June 26, 2014&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Dennis Brown</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48778</id>
    <published>2014-06-03T09:40:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T09:42:05-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48778-notre-dame-receives-grand-challenges-explorations-grant-for-research-in-global-health-and-development/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame receives Grand Challenges Explorations grant for research in global health and development</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p style="width: 301px;" class="image-right captioned"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/134434/pad_lab_300.jpg" alt="" /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PAD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://padproject.nd.edu/"&gt;Marya Lieberman&lt;/a&gt; , associate professor of chemistry and biochemistry at the University of Notre Dame, has received a &lt;a href="http://www.grandchallenges.org/Explorations/Pages/Introduction.aspx"&gt;Grand Challenges Explorations grant&lt;/a&gt; , an initiative funded by the &lt;a href="http://www.gatesfoundation.org/"&gt;Bill&amp;amp;Melinda Gates Foundation&lt;/a&gt; . Lieberman will pursue an innovative global health and development research project, titled “Printed test cards for rapid field screening of human and animal medications.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grand Challenges Explorations funds individuals worldwide to explore ideas that can break the mold in how persistent global health and development challenges are solved. Lieberman’s project is one of more than 50 Grand Challenges Explorations Round 12 grants announced Tuesday (June 3) by the Bill&amp;amp;Melinda Gates Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To receive funding, Lieberman and other Grand Challenges Explorations Round 12 winners demonstrated in a two-page online application a bold idea in one of five critical global heath and development topic areas that included agriculture development, behavior change and looking into animal and human health. Applications for the &lt;a href="http://www.grandchallenges.org/GrantOpportunities/Pages/default.aspx"&gt;next round&lt;/a&gt; will be accepted starting in September.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieberman’s team has designed an inexpensive &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/40904-notre-dame-researchers-put-chemistry-lab-on-paper-to-detect-low-quality-medicine/"&gt;paper test card&lt;/a&gt; that can detect low-quality medications and apply economic pressure to companies that manufacture or distribute them. The World Health Organization estimates that 10 percent to 30 percent of human medications are of poor quality and an unknown percentage of animal medications is substandard or falsified. There is little chance that poor quality products will be caught by pharmaceutical buyers or drug regulatory agencies in developing countries, because it is so expensive to collect and test them, so low-quality products continue to harm both people and animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="width: 301px;" class="image-left captioned"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/134315/marya_lieberman_300.jpg" alt="" /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Marya Lieberman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lieberman’s team will design a test card to monitor 50 types of human and animal medicines. Testing a sample of a medication is economical and accessible as there is no instrument to purchase, and the results of the test card can be read by eye or with a cellphone photograph. The test cards will enable people who buy large quantities of human or animal medications to steer clear of low-quality products and will help regulators to hold companies responsible for the quality of the medications they sell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.grandchallenges.org/Explorations/Pages/Introduction.aspx"&gt;Grand Challenges Explorations&lt;/a&gt; is a $100 million initiative funded by the Bill&amp;amp;Melinda Gates Foundation. Launched in 2008, more than 950 people in more than 55 countries have received Grand Challenges Explorations grants. The grant program is open to anyone from any discipline and from any organization. The initiative uses an agile, accelerated grant-making process with short two-page online applications and no preliminary data required. Initial grants of $100,000 are awarded two times each year. Successful projects have the opportunity to receive a follow-on grant of up to $1 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://chemistry.nd.edu/people/marya-lieberman/"&gt;Lieberman&lt;/a&gt; is a member of Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://globalhealth.nd.edu"&gt;Eck Institute for Global Health&lt;/a&gt; , which funded her initial exploratory research. She has partnered with the &lt;a href="http://ampathkenya.org/"&gt;Academic Model Providing Access to Healthcare&lt;/a&gt; ( &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AMPATH&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; ), which consists of Moi University School of Medicine and Moi Teaching and Referral Hospital in Eldoret, Kenya, and a consortium of North American academic centers. She has also partnered with &lt;a href="http://www.sidai.com/"&gt;Sidai&lt;/a&gt; , which provides quality services to livestock keepers across Kenya. Her work is also supported by Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://advanceddiagnostics.nd.edu/"&gt;Advanced Diagnostics and Therapeutics&lt;/a&gt; , which provides diagnostics for the developing world. The &lt;a href="http://padproject.nd.edu/"&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PAD&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; project&lt;/a&gt; is an evolving collaboration with Toni Barstis, professor of chemistry and physics at Saint Mary’s College, and with Notre Dame professors Holly Goodson, Patrick Flynn, Christopher Sweet, David Go and Matthew Champion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Marissa Gebhard, 574-631-4465, &lt;a href="mailto:gebhard.3@nd.edu"&gt;gebhard.3@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Marissa Gebhard</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48779</id>
    <published>2014-05-28T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T09:44:14-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48779-notre-dame-study-reveals-that-having-and-raising-offspring-proves-costly-for-baboon-moms/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame study reveals that having and raising offspring proves costly for baboon moms</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p style="width: 301px;" class="image-right captioned"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/133948/baboon_300.jpg" alt="" /&gt; Yellow baboons&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new &lt;a href="http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00265-014-1729-4"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt; by University of Notre Dame biologist &lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/archie/"&gt;Elizabeth Archie&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://www.museums.or.ke/"&gt;National Museums of Kenya&lt;/a&gt; examining yellow baboons over a 29-year period demonstrates that having offspring influences the health of female baboons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists are already aware that reproduction can be dangerous and energetically costly, exposing individuals to physical harm, infectious disease and reduced immunity. Archie and her fellow researchers used data collected as part of the &lt;a href="http://amboselibaboons.nd.edu/"&gt;Amboseli Baboon Research Project&lt;/a&gt; near Kilimanjaro, Kenya, to analyze how long-lived, slow-reproducing species such as primates adjust to the dangers of reproduction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They detected 707 injuries to 160 female baboons between 1982 and 2011. The injuries of lactating baboons were about 21 percent less likely to heal in a given time period than those of non-lactating baboons. The researchers believe this may be because females are in poorer physical condition or have less energy in general. This influences how well a wound can heal, tissue is repaired and infections are curbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis of the data makes it possible to predict the risk of injury to specific females by taking their ovarian cycle, dominance rank and age into account, as well as whether their social group is separating into two or more distinct groups. Ovulating female baboons are, for instance, twice as likely to be wounded as those who are in the less fertile days of their cycle. Such injuries occur in the context of reproductive competition through interactions with both adult male and female baboons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers note that it is not at all surprising that low-ranking female baboons experience higher injury risk than high-ranking females. Prior research has shown that these baboons are subject to more aggression and are less likely to be supported in conflicts than higher-ranking females.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Older females might incur more injuries because they take greater risks to make the best of their declining reproductive years, or because their health and resilience are generally failing. Old age has another drawback for female baboons: Older ones tend to heal more slowly than younger females, because immunity and subsequent wound healing commonly decline with age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Amboseli Baboon Research Project is one of the world’s longest-running studies of a wild primate. Trained observers there have made almost daily notes on yellow baboons since 1971.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study by Archie and her fellow researchers appears in Springer’s journal &lt;a href="http://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s00265-014-1729-4"&gt;Behavioral Ecology and Sociobiology&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.nd.edu/archielab/"&gt;Archie’s Notre Dame lab&lt;/a&gt; combines field work and genetics research to understand the causes and consequences of social behavior in wild mammals. Her research team examines how migration, mating and social patterns impact the genetics and evolution of a species and its fitness and susceptibility to diseases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Elizabeth Archie, 574-631-0178, &lt;a href="mailto:earchie@nd.edu"&gt;earchie@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>William G. Gilroy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48780</id>
    <published>2014-05-22T09:45:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T09:46:22-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48780-large-binocular-telescope-committee-selects-crepps-ilocator-to-be-built/"/>
    <title>Large Binocular Telescope committee selects Crepp’s iLocator to be built</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://science.nd.edu/assets/133602/5.13.14_justin_crepp_1.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group that oversees the Large Binocular Telescope (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;LBT&lt;/span&gt;) has selected the team led by &lt;a href="http://physics.nd.edu/people/faculty/justin-r-crepp/"&gt;Justin Crepp&lt;/a&gt; , the Freimann Assistant Professor of Physics at the University of Notre Dame, to build a new astronomical spectrometer named “iLocater” for its next-generation of instruments. The instrument was selected from among new hardware concepts proposed by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LBT&lt;/span&gt; observatory&amp;#8217;s domestic and international partners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; iLocater is an ultra-precise spectrometer that will be built in the astrophysics laboratory at Nieuwland Science Hall. It will detect and study Earth-like planets located within the habitable zone around the nearest stars. In addition to determining planetary orbits as well as their mass and density, iLocater will also probe their atmospheres to assess chemical composition. The group that approved the project included the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LBT&lt;/span&gt; science steering committee, board, and observatory director.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iLocater is the first high-resolution astronomical spectrometer designed to operate at infrared wavelengths and behind an adaptive optics system which corrects for image blurring effects caused by Earth’s atmosphere. Crepp, says the results from NASA’s Kepler space mission have motivated his research by discovering several planets in the habitable zone around distant stars–some 500 light-years away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Kepler is telling us the statistics of exoplanets and that Earth-like worlds may indeed be common,” he says. “We would like to build an instrument that searches for planets much closer to home … the solar neighborhood must be teeming with small terrestrial worlds with potentially hospitable climates. By studying these planets, we can learn about their physical properties to place the existence of Earth (and its inhabitants) into context.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crepp’s instrument is supported in part by a &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt; Early Career Fellowship that will help fund iLocater’s initial development stage. However, he is seeking additional support to complete the project. The technology being developed at Notre Dame will allow for extrasolar planet studies of unprecedented detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We can probe their atmospheres and ask the question: ‘Do these planets have a similar composition as the Earth? Do they have oxygen, carbon dioxide, nitrogen, and all of the other chemical constituents that we think may be necessary for the development of life?’” Crepp says. “Now, instead of speculating about life, we are one step closer to answering that question.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;LBT&lt;/span&gt; is the largest and most advanced telescope facility in the world. It is operated by a consortium consisting of Notre Dame, Ohio State, the University of Arizona, the University of Minnesota, the University of Virginia, and the nations of Italy and Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Gene Stowe</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48785</id>
    <published>2014-05-16T09:55:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-12T10:45:47-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48785-kellogg-researchers-win-usaid-grants-to-investigate-democracy-human-rights-and-governance-in-africa/"/>
    <title>Kellogg researchers win USAID grants to investigate democracy, human rights and governance in Africa</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p style="width: 301px;" class="image-right captioned"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/133129/jaimie_bleck_300.jpg" alt="" /&gt; Jaimie Bleck&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;USAID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; announced winners of a new, nationwide competition for innovative projects in the field of democracy, human rights and governance last week, scholars associated with the University of Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt; had won two of the coveted nine awards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame political scientist &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/bleck.shtml"&gt;Jaimie Bleck&lt;/a&gt; and economist Philippe LeMay-Boucher of Scotland’s Heriot-Watt University received a $90,000 grant to &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/48370-political-scientist-jaimie-bleck-wins-acls-usai/"&gt;examine the role of Malian discussion groups known as grinw&lt;/a&gt; in rebuilding civil society and democracy in Mali, where a recent coup and insurgency has torn apart a state known for inter-ethnic tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We are interested in the role these indigenous informal institutions play in Mali’s post-conflict reconstruction—and in particular if they are able to help rebuild trust between ethnic groups and faith in democracy,” said Bleck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notre Dame political scientist &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/dowd.shtml"&gt;Rev. Robert Dowd, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt; , and University of Virginia economist Molly Lipscomb received a $75,000 grant to study the link between public health, good governance and democratic politics in East Africa. They are building on a project already underway in western Uganda to examine whether citizens view local leaders who promote public-health initiatives as more popular and effective than other leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What is in the best interest of politicians is not always in the best interest of the public in the developing world,” said Dowd. “We want to see how good public service delivery can also be good politics at the local level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="width: 301px;" class="image-left captioned"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/133126/father_bob_dowd_300.jpg" alt="" /&gt; Rev. Robert Dowd, C.S.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both projects, combining regional expertise in Africa with cutting-edge methodology, stem from interdisciplinary research collaborations developed at the Kellogg Institute, where Bleck and Dowd are faculty fellows and Dowd directs the &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/index.shtml"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development Studies and Solidarity&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bleck, the Ford Family Assistant Professor of Political Science, and LeMay-Boucher found immediate common interest in West Africa when he arrived at the institute last fall on a &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/vfellowships/index.shtml"&gt;Kellogg Visiting Fellowship&lt;/a&gt; . Lipscomb and Dowd’s collaboration dates to her time as a Kellogg faculty fellow, before moving to the University of Virginia in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The projects benefited from initial Kellogg seed grants that the researchers leveraged for additional funding. In the case of Bleck and LeMay-Boucher, the &lt;a href="http://ndigd.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Initiative for Global Development&lt;/a&gt; provided expert assistance as the pair developed their &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;USAID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a wonderful opportunity to develop our project in Mali with great flexibility,” said LeMay-Boucher of the new funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selected from a pool of 103 proposals, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;USAID&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; grants are issued through the &lt;a href="http://www.iie.org/Programs/USAID-Democracy-Fellows-and-Grants-Program"&gt;Democracy Fellows and Grants Program&lt;/a&gt; implemented by the Institute of International Education. The research findings will inform the field programs of USAID’s &lt;a href="http://www.usaid.gov/what-we-do/democracy-human-rights-and-governance"&gt;Center of Excellence on Democracy, Human Rights and Governance&lt;/a&gt; ( &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Center), which is integrating human rights, accountability and civil society issues throughout its core development work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new grants were made possible with support from the American people and by funding from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DRG&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Center and the Bureau for Africa’s Office of Sustainable Development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Elizabeth Rankin, 574-631-9184, &lt;a href="mailto:erankin3@nd.edu"&gt;erankin3@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Elizabeth Rankin</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48781</id>
    <published>2014-05-16T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T09:49:35-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48781-notre-dame-study-reveals-that-particle-size-matters-for-environmental-dna-monitoring/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame study reveals that particle size matters for environmental DNA monitoring</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p style="width: 301px;" class="image-right captioned"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/133177/many_carp_300.jpg" alt="" /&gt; Common carp&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Notre Dame scientists have now published the first detailed investigation of just how small (or big) environmental &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; , or eDNA, particles really are, and their results provide important guidance for all eDNA monitoring programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like investigators combing a crime scene for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; traces from suspects or victims, ecologists now apply similar genetic tests to search the environment for important species. These traces of animal or plant &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in water, soil and air are called environmental &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; . Aquatic eDNA monitoring is emerging as a powerful way to detect harmful species like invasive Asian carp and Burmese pythons or beneficial species like Chinook salmon and Idaho giant salamander. Because this tool is new, little is known about these tiny &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; -containing bits and how to best capture them from water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using common carp, one of the 30 worst invasive species worldwide, the researchers found eDNA in particles ranging from smaller than a mitochondrion to larger than a grain of table salt. Most of the eDNA was in particles between 1 and 10 micrometers, about the same diameter as a single strand of spider silk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“What this means is that eDNA monitoring programs can focus on capturing particles much larger than &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; molecules—which is more affordable and time-saving than methods that target the tiniest particles,” graduate student &lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/grad-students/turner/"&gt;Cameron Turner&lt;/a&gt; , who led the research, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Methods such as centrifugation, although effective, can be very inefficient and limited to small water samples. Monitoring of eDNA in large areas such as the entire Great Lakes watershed requires methods that can handle more water in less time and at lower cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new study from the lab of &lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/lodge/"&gt;David Lodge&lt;/a&gt; , Notre Dame’s Ludmilla F. and Stephen J. Galla Professor of Biological Sciences, and freely available online in the journal &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/2041-210X.12206/abstract"&gt;Methods in Ecology and Evolution&lt;/a&gt; , compared performance across centrifugation and filter pore sizes from 0.2 to 180 micrometers. It also provides a simple equation for calculating combinations of filter pore size and water volume to capture equivalent amounts of eDNA. The scientists used a highly specific quantitative &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;PCR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; test to measure carp eDNA, but they also quantified total eDNA—the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; from any species—and found it was most concentrated in particles smaller than 1 micrometer. Because abundant total eDNA can interfere with the detection of eDNA from a rare species, this result further recommends the use of filter pore sizes greater than 1 micrometer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turner and his co-authors believe that their research will help eDNA researchers and environmental managers using eDNA tools around the globe understand eDNA in the environment and select the best tools to capture it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Finding eDNA from rare species can be like looking for a needle in a haystack,” postdoctoral researcher &lt;a href="http://www3.nd.edu/~lodgelab/?page_id=508"&gt;Matthew Barnes&lt;/a&gt; , also involved with the study, said. “Our research describes the needle so we know what we’re looking for.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper can be found at &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/2041-210X.12206/abstract"&gt;onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/2041-210X.12206/abstract&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Cameron Turner, &lt;a href="mailto:cturner3@nd.edu"&gt;cturner3@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>William G. Gilroy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48782</id>
    <published>2014-05-15T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T09:49:19-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48782-new-paper-examines-natural-selections-role-in-parallel-evolution-and-speciation/"/>
    <title>New paper examines natural selection’s role in parallel evolution and speciation</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/133086/soria_carrascos_300.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://federlab.nd.edu/"&gt;Jeffrey L. Feder&lt;/a&gt; , a professor of biological sciences at the University of Notre Dame, is a co-author of a paper featured Thursday (May 15) on the cover of the May 16 issue of the prestigious journal &lt;a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/344/6185/738.full"&gt;Science&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper describes the genomic basis for parallel evolution in the walking stick insect, Timema cristinae. Parallel evolution occurs when similar traits evolve independently in different related populations due to natural selection. There are many examples documenting parallel changes in the physical appearance and physiological characteristics of organisms when they independently experience the same environmental conditions in nature. What was not known until now was the degree to which the same or different sets of genes underlie these parallel “phenotypic” changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To determine this, Feder and colleagues transplanted different “ecotypes” of Timema specialized to feed on two different species of plants between the plants at a field site in southern California. Through Next Generation &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; sequencing of the offspring of surviving individuals, they measured the degree to which genes across the entire genome of the stick insects changed in response to the experimental manipulation. These results provided a base line to compare to patterns of genomic divergence observed in nature among a series of geographically separated pairs of Timema populations attacking the two plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers reported finding that early stages of parallel speciation in the stick insect involved mostly non-parallel genetic divergence between the ecotypes. However, they also detected parallel genomic divergence for a subset of genes across populations involving mostly changes in protein coding regions of genes having specific molecular functions. Thus, some genetic changes appear to be shared while others differ when populations evolve similar adaptive traits in parallel. Feder and his fellow researchers stressed that their findings were enabled by the whole genome &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DNA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; sequencing approach and bioinformatics strategy used in the study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick Nosil at the University of Sheffield was senior author of the paper. The paper can be found at &lt;a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/344/6185/738.full"&gt;www.sciencemag.org/content/344/6185/738.full&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Jeffrey L. Feder, 574-631-4159, &lt;a href="mailto:Jeffrey.L.Feder.2@nd.edu"&gt;Jeffrey.L.Feder.2@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>William G. Gilroy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48783</id>
    <published>2014-05-15T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T09:51:08-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48783-haifeng-gao-receives-research-award-from-the-department-of-army/"/>
    <title>Haifeng Gao receives research award from the Department of Army</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://energy.nd.edu/assets/133058/haifeng_gao.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://chemistry.nd.edu/people/haifeng-gao/"&gt;Haifeng Gao&lt;/a&gt; , cSEND Faculty, and Assistant Professor of chemistry and biochemistry at the University of Notre Dame, was recently awarded a $150,000 research award from the Chemical Sciences Division of the Department of Army’s Research Office. The research award will begin this summer and can be used for three years of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be considered for the award, Gao submitted a proposal titled, “Regulating inter-polymer chain reaction in nanospace: an efficient method to produce hyperbranched polymer with uniform structure.” Over 200 million tons of synthetic polymers are produced annually around the world. All synthetic polymers carry distributions on molecular weights, chemical compositions, and architectures, so developing robust synthetic methods to accurately control polymer structures is critical for inventing new polymer materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyperbranched polymers with tree-like shapes and multiple chain ends have promising applications in specialty additives, microelectronics, biomedicines and other materials. However, when synthesizing hyperbranched polymers, there is a lack of control in the inter-polymer chain reactions, which significantly limits the function of the polymer materials. Gao will use this research funding to develop a reliable synthetic method to produce hyperbranched polymers with high molecular weight and uniform structure by using discrete confined space to segregate polymer-polymer reactions within each confined nanospace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The new concept of utilizing a confined environment to regulate polymer-polymer reactions is expected to stimulate broad interest on the structural control of polymers with complex architectures that are challenging to achieve in bulk or solution polymerization processes,” Gao said in his proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successfully controlling polymer structures has many useful applications for the Army. Polymer materials are used in many pieces of military equipment, such as sensors on detecting explosives and toxins, which can help protect the lives of soldiers and expand their sensing capabilities in the field.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>&amp;nbsp;</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48786</id>
    <published>2014-05-09T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-12T10:46:09-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48786-notre-dame-ace-program-receives-national-americorps-grant/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame ACE program receives national AmeriCorps grant</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/132482/ace_new_orleans_300.jpg" alt="" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu"&gt;Alliance for Catholic Education&lt;/a&gt; program has received a $207,000 &lt;a href="http://www.nationalservice.gov/programs/americorps"&gt;AmeriCorps&lt;/a&gt; grant from the &lt;a href="http://www.nationalservice.gov/"&gt;Corporation for National and Community Service&lt;/a&gt; ( &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNCS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; ) to support 147 AmeriCorps members who will serve as teachers of record in rural and urban schools throughout the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AmeriCorps members supported by these grants will serve in 50 cities in 14 states. This grant will allow &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to expand its impact and to ensure the placement of carefully formed teachers in the most high-need schools. This partnership with AmeriCorps enables &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to recruit highly talented candidates; supports ACE’s cohesive, research-based high quality academic teacher training; and enables &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to place these members as teachers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“AmeriCorps is an indispensable resource to help meet critical challenges facing our communities,” said &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu/directory/john-staud-phd"&gt;John Staud&lt;/a&gt; , senior administrative director of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; . “We’re thrilled that the Corporation for National and Community Service has recognized the value that AmeriCorps members serving with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; offer to communities across the United States. These AmeriCorps members will meet pressing local needs as they develop civic and leadership skills that can last a lifetime.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“AmeriCorps members are improving the lives of millions of citizens and having a positive and lasting impact on the toughest challenges facing our communities,” said Wendy Spencer, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CEO&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNCS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; . “While they serve others, AmeriCorps members also expand opportunity for themselves—gaining skills and experience to jump-start their careers. As we mark the 20th anniversary of AmeriCorps, we congratulate &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; for its strong application and thank all AmeriCorps members for their dedication to service.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.nationalservice.gov/newsroom/press-releases/2014/national-service-agency-announces-205-million-americorps-funding"&gt;2014 AmeriCorps grant cycle&lt;/a&gt; was highly competitive, due to the strong and growing demand by organizations seeking AmeriCorps resources. The 2014 competition prioritized investments in economic opportunity, education, veterans and military families and disaster services and continued a new initiative for governors and mayors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the grant funding, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNCS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; will make available $163 million in education scholarships for the AmeriCorps members funded by these grants. After completing a full term of service, AmeriCorps members receive an award of $5,645 that they can use to pay for college or to pay back student loans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AmeriCorps engages more than 75,000 members in intensive service annually to serve through nonprofit, faith-based and community organizations at 25,000 locations across the country. These members help communities tackle pressing problems while mobilizing millions of volunteers for the organizations they serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AmeriCorps program marks its 20th anniversary in 2014. Since 1994, more than 830,000 Americans have provided more than 1 billion hours of service addressing critical challenges from poverty and hunger to disasters and the dropout crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is a leading program of the University of Notre Dame that recruits, educates and supports talented college graduates who serve as teachers in under-resourced schools across the United States. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;ACE&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; teachers simultaneously participate in an innovative two-year &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu/academics/med"&gt;Master of Education&lt;/a&gt; degree that prepares them for the rigors of the classroom and to become the next generation of educational leaders for America’s elementary and secondary schools. For more information, visit &lt;a href="http://ace.nd.edu/teach/"&gt;ace.nd.edu/teach&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AmeriCorps is administered by the Corporation for National and Community Service, a federal agency that engages more than 5 million Americans in service through AmeriCorps, Senior Corps, the Social Innovation Fund and the Volunteer Generation Fund. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CNCS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; also leads the president’s national call to service initiative, &lt;a href="http://www.serve.gov/"&gt;United We Serve&lt;/a&gt; . For more information, visit &lt;a href="http://www.NationalService.gov"&gt;www.NationalService.gov&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Kathleen Fulcher, 574-631-7052, &lt;a href="mailto:ace.1@nd.edu"&gt;ace.1@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Bill Schmitt</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48784</id>
    <published>2014-05-07T09:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-10T09:54:26-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48784-new-paper-provides-important-insights-into-how-carcinoma-associated-fibroblasts-function-in-breast-cancers/"/>
    <title>New paper provides important insights into how carcinoma-associated fibroblasts function in breast cancers</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p style="width: 301px;" class="image-right captioned"&gt;&lt;img src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/132404/pd_caf_image_300.jpg" alt="" /&gt; Carcinoma-associated fibroblasts (CAFs)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new paper by a team of researchers led by &lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/faculty/schafer/"&gt;Zachary T. Schafer&lt;/a&gt; , Coleman Assistant Professor of Cancer Biology in the &lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Biological Sciences&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Notre Dame, offers important new insights into the role carcinoma-associated fibroblasts (CAFs) play in tumor biology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of recent studies have revealed CAFs to be a major contributor to tumor progression through a variety of mechanisms. Despite this information, the precise role CAFs play in augmenting the growth of tumors is still poorly understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their new paper, Schafer and his fellow researchers describe a critical role for CAFs in blocking anoikis, a cell death process that inhibits the spread of tumor cells to distant sites, through the secretion of insulin-like growth factor-binding proteins (IGFBPs). They revealed the precise molecular mechanism utilized by IGFBPs to inhibit anoikis: the stabilization of an anti-cell-death protein called Mcl-1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“While cells present in the tumor microenvironment are now widely appreciated to actively contribute to tumor progression, our studies have unveiled a novel mechanism by which this can occur,” Schafer said. “Therapies designed to hinder this role for IGFBPs might be particularly useful in slowing breast cancer metastasis.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schafer noted, however, that additional pre-clinical studies are necessary to better understand which IGFBPs might be amenable to target and to determine the precise point during tumor progression that &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IGBFP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; inhibition could be effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study stems from a &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/27097-notre-dame-cancer-researcher-named-v-scholar/"&gt;V Scholar Award&lt;/a&gt; from the V Foundation for Cancer Research that was awarded to Schafer in 2011. Schafer notes that this paper was made possible by the contribution of a diverse and multidisciplinary team of scientists. In particular, the patient &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CAF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; samples utilized in this study were obtained through a collaboration with &lt;a href="http://www.sbmf.org/index.php/pathologists/page/Dr.%20William%20Kaliney"&gt;William Kaliney&lt;/a&gt; , the executive vice president of the South Bend Medical Foundation. Co-first authorship on this paper was shared by &lt;a href="http://biology.nd.edu/people/grad-students/kelsey-weigel/"&gt;Kelsey Weigel&lt;/a&gt; , a graduate student in Schafer’s lab, and Ana Jakimenko, a former postdoctoral fellow in his lab. Additional contributors include Brooke Conti, a Ph.D. student at The Rockefeller University and a 2013 Notre Dame graduate; &lt;a href="http://harpercancer.nd.edu/people/w-matthew-leevy/"&gt;W. Matthew Leevy&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://ndiif.nd.edu/histology/histology-staff/"&gt;Sarah Chapman&lt;/a&gt; from the Notre Dame Integrated Imaging Facility; and &lt;a href="http://chemistry.nd.edu/people/matthew-champion/"&gt;Matthew Champion&lt;/a&gt; from the &lt;a href="http://massspec.nd.edu/"&gt;Mass Spectrometry&amp;amp;Proteomics Facility&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://chemistry.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper was published online on May 7 in the journal &lt;a href="http://mcr.aacrjournals.org/content/early/2014/05/06/1541-7786.MCR-14-0090.abstract?sid=288e0901-dbd9-4bc7-bd95-c4abd9d9d6c8"&gt;Molecular Cancer Research&lt;/a&gt; . It can be found at &lt;a href="http://mcr.aacrjournals.org/content/early/2014/05/06/1541-7786.MCR-14-0090.abstract"&gt;mcr.aacrjournals.org/content/early/2014/05/06/1541-7786. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;MCR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; -14-0090.abstract&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Zachary T. Schafer, 574-631-0875, &lt;a href="mailto:zschafe1@nd.edu"&gt;zschafe1@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>William G. Gilroy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48250</id>
    <published>2014-05-05T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-09T10:30:21-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48250-new-study-highlights-the-benefits-of-eportfolios-in-engineering-education/"/>
    <title>New study highlights the benefits of ePortfolios in engineering education</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://research.nd.edu/assets/132545/computer300.jpg" title="computer300" alt="computer300" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new study by a team of University of Notre Dame researchers reveals that electronic portfolios can be quantitatively and qualitatively analyzed to generate learning engagement analytics that indicate the level to which students are surviving or thriving during their first-semester Intro to Engineering course. This information can provide instructors, teaching assistants and advisers critical early warning signs that can help with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;STEM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; retention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electronic portfolios, or ePortfolios, are digitized collections of material including demonstrations, resources and accomplishments that represent an individual, group or institution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www3.nd.edu/~nchawla/"&gt;Nitesh Chawla&lt;/a&gt; , Frank Freimann Collegiate Associate Professor of Computer Science and Engineering and director of the &lt;a href="http://www.icensa.com/"&gt;Interdisciplinary Center for Network Science and Applications&lt;/a&gt; (iCeNSA), pointed out that ePortfolios have been used in higher education for more than a decade for classroom and program assessments and to support the accreditation and professional licensing of degrees in fields such as education and nursing. More recently, higher education institutions have been using ePortfolios with career services to prepare students for professional transitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Notre Dame has become a leader in the last three years in integrating ePortfolios into the advising process to improve the mentoring process and relationship and help students integrate all their educational experiences in, across and outside of classes throughout multiple years,” &lt;a href="https://nd.digication.com/ambrose/Welcome/"&gt;G. Alex Ambrose&lt;/a&gt; , coordinator of the &lt;a href="http://eportfolio.nd.edu/"&gt;University ePortfolio Initiative&lt;/a&gt; and assistant professional specialist in the &lt;a href="http://ess.nd.edu/"&gt;Education, Schooling and Society&lt;/a&gt; department, said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a best paper runner-up presented at the recent Conference on Learning Analytics and Knowledge, Chawla and his fellow researchers showed that, given the very nature of how ePortfolios are used at Notre Dame, they can be analyzed to measure student engagement levels providing a new digital learning environment opposed to traditional learning management systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Given a series of quantitative features extracted from each students’ ePortfolio describing their interactions with that tool, we are able to provide an estimate of how engaged each student is to their academic program and with respect to his or her peers,” &lt;a href="http://www3.nd.edu/~eaguiar/"&gt;Everaldo Aguiar&lt;/a&gt; , a doctoral student of Chawla and &lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/jbrockman"&gt;Jay Brockman&lt;/a&gt; , associate professor of computer science and engineering and associate dean of engineering, said. “Furthermore, we also showed that there is a significant correlation between these metrics and retention outcomes. That is, students who are described as being highly engaged, based on these ePortfolio-based features, are more likely to be retained in the engineering program than those who display lower levels of engagement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information is especially helpful when incorporated into the design of early-warning systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We showed that the predictions made by models that had been augmented with ePortfolio-based engagement features were significantly more accurate than those made by models that did not consider that information,” Chawla said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although their paper focused on engineering education, the researchers believe there are many areas where the use of ePortfolios would prove beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our work is ground-breaking in this topic from the integration of various types of data,” Chawla said. “We think there are several areas that can be explored and potentially useful for the next generation of learning analytics by both qualitative and quantitative analysis of data. We can then begin to answer questions about retention, engagement and even success.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper was prepared in collaboration with Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://fys.nd.edu"&gt;First Year of Studies&lt;/a&gt; program. The authors include Aguiar, Chawla, Ambrose, Brockman and &lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu/profiles/vgoodrich"&gt;Victoria Goodrich&lt;/a&gt; , an assistant professional specialist in the &lt;a href="http://engineering.nd.edu"&gt;College of Engineering&lt;/a&gt; . The research was supported in part by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NSF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;STEM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; Enhancement Program ( &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;STEP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; ) grant, titled “ &amp;quot;Finding Your Vocation in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;STEM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;quot;:http://stepcentral.net/projects/251 .”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Nitesh Chawla, 574-631-8716, &lt;a href="mailto:nchawla@nd.edu"&gt;nchawla@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>William G. Gilroy</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48249</id>
    <published>2014-04-23T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-09T10:28:32-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48249-notre-dame-and-cornell-awarded-3-8-million-to-study-hope-and-optimism/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame and Cornell awarded $3.8 million to study hope and optimism</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p style="width: 301px;" class="image-right captioned"&gt;&lt;img src="http://research.nd.edu/assets/132544/samuel_newlands_300.jpg" title="samuel_newlands_300" alt="samuel_newlands_300" /&gt; Samuel Newlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a $3.8 million grant from the &lt;a href="http://www.templeton.org"&gt;John Templeton Foundation&lt;/a&gt; , University of Notre Dame philosopher &lt;a href="http://samnewlands.com"&gt;Samuel Newlands&lt;/a&gt; and Cornell philosopher &lt;a href="http://www.chignell.net"&gt;Andrew Chignell&lt;/a&gt; will co-direct a new research project called “ &lt;a href="http://hopeoptimism.org"&gt;Hope and Optimism: Conceptual and Empirical Investigations&lt;/a&gt; .”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three-year, interdisciplinary effort will explore the theoretical, empirical and practical dimensions of hope and optimism, funding new research in the social sciences, philosophy and analytic theology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I am very excited about this project,” said Newlands, the William J. and Dorothy K. O’Neill Collegiate Associate Professor of &lt;a href="http://philosophy.nd.edu/"&gt;Philosophy&lt;/a&gt; in Notre Dame’s &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu"&gt;College of Arts and Letters&lt;/a&gt; and co-director of the &lt;a href="http://philreligion.nd.edu"&gt;Center for Philosophy of Religion&lt;/a&gt; . “There are not a lot of topics in academia that have such broad appeal and invite careful, specialized research at the same time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Templeton Foundation grant is the largest received by the philosophy departments of the universities to date. With additional funding from Notre Dame and Cornell, the collaborative venture will total $4.5 million. It will include three research initiatives, residential and non-residential fellowship programs, two conferences, writing projects by the co-directors, and creative stage and screen competitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Grants of this size in the humanities are unusual,” said Chignell, associate professor of philosophy at Cornell’s &lt;a href="http://philosophy.cornell.edu/"&gt;Susan Linn Sage School of Philosophy&lt;/a&gt; . “Grants that range across the humanities and social sciences and are shared between two universities are extremely rare. So this is an exciting endeavor and offers new opportunities for all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It could be that by adding people from two universities, we will get a result that is greater than the sum of its parts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Power of Optimism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope and optimism pervade popular discourse. Politics, business, advertising, self-help and religion promote them; doctors and psychologists urge people to cultivate them; and artistic mediums creatively explore their sources and roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there has been a growing trend in the social sciences to examine positive character traits and virtues, Newlands said, more research is needed on the sources and roles of optimism and hope. These concepts are especially important, he noted, as numerous studies have shown significant correlations between optimism and overall physical and psychological well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If you had the ability to choose a single psychological trait that you could improve in yourself, I might recommend optimism because it is correlated with so many other good measures,” he said. “Optimists tend to have longevity, be very healthy, have great life satisfaction and be successful. And this is holding fixed for economic, religious and socio-status measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“But what about hope? Does hopefulness have a similar kind of high correlation with psychological health, general social status and well-being? How might psychologists and sociologists measure hopefulness? These are among the questions we want to address with this project.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chignell agreed that hope and optimism play fundamental roles in human psychology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Let’s suppose hope involves the belief that something you desire is really possible, and perhaps a willingness to act in certain ways given that belief and desire,” he said. “I think that hope — the belief that things you desire have not been ruled out — is essential to our psychological health and ability to keep going.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Newlands, the hope and optimism project also “dovetails perfectly” with Notre Dame’s Catholic mission. “As a Catholic university, we take the theological virtues very seriously. And of the three — faith, hope and love — hope is probably the least explored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I think the Christian faith is a profoundly hopeful religious outlook,” Newlands said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Refractions of Hope&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Newlands and Chignell appreciate the cross-disciplinary aspect of the project, which will include an advisory board of various scholars and scientists who have studied hope and optimism. A planning workshop in January 2013 brought together leaders from multiple disciplines to discuss the latest research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Scheier, professor of psychology at Carnegie Mellon University, attended the workshop and looks forward to further work on the initiative. “The hope and optimism project promises to facilitate interaction between scholars and researchers of diverse disciplines to further our understanding of optimism and hope in significant ways,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The multifaceted project also includes two public components — a playwriting competition and an amateur video competition — requesting submissions that innovatively represent hope and the role it plays in human life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To the credit of the John Templeton Foundation, they strongly support academic research, but they also believe that research should not be done in a vacuum of public interest and discussion,” said Newlands. “So, we thought about ways we could engage different kinds of public audiences with these topics, given how relevant they are.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to supporting the competitions, the project will also fund the premiere of the winning play and host a number of the two- to three-minute videos on the &lt;a href="http://hopeoptimism.org"&gt;Hope and Optimism website&lt;/a&gt; . Newlands anticipates that these creative elements will “provide an avenue for seeing refractions of hope in a different, gripping narrative way, rather than just reading a research study.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Samuel Newlands, 574-631-6471, &lt;a href="mailto:snewlands@nd.edu"&gt;snewlands@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Carrie Gates</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48248</id>
    <published>2014-04-17T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-09T10:26:54-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48248-astronomers-discover-earth-sized-planet-in-habitable-zone/"/>
    <title>Astronomers discover Earth-sized planet in habitable zone</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;University of Notre Dame astrophysicist &lt;a href="http://physics.nd.edu/people/faculty/justin-r-crepp/"&gt;Justin R. Crepp&lt;/a&gt; and researchers from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NASA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; working with the Kepler space mission have detected an Earth-like planet orbiting the habitable zone of a cool star. The planet, which was found using the Kepler Space Telescope, has been identified as Kepler-186f and is 1.11 times the radius of the Earth. Their research, titled “An Earth-sized Planet in the Habitable Zone of a Cool Star,” will be published in the journal &lt;a href="http://www.sciencemag.org/content/344/6181/277"&gt;Science&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday (April 17).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right captioned"&gt;&lt;a href="http://research.nd.edu/assets/130942/original/kepler186f_comparisongraphic_sm.jpg"&gt;&lt;img src="http://research.nd.edu/assets/132542/kepler186f_comparisongraphic_sm_300.jpg" title="kepler186f_comparisongraphic_sm_300" alt="kepler186f_comparisongraphic_sm_300" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kepler-186f is part of a multiplanet system around the star Kepler 186, which has five planets, one of which is in the center of the habitable zone — the region around a star within which a planet can sustain liquid water on its surface. While there have been other discoveries of Earth-sized and smaller planets, those planets have been found in orbits that are too close to their host stars for water to exist in liquid form. Findings taken from three years of data show that the intensity and spectrum of radiation from Kepler-186f indicate that the planet could have an Earth-like atmosphere and water at its surface that is likely to be in liquid form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The host star, Kepler 186, is an M1-type dwarf star, which means it will burn hydrogen forever, so there is ample opportunity to develop life around this particular star. And because it has just the right orbital period, water may exist in a liquid phase on this planet,” said Crepp, who is the Frank M. Freimann Assistant Professor of &lt;a href="http://physics.nd.edu"&gt;Physics&lt;/a&gt; in the &lt;a href="http://science.nd.edu"&gt;College of Science&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crepp is building an instrument at Notre Dame named the &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/44617-nasa-awards-career-fellowship-to-notre-dame-astrophysicist/"&gt;iLocater&lt;/a&gt; that will be the first ultra-precise Doppler spectrometer to be fiber-fed and operated behind an adaptive optics system. His instrument, to be installed at the Large Binocular Telescope in Arizona, will identify terrestrial planets orbiting in the habitable zone of nearby M-dwarf stars, much closer to the Sun than Kepler-186, by achieving unprecedented radial velocity precision at near-infrared wavelengths. He and his research collaborators will also probe nearby terrestrial planets to determine what their atmospheres are made of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Professor Justin Crepp’s outstanding exoplanet research is helping us comprehend our complex universe and in particular those planets that are in the habitable zone. This much-anticipated discovery is shedding new light on planetary systems and their composition,” said &lt;a href="http://science.nd.edu/about/office-of-the-dean/"&gt;Greg Crawford&lt;/a&gt; , dean of the College of Science at the University of Notre Dame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crepp is one of only 11 &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/43284-nasa-names-justin-crepp-a-kepler-participating-scientist/"&gt;Kepler Participating Scientists&lt;/a&gt; in the country. He and his colleagues are advancing the goals of the Kepler Mission by seeking to find terrestrial planets comparable in size to Earth, especially those in the habitable zone of their stars where liquid water exists and where life may be sustained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt; : Justin Crepp, 574-631-4092, &lt;a href="mailto:jcrepp@nd.edu"&gt;jcrepp@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; _&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Marissa Gebhard</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48247</id>
    <published>2014-04-16T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-09T10:23:58-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48247-notre-dame-theologians-explore-life-death-and-resurrection-in-rwanda/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame Theologians Explore Life, Death, and Resurrection in Rwanda</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;The genocide in Rwanda, whose 20th anniversary is being observed worldwide this month, began only a few days after Easter. That the hatred that cost the lives of a million people in this overwhelmingly Christian country could be unleashed so near to Holy Week seems paradoxical, ironic, or even blasphemous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="width: 300px;" class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://research.nd.edu/assets/132540/rwanda_300.jpg" title="rwanda_300" alt="rwanda_300" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But for Jean Bosco Rutagengwa, it is most of all a searing mystery. “This country went through what Jesus Christ went through,” he says of his homeland. “Life, death, and resurrection.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rutagengwa and his wife, Christine, survived the killing 20 years ago, taking refuge in the Hôtel des Mille Collines (the subject of the 2004 film &lt;em&gt;Hotel Rwanda&lt;/em&gt; ). Now residents of Nashua, N.H., and the parents of University of Notre Dame freshman student Christine Rutagengwa, they returned to Rwanda last December.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rutagengwas joined a team of Notre Dame theologians and others led by Rev. Daniel Groody, C.S.C., associate professor of theology and director of the Center for Latino Spirituality and Culture at Notre Dame, to make a short film, &lt;em&gt;Return to Rwanda: A Journey of Hope&lt;/em&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We went to Rwanda to enter into both the history of the events of the genocide and the challenges they present to all of us, especially as we search to know the God who is present among us in the Incarnate Word,” Father Groody says. “We are still looking for the best venues to disseminate the film, but for now we wanted to get it out by the 20th anniversary of the genocide in order to remember the victims and provide a space for people to tell their story. As the events of the genocide happened around the time of Holy Week 20 years ago, we hope it will also be an occasion today to remember all those who suffered such tragedies, and to reflect on both the difficult questions and the faith that emerge from this context.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other members of the team, all of whom stayed at the Hôtel des Mille Collines during their visit, were Rev. Virgilio P. Elizondo, professor of pastoral and Hispanic theology, and Colleen Cross, project coordinator of Notre Dame’s Institute for Latino Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Our research in Rwanda emerged from the desire to understand human life and God’s presence within it, from contexts of acute vulnerability, among the poor and suffering, among those who are crucified today,” Father Groody says. “Jesus himself lived and ministered and walked amid such contexts, and theologically speaking, such margins are places of great revelation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Father Groody, “the Rutagengwas asked us to walk with them in the search to understand where God was in the context of genocide. The golden thread of such research is to try to understand the dynamics of how people believe amidst such unbelievable circumstances, how they find hope amidst such hopeless situations, and how they find strength to trust in God amidst the evil of genocide. In all of this, it is a process of faith seeking understanding from the context of human suffering and the search to find the seeds of resurrection as they burst forth amidst the darkness of our world today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;Learn More&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu/people/faculty/virgilio-p-elizondo/"&gt;Rev. Virgilio P. Elizondo faculty page&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu/people/faculty/daniel-g-groody/"&gt;Rev. Daniel Groody, C.S.C. faculty page&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu"&gt;Department of Theology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://latinostudies.nd.edu"&gt;Institute for Latino Studies&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://vimeo.com/90597947"&gt;Return to Rwanda: A Journey of Hope  film&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/H%C3%B4tel_des_Mille_Collines"&gt;Hôtel des Mille Collines&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0395169/"&gt;Hotel Rwanda film&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;Originally published at &lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/47728-notre-dame-theologians-explore-life-death-and-resurrection-in-rwanda/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48246</id>
    <published>2014-04-11T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-09T10:20:36-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48246-researchers-awarded-grant-to-study-israeli-palestinian-conflict/"/>
    <title>Researchers Awarded Grant to Study Israeli-Palestinian Conflict</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;Three Notre Dame researchers—combining expertise in psychology, religion, and peace—have been awarded a grant from Notre Dame International’s Global Collaboration Initiative to study the Israeli-Palestinian conflict. The researchers will join with a team of scholars from universities in Israel and Palestine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Principal investigator Mark Cummings, along with Laura Miller and Atalia Omer, plans to address the conflict from a “social-ecological” perspective, focusing on the interplay between different levels of society, such as individuals, families, communities, and political groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="width: 164px;" class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://research.nd.edu/assets/132536/cummings_mark_web_resized.jpg" title="cummings_mark_web_resized" alt="cummings_mark_web_resized" /&gt; Mark Cummings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s unlikely one can resolve political tensions between government leaders, communities and families by addressing just one level of society,” says Cummings, professor and Notre Dame Chair of Psychology and a fellow of the Kroc Institute for International Peace Studies. “It’s important to explore how multiple levels of society interact and interconnect.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research project will benefit from the perspectives of scholars from multiple areas within psychology as well as religious studies, says Miller, assistant professor of psychology and peace studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="width: 200px;" class="image-left"&gt;&lt;img src="http://research.nd.edu/assets/132537/miller_resized.jpg" title="miller_resized" alt="miller_resized" /&gt; Laura Miller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To have such diversity within a team—a clinical psychologist, a developmental psychologist, a political psychologist, and a scholar of religious studies—is rare,” Miller says. “Religion is an integral part of how people think of themselves, and a psychological evaluation that considers it is more complete.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="width: 200px;" class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://research.nd.edu/assets/132538/omer_200.jpg" title="omer_200" alt="omer_200" /&gt; Atalia Omer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Global Collaboration Initiative aims to foster international research collaborations among Notre Dame faculty and scholars around the globe. The grants are provided through Notre Dame International, the office dedicated to enhancing Notre Dame’s international visibility, expanding global research, education and community engagement opportunities and strengthening international programs on and off campus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research team plans to build long-term relationships among scholars, using these relationships to bolster peacebuilding efforts, says Omer, assistant professor of religion, conflict and peace studies in the Kroc Institute and Department of Sociology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We’re looking forward to working with other parties to think constructively about processes of change in the region.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;Learn More&amp;gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://psychology.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-by-alpha/e-mark-cummings/"&gt;Mark Cummings faculty page&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://psychology.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-by-alpha/laura-miller/"&gt;Laura Miller faculty page&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://kroc.nd.edu/facultystaff/faculty/atalia-omer"&gt;Atalia Omer faculty page&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://psychology.nd.edu"&gt;Department of Psychology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://sociology.nd.edu"&gt;Department of Sociology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://kroc.nd.edu"&gt;Kroc Institute&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu"&gt;Notre Dame International&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://international.nd.edu/global-collaboration-initiative-gci/"&gt;Global Collaboration Initiative&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/44854-notre-dame-international-funds-global-research-collaborations/"&gt;Related story: Notre Dame International Funds Global Research Collaborations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;Originally published at &lt;a href="http://kroc.nd.edu/news-events/news/researchers-awarded-grant-study-israeli-palestinian-conflict-1611"&gt;kroc.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt; .&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Renée LaReau</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:research.nd.edu,2005:News/48245</id>
    <published>2014-04-10T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2014-05-09T10:17:09-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://research.nd.edu/news/48245-notre-dame-psychologist-darcia-narvaez-to-co-direct-2-6-million-virtue-project/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame Psychologist Darcia Narvaez to Co-Direct $2.6 Million Virtue Project</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p style="width: 164px;" class="image-right"&gt;&lt;img src="http://research.nd.edu/assets/132535/darcia_narvaez_al_web.jpg" title="darcia_narvaez_al_web" alt="darcia_narvaez_al_web" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darcia Narvaez, a professor of psychology in Notre Dame’s College of Arts and Letters, and Nancy Snow, a professor of philosophy at Marquette University, are co-directing a new, interdisciplinary research initiative on virtue, character, and the development of the moral self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three-year project is supported by a $2.6 million grant from the Templeton Religion Trust, which funds “discoveries relating to the big questions of human purpose and ultimate reality.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “Self, Motivation, and Virtue” initiative will award seed funding to 10 new research proposals. The winning projects will use innovative research methods to explore how individuals develop virtue in their lives and how virtue can be cultivated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;How Virtue Develops&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This is a deeply interdisciplinary initiative,” Narvaez says. “Each proposal we review must involve multi-disciplinary teams. This requirement will ensure that science and humanities work hand in hand. After all, we know that virtue, like life, involves both areas of scholarship.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The virtue initiative will also produce an interdisciplinary forum, a website, several book projects, and two conferences, one at Marquette and one at Notre Dame. The publishing projects include a book on the science of virtue, co-written by Narvaez and Snow; a co-edited volume featuring articles by the initiative’s research grant awardees; and a co-edited volume of chapters written by moral self researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The research collaborations among scientists, humanists, theologians, psychologists, and philosophers will examine how virtue develops. “We want to take a deeper dive into whether the development of virtue involves memories, genetics, etc.,” Snow says. “In this way, we can develop a more comprehensive picture of how key periods in our lives—adolescence, retirement, physical decline, traumatic incidents—play a role.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding how individuals develop virtue—and what motivates virtuous behavior—can help families, educators, and communities better address important societal issues, such as bullying, the researchers say. And that goal, they note, aligns perfectly with the Catholic mission of both universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;Evolution and Morality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Narvaez, who joined Notre Dame’s Department of Psychology in 2000, focuses her research on moral cognition, moral development, and moral character. She is the author of &lt;em&gt;Neurobiology and the Development of Human Morality: Evolution, Culture and Wisdom&lt;/em&gt; , due out in August 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She also hosted two symposia with accompanying co-edited books: &lt;em&gt;Evolution, Early Experience, and Human Development&lt;/em&gt; (Oxford University Press, 2013) and &lt;em&gt;Ancestral Landscapes in Human Evolution: Culture, Childrearing, and Social Wellbeing&lt;/em&gt; (Oxford University Press, 2014). Co-editors on the latter book include three Notre Dame colleagues: Agustín Fuentes, professor and chair of the Department of Anthropology; James McKenna, the Rev. Edmund P. Joyce, C.S.C, Professor of Anthropology; and Kristen Valentino, a William J. Shaw Center for Children and Families Assistant Professor of Psychology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next interdisciplinary &lt;a href="http://ccf.nd.edu/symposium/"&gt;symposium&lt;/a&gt; takes place September 27-30, 2014, and focuses on pathways to child flourishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“My own work is interdisciplinary, so the grant project approach comes naturally to me,” Narvaez says. “But to others it does not. In this new project, I look forward to helping others consider their research through an interdisciplinary lens.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class="alt"&gt;Learn More&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://psychology.nd.edu"&gt;Department of Psychology&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://psychology.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-by-alpha/darcia-f-narvaez/"&gt;Darcia Narvaez faculty page&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/~dnarvaez/"&gt;Darcia Narvaez’ professional page&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://www.marquette.edu/phil/faculty_snow.shtml"&gt;Nancy Snow’s Marquette faculty page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://books.wwnorton.com/books/detail.aspx?id=4294978773"&gt;Neurobiology and the Development of Human Morality&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://ukcatalogue.oup.com/product/9780199964253.do"&gt;Ancestral Landscapes in Human Evolution: Culture, Childrearing and Social Wellbeing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://ukcatalogue.oup.com/product/9780199755059.do"&gt;Evolution, Early Experience and Human Development&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://ccf.nd.edu/symposium/"&gt;Pathways to Child Flourishing Symposium&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/16831-research-shows-child-rearing-practices-of-distant-ancestors-foster-morality-compassion-in-kids/"&gt;Related story: Research Shows Child Rearing Practices of Distant Ancestors Foster Morality, Compassion in Kids&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;a href="http://al.nd.edu/news/36758-modern-parenting-may-hinder-brain-development-research-shows/"&gt;Related story: Modern Parenting May Hinder Brain Development, Research Shows&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</content>
    <author>
      <name>Kate Garry</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
