<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:/news</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news.atom"/>
  <title>Diversity at Notre Dame // Diversity at Notre Dame</title>
  <updated>2014-01-17T12:35:00-05:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/45652</id>
    <published>2014-01-17T12:35:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2014-01-17T12:38:29-05:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/45652-prayer-service-to-honor-dr-martin-luther-king-jr/"/>
    <title>Prayer Service to honor Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C. invites all students ,faculty, staff, and their families to attend a prayer service to honor the legacy of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The service will be held Monday, January 20 at 11:45 a.m. in the rotunda of the main building.&amp;nbsp; A reception will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href="https://equity.nd.edu/assets/122152/mlk_prayer_service.pdf%22%3Emlk_prayer_service.pdf"&gt;Details&lt;/a&gt; (PDF)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Scott Palmer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42887</id>
    <published>2013-09-10T14:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T14:20:54-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42887-president-s-oversight-committee-on-diversity-and-inclusion/"/>
    <title>President's Oversight Committee on Diversity and Inclusion</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p&gt;
	On September 10, 2013 President John I. Jenkins, C.S.C. announced the creation of a President&amp;#39;s Oversight Committee on Diversity and Inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;img alt="pdficon_small" src="http://diversity.nd.edu/assets/112547/pdficon_small.png" title="pdficon_small"http://diversity.nd.edu/&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;a href="/assets/112554/president_s_oversight_committee_on_diversity_and_inclusion.pdf"&gt;Read more.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Deidra Sterling</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42984</id>
    <published>2013-09-05T13:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-24T13:43:46-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42984-notre-dame-forum-events-to-explore-women-in-leadership/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame Forum events to explore women in leadership</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="2013-14 Notre Dame Forum" class="noborder" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/110986/forum_2013_300.jpg" title="2013-14 Notre Dame Forum" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The 2013-14 Notre Dame Forum, titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://forum2013.nd.edu/"&gt;Women in Leadership&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; will include a variety of events focusing on the roles and realities of women who are leaders in their fields, beginning with an event this month featuring two leaders in the U.S. Department of Defense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;The goal of this year&amp;rsquo;s forum is to spotlight over the course of the academic year the extraordinary contributions and achievements of women across a range of fields, creating opportunities for the Notre Dame community to learn from the personal accounts of women who have risen to the top of their professions,&amp;rdquo; said University of Notre Dame President &lt;a href="http://president.nd.edu"&gt;Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;I hope this topic will also foster ongoing campus dialogue about the barriers and benefits to women&amp;rsquo;s advancement in this nation and globally, and to encourage reflection on principles of justice and equality, values essential to society&amp;rsquo;s flourishing.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Established by Father Jenkins in 2005, the Notre Dame Forum has featured major talks by leading authorities on complex issues related to immigration, sustainability, global health, the global marketplace, K-12 education and the role of faith in a pluralistic society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Michèle Flournoy and Gen. Ann Dunwoody" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/110995/flournoy_dunwoody.jpg" title="Michèle Flournoy and Gen. Ann Dunwoody" /&gt; Mich&amp;egrave;le Flournoy and Gen. Ann Dunwoody&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In the &lt;a href="http://forum2013.nd.edu/events/2013/09/16/19896-getting-to-the-top-at-the-pentagon/"&gt;first event of this year&amp;rsquo;s forum&lt;/a&gt;, Mich&amp;egrave;le Flournoy, the highest-ranking civilian woman in Pentagon history, and Gen. Ann Dunwoody, the first woman to achieve the rank of four-star general, will be featured. In a conversation moderated by Anne Thompson of &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NBC&lt;/span&gt; News, Flournoy and Dunwoody will share their experiences as leaders, as well as their insights about the challenges facing the Pentagon and the United States today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The event will take place at 7 p.m. Sept. 16 at the Leighton Concert Hall in the DeBartolo Performing Arts Center. Admission is free but tickets are required. More information is available at &lt;a href="http://forum2013.nd.edu/"&gt;forum2013.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/42397-notre-dame-forum-events-to-explore-women-in-leadership/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;September 05, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42872</id>
    <published>2013-08-26T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T13:32:38-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42872-community-events-will-celebrate-africa-the-african-diaspora/"/>
    <title>Community events will celebrate Africa, the African diaspora</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;a href="http://diversity.nd.edu/assets/110063/africana_digital.pdf"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Africana World" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/110009/africana_digital_300.jpg" title="The Africana World" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Click on picture for larger view&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://africana.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Africana Studies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://publicaffairs.nd.edu/civic-leadership/notre-dame-downtown/"&gt;Office of Community Relations&lt;/a&gt; are working together to present a yearlong community celebration of Africa and the African diaspora. The series of programs, lectures and events, called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://artsandculture.nd.edu/community-relations/the-africana-world/"&gt;The Africana World&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;rdquo; is a collaboration between local higher education institutes and community organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The series begins at 6 p.m. Wednesday (Aug. 28) at the &lt;a href="http://artsandculture.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Center for Arts and Culture&lt;/a&gt; with an artist talk by &lt;a href="http://www.cca.edu/academics/faculty/cbernardi"&gt;Claudia Bernardi&lt;/a&gt; called &amp;ldquo;Walls of Hope: African American Elders Share Memories of Integration during the Civil Rights Movement in the &amp;rsquo;60s.&amp;rdquo; An internationally known artist, Bernardi will discuss her most recent collaborative project undertaken with students from Mary Baldwin College, African-American elders from Staunton, W.V., and the &lt;a href="http://wallsofhope.org/"&gt;School of Art&lt;/a&gt; in Perquin, El Salvador. Bernardi will also be working with &lt;a href="http://artsandculture.nd.edu/segura-arts-studio/joe-segura/"&gt;Joe Segura&lt;/a&gt; on a collaborative project in the art studio. Both the talk and a reception afterward are open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Jackie Rucker, associate director of community relations for Notre Dame, said that the focus on the series this year came from a desire to commemorate the anniversary of Martin Luther King Jr.&amp;rsquo;s October 1963 visit to campus. &amp;ldquo;Fifty years ago, Martin Luther King spoke at Notre Dame,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;He was invited by people in the community and they needed a venue. Father Hesburgh volunteered the Stepan Center. A few people on campus were wondering how to commemorate the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;We started to get some events together; some were focused on modern-day African-American culture, some on history. Once we started sharing this with people across the community, we heard from a lot of people who wanted to be a part of it,&amp;rdquo; Rucker said. &amp;ldquo;It will be a communitywide program showcasing Africa and the African diaspora. What I think is really cool about it is it started as a commemoration of the visit 50 years ago that started as a community invitation and is now a communitywide event.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Several public events are planned throughout the fall semester, with more coming in the spring. In addition to Wednesday&amp;rsquo;s artist talk, an exhibition titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://artsandculture.nd.edu/events/2013/10/25/19481-the-african-presence-in-mexico/"&gt;The African Presence in Mexico&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; will open Aug. 22 (Thursday) in the Crossroads Gallery for Contemporary Art in the Center for Arts and Culture. Planned events include film screenings, gospel concerts, lectures and luncheons. A full calendar, updated daily, is online at &lt;a href="http://artsandculture.nd.edu/community-relations/the-africana-world/"&gt;artsandculture.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In September, the Indiana University South Bend Civil Rights Heritage Center will host a gospel memorial concert at the Greater St. John Missionary Baptist Church, 101 N. Adams St., South Bend, that will feature Dianne Robertson Braddock, the sister of Carole Robertson, one of the four schoolgirls killed in the Birmingham, Ala., church bombing the morning of Sept. 15, 1963. Braddock will deliver a keynote address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;In October, our big thing will be Taylor Branch, who spent years chronicling the life of Martin Luther King,&amp;rdquo; Rucker said. Branch, a Pulitzer Prize-winning author, will speak at a community luncheon as well as participate in an informal conversation on journalism today before giving a lecture titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://artsandculture.nd.edu/events/2013/10/01/19531-myth-miracles-from-the-king-years-a-lecture-by-taylor-branch/"&gt;Myth and Miracles from the King Years&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; on Oct. 1 (Tuesday).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The series is sponsored by several Notre Dame and community partners, including the &lt;a href="http://journalism.nd.edu/"&gt;John W. Gallivan Program in Journalism, Ethics and Democracy&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href="http://artsandculture.nd.edu/crossroads-gallery/"&gt;Crossroads Gallery for Contemporary Art&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href="http://performingarts.nd.edu/"&gt;DeBartolo Performing Arts Center&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href="http://ftt.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Film, Television, and Theatre&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href="http://fys.nd.edu/"&gt;First Year of Studies&lt;/a&gt; program; the &lt;a href="http://history.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of History&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href="http://msps.nd.edu/"&gt;Multicultural Student Programs and Services&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href="http://artsandculture.nd.edu/"&gt;Notre Dame Center for Arts and Culture&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href="https://law.nd.edu/international/center-for-civil-and-human-rights/"&gt;Center for Civil and Human Rights&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href="http://provost.nd.edu/"&gt;Office of the Provost&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href="http://seguraarts.nd.edu/"&gt;Segura Arts Studio&lt;/a&gt;; the &lt;a href="http://sniteartmuseum.nd.edu/"&gt;Snite Museum of Art&lt;/a&gt;; and &lt;a href="http://uc.nd.edu/"&gt;University Communications&lt;/a&gt;. Community co-sponsors include Bethel College, Indiana University Medical School, Indiana University South Bend, the IU South Bend Civil Rights Heritage Center, the Center for History, Saint Mary&amp;rsquo;s College, Providing Options, the South Bend Heritage Foundation and Visit South Bend Mishawaka.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	For a full list of events and programming, visit &lt;a href="http://artsandculture.nd.edu/community-relations/the-africana-world"&gt;artsandculture.nd.edu/community-relations/the-africana-world&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Brittany Collins&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/42171-community-events-will-celebrate-africa-the-african-diaspora/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;August 26, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Brittany Collins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42873</id>
    <published>2013-08-22T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T13:32:15-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42873-notre-dame-will-admit-undocumented-students/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame will admit undocumented students</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="University of Notre Dame" class="noborder" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/102310/colorseal200.jpg" title="University of Notre Dame" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The University of Notre Dame has adopted changes in its admission policies that will make possible the admission of undocumented students who successfully compete for a place in its first-year and transfer classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;In making the decision to admit academically qualified men and women who are undocumented,&amp;rdquo; said Don Bishop, associate vice president for undergraduate enrollment, &amp;ldquo;we will strengthen our incoming class and give deserving young people the chance for a Notre Dame education.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Notre Dame is committed to meeting the full demonstrated financial need for all admitted students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Dennis Brown&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/41844-notre-dame-will-admit-undocumented-students/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;August 22, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Dennis Brown</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42874</id>
    <published>2013-05-14T10:20:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T13:30:13-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42874-robinson-center-and-notre-dame-students-create-a-children-s-book/"/>
    <title>Robinson Center and Notre Dame students create children's book</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="RCLC students work on &amp;quot;Every Child Has a Story&amp;quot;" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/101816/rclc_book_300.jpg" title="RCLC students work on &amp;quot;Every Child Has a Story&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	With the help of a group of University of Notre Dame undergraduate students, children from the &lt;a href="http://rclc.nd.edu/"&gt;Robinson Community Learning Center&lt;/a&gt; worked together to publish a book of their stories and artwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://everychildhasastory.wordpress.com/"&gt;Every Child Has a Story,&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; the self-published children&amp;rsquo;s book features three stories with drawings that were created by the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RCLC&lt;/span&gt; students, all between the ages of 7 and 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In spring 2011, a group of about 10 undergraduates from Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://sibc.nd.edu/"&gt;Student International Business Council&lt;/a&gt; decided to create and market a book with the students from the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RCLC&lt;/span&gt; that could provide continued income to the center. Many of the Notre Dame students in the group, working as the Global Development section of the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIBC&lt;/span&gt;, volunteered at the Robinson Center and saw an opportunity to help develop the children&amp;rsquo;s literacy and creativity skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Velshonna Luckey, youth development program director at the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RCLC&lt;/span&gt;, said the children collaborated on the content for the book. &amp;ldquo;The students were divided into small teams and they worked on a few ideas,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;The process was an entire year &amp;ndash; ideas, characters, story and illustration. Each story had to be accompanied with a picture. After all the stories were completed &amp;ndash; some groups had multiple stories &amp;ndash; the top stories from each group were selected.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-left"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Page from &amp;quot;Every Child Has a Story&amp;quot;" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/101817/white_house_200x.jpg" title="Page from &amp;quot;Every Child Has a Story&amp;quot;" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The book contains three of these stories, accompanied by illustrations. One of the stories, for example, is about a visit to the White House to meet President Barack Obama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Last year, the group worked extremely hard to get a professional designer to prepare the book for print,&amp;rdquo; Luckey said. &amp;ldquo;The final version is absolutely beautiful!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The Notre Dame students decided to publish the book through &lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/Every-Child-Has-Story-Edition/dp/1480262528/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1368544867&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=Every+Child+Has+a+Story+notre+dame"&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/a&gt;, setting it up so that the proceeds from sales go back to the Robinson Center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Because so many people are involved at the Robinson Center, we wanted to do as much as we could because they do so much for the kids and the community,&amp;rdquo; said freshman Lisa Wuertz, an &lt;span class="caps"&gt;SIBC&lt;/span&gt; member and Robinson Center volunteer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	After facing setbacks such as when the initial project leader left to study abroad and challenges with printing, the finished book was published in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;It has been amazing for the students seeing their original work in a published book,&amp;rdquo; Luckey said. &amp;ldquo;We spend a lot of time encouraging our students to write and realize that every book they read was started by someone having a good idea and a willingness to work hard to get it published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see the stories the students came up with. It was a lot of fun to see them work with the college students as well. They were a very interesting group of children with very diverse interest and personalities, and they had to work as a team, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t always easy. So they learned a lot about working in groups, sharing ideas and compromise.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Paperback copies of &amp;ldquo;Every Child Has a Story,&amp;rdquo; sold for $12, are available &lt;a href="https://www.createspace.com/4048769"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; or at the Hammes Notre Dame Bookstore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Brittany Collins&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/39948-robinson-center-and-notre-dame-students-create-a-children-s-book/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;May 14, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Brittany Collins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42875</id>
    <published>2013-04-19T10:20:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T13:26:45-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42875-father-jenkins-calls-for-reform-of-immigration-policies/"/>
    <title>Father Jenkins calls for reform of immigration policies</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C." src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/75232/jenkins300.jpg" title="Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href="http://president.nd.edu/"&gt;Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, president of the University of Notre Dame, joined other national leaders of higher education calling for reforms in United States immigration policies on Friday (April 19), the &lt;a href="http://www.immigrationforum.org/"&gt;National Immigration Forum&lt;/a&gt; Campus Day of Action for Immigration Reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Notre Dame is proud of a long history of educating immigrant communities,&amp;rdquo; Father Jenkins said, &amp;ldquo;and our Catholic tradition urges us to provide welcome to the stranger among us. While recognizing the complex legal, economic, social and political questions surrounding immigration in our nation, we join others in calling for just and effective immigration reform. We urge particular attention to reform that will allow deserving, academically qualified young men and women who were brought to the United States as children to have access to higher education in the United States and opportunities following from educational achievement. By educating these young people, we will improve their lives, enrich our nation and live up to our values.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In October 2011, Father Jenkins, with Rev. Dennis H. Holtschneider, C.M., president of DePaul University, led the first of a series of meetings sponsored by the &lt;a href="http://www.accunet.org/i4a/pages/index.cfm?pageid=1"&gt;Association of Catholic Colleges and Universities&lt;/a&gt; to discuss how Catholic colleges and universities might contribute to immigration reform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	More recently, at Notre Dame, Father Jenkins convened a presidential task force, co-chaired by &lt;a href="http://law.nd.edu/directory/paolo-carozza/"&gt;Paolo Carozza&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu/people/faculty/timothy-matovina/"&gt;Timothy Matovina&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://iei.nd.edu/people/iei-fellows/rev-timothy-scully-c-s-c/"&gt;Rev. Timothy Scully, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt; to study how the University could make a unique and meaningful contribution to the current national debate on immigration. Among the task force&amp;rsquo;s recommendations is a seminal academic conference on engagement of immigrants through the perspective of Catholic faith and tradition, particularly emphasizing the experience and contributions of people in the United States who are, or at one time were, undocumented. The conference will be held in March 2014, and its proceedings will be widely disseminated to scholars, church leaders and the wider public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Scholars at Notre Dame have been leaders within higher education on the topic of immigration reform. &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/faculty/fellows/groody.shtml"&gt;Rev. Daniel G. Groody, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, has become an internationally recognized author, speaker and filmmaker on issues related to migration, Latino spirituality, globalization and Catholic social teaching. In addition to the &lt;a href="http://socialconcerns.nd.edu/"&gt;Center for Social Concerns&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://latinostudies.nd.edu/"&gt;Institute for Latino Studies&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt;, several other Notre Dame groups and programs have become involved in immigration research, policy and service. These include the &lt;a href="https://law.nd.edu/international/center-for-civil-and-human-rights/"&gt;Center for Civil and Human Rights&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu/"&gt;Department of Theology&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://iei.nd.edu/"&gt;Institute for Educational Initiatives&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="http://isla.nd.edu/"&gt;Institute for Scholarship in the Liberal Arts&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://kroc.nd.edu"&gt;Kroc Institute for International Peace Studies&lt;/a&gt;, among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/39278-father-jenkins-calls-for-reform-of-immigration-policies/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;April 19, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42876</id>
    <published>2013-04-08T10:20:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T13:25:10-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42876-abdolkarim-soroush-muslim-intellectual-and-reformer-to-address-notre-dames-quran-seminar/"/>
    <title>Abdolkarim Soroush, Muslim intellectual and reformer, to address Notre Dame’s Qur’an Seminar</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Abdolkarim Soroush" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/98330/saroush300.jpg" title="Abdolkarim Soroush" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href="http://www.drsoroush.com/"&gt;Abdolkarim Soroush&lt;/a&gt;, the Iranian scholar, human rights advocate and religious reformer, will give a lecture on &amp;ldquo;The Qur&amp;rsquo;an, Philosophy and Law&amp;rdquo; Thursday (April 11) at 7:30 p.m. in Room 1140 of the Eck Hall of Law at the University of Notre Dame.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Soroush&amp;rsquo;s lecture is the last of a series sponsored by the &lt;a href="http://quranseminar.nd.edu/"&gt;Qur&amp;rsquo;an Seminar&lt;/a&gt;, an academic project hosted by Notre Dame to advance Qur&amp;rsquo;anic scholarship, encourage collaboration among international scholars and present public lectures by leading Muslim intellectuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Soroush, a former professor of the University of Tehran and now a visiting scholar at Yale, Princeton, Harvard and the Wissenschaftskolleg in Berlin, is widely considered the most influential figure in religious intellectual movements in Iran. He was named by Time magazine in 2005 as one of the world&amp;rsquo;s 100 most influential people, and both his supporters and critics have compared his role in arguing for the reform of Islam with that of Martin Luther in reforming Christianity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Abdolkarim Soroush was counted among Time magazine&amp;rsquo;s 100 most influential people because of his fearless campaign for liberty and human dignity in Iran,&amp;rdquo; according to &lt;a href="http://theology.nd.edu/people/faculty/gabriel-said-reynolds/"&gt;Gabriel Said Reynolds&lt;/a&gt;, Tisch Family Associate Professor of Islamic Studies and Theology at Notre Dame and co-director of the Qur&amp;rsquo;an Seminar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;What Time magazine missed, however, is the profound influence that Dr. Soroush has had on a generation of thinkers in both the Islamic world and the West. Dr. Soroush is an intellectual who presents a case for human rights that is meaningful to believers of various religious traditions. Moreover, as an intellectual he has always maintained that the insights of rigorous academic studies are, far from a threat, an important resource to people of faith. In his lecture at Notre Dame, as part of the Qurʾan Seminar, he will reflect on the latest advances in our knowledge of the Qurʾan in the light of Muslim belief.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;: Gabriel Reynolds, 574-631-5138, &lt;a href="mailto:reynolds@nd.edu"&gt;reynolds@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/39026-abdolkarim-soroush-muslim-intellectual-and-reformer-to-address-notre-dames-quran-seminar/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;April 08, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42877</id>
    <published>2013-03-10T10:00:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T13:31:55-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42877-laetare/"/>
    <title>Founders of SPRED, religious education network for people with developmental disabilities, to receive 2013 Laetare Medal</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="laetaremedal" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/39713/laetaremedal.jpg" title="laetaremedal" /&gt; Laetare Medal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Sister Susanne Gallagher, S.P.; Sister Mary Therese Harrington, S.H.; and Rev. James H. McCarthy, founders of the &lt;a href="http://www.spred.org/index.html"&gt;Special Religious Education Development Network&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;SPRED&lt;/span&gt;), will receive the University of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s 2013 Laetare Medal, the oldest and most prestigious honor given to American Catholics, at Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://commencement.nd.edu/"&gt;168th University Commencement ceremony&lt;/a&gt; May 19 (Sunday).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;Sisters Gallagher and Harrington and Father McCarthy have summoned the Church to a crucial and too often overlooked ministry,&amp;rdquo; said Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s president, &lt;a href="http://president.nd.edu/"&gt;Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Insisting that a developmental disability neither tempers Christ&amp;rsquo;s invitation nor restricts one&amp;rsquo;s right to respond, they have ushered countless people to their rightful place at the Eucharistic table.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	SPRED&amp;rsquo;s ministry began in 1960, when Father McCarthy, a priest of the Archdiocese of Chicago, began working with parents, special educators and catechist volunteers of several archdiocesan parishes to make Catholic liturgies and catechesis more accessible to children and adult parishioners with developmental disabilities. Sister Harrington, a member of the Society of Helpers, joined him in 1963 to help with catechetical and administrative work, and Sister Gallagher, a member of the Sisters of Providence, joined them in 1967, assisting both with administration and the training of new special catechists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Energized by the renewed emphasis on catechesis in the wake of the Second Vatican Council, SPRED&amp;rsquo;s ministry expanded beyond Chicago in the 1960s and now the 52-year-old network administers faith formation and sacramental initiation programs for people with special needs in 28 Catholic dioceses and 200 parishes nationwide (including in Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s own diocese of Fort Wayne/South Bend) as well as small faith groups in several other countries including England, Ireland, Scotland, Australia, South Africa, Malta and Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Sister Susanne Gallagher, S.P.; Sister Mary Therese Harrington, S.H.; and Rev. James H. McCarthy" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/95593/spred_laetare.jpg" title="Sister Susanne Gallagher, S.P.; Sister Mary Therese Harrington, S.H.; and Rev. James H. McCarthy" /&gt; Sister Susanne Gallagher, S.P.; Sister Mary Therese Harrington, S.H.; and Rev. James H. McCarthy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	According to its mission statement, SPRED&amp;rsquo;s work is premised on a belief that &amp;ldquo;the Church, the Sacraments and the Love of God are here for all of us. Every man, woman and child has a right to come into the Church and live its liturgy, experience its rich history and traditions, and feel the presence of God in their lives. It is our obligation as Christians to help as we can to make that right a reality for those with physical, mental, emotional and intellectual challenges.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The Laetare (pronounced Lay-tah-ray) Medal is so named because its recipient is announced each year in celebration of Laetare Sunday, the fourth Sunday in Lent on the Church calendar. &amp;ldquo;Laetare,&amp;rdquo; the Latin word for &amp;ldquo;rejoice,&amp;rdquo; is the first word in the entrance antiphon of the Mass that Sunday, which ritually anticipates the celebration of Easter. The medal bears the Latin inscription, &amp;ldquo;Magna est veritas et prevalebit&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;Truth is mighty, and it shall prevail&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Established at Notre Dame in 1883, the Laetare Medal was conceived as an American counterpart of the Golden Rose, a papal honor which antedates the 11th century. The medal has been awarded annually at Notre Dame to a Catholic &amp;ldquo;whose genius has ennobled the arts and sciences, illustrated the ideals of the Church and enriched the heritage of humanity.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Among the 136 previous recipients of the Laetare Medal are Civil War Gen. William Rosecrans, operatic tenor John McCormack, President John F. Kennedy, Catholic Worker foundress Dorothy Day, novelist Walker Percy, Cardinal Joseph Bernardin, labor activist Monsignor George G. Higgins, and jazz composer Dave Brubeck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/38187-laetare/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;March 10, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42878</id>
    <published>2013-02-28T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T13:31:29-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42878-notre-dame-to-host-2013-conference-of-the-africa-faith-justice-network/"/>
    <title>Notre Dame to host 2013 conference of the Africa Faith and Justice Network</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Africa Faith &amp;amp; Justice Network" class="noborder" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/94671/afjn200x.jpg" title="Africa Faith &amp;amp; Justice Network" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The 2013 conference of the &lt;a href="http://www.afjn.org/"&gt;Africa Faith and Justice Network&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AFJN&lt;/span&gt;) will be hosted by the University of Notre Dame this weekend (March 1-3).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The 30th annual &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AFJN&lt;/span&gt; conference, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://www.afjn.org/"&gt;Justice for Africa: Justice for the World,&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; will bring together some 200 scholars, religious and social workers, and policymakers to discuss and reflect on issues of peacebuilding, human rights and social justice in African countries and communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Cardinal Peter Turkson of Ghana, president of the Pontifical Council for Justice and Peace and reputed papabile, or plausible candidate for election as Pope, had planned to attend and give the keynote address at the conference, but was unable to do so due to the upcoming conclave in Rome for the election of Pope Benedict&amp;rsquo;s successor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&amp;ldquo;We are honored that the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AFJN&lt;/span&gt; will be holding its annual conference at Notre Dame,&amp;rdquo; said &lt;a href="http://politicalscience.nd.edu/faculty/faculty-list/rev-robert-dowd-c-s-c/"&gt;Rev. Robert A. Dowd, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, director of the &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/ford/index.shtml"&gt;Ford Family Program in Human Development Studies and Solidarity&lt;/a&gt; in Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;ldquo;For the last 30 years &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AFJN&lt;/span&gt;, informed by Catholic social teaching, has promoted just U.S. relations with Africa. This conference will provide Notre Dame students, faculty and staff with the opportunity to learn from and participate in AFJN&amp;rsquo;s important work of promoting a more just and peaceful world.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;span class="caps"&gt;AFJN&lt;/span&gt; is a community of advocates for responsible U.S. relations with Africa. It works closely with Catholic missionary congregations and numerous Africa-focused coalitions of all persuasions to advocate for U.S. economic and political policies benefiting Africa&amp;rsquo;s poor majority, facilitating an end to armed conflict, establishing equitable trade and investments and promoting sustainable development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;: Rev. Robert A. Dowd, C.S.C., 574-631-4454, &lt;a href="rdowd1@nd.edu"&gt;rdowd1@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/37986-notre-dame-to-host-2013-conference-of-the-africa-faith-justice-network/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;February 28, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42879</id>
    <published>2013-02-12T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T13:31:08-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42879-robinson-community-learning-center-to-celebrate-12th-anniversary/"/>
    <title>Robinson Community Learning Center to celebrate 12th anniversary</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Robinson Community Learning Center" src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/82262/rclc_200.jpg" title="Robinson Community Learning Center" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The &lt;a href="http://rclc.nd.edu/"&gt;Robinson Community Learning Center&lt;/a&gt; will celebrate its 12th anniversary from 5:30 to 7:30 p.m. Feb. 15 (Friday) at the center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Guest speakers for the celebration will include &lt;a href="http://president.nd.edu/"&gt;Rev. John I. Jenkins, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, president of the University of Notre Dame; South Bend Mayor Pete Buttigieg; U.S. Sen. Joe Donnelly; and a representative from U.S. Rep. Jackie Walorski&amp;rsquo;s office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The evening will include live music from local band &lt;a href="http://www.kennedyskitchen.com/"&gt;Kennedy&amp;rsquo;s Kitchen&lt;/a&gt; along with an awards ceremony and refreshments. &lt;a href="http://rclc.nd.edu/programs/shakespeare/monologue-competition/"&gt;Paul Ferguson&lt;/a&gt;, a freshman at Saint Joseph High School who won first place in the high school division of the fifth annual &lt;a href="http://shakespeare.nd.edu/"&gt;Shakespeare at Notre Dame&lt;/a&gt; Regional Shakespeare Monologue Competition in December, will recite his &amp;ldquo;Hamlet&amp;rdquo; monologue. He is participating in the state competition in Indianapolis in March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	In the past few months, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RCLC&lt;/span&gt; has been working to initiate a center-wide writing theme focusing on civic engagement. Many &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RCLC&lt;/span&gt; participants have been exploring the theme of community through writing samples, which will be on display throughout the center during the celebration. The &lt;a href="http://newsinfo.nd.edu/news/37136-young-photographers-document-community-history-of-south-bends-northeast-neighborhood/"&gt;Photoformers&amp;rsquo; exhibit&lt;/a&gt;, which consists of photos and stories collected by students from residents of South Bend&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://northeastneighborhood.com/"&gt;Northeast Neighborhood&lt;/a&gt;, will also be on display.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RCLC&lt;/span&gt; is located at 921 N. Eddy St., South Bend. Founded in 2001 as a community-driven education center sponsored by Notre Dame in partnership with school, religious and civic leaders, the center offers innovative tutoring, violence prevention, youth entrepreneurship and performing arts projects for adults and children in South Bend&amp;rsquo;s Northeast Neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact&lt;/strong&gt;: Jennifer Knapp Beudert, &lt;span class="caps"&gt;RCLC&lt;/span&gt; manager, 574-631-2686, &lt;a href="mailto:knappbeudert.1@nd.edu"&gt;knappbeudert.1@nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Brittany Collins&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/37564-robinson-community-learning-center-to-celebrate-12th-anniversary/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;February 12, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Brittany Collins</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:diversity.nd.edu,2005:News/42880</id>
    <published>2013-01-08T10:00:00-05:00</published>
    <updated>2013-09-20T13:30:41-04:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://diversity.nd.edu/news/42880-rev-william-lies-c-s-c-to-receive-keep-the-dream-alive-award/"/>
    <title>Rev. William Lies, C.S.C., to receive Keep the Dream Alive Award</title>
    <content type="text/html">&lt;p class="image-right"&gt;
	&lt;img alt="Rev. William M. Lies, C.S.C." src="http://news.nd.edu/assets/89635/fr_lies_280.jpg" title="Rev. William M. Lies, C.S.C." /&gt; Rev. William M. Lies, C.S.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	&lt;a href="http://www.nd.edu/about/leadership/council/william-lies/"&gt;Rev. William M. Lies, C.S.C.&lt;/a&gt;, vice president for mission engagement and church affairs at the University of Notre Dame, will receive a Keep the Dream Alive Award from Catholic Charities &lt;span class="caps"&gt;USA&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CCUSA&lt;/span&gt;) on Saturday (Jan. 12) at a Mass in Holy Comforter-Saint Cyprian Roman Catholic Church in Washington, D.C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	CCUSA&amp;rsquo;s Keep the Dream Alive Awards are given annually to honor Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. and &amp;ldquo;contemporary heroes who keep his dream alive through their work to reduce poverty in America.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Father Lies is one of four recipients of this year&amp;rsquo;s Keep the Dream Alive Awards. He will join Carolyn Tisdale, former executive director of Catholic Charities of West Tennessee; Beverly Carrol, assistant director in the United States Conference of Catholic Bishops Secretariat for Cultural Diversity in the Church; and the Honorable Arthur Burnett Sr., retired judge of the District of Columbia Superior Court.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Father Lies, who also is a faculty fellow of the &lt;a href="http://kellogg.nd.edu/"&gt;Kellogg Institute for International Studies&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="http://kroc.nd.edu/"&gt;Kroc Institute for International Peace Studies&lt;/a&gt;, earned his bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in English with minors in French and philosophy from Saint John&amp;rsquo;s University in Collegeville, Minn. He received his master of divinity degree from Notre Dame and his doctorate in political science from the University of Pittsburgh. He entered the Congregation of Holy Cross in 1987, finished his theological training in 1993 and was ordained a year later at the Basilica of the Sacred Heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
	Before his appointment to his present position last February, Father Lies served as executive director of Notre Dame&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="http://socialconcerns.nd.edu/"&gt;Center for Social Concerns&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSC&lt;/span&gt;) for 10 years. The &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSC&lt;/span&gt; offers community-based learning courses and supports community-based research and service opportunities inspired by the Gospel and the Catholic social tradition. During his tenure, the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CSC&lt;/span&gt; doubled its financial resources, staff and faculty and, together with the &lt;a href="http://icl.nd.edu/"&gt;Institute for Church Life&lt;/a&gt;, relocated to new headquarters in Geddes Hall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;
	Originally published by &lt;span class="rel-author"&gt;Michael O. Garvey&lt;/span&gt; at &lt;span class="rel-source"&gt;&lt;a href="http://news.nd.edu/news/36743-rev-william-lies-c-s-c-to-receive-keep-the-dream-alive-award/"&gt;news.nd.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;span class="rel-pubdate"&gt;January 08, 2013&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    <author>
      <name>Michael O. Garvey</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
