<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Franklin &#38; Marshall Magazine</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2014-06-03T18:26:24Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu" />
	<id>http://magazine.fandm.edu/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.6.1">WordPress</generator>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Nancy J. McCann</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Averting a Cocoa Crisis]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/22/averting-a-cocoa-crisis/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5589</id>
		<updated>2014-05-22T18:50:44Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-22T18:50:44Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Cover" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Features" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Is a global chocolate shortage on the horizon? An F&#038;M graduate works with West African farmers as questions linger about the long-term cocoa supply.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/22/averting-a-cocoa-crisis/"><![CDATA[<h2>Is a global chocolate shortage on the horizon? An F&amp;M graduate works with West African farmers as questions linger about the long-term cocoa supply.</h2>
<div id="attachment_5600" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 232px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/1.jpg" rel="lightbox[5589]"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5600" alt="Kip Walk ’84 at the Port of Camden, where a crane unloads cocoa beans fresh off a ship from West Africa." src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/1-e1400784259179-222x300.jpg" width="222" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kip Walk ’84 at the Port of Camden, where a crane unloads cocoa beans fresh off a ship from West Africa. Photo by Dave Debalko</p></div>
<p>The hot equatorial sun beats down on a grove of cocoa trees in Côte d'Ivoire—or Ivory Coast—a West African nation on the Gulf of Guinea. At the base of one of the trees, a couple of local farmers give visitors a tutorial on how to extract the almond-sized cocoa beans from the larger pods. One of the guests, Kip Walk ’84, gets into a rhythm as he slices and scoops the pods by the dozen and places the pulp-coated beans in a large bowl.</p>
<p>Walk is a sustainability executive with Blommer Chocolate Company, the largest cocoa processor and ingredient chocolate supplier in North America. He’s visiting Ivory Coast on a business trip to introduce agricultural practices and better farm management to cocoa farmers. The owner of this farm, a woman named Madame Sopi, invited him to lunch on this humid morning—with a catch.</p>
<p>“Of course, if you’re going to stay for lunch, you’re going to have to earn it,” Madame Sopi said.</p>
<p>Walk did as he was told, and went out to the field to start working with a smile on his face.</p>
<p>“Her confidence and leadership ability made me smile,” Walk says about Madame Sopi. “Her husband had left her so she was working a farm that she inherited from her father. It was an absolutely beautiful farm. She had taken the Blommer training for good agricultural practices and best farm management and really put it to use. She’s been successful in getting her farm certified under the Rainforest Alliance Program. She was running the farm like a business, which is one of our goals: to demonstrate that these farms can be a viable business option to these farmers long-term.”</p>
<p>Small farms like Madame Sopi’s are the backbone of the global cocoa industry because they produce the foundation for chocolate products. Approximately two-thirds of the world’s cocoa comes from West Africa, with Ivory Coast alone producing a third. The average farm produces roughly one metric ton of cocoa beans each year, which equates to only 15 or 16 burlap bags weighing around 150 pounds each. There are “millions of family-run farms contributing to this global supply chain of chocolate,” Walk says.</p>
<p>The supply chain has made headlines around the world in recent months as industry experts wonder whether a cocoa shortage is in the offing. Global demand for cocoa currently exceeds supply as residents in developing nations buy more chocolate and some cocoa farmers switch to different crops. Walk’s job is to encourage farmers to stick with cocoa and use sustainable practices.</p>
<p>“We’re seeing land developed for cocoa lost to other commodities such as rubber, palm and other food crops,” he says. “One of the long-term views is that if this were to continue and cocoa cannot demonstrate itself as a viable crop for smallholder farms, then we really are at a long-term supply risk. That’s one of the basic points that the industry is focusing on: surety of supply for the next several decades.”</p>
<h3>Revitalization: The Key to Sustainability</h3>
<div id="attachment_5602" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 235px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/2.jpg" rel="lightbox[5589]"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5602" alt="Courtesy of Blommer Chocolate Company" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/2-225x300.jpg" width="225" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy of Blommer Chocolate Company</p></div>
<p>Land expansion is no longer a viable solution for increasing cocoa production because little land is available and suitable for cocoa, so the industry is concentrating on farm revitalization. Walk identifies three primary ways to achieve this goal: Good Agricultural Practices (GAP); promoting stronger planting material via tree grafting or creating seedling nurseries; and Aspect of Inputs—engaging farmers to use fertilizers as well as proper management of pesticides and herbicides.</p>
<p>GAT includes proper tree pruning, disease and pest management of the trees, and harvesting at the correct time. Even something as mundane as pulling or preventing weeds allows the tree to utilize its energy for the production of fruit—the cocoa pod.</p>
<p>Grafting in West Africa and other countries is a relatively new technology, especially on family farms. Farmers select stronger material and graft it onto older tree stock. “The genetics of that graft become the primary and the new material brings additional production or disease resistance—whatever you’re selecting—and that farm can be revitalized in the space of about 18 months,” says Walk. “It’s extremely successful in countries like Indonesia and Ecuador.”</p>
<p>If all three methods—GAP, grafting/seedling nurseries and Aspect of Inputs—are used together, some farms could double or even triple their capacity over a period of years, according to Walk. “If that could be done, obviously the farmer sees an improvement in income by bringing more cocoa to the marketplace. The hope is that cocoa farming is then seen as a viable business as opposed to just a subsistence crop. The yield would very comfortably be able to compete against some of those other crops that are right now vying for the same land.”</p>
<p>Visiting the farms often poses logistical challenges for Walk and his colleagues in the cocoa industry. Typically, the family farms are approximately four to eight acres in size, and very dispersed. “That’s why most [sustainability] programs try to work with co-operatives, because you have a group of farmers already aggregated and working within a single structure,” Walk says. “In a country like the Ivory Coast where roads are challenging, it may take you three hours to go 10 miles down the road. Generally, the farm population is extremely welcoming. They're very pleased to see you’re there and willing to support them.”</p>
<div id="attachment_5608" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/pacts-115.jpg" rel="lightbox[5589]"><img class="size-large wp-image-5608" alt="pacts-115" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/pacts-115-600x400.jpg" width="600" height="400" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy of Blommer Chocolate Company</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>A Long-Term Shortage?</h3>
<div id="attachment_5604" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 234px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/4.jpg" rel="lightbox[5589]"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5604" alt="Courtesy of Blommer Chocolate Company" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/4-224x300.jpg" width="224" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy of Blommer Chocolate Company</p></div>
<p>A massive crane swings burlap bags of cocoa beans off a ship from the Ivory Coast on a blustery March day along the banks of the Delaware River in Camden, N.J. The ship has just completed a 14-day journey across the Atlantic loaded with 10,000 tons of cocoa beans. The creamy, sweet scent of cocoa fills the air as flatbed trucks line up to carry the cargo to a nearby warehouse.</p>
<p>Eighty percent of the American cocoa supply arrives through the Ports of Philadelphia and Camden, Walk says. Inside the warehouse, 65 workers and 26 forklifts move 200 tons of cocoa beans an hour into neat rows piled 20 feet high. “It’s organized chaos,” the warehouse manager says. Surrounded by thousands of bags of cocoa beans, Walk talks about a possible cocoa shortage in the future.</p>
<p>“Obviously there’s still chocolate on your shelves at the grocery stores,” he says. “There’s no real risk of those going away in the near-term. The real focus for the industry is at the farm level to avoid a long-term shortage.</p>
<p>“In 2000, the supply and demand was still in balance, but you could already see indications of an aging farm population, significant disease and pest pressure on the farms. It started to become a general view in the cocoa industry that the crop was at risk of plateauing from a production standpoint and potentially could even start to diminish. At Blommer, we started to look at ways to build the skill levels of the farmers to improve the yield per acre and produce additional income for the farmers.”</p>
<p>Walk didn’t set out to work in the chocolate world when he graduated with a degree in American studies at F&amp;M. A high school social studies teacher: that was the plan. But after spending college breaks and summer vacations working in New York City at several commodity houses that traded cocoa, it happened—a full-time job in the land of chocolate. Before graduating from F&amp;M, Walk accepted an offer to work as a broker at the Cocoa Futures Exchange in the World Trade Center.</p>
<p>In 1988, Walk left the frenetic trading floor of the Futures Exchange to work for Blommer, headquartered in Chicago. Twenty-five years later, he is still with the family-owned-and-operated company, now based outside Philadelphia, having worked his way up through the sales department, quality assurance, logistics, and procurement in the commodities division. In 2002, he began participating in the newly formed, industry-led international sustainability group World Cocoa Foundation, based in Washington, D.C., and took an active role in developing models that address the forecasted challenges in the supply chain. He chaired the organization from 2008 to 2011.</p>
<div id="attachment_5603" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/3.jpg" rel="lightbox[5589]"><img class="size-large wp-image-5603" alt="Courtesy of Blommer Chocolate Company" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/3-600x450.jpg" width="600" height="450" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy of Blommer Chocolate Company</p></div>
<h3>Meeting Demand in New Markets</h3>
<p>The family cocoa farms in West Africa are a world away from the headquarters of chocolate companies of the United States. This is where beans are handpicked from cocoa pods, which are manually cut from the cocoa trees with a machete. Because children sometimes work on the family farms, the cocoa industry has had to address the issue of child labor</p>
<p>“The biggest issue is children doing work on their family farms that is not age-appropriate, such as 8-year-olds using machetes, 10-year-olds spraying pesticides, kids carrying heavy loads, and in some instances not being allowed to attend school,” Walk says. “Blommer, the industry at large and the certification groups are all actively working on mitigating and eliminating these issues through education, monitoring and remediation.”</p>
<div id="attachment_5607" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/FM_KipWalk_208.jpg" rel="lightbox[5589]"><img class="size-large wp-image-5607" alt="Dave Debalko" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/FM_KipWalk_208-600x399.jpg" width="600" height="399" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Dave Debalko</p></div>
<p>At the other end of the supply chain are the two biggest consumers of chocolate: the European and United States markets. The growth potential and biggest targets for the chocolate industry are in Asia and India, according to Walk. “If China and India develop a real taste for chocolate—in China, chocolate is not a traditional treat but is growing in popularity—the demand for chocolate or cocoa products is going to continue to see positive growth over the next couple of decades.”</p>
<p>Sustainable farming will play a key role in meeting demand in these new markets. Large international groups, including The Rainforest Alliance, Fair Trade USA, and the World Cocoa Federation, are illuminating the importance of cocoa sustainability. Individual companies, such as Starbucks, General Mills, Costco and Blommer, also have their own sustainability initiatives.</p>
<p>Sustainable Origins is the Blommer initiative that encompasses all of the company’s work in sustainability. Blommer is involved in several private sustainability programs in Ivory Coast, Ecuador and Indonesia. More than 60,000 farmers are participating and have seen better crop yields and premium pricing. The company plans to invest an incremental $45 million in cocoa sustainability efforts by 2020 as a part of its Sustainable Origins program.</p>
<p>“We’re driven by an effort to meet rising consumer demand and to help our customers achieve their sustainability goals,” Walk says. “Blommer pledges to reach an additional 50,000 farmers worldwide, building on existing farmer programs to expand our current farmer base to over 100,000.”</p>
<p>Luckily for chocolate lovers, sustainable practices are increasing thanks to Walk and his colleagues. Still, only 15 percent of the world’s cocoa falls under one of the sustainability banners, Walk says. “There are certainly areas or programs where you can point to benefits of the implementation of those programs, but scaling it up is still going to be a challenge for the industry. There’s still quite a bit of work to be done.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/22/averting-a-cocoa-crisis/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/22/averting-a-cocoa-crisis/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Daina Savage</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Secrets in the Clouds]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/secrets-in-the-clouds/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5592</id>
		<updated>2014-05-22T19:41:26Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-21T18:59:58Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Features" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Frontpage" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[How is a changing climate affecting the cloud forest ecosystem? An F&#038;M professor and her students scale heights to find out.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/secrets-in-the-clouds/"><![CDATA[<h2>How is a changing climate affecting the cloud forest ecosystem? An F&amp;M professor and her students scale heights to find out.</h2>
<div id="attachment_5611" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-large wp-image-5611" alt="1_1" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/1_1-600x200.jpg" width="600" height="200" /><p class="wp-caption-text">The mountains of Monteverde, Costa Rica, provide a moisture-rich environment that supports a complex ecosystem. Photo courtesy of Sybil Gotsch.</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>It’s the first warm day of spring in Lancaster, and a handful of Franklin &amp; Marshall students are tethered high among the treetops in a wooded area tucked beyond the Baker Campus athletic fields along Harrisburg Pike. Sixty feet below are their classmates, offering encouragement and instruction as the music of songbirds fills the air. And swinging from the trees with a broad smile and watchful eye is their delighted professor.</p>
<p>While certainly a high-spirited adventure, this day is designed as a rehearsal, ensuring that the students are ready for a summer research project that will test their physical stamina and problem-solving skills.</p>
<div id="attachment_5616" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 288px"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5616" alt="Courtesy of Sybil Gotsch" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/6-278x300.jpg" width="278" height="300" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Courtesy of Sybil Gotsch</p></div>
<p>“The first day is always a rude awakening,” says Sybil Gotsch, assistant professor of biology at F&amp;M, as her students grumble about needing to return to the gym to work on their cores and quads. The team will train at the College’s Baker Campus each week until the students can scale the heights with ease in preparation for a truly hands-on research project this summer in the mountains of Monteverde, Costa Rica. They hope to build on work done by F&amp;M students in the summer of 2013 in the tropical montane cloud forest—a moisture-rich environment, often enveloped in mist, that supports a complex ecosystem 4,660 feet above sea level—gathering data that could answer questions about changing global climate.</p>
<p>Their days in Costa Rica will be shrouded in perpetual dampness 100 feet above ground in the foggy canopy of trees as they investigate the movement of moisture through epiphytes, or “air plants,” living among the branches. Gotsch and her students are climbing to reach what she calls the “low-hanging fruit” of original scientific research. They will slog through mud and carry more than 500 pounds of equipment to the site before placing hundreds of sensors in the treetops to measure plant responses to moisture levels—all in an effort to determine how environmental conditions are affecting the cloud forest ecosystem.</p>
<p>“If we get an answer, it’s a novel answer,” Gotsch says. “We don’t know a lot, because who wants to go out and do it? Who wants to get this muddy?”</p>
<p>It may be dirty work, but clearly F&amp;M students relish the opportunity to dig deep—or climb high—to answer unexplored questions. It’s why Alexander “Lex” Darby ’15 chose F&amp;M. “I think this is work that a grad student would be doing,” he says. “I came here to do research of this nature, although, of course, you have to be comfortable in a tree to do it.”</p>
<p>“And you have to love plants,” chimes in Mackenzie Dix ’14. “Last year in Costa Rica, we had the chance to work through protocols and try to figure things out with our professor because everything that we’re doing has never been done before.”</p>
<div id="attachment_5615" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-large wp-image-5615" alt="Courtesy of Sybil Gotsch" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/5-600x398.jpg" width="600" height="398" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Sybil Gotsch, F&amp;M assistant professor of biology, studies epiphytes—or “air plants”—living in the canopies of rainforests. Courtesy of Sybil Gotsch</p></div>
<h3>Speaking for the Trees</h3>
<p>The epiphytes growing in the canopy of the Monteverde cloud forests are indicator plants, which serve as markers of environmental conditions. As climate change raises the average altitude of the clouds, the moisture needed by the epiphytes lifts just out of reach, leaving them vulnerable.</p>
<p>The Costa Rican epiphytes comprise a vast community of plants including mosses, vascular plants such as orchids, bromeliads and ferns, among many others. Gotsch says the epiphyte canopies create microhabitats for other organisms and store water and nutrients that can provide important inputs to the ecosystem.</p>
<p>“I think scientists and the public appreciate the tropical montane cloud forests because they have such high biodiversity,” Gotsch says. “On the other hand, it’s harder for people to appreciate the role that this forest, and specifically the canopy plants, have on processes like water cycling.”</p>
<p>Gotsch says that a deeper understanding of this influence can help shape public policy and steer economic decisions. “I’m not only passionate about understanding how plants do what they do, but I feel responsible for doing something meaningful,” she says. “How important are epiphytes to water cycling? We basically have huge bushes in the trees, and if you were to get rid of them, you’d have a completely different forest. But what does that mean? We hope to put a number on the importance of a community that nobody sees.”</p>
<div id="attachment_5612" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-large wp-image-5612" alt="Professor Gotsch and her students ascend trees at F&amp;M’s Baker Campus in preparation for summer research in Costa Rica. Photo by Melissa Hess." src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/2c-600x400.jpg" width="600" height="400" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Professor Gotsch and her students ascend trees at F&amp;M’s Baker Campus in preparation for summer research in Costa Rica. Photo by Melissa Hess.</p></div>
<div id="attachment_5613" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-large wp-image-5613" alt="Photo by Melissa Hess" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/3_1-600x400.jpg" width="600" height="400" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Melissa Hess</p></div>
<p>Last summer’s research focused on the verdant moist heart (what Gotsch refers to as the “Ritz”) of the tropical cloud forest. The students affixed and monitored sensors throughout the canopy in efforts to study the ecophysiology of 14 common vascular epiphyte species. They found that the epiphytes take advantage of the water in clouds and fog to offset water loss due to transpiration. In one month, the plants replenished 70 percent of the water lost due to transpiration by reabsorbing water through the leaves. “Our work showed that the canopy community might be quite dependent on cloud water for its continued survival,” Gotsch says.</p>
<p>This summer, the questions go deeper. Gotsch wants to know what happens when climate change lifts the clouds too far above the canopy for the epiphytes to draw sustenance.</p>
<p>“If you go 10 minutes down the mountainside where there’s less cloud cover, it’s a very different forest,” she says. “I’m interested in studying how epiphyte communities change as precipitation and cloud cover changes and whether we see differences in ecological strategies to cope with drought in different sites.”</p>
<p>What’s happening further down the mountain may point to what could happen in a drier future, not only for the canopy epiphytes, but also for the entire ecosystem.</p>
<h3>Balance in a Changing Environment</h3>
<p>The drought-stress response of plants may be the focus of the summer research, but the F&amp;M team is also looking at the effects of climate and land-use change on the broader biological community. By studying the differences and adaptations of plants, the team hopes the research will illuminate evolutionary strategies in response to a changing climate.</p>
<p>“Comparing the functional traits of similar species in these different locations will give us insight into how certain species are affected by changes in climate, and whether they’ll be able to survive these changes,” says Andrew Glunk ’15, who will return to Costa Rica for his second summer of research. “This is important because our study site (Monteverde) has documented decreases in cloud cover and rainfall, two things essential to epiphyte life.”</p>
<p>Other members of the team are working diligently in Lancaster, crafting experiments in the lab by creating their own clouds. In the College’s Steinman Plant Growth Facility, Dix is working on an independent study project measuring how plants absorb water from the air and their responses in the absence of available moisture. To test these responses, she had to figure out how to craft a fog box to simulate cloud forest conditions. With engineering help from F&amp;M electronics engineer Steve Spadafore and a modified fan, she connected sensors to plant stems so she can see what happens when she subjects the plants to drought conditions and then offers them a cloud bath.</p>
<p>“I’m trying to see how important cloud water is to plants under stress,” she says. “If they don’t get water from the soil, will they rehydrate through their leaves?” She’s discovering that plants experiencing drought react differently. “I didn’t really appreciate how much original research I’d get to do as an undergraduate,” she says.</p>
<h3>‘My Cathedral’</h3>
<p>It’s this hands-on approach that has always inspired Gotsch, and it’s what she loves sharing with students. Her own desire to become a biologist should have come as no surprise to her family. As a child she wanted to live her life outdoors, collecting pressed leaves she gathered and creating her own textbooks. When a high school biology teacher took classes outside for real-world lessons, Gotsch knew she had found her calling.</p>
<p>“That moment it hit me. I can go outside and learn about how the world works. I can understand what I see in a forest,” she recalls. “Once you walk in the forest with the veil lifted, everything changes.”</p>
<p>That inspiration fuels all of her research. Rather than shy away from physical, messy fieldwork, she embraces it.</p>
<p>“People say, ‘Don’t you worry about getting hit by lightning in a tree?’ But I feel so lucky,” she says. “This is my cathedral. By bringing my students, who are so talented in so many disciplines, to this incredible place, they can help me describe the majesty.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/secrets-in-the-clouds/#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/secrets-in-the-clouds/feed/atom/" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Magazine Staff</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[A Brotherhood for Life]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/a-brotherhood-for-life/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5594</id>
		<updated>2014-05-22T19:41:43Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-21T18:58:28Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Features" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Frontpage" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ten Years After Its Founding, F&#038;M Student Group “IMPACT” Takes Its Model Across the Country]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/a-brotherhood-for-life/"><![CDATA[<h2>Ten Years After Its Founding, F&amp;M Student Group “IMPACT” Takes Its Model Across the Country</h2>
<p><em>By Andrew Clark</em></p>
<p>When he was a sophomore at Franklin &amp; Marshall College in 2004, Aviel Ayoung ’06 traveled to Colgate University to visit some friends. He saw something there that caught his eye, something that he needed to take back to F&amp;M. It wasn't a sweatshirt or a poster for his dorm. He had seen a group that was less of a student club and more of a brotherhood, a collection of men from different cultures who worked together to help the community—and each other.</p>
<p>When he got back to campus, he joined forces with Joaquim Hamilton ’06 to create a similar presence in Lancaster.</p>
<p>As Hamilton will tell you, there was a need for this kind of organization. “We wanted a place to talk about issues and careers, a place where we could be social and serious at the same time,” he says.</p>
<p>Hamilton and Ayoung took the initiative to fill this void, creating IMPACT (Intelligent Men of Color Purposefully Accomplishing College Together). The aim of the organization is to encourage African American and Latino men to form bonds—from meetings to programs to events—to share their experiences with one another and help each other excel in college and in the professional world.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5620" alt="" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/Fun-group-shot-600x399.jpg" width="600" height="399" /></p>
<p>As it celebrates its 10th anniversary, IMPACT—which is open to students of all backgrounds—continues to grow both on campus and elsewhere. There is currently an effort to turn IMPACT into a national presence, and other campuses are following the F&amp;M model in launching their own chapters.</p>
<p>“A random idea in a dorm room more than 10 years ago has turned into my life’s purpose for the foreseeable future. I truly couldn’t imagine my story without IMPACT,” says Hamilton, director of college connection at Philadelphia Futures, a nonprofit organization devoted to aiding low-income, first-generation college students. “IMPACT forced me to be a role model. It allowed me to understand how my everyday experience can help shape someone else’s choices. Ultimately, it allowed me to understand that my voice and actions can actually change the world.”</p>
<h3>A Game-Changer</h3>
<p>From classes and paying bills to being away from home for the first time and preparing for the next step in life, the college years can be daunting for 18-to-22 year olds. And considering the social issues that students can face, the benefits of a support system become obvious.</p>
<p>Oliver Tingling ’11 faced those challenges when he stepped onto campus in the fall of 2007. But during his first year, the Bronx native found IMPACT. For Tingling, it was a game-changer.</p>
<p>“When I was a freshman, IMPACT gave me a support team,” recalls Tingling. “I learned tips for my professional life. It allowed me to learn how to speak to professionals, and it's helping me, in my professional life, with Apple Inc. right now.”</p>
<p>What makes IMPACT so effective, its members say, is that it’s not your standard college club. Think of the organization as a collection of brothers who always have each other’s best interests in mind. They mentor one another, through tutoring or helping someone figure out how to balance his life. IMPACT creates workshops to educate its members about important steps, such as how to plan financially. It links members to a wide network of professionals so they can learn about how to take the next step in building a career. And it fosters discourse about issues that can detract from someone's success in college—particularly issues that affect men of color. For IMPACT, being inclusive is critical.</p>
<p>“One of the best aspects of IMPACT is that it branches into so many areas,” says Tingling, who remains involved with the organization. “It’s a support system. It’s a brotherhood. It’s about getting involved with the community. It’s about preparing you for the next step as a young professional.”</p>
<p>In the decade since its inception, IMPACT has been a force when it comes to charitable efforts, as both the local community and those beyond Lancaster’s borders have felt the effects of its initiatives. During one fundraiser, IMPACT raised $2,000 for F&amp;M’s Soccer Africa project, in which F&amp;M students introduce public-health issues to South African youth through sport-based education.</p>
<p>F&amp;M alumni have introduced this facet of the IMPACT model to other institutions, as well. The Arcadia University (in Glenside, Pa.) chapter of the organization, founded by F&amp;M alumnus Stephen Tyson ’07, held a basketball tournament to raise money for Playgrounds for Palestine.</p>
<h3>Spreading the Word</h3>
<p>Like Hamilton and Ayoung, as a newly arrived student at F&amp;M, Tyson felt he needed a support system. He quickly joined IMPACT, reaping the benefits the organization offered. These days, Tyson is the director for the Young Men's Initiative at Philadelphia Futures.</p>
<p>“When I arrived on campus, there was no IMPACT,” recalls Tyson. “Then everything changed. I had a place that gave me familiarity that wasn't there before. From there, I built a lasting camaraderie. We went out and did work in the community. We continued to grow.”</p>
<p>After graduating from F&amp;M, Tyson pursued a master’s degree in international peace and conflict resolution at Arcadia. When he got to the university’s Glenside campus, he saw a need for an organization like IMPACT. His solution? Start another chapter. Setting IMPACT in motion at another school shows the power of the organization, he says.</p>
<div id="attachment_5619" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><img class="size-large wp-image-5619" alt="Students from F&amp;M and Arcadia University celebrate the launch of Arcadia’s IMPACT chapter." src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/Arcadia-Large-Student-Shot-by-OT-600x399.jpg" width="600" height="399" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Students from F&amp;M and Arcadia University celebrate the launch of Arcadia’s IMPACT chapter.</p></div>
<p>“It’s definitely a testament to the impact of IMPACT,” says Tyson, who is currently pursuing an Ed.D at Arcadia. “There wasn’t anything like this on [Arcadia’s] campus. It gave a sense of camaraderie. People on other campuses are asking how to start a chapter. They’ve felt that there’s a lack of places like this on their campuses.”</p>
<p>Last fall, the University at Buffalo launched its own chapter of IMPACT after a member of the university contacted the F&amp;M IMPACT group, which helped the new chapter with its infrastructure. And this could be just the beginning. Two years ago, nine members of IMPACT—Hamilton, Tyson, Tingling, Lorenzo Daughtry-Chambers ’11, Paul Fields, Shadoe Tarver ’10, Derek Pediford ’10, Michael Armstrong ’11 and Lipton Thompson Jr.—turned IMPACT from a campus student group into a 501(c)(3) nonprofit organization.</p>
<p>Back on the F&amp;M campus, the organization remains a significant part of many students’ lives. Current IMPACT president Keiran Miller ’15 will never forget the day he received his IMPACT hoodie during his first year, or the numerous conversations that have helped him adjust to—and succeed in—college.</p>
<p>“I never had a solid group of male friends growing up,” Miller says. “I was always hanging out with my female friends, and I’d be the odd one out. IMPACT allows me to have a network of highly driven men I can rely on in a crisis. The support is immense…I met the older brothers three months ago, and I felt like I was part of something incredible; a movement that would transcend these four years at F&amp;M and take me forward in life.”</p>
<p>As IMPACT aspires to greater heights, one memory from the F&amp;M campus remains etched in Hamilton's mind.</p>
<p>“During my senior year, we packed the Barshinger Center for the IMPACT Male Auction,” Hamilton remembers. “It was a very symbolic moment for us as an organization. We had men from all races and backgrounds and campus affiliations. We raised more than $3,000 for the Milagro House (a long-term, education-based program in Lancaster committed to restoring the lives of homeless women and children). It was great to welcome the larger community into our world, and begin to change the social culture at F&amp;M.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/a-brotherhood-for-life/#comments" thr:count="1"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/a-brotherhood-for-life/feed/atom/" thr:count="1"/>
		<thr:total>1</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Magazine Staff</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[F&amp;M Arts Review Vol. III Excerpts]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/fm-arts-review-vol-iii-excerpts/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5596</id>
		<updated>2014-05-22T19:41:52Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-21T18:57:35Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Features" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Frontpage" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[F&#038;M Alumni Arts Review is an annual publication showcasing literary and visual works by F&#038;M alumni]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/fm-arts-review-vol-iii-excerpts/"><![CDATA[<p><em>The writing and art on pages 24 and 25 appear in Volume III of the F&amp;M Alumni Arts Review, an annual publication showcasing literary and visual works by F&amp;M alumni. The theme of this year’s Review is “Shift.” To see work by other alumni and learn how to submit work for Volume IV, visit <a href="http://fandm.edu/alumni-arts-review">fandm.edu/alumni-arts-review</a>. The submission period for next year’s edition opens Aug. 15.</em></p>
<h3>Tawes Creek</h3>
<p><em>John Shire ’66</em></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5623" alt="John_Shire_Tawes_Creek" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/John_Shire_Tawes_Creek-600x406.jpg" width="600" height="406" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>In Memoriam</h3>
<p><em> Kelly Schenke ’95</em></p>
<p>“I’m what you would call</p>
<p>a slacker,” he said, leaning back,</p>
<p>arms folded, embracing</p>
<p>his own story, the near misses</p>
<p>the posture of sin, that twisted grin</p>
<p>making his eyes seem darker</p>
<p>than they already were,</p>
<p>fiercer than the life I pretend</p>
<p>that he lived.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Stitched Fish</h3>
<p><em>Susan Hagner ’83</em></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5626" alt="stitched_fish_2" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/stitched_fish_2-413x600.jpg" width="413" height="600" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Transmute</h3>
<p><em>Richard Kanter ’89</em></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5625" alt="Kanter-Transmute" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/Kanter-Transmute-414x600.jpg" width="414" height="600" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h3>Underway; Shift Colors</h3>
<p><em>G. Michael Brown ’71</em></p>
<p>Bill is 87, a native Mainer, and a man with as many real adventures as Walter Mitty had imaginary ones, and a Down East accent as thick as molasses in February. I met him 20 years ago, when I moved to Maine. As I showed interest in our state and our town’s history, “Chief,” being a living piece of it, quickly became a mentor.</p>
<p>At first, our excursions took all of an hour and were limited to the neighborhood—albeit with the historical insights of a Smithsonian docent. We’d both had lengthy careers in the Navy; his lasted 20 years, and his tattoos, body art from Manila and Marseilles’ adventures, are now just distorted and faded inked memories. As we began each trip, we’d salute each other with what those in the Navy traditionally say as a ship pulls away from the pier: “Underway; Shift Colors!”</p>
<p>Chief has a story for every building and barn, and it soon became evident that I am to carry this knowledge forward. The one-room schoolhouse where he’d arrived pre-dawn in the frigid winter to start the stove, thus earning a quarter a week; the town’s laundry building that 70 years ago served as the middle school; the swimming hole where skinny dipping had once been commonplace.</p>
<p>Eventually our trips grew in time and distance; from an hour’s walk around town to camping for days in Maine’s North Woods (which brought me as close to hypothermia as I ever care to come). Dirt logging roads. Small town diners. Dexter, Rumford, Ashland.</p>
<p>He’d worked, explored, and hunted in most every corner of the state and was determined to make a Mainer out of me. Finally, after years of being pushed off one-lane dirt roads by fast-moving logging trucks, I’m not fazed anymore.</p>
<p>Chief has begun to show his years, physically and mentally. When next we say “Underway; Shift Colors,” I’ll be taking the helm as the “Maine Man.”</p>
<p>Perhaps fall foliage in Eustis?</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/fm-arts-review-vol-iii-excerpts/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/fm-arts-review-vol-iii-excerpts/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Chris Karlesky ’01</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaching a Generation of Digital Natives]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/teaching-a-generation-of-digital-natives/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5598</id>
		<updated>2014-05-22T19:42:02Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-21T18:56:22Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Features" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Frontpage" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Emerging technologies help professors prepare for a new age of academic engagement]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/teaching-a-generation-of-digital-natives/"><![CDATA[<h2>Emerging technologies help professors prepare for a new age of academic engagement</h2>
<div id="attachment_5628" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/14-04-24-ipad-student-MH-38.jpg" rel="lightbox[5598]"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5628" alt="Melissa Schlags ’17 uses an iPad to view a screencast for her Biology 110 course at F&amp;M. The screencasts have created more opportunities for discussion in the course." src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/14-04-24-ipad-student-MH-38-200x300.jpg" width="200" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Melissa Schlags ’17 uses an iPad to view a screencast for her Biology 110 course at F&amp;M. The screencasts have created more opportunities for discussion in the course.</p></div>
<p>For Dan Ardia and his students in introductory biology, it was time for some old-fashioned Socratic discussion.</p>
<p>Throughout his teaching career, the associate professor of biology at Franklin &amp; Marshall noticed he was spending much of his time in class and during office hours repeating answers to similar questions, while opportunities for more meaningful discussion faded. “It seemed like an inefficient use of everyone’s time,” he says. “So I began to ask, ‘What if I recorded this?’”</p>
<p>Ardia began preparing screencasts—narrated topical presentations students can access on their computers or mobile devices—to convey the prolific amounts of material. The videos worked so well that he could eliminate the 1,300-page, six-pound textbook used in most sections of Biology 110 at F&amp;M.</p>
<p>“It’s been very liberating. It’s opened up opportunities to discuss case studies and data in class,” Ardia says. “We now have deeper discussion because more students are engaged. I love the fact that they can access some of the answers to their questions anytime, anywhere. They’re ready to be stimulated in different ways.”</p>
<p>A 2012 survey by the Pearson Foundation backs up Ardia’s thinking, as 90 percent of students who owned tablet computers said tablets are valuable for educational purposes, while two-thirds said they helped them study more efficiently.</p>
<p>Melissa Schlags ’17, a student in Ardia’s intro biology course during the spring semester, says it was helpful to have the recorded audio and visual reinforcement of core concepts. But she says Ardia’s organization of the material was the key, not just the fact that it was available on video.</p>
<p>“I re-watched all the videos before exams,” says Schlags, a self-proclaimed science fair kid. “In class, Professor Ardia would talk about how things apply to the real world, or discuss a relevant New York Times article, because we came in with knowledge we learned in the screencasts.”</p>
<p>The use of screencasts is an example of blended learning, an emerging pedagogy that combines in-person instruction with digital learning. Ardia is among a handful of professors who have adopted screencasts as advances in technology make new approaches to teaching possible. Against the backdrop of those rapid advances, the College recently launched a task force on instructional technology to support teaching in all disciplines with sustainable models of technology. It’s all happening as a new generation of students—a generation of “digital natives” familiar with the latest mobile and digital technology—enters college.</p>
<p>“There is unlikely to be one model for every professor and every classroom,” says Alan Caniglia, F&amp;M’s vice president for planning and vice provost, who chairs the task force. “This is a multi-pronged initiative to find the best way to support faculty in their development of new teaching methods. The point is not just to innovate—it’s to promote student learning.”</p>
<h3>Access to Learning</h3>
<div id="attachment_5629" class="wp-caption alignright" style="width: 210px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/img001-copy.jpg" rel="lightbox[5598]"><img class="size-medium wp-image-5629" alt="A computer lab created opportunities for student-faculty engagement in the 1980s." src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/img001-copy-200x300.jpg" width="200" height="300" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">A computer lab created opportunities for student-faculty engagement in the 1980s.</p></div>
<p>It’s been three decades since the introduction of personal computers took the F&amp;M campus by storm. In the mid-1980s, F&amp;M became a Mac campus, and the administration encouraged first-year students to purchase personal computers. Around the same time, then-F&amp;M President James Powell said all faculty members should have computers, and there was a sense, Caniglia remembers, “that we had gone off to the races.”</p>
<p>Computer labs opened on campus, a network was established, and soon email became a new way to communicate. The College also invested in a language lab, which opened in the basement of Stager Hall as a resource for professors and students in the foreign languages. For Professor of Spanish Kim Armstrong, it was the beginning of a fascination with technology and its potential to help students learn.</p>
<p>“It was state-of-the-art for the time,” Armstrong says. “The lab had interconnected cassette recorders where students could record their voices. We asked ourselves, ‘should we add computers to this space?’ And so they did. The computers enabled us to experiment with the Internet and software applications for the foreign languages. That’s when I realized technology could enhance what we’re doing with students. It gave us a fresh opportunity to innovate.”</p>
<p>A member of the technology task force, Armstrong remains as passionate about new technology as she was in the early 1990s. She served on a technology working group last summer with Ardia and Professor of Sociology Carol Auster, surveying the technology landscape in higher education and raising questions about the future of technology at F&amp;M. Like Ardia and Auster, Armstrong incorporates screencasts into her courses but says the core of F&amp;M’s liberal arts education hasn’t changed.</p>
<div id="attachment_5631" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/img005-copy.jpg" rel="lightbox[5598]"><img class="size-large wp-image-5631" alt="Students pick up computers and printers during Orientation Weekend in the 1990s." src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/img005-copy-600x398.jpg" width="600" height="398" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Students pick up computers and printers during Orientation Weekend in the 1990s.</p></div>
<p>“We are still mostly teaching students the way we did decades ago,” Armstrong says in her office in Keiper Liberal Arts Building. “What’s changing is access to learning. Blended learning gives students immediate feedback and a chance to review difficult concepts 24/7 when an instructor is not available. But face-to-face time, class discussions, interaction with peers and instructors, and office hours remain vital to learning.”</p>
<p>Last fall, Auster used blended learning in her introductory sociology course for the first time. She narrated eight videos that students could view on Google Drive, part of F&amp;M’s Google Apps for Education program. “The beauty is that it creates more time for discussion,” she says, explaining that previously she would have taken time to lecture about those concepts. “When I surveyed the students after I had posted a couple of screencasts, 53 of 54 students in the two sections said they wanted to continue the screencasts. Part of it might be that they’re digital natives. They grew up with this. I think my screencasts got better with time.”</p>
<p>Google Drive is home to much more than Auster’s screencasts. On one day in mid-April, the F&amp;M community was storing more than 358,000 documents on Google Drive—the majority of them images and written documents. It added up to 1.3 Terabytes of data—the capacity of more than 330 typical MacBook Pro laptops.</p>
<p>“Last semester, the students and I needed to work on a common document, and I was going to put it in Blackboard [an education software program]. One student suggested we use Google Docs,” Armstrong says. “It was a brilliant solution because they could not only share and edit with me, but also with their peers.”</p>
<h3>Lightning Speed</h3>
<p>Armstrong compares the state of technology in higher education to a scene in “Harry Potter,” where Harry touches a wall that opens to reveal a different world. “Technology is helping us to transform education for a whole new generation of learners,” she says. “We’re making magic happen, brick-by-brick.</p>
<p>Helping students and professors tap into new technologies is Teb Locke, F&amp;M’s director of instructional and emerging technologies. Locke is cautious when talking about the impact of new tools in F&amp;M classrooms.</p>
<p>“I don’t think technology changes how students learn,” he says. “But it’s providing new and different means for faculty to have students engage with the content, analyze problems, and visualize things. Technology can get in the way sometimes. It works best when it’s well integrated.”</p>
<p>Locke has many different conversations with professors about approaches to teaching. In the end, there’s no “one-size-fits-all approach,” he says. “At a liberal arts college, you have traditions and different comfort with technology. It’s a melting pot of teaching methods. Sometimes even I feel like I’m not up with the times. Talking with our student worker the other day, I thought to myself, ‘Gosh, I'm kind of a dinosaur already.’”</p>
<p>Technology is evolving at lightning speed, Armstrong says. But she believes professors shouldn’t feel pressured to use emerging technology if it doesn’t fit their style of teaching. “I knew a fellow grad student who used a guitar in her teaching. I never could have pulled that off. So many professors are wonderful teachers. I can’t lecture for 50 minutes, but for others, that’s their strength. Other people are great at leading discussions. And the iPad works for some people, too.”</p>
<p>Two years ago, a small group of professors, Armstrong included, were part of a pilot program in which all students received an iPad for a course. Armstrong loaded each with PowerPoint presentations, and students took notes on the device. “It made me feel a little bit more nimble as a teacher,” she says.</p>
<p>Auster has been nimble, too, especially in her spring semester “iSoc” course, which examined the impact of technology on individuals, relationships and society. The syllabus evolved as the semester went on because so many new articles were being published about technology. “The syllabus is never done,” she says. “But even though this is a course about technology, the students have their electronics off in my class. It’s probably one of the few moments they’re not connected during the day.”</p>
<p>Just then, the phone rings in Auster’s office. Before she can answer it, it stops.</p>
<p>“My phone never rings,” she says. “It’s only email now. That was strange.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/teaching-a-generation-of-digital-natives/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/teaching-a-generation-of-digital-natives/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Chris Karlesky ’01</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Teaming Up for Lessons of Leadership]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/teaming-up-for-lessons-of-leadership/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5634</id>
		<updated>2014-05-22T19:42:11Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-21T18:55:51Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Frontpage" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Matters" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[The Harwood Leadership Seminar saw 12 varsity athletes and 12 non-athletes participating in a series of workshops throughout the 2013-14 academic year, exploring dimensions of leadership such as building a team, self-discipline, accountability and resilience.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/teaming-up-for-lessons-of-leadership/"><![CDATA[<p>As a key member of Franklin &amp; Marshall’s 2013 Centennial Conference champion and NCAA quarterfinalist men’s soccer team, Chase TenBrook ’16 is not easily flustered. But cover the floor with mousetraps and insert a blindfold into the equation, and even he gets a bit uneasy.</p>
<p>That’s the precise situation in which TenBrook and 23 other F&amp;M sophomores found themselves recently at Lancaster’s Spooky Nook Sports complex, where they were guiding each other through a maze of traps during a team-building exercise.</p>
<p>“It was a very nerve-wracking experience,” TenBrook says. “But it was interesting to see the leadership techniques each group used to its advantage. One group had a clapping technique, while others had verbal commands dealing with foot placement. It showed me that leadership is a high-risk, high-reward situation. Everyone has different approaches to leadership. There is no cookie-cutter image of a leader.”</p>
<p>The trip to Spooky Nook was part of the College’s Harwood Leadership Seminar, a program introduced in 2012 for F&amp;M sophomores and made possible by a gift from F&amp;M Trustee Brett Harwood ’71. The students—12 varsity athletes and 12 non-athletes—participated in a series of workshops throughout the 2013-14 academic year, exploring dimensions of leadership such as building a team, self-discipline, accountability and resilience. More than 100 students applied for this year’s program, which was designed and facilitated by athletic coaches and professional staff members of the Office of the Dean of the College.</p>
<div id="attachment_5635" class="wp-caption alignnone" style="width: 610px"><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/Harwood-option-1.jpg" rel="lightbox[5634]"><img class="size-large wp-image-5635" alt="F&amp;M Trustee Brett Harwood ’71 meets students participating in the leadership seminar he created." src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/Harwood-option-1-e1400786533933-600x436.jpg" width="600" height="436" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">F&amp;M Trustee Brett Harwood ’71 meets students participating in the leadership seminar he created.</p></div>
<p>The program arose out of Harwood’s observation during his years in business that athletes have distinctive leadership and teamwork abilities. Principal and co-founder of Harwood Properties LLC, Welcome Parking LLC, and the Parking Advisory Group LLC, Harwood got the idea for the program after a conversation with F&amp;M alumnus and former lacrosse player Jake Gladstone ’10, a financial analyst.</p>
<p>“In my meeting with Jake, he gave me sound financial advice. I realized it took me a while to learn some of the things he learned as a college athlete,” says Harwood, who worked with former Dean of the College Kent Trachte to start the program. “He already had experience with winning, losing, resilience and building a team.”</p>
<p>Beth Throne, F&amp;M’s associate vice president for student and post-graduate development and a former attorney, says the Harwood program helps students develop the qualities employers want to see in the job market. “This is an example of the value of a broad liberal arts education,” Throne says. “Students are developing the ability to work in teams, persevere and lead—exactly the kinds of things that will help them in their careers and their lives.”</p>
<p>This year’s Harwood participants say the workshops helped them develop a variety of skills, from collaboration to communication to teamwork. A two-day leadership course at Gettysburg Battlefield was a highlight for many students.</p>
<p>“The Gettysburg trip was the most memorable part of the program,” says Kabir Hossain ’16, who credits the seminar for helping him become more assertive. “I learned a lot about the Civil War, and how the leadership differed on both sides.”</p>
<p>Asfiyan Amin ’16 recalls surveying different spots on the battlefield and examining the strategies employed by the Union and Confederate forces. “Having that context was integral in cementing the different leadership qualities we discussed afterward,” he says.</p>
<p>At Spooky Nook, mousetraps weren’t the only obstacles the students had to navigate. Hannah Rose Nussbaum ’16, a member of the women’s basketball team, credits a rock-climbing exercise for part of her leadership development. “We had to trust each other because we were holding each other up in case we slipped,” Nussbaum said, adding that between rock climbing and the mousetrap exercise, “I learned so many things that day about communication, and not being closed-minded.”</p>
<p>The Harwood Leadership seminar taught Ashley Christopherson ’16 that there is no such thing as one version of a leader. “I’m a pretty reserved, quiet person,” she said. “Realizing how different everyone is encouraged me to be myself, be confident and not try to conform to being a certain type of leader.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/teaming-up-for-lessons-of-leadership/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/teaming-up-for-lessons-of-leadership/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Timothy Brixius</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Video Spotlight: Aaron Bass &#8217;01]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/video-spotlight-aaron-bass-01/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5637</id>
		<updated>2014-05-22T19:42:22Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-21T18:54:38Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Profiles" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Aaron Bass ’01, principal of KIPP: DuBois Collegiate Academy in Philadelphia, discusses his educational philosophy and passion for preparing students for college.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/video-spotlight-aaron-bass-01/"><![CDATA[<p>Each issue of Franklin &amp; Marshall Magazine links to a video about an alumnus or alumna doing exciting work. The latest profile features Aaron Bass ’01, principal of KIPP: DuBois Collegiate Academy in Philadelphia, who discusses his educational philosophy and passion for preparing students for college.</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/91636188?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" width="600" height="338" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p><em>Video produced by Alexander Monelli</em></p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/video-spotlight-aaron-bass-01/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/21/video-spotlight-aaron-bass-01/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Magazine Staff</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Magical Memories of a Snowy Visit]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/20/magical-memories-of-a-snowy-visit/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5650</id>
		<updated>2014-05-27T19:31:42Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-20T19:31:33Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Voices" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Much like this year, the early months of 1979 brought heavy snow to Pennsylvania. So it was perhaps not a shock that I would be snowed in at F&#038;M during my campus visit as a prospective student.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/20/magical-memories-of-a-snowy-visit/"><![CDATA[<h2>From the Twitterverse</h2>
<p><strong>Ryan Massey:</strong> Everyone is cool, until they get in the passenger seat of their mom’s station wagon. Have a good summer, FandMCollege!</p>
<p><strong>David Kieran: </strong>FandMCollege student in my “After War” seminar: “This course has taught me to become comfortable with the uncomfortable.”</p>
<p><strong>Karmin:</strong> Performing at Franklin &amp; Marshall College tonight. The seniors invited us to the after-party!</p>
<p><strong>Treat Williams ’73:</strong> One of the greatest honors of my life is to have attended the same college, Franklin &amp; Marshall, as Dick Winters. Heroes all.</p>
<p><strong>Lisa Bonchek Adams ’91:</strong> Find a bit of beauty in the world today. Share it. If you can’t find it, create it. Some days this may be hard to do. Persevere.</p>
<p><strong>Karly Anna ’18:</strong> I just get so excited every time I think of my future home, FandMCollege.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h2>Letter to Editor</h2>
<h3>Magical Memories of a Snowy Visit</h3>
<p>Much like this year, the early months of 1979 brought heavy snow to Pennsylvania. So it was perhaps not a shock that I would be snowed in at F&amp;M during my campus visit as a prospective student.</p>
<p>My host, Nanine Hartzenbusch ’82, and some friends were invited to dinner off campus the night of the storm. Although I was supposed to be out of the picture by then, Nanine kindly included me in the dinner party.</p>
<p>Who knows which factors exactly caused me to choose F&amp;M over the other college that had also accepted me? Perhaps it was the chance to see a rehearsal of the late Hugh Evans’ production of “Romeo and Juliet.” Or the happy chaos of the College Center the next morning as calls of canceled classes were recorded on long scrolls of flip-chart paper. The high spirits of one student making his way through the atrium on cross-country skis certainly made an impression on me.</p>
<p>Once I matriculated that fall, it wasn’t long before the rigor of F&amp;M occluded the magical memories of my snowy visit. As a first-generation student with work-study hours added to my schedule, I found it challenging to do well in my classes—and to navigate college life. But I studied with unforgettable professors and made lifelong friends, including my husband. I tackled a double major and spent my whole junior year abroad. At graduation, the College honored me with the Williamson Medal. Since then, I have been committed to giving back to F&amp;M, currently as a member of the Alumni Association Board.</p>
<p>Why did I choose F&amp;M? I’d like to say it was that I understood the value of a first-class liberal arts education. But I suspect it had a lot to do with being snowbound there, and the wonderful dinner at the off-campus apartment of Rahul Akerkar ’81, so wonderfully featured in your Winter issue (“Flavor from the Soul”).</p>
<p>Vanessa Christman ’83<br />
Bryn Mawr, Pa.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/20/magical-memories-of-a-snowy-visit/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/20/magical-memories-of-a-snowy-visit/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Daniel Porterfield</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[The Power of Hands-on Inquiry]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/20/the-power-of-hands-on-inquiry/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5647</id>
		<updated>2014-05-27T19:23:55Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-20T19:22:20Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="President&#039;s Perspective" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Why does F&#038;M create so many research opportunities for undergraduates? Because we know that students learn the most when they engage directly with knowledge creators in hands-on inquiry.]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/20/the-power-of-hands-on-inquiry/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/14-04-11-Spring-Research-Fair-MH-5.jpg" rel="lightbox[5647]"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-5648" alt="14-04-11 Spring Research Fair MH-5" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/05/14-04-11-Spring-Research-Fair-MH-5-300x200.jpg" width="300" height="200" /></a>A highlight of spring at Franklin &amp; Marshall is the research fair, where students present posters and give short talks about the research they’ve undertaken over the past year in disciplines ranging from microbiology to landscape architecture, ethnography to ecology, and politics to public health. It’s exciting to see how so many of our students have spent months exploring a question in incredible depth, and the intangible lessons they learn through that process.</p>
<p>Why does F&amp;M create so many research opportunities for undergraduates? Because we know that students learn the most when they engage directly with knowledge creators in hands-on inquiry. Research projects with real-world import require students to connect advanced knowledge, theories and techniques to a concrete question.</p>
<p>It’s inspiring to see how much students learn beyond the deeper knowledge of a specific subject. Research enables students to pursue a hypothesis wherever it leads—even when the result is inconclusive—which instills a respect for intellectual integrity and the hard labor of getting something right. It is a reality of advanced learning and discovery that powerful inquiry often leads to dead ends, which is fine. True scholars don’t just try to find answers; their enduring job is to pose important questions.</p>
<p>It’s been rewarding to see this kind of growth in students like Jack Madden ’14, who as a sophomore analyzed data from an Australian radio telescope and discovered a rare, extragalactic pulsar. Designed to make it easier for astronomers to spot new pulsars amid the “background noise” telescopes detect, Jack’s senior honors project is assessing the effectiveness of an automated pulsar search algorithm.</p>
<p>Students also learn a great deal about the ethics of scholarship through research—from representing one’s findings accurately and acknowledging the work of others to interacting with other cultures respectfully. For example, Ariel Eland ’14 explored questions of ethnic, religious and political identity with Brazilian musicians, while several of our students are working directly with local Amish and Mennonite communities to foster interaction with modern medical resources.</p>
<p>For many of our students in the sciences, taking part in a nationally funded research project also underscores the value of intellectual collaboration—of working on one small part of a large jigsaw puzzle to advance global knowledge. Take Ryan Samuels ’14, who spent last summer studying volcanoes in New Mexico to help scientists understand what they are learning from the Mars Global Surveyor. Ryan’s work is helping clarify that some surface channels previously thought to have been etched by the flow of water were more likely created by volcanoes. Through this project, Ryan has joined the international community of scientists, including NASA researcher Jacob Bleacher '00, working to build our understanding of the geologic history of Mars.</p>
<p>That’s why F&amp;M has been a national leader in engaging undergraduates in research, and why we’re continuing to expand opportunities for students to receive summer funding, travel grants, and support beyond graduation to help them publish the findings of their honors research. By educating the knowledge creators of tomorrow, we serve the greater good.</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/20/the-power-of-hands-on-inquiry/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/20/the-power-of-hands-on-inquiry/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mickey Blymier</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Call Him a Division I All-American]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/03/call-him-a-division-i-all-american/" />
		<id>http://blogs.fandm.edu/magazine/?p=5692</id>
		<updated>2014-06-03T18:26:24Z</updated>
		<published>2014-05-03T18:23:46Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="Go Diplomats" /><category scheme="http://magazine.fandm.edu" term="spring14" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rick Durso ’15 Writes a New Chapter in F&#038;M’s Wrestling Tradition]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/03/call-him-a-division-i-all-american/"><![CDATA[<h2>Rick Durso ’15 Writes a New Chapter in F&amp;M’s Wrestling Tradition</h2>
<p>Keith Spalding was in his 19th year as president of Franklin &amp; Marshall College. The basement of Mayser Center, which had a dirt floor, was known as “The Pit.” And F&amp;M wrestler Craig Blackman ’81 took fifth at the NCAA Division I Championships to earn All-America honors.</p>
<p>It was 1981, the last time a Diplomat wrestler garnered All-America recognition. That changed in March, when F&amp;M standout Rick Durso ’15 placed eighth in the 141-pound bracket of the NCAA Division I Championships in Oklahoma City to become the first F&amp;M All-American wrestler in more than three decades.</p>
<p><a href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/06/dursorichard-wrestlimg-army11.2.1304.jpg" rel="lightbox[5692]"><img class="alignnone size-large wp-image-5693" alt="durso,richard-wrestlimg-army11.2.1304" src="http://magazine.fandm.edu/files/2014/06/dursorichard-wrestlimg-army11.2.1304-600x367.jpg" width="600" height="367" /></a></p>
<p>Durso’s run through the NCAA Championships has put the Diplomats back on the map in the Division I wrestling world and has set high expectations for student-athletes who will follow him at F&amp;M, says Diplomat head coach Mike Rogers. Wrestling is the only F&amp;M varsity sport that competes at the Division I level.</p>
<p>“Rick placing in the top eight in Division I is a major accomplishment for the program, as it shows that you can accomplish your goals at Franklin &amp; Marshall,” said Rogers, whose team posted a 7-6 dual-meet record for its first winning season in eight years. “It also has established our program on a national level. He laid the groundwork and blazed the trail for athletes to follow.”</p>
<p>“You can clearly accomplish the same things here as you can anywhere else in the country,” Durso said. “We have great coaches, and they provide us with the necessary tools to make it to the top.”</p>
<p>A native of Broomall, Pa., Durso started the season with 13 consecutive wins and ended with the second-most victories in F&amp;M history with 37—behind only the 39 wins he earned during his sophomore campaign. He captured four tournament titles during the season and won three straight matches in the consolation bracket of the prestigious Ken Kraft Midlands Championship at Northwestern University to place fourth, the best-ever finish for an F&amp;M wrestler at the tournament.</p>
<p>Durso earned third at the Eastern Intercollegiate Wrestling Association (EIWA) Championships, the junior's third straight trip to that competition’s medal stand. To get there, he had to claw his way back through the consolation bracket after suffering a 4-2 upset at the hands of Boston University’s Tyler Scotton—the wrestler he later defeated, 3-0, in the third-place match.</p>
<p>In Oklahoma City, Durso started out with two early decisions before dropping a close 4-3 match to No. 4 Devin Carter from Virginia Tech. He bounced back in the consolation round with a dominating 13-2 major decision over Oklahoma State’s Anthony Collica in front of Collica’s home crowd to secure All-America status, before dropping his last two matches of the tournament.</p>
<p>“We expect Rick not only to compete for All-America status again next year, but to fight for a national title,” Rogers said. “I think Rick has the ability and the skills to be the top wrestler in his weight class in the country.”</p>
<p>Durso currently ranks second on the all-time F&amp;M victory list with a record of 106-28 and trails only Blackman, who racked up 117 wins in his career. If he is able to accomplish his goal of becoming a national champion, he would become just the third F&amp;M wrestler to do so, joining Chris Black ’72 and John Stevenson ’72—and it would be another important step in restoring glory to F&amp;M’s rich wrestling tradition.</p>
<p>“I’ve had a lot of alumni reach out to me, whether it’s at tournaments or messaging me on Facebook,” Durso said. “They are very supportive and enthusiastic about what we are doing with the program, and having their support means a lot to me, my teammates, and our coaches.”</p>
]]></content>
		<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/03/call-him-a-division-i-all-american/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://magazine.fandm.edu/2014/05/03/call-him-a-division-i-all-american/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
