<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><feed
  xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  xmlns:thr="http://purl.org/syndication/thread/1.0"
  xml:lang="en-US"
  xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-atom.php"
   >
	<title type="text">Mennonite Church USA</title>
	<subtitle type="text"></subtitle>

	<updated>2014-07-21T17:56:34Z</updated>

	<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" />
	<id>http://www.mennoniteusa.org/feed/atom/</id>
	<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/feed/atom/" />

	<generator uri="http://wordpress.org/" version="3.9.1">WordPress</generator>
	<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mennonite Church USA</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Central District Conference hosts “Black Mennonite Women Rock!”]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/central-district-conference-hosts-black-mennonite-women-rock/" />
		<id>http://www.mennoniteusa.org/?p=17819</id>
		<updated>2014-07-21T15:28:28Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-21T15:28:28Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="News" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cassopolis, Mich. (Camp Friedenswald)—Central District Conference invites women of all races and faith expressions to their annual women’s retreat at Camp Friedenswald, Cassopolis, Mich., Sept. 12–14, 2014. “Black Mennonite Women Rock” will celebrate Anabaptist-Mennonite faith through an African-American cultural style. This retreat is for all women across Mennonite Church USA and beyond. It is an...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/central-district-conference-hosts-black-mennonite-women-rock/"><![CDATA[<p>Cassopolis, Mich. (Camp Friedenswald)—Central District Conference invites women of all races and faith expressions to their annual women’s retreat at Camp Friedenswald, Cassopolis, Mich., Sept. 12–14, 2014.</p>
<p>“Black Mennonite Women Rock” will celebrate Anabaptist-Mennonite faith through an African-American cultural style.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Timeline_Image.jpg"><img class="alignleft  wp-image-17820" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Timeline_Image-300x199.jpg" alt="Timeline_Image" /></a>This retreat is for all women across Mennonite Church USA and beyond. It is an opportunity to enjoy black culture, learn through the lives and stories of black women, and celebrate the leadership gifts of black women in the Mennonite Church.</p>
<p>In addition to classic camp activities such as pontoon boating, hikes through nature, and fellowship around a campfire, this weekend will feature a screening of the documentary “Dark Girls,” along with small group discussion, workshops and the “Ebony Café,” featuring dancing, spoken word and poetry.</p>
<p>Quilting will be a prominent focus of the weekend, with an emphasis on the “Identity Quilt” brought by organizer Cyneatha Millsaps, pastor at Community Mennonite Church in Markham, Ill. Community Mennonite, a racially diverse congregation, and Hively Avenue Mennonite Church, a predominantly white congregation in Elkhart, Ind., have partnered to produce this quilt, which depicts the story of African Americans.</p>
<p>Beginning with their removal from their homelands into forced slavery, the quilt moves through the Civil Rights era and continues to the present, revealing both the struggles and the triumphs of the African-American experience. The quilt is one way the congregations are seeking to address the ever-present challenges of racism and reconciliation.</p>
<div id="attachment_16689" style="width: 146px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/Cyneatha.jpg"><img class="wp-image-16689" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2011/10/Cyneatha-261x300.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Cyneatha Millsaps</p></div>
<p>“As Christians I don’t believe we are supposed to go it alone,” Pastor Millsaps said. “When we know each other better across racial lines, it makes it easier for us to talk together. As black people, we know a lot about white people, but that knowing is not often reciprocal.”</p>
<p>Black Mennonite Women Rock seeks to create safe places for uncomfortable and important conversations to take place among the women gathered.</p>
<div id="attachment_17823" style="width: 146px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Hyacinth-Stevens.jpg"><img class="wp-image-17823" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Hyacinth-Stevens.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Hyacinth Stevens</p></div>
<p>Hyacinth Stevens, co-pastor of King of Glory Tabernacle in the Bronx, N.Y., is the keynote speaker. She pastors alongside her husband, Benjamin Stevens. They have four children ranging in age from three to 13. Hyacinth is also the executive director of Project Charisma After School Center in the Bronx. Stevens has a passion for the empowerment of children and women in the community she serves.</p>
<div id="attachment_17822" style="width: 149px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/CrystalSellersBattle.jpg"><img class="wp-image-17822" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/CrystalSellersBattle-199x300.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Crystal Sellers Battle</p></div>
<p>Dr. Crystal Y. Sellers Battle, assistant professor of music at Bluffton (Ohio) University, will lead music. In addition to teaching, Sellers Battle directs the university gospel choir and serves as the director of Project H.O.M.E., a mentoring program for students of color enrolled at Bluffton University.</p>
<div id="attachment_17307" style="width: 152px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Thompson_Sarah.jpg"><img class="wp-image-17307" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/Thompson_Sarah-249x300.jpg" alt="Sarah Thompson is a graduate of Anabaptist Mennonite Biblical Seminary and currently works as outreach coordinator for Christian Peacemaker Teams." /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sarah Thompson</p></div>
<p>Sarah Thompson, executive director of Christian Peacemaker Teams, will lead a workshop titled “Black and Ethnic Mennonite.” Through her work in the international peace movement as a public speaker and community organizer, she is adept at bringing people together across lines of difference and building momentum for positive social change.</p>
<p>Other speakers include Tia Curry-Cook, Regina Shands Stoltzfus, Joanna Shenk and Nekeisha Alexis-Baker.</p>
<p>For more information, see <a href="http://www.friedenswald.org/programs_womens/retreat">www.friedenswald.org/programs_womens/retreat</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/central-district-conference-hosts-black-mennonite-women-rock/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/central-district-conference-hosts-black-mennonite-women-rock/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Mennonite Church USA</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Spiritual Budget: Managing My Talents]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/spiritual-budget-managing-my-talents/" />
		<id>http://www.mennoniteusa.org/?p=17817</id>
		<updated>2014-07-21T15:07:02Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-21T15:07:02Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Menno Snapshots" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Stewardship" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Glen Guyton As the person responsible for planning the national convention for Mennonite Church USA I get a lot of feedback from people across the denomination.  We, Mennonites, are a very passionate bunch.  We are a very intelligent and gifted group. Mennonites tend to care about a lot of issues of social justice and...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/spiritual-budget-managing-my-talents/"><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_15991" style="width: 209px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/GlenGuyton1.jpg"><img class="wp-image-15991 size-medium" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/GlenGuyton1-199x300.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Glen Guyton is the Chief Operations Officer for Mennonite Church USA and Director of Convention Planning</p></div>
<p><em>By Glen Guyton</em></p>
<p>As the person responsible for planning the <a href="http://convention.mennoniteusa.org/">national convention for Mennonite Church USA</a> I get a lot of feedback from people across the denomination.  We, Mennonites, are a very passionate bunch.  We are a very intelligent and gifted group. <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/about-us/">Mennonites</a> tend to care about a lot of issues of social justice and it impacts how we desire to engage the world.</p>
<p>The Mennonite Church USA Healing &amp; Hope vision statement says, “God calls us to be followers of Jesus Christ and, by the power of the Holy Spirit, to grow as communities of grace, joy and peace, so that God’s healing and hope flow through us to the world.” That flow requires resources; it takes time and energy to get things done.  Any wise steward knows that resources are finite; there is a limit to what we can do.</p>
<p>As Christians we have to realize that God sent Christ to save the world and none of us have been given the power to deliver salvation.  At our very best we are an extension of God’s love without the omnipresence or omnipotence of Yahweh. We have a spiritual limit (time, talent, resources) and therefore we need to have a spiritual budget.</p>
<p>Mennonites are outraged by, interested in, or deeply concerned about a lot of “good” things: creation care; Israel/Palestine; immigration; LGBTQ inclusion; John Howard Yoder; Gender equality; drones; and racism, to name a few. The champions/advocates of each of these issues want me and the denominational staff to also be champions/advocates of these same issues.</p>
<p>But as a good steward of both myself and of the denominational resources, I understand that I cannot be.  I need to be able to listen to God in my personal calling and my vocational calling.</p>
<p>“So here’s what I want you to do, God helping you: Take your everyday, ordinary life—your sleeping, eating, going-to-work, and walking-around life—and place it before God as an offering. Embracing what God does for you is the best thing you can do for him. Don’t become so well-adjusted to your culture that you fit into it without even thinking. Instead, fix your attention on God. You’ll be changed from the inside out. Readily recognize what he wants from you, and quickly respond to it…”(Romans 12:1-2 MSG)</p>
<p>I have often told our staff that, Mennonite Church USA and its affiliated organizations must become leaner and more nimble in order to stay relevant and to be able to move with God’s Spirit.  Can we, as a denomination response to God’s call if we are bogged down by “worldly” issues or “good” causes that may or may not be Godly causes?</p>
<p>What if as good stewards, we decided that Mennonite Church USA (the denomination) would only focus on three things as illustrated in <em><a href="http://www.goshen.edu/mhl/Refocusing/d-av.htm">The Anabaptist Vision</a> </em>by Harold Bender:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Discipleship:</strong> Teaching its members how to live their everyday lives with Jesus as the center of our faith.</li>
<li><strong>Community:</strong> Demonstrating that the church is a family and providing the structure for members to voluntarily commit themselves to one another under mutually agreed upon covenants.</li>
<li><strong>Peace and nonresistance:</strong>  Advocating for peace and justice in our nation and world and providing tools to help others resist violence and injustice.</li>
</ol>
<p>I wonder how that church would look?</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/spiritual-budget-managing-my-talents/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/spiritual-budget-managing-my-talents/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Joanna Shenk</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[KC2015 Speaker Line-Up Announced]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/kc2015-speaker-line-up-announced/" />
		<id>http://www.mennoniteusa.org/?p=17508</id>
		<updated>2014-07-17T16:22:03Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-17T15:08:31Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Convention" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Menno Snapshots" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post was originally shared on the Mennonite Church USA Convention website.  By Convention Staff Worship is the keystone event at convention. Every two years, we come together to be encouraged. We come together to be challenged. We come together to be inspired and energized. We come together to celebrate God in our midst, and...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/kc2015-speaker-line-up-announced/"><![CDATA[<p style="color: #666666;"><em>This post was originally shared on the Mennonite Church USA <a href="http://convention.mennoniteusa.org/kc2015-speaker-line-up-announced/" target="_blank">Convention website</a>. </em></p>
<p style="color: #666666;"><em>By Convention Staff</em></p>
<p style="color: #666666;">Worship is the keystone event at convention. Every two years, we come together to be encouraged. We come together to be challenged. We come together to be inspired and energized. We come together to celebrate God in our midst, and to recommit ourselves to following Jesus “on the way.”</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">We’ve got a great group of speakers planned for KC2015. Check them out!</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;">Tuesday Night, June 30</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;"><a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #009a49 !important;" href="http://i1.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/MichelleArmster.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2058" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;" src="http://i1.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/MichelleArmster.jpg?resize=150%2C150" alt="MichelleArmster" /></a>Michelle Armster</strong> is a pastor, preacher and teacher. She currently serves as the Director for Mennonite Central Committee Central States. Throughout her career, she has provided resourcing, consulting and training for church<span class="text_exposed_show" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;">es, agencies and communities on conflict transformation, and restorative justice. She has had many years of extensive training and experience in meditation, facilitation, conciliation, restorative justice, arbitration, victim/offender mediation, anti-racism and alternatives to violence. She graduated from Lancaster Theological Seminary’s Masters of Divinity program in 2007. Equally as important, she is a creative soul, weaving song and drama through all dimensions of her life. She enjoys creative writing, acting, and singing.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;">Wednesday Morning, July 1</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;"><a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #009a49 !important;" href="http://i0.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/isaac_villegas-5.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-1918" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;" src="http://i0.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/isaac_villegas-5.jpg?resize=150%2C150" alt="isaac_villegas-5" /></a> Isaac S. Villegas</strong> is the pastor of Chapel Hill Mennonite Fellowship in North Carolina. He serves on the Executive Board of Mennonite Church USA and on the Governing Board of the North Carolina Council of Churches.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;">Wednesday Evening, July 1 <em style="font-weight: inherit;">and </em>Saturday Morning, July 4</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;"><a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #009a49 !important;" href="http://i2.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/MicheleHershberger.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2063" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;" src="http://i2.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/MicheleHershberger.jpg?resize=150%2C150" alt="MicheleHershberger" /></a>Michele Hershberger </strong>has been serving the Mennonite Church for over 25 years. She’s been a youth pastor, speaker, playwright and teacher. She now serves as Chair of the Bible and Ministry Department at Hesston College, where<span class="text_exposed_show" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;"> she teaches Bible and Youth Ministry….and loves it! Michele has written extensively, including the books God’s Story, Our Story and A Christian View of Hospitality. Recently she spent a year teaching Bible in Klaipeda, Lithuania at LCC International University. Michele is married to Del Hershberger and they have three young adult children.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;">Thursday Morning, July 2</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;"><a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #009a49 !important;" href="http://i1.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/PatriciaShelly.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2059" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;" src="http://i1.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/PatriciaShelly.jpg?resize=150%2C150" alt="PatriciaShelly" /></a>Patricia Shelly </strong>is the current moderator-elect of Mennonite Church USA and professor of Bible and religion at Bethel College, where she has taught since 1985. She also served as campus minister of chapel and worship. Patty <span class="text_exposed_show" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;">graduated from Bethel and did graduate work at the Iliff School of Theology and the University of Denver, where she earned her Master of Divinity degree and completed her Ph.D. in biblical interpretation, with a doctoral thesis on “Amos and Irony.” Patty developed an interest in biblical geography and archaeology after eight months of study in Jerusalem, and has been leading study seminars to Israel/Palestine ever since. She is an active member of Bethel College Mennonite Church in North Newton, Kan.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;">Friday Morning, July 3</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;"><a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #009a49 !important;" href="http://i2.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/MillsapsCyneatha.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2060" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;" src="http://i2.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/MillsapsCyneatha.jpg?resize=150%2C150" alt="Millsaps,Cyneatha" /></a>Pastor Cyneatha Millsaps</strong> lives in Markham, Ill., and is the Pastor of Community Mennonite Church in Markham. She is married to Steven and together they have seven children and 19 grandchildren. Cyneatha is also a consultant for the Illinois Mennonite Conference.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;">Friday Night, July 3</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;"><a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #009a49 !important;" href="http://i1.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/LukeHartman.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2061" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;" src="http://i1.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/LukeHartman.jpg?resize=150%2C150" alt="LukeHartman" /></a>Luke Hartman </strong>is a long-time educator who currently serves as the Vice President for Enrollment at Eastern Mennonite University. He has taught public middle school and high school students with exceptional learning and behav<span class="text_exposed_show" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;">ioral needs and served as a behavioral consultant aiding teachers with challenging students. Luke has also taught in the education departments at <a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #3b5998;" href="https://www.facebook.com/pages/Hesston-College/104191926282613" data-hovercard="/ajax/hovercard/page.php?id=104191926282613">Hesston College</a>, Bethel College, and <a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #3b5998;" href="https://www.facebook.com/EasternMennonite" data-hovercard="/ajax/hovercard/page.php?id=112642959273">Eastern Mennonite University</a>. He most recently served the Harrisonburg City Public School system as an administrator of the most diverse middle school per capita in the state of Virginia, a school in which he helped to open. A graduate of Hesston College, Eastern Mennonite University, Wichita State University and Virginia Tech, Luke’s dissertation focused on prejudice reduction through diversity coursework and he continues to focus on multiculturalism and social justice in the field of education.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;">Sunday Morning, July 5 </strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><strong style="font-style: inherit;"><a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #009a49 !important;" href="http://i2.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shane8.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-thumbnail wp-image-2062" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;" src="http://i2.wp.com/convention.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/02/shane8.jpg?resize=150%2C150" alt="shane8" /></a>Shane Claiborne</strong> graduated from Eastern University and did graduate work at Princeton Seminary. His adventures have taken him from the streets of Calcutta where he worked with Mother Teresa to the wealthy subu<span class="text_exposed_show" style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit;">rbs of Chicago where he served at Willow Creek, a “mega-church”. As a peacemaker, his journeys have taken him to some of the most troubled regions of the world – from Rwanda to the West Bank – and he’s been on peace delegations in Afghanistan and Iraq. Shane is a founder and board member of The Simple Way, a faith community in inner city Philadelphia that has helped birth and connect radical faith communities around the world. Shane writes and travels extensively speaking about peacemaking, social justice, and Jesus.</span></p>
<p style="color: #666666;">
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/kc2015-speaker-line-up-announced/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/kc2015-speaker-line-up-announced/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Joanna Shenk</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Anabaptist Songwriting Challenge]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/anabaptist-songwriting-challenge/" />
		<id>http://www.mennoniteusa.org/?p=17464</id>
		<updated>2014-07-15T21:14:58Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-16T14:13:39Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Convention" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Menno Snapshots" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This post was originally shared on the Mennonite Church USA Convention website. In an effort to promote songwriting among Mennonites in the United States, and to broaden the musical spectrum congregationally and communally, Mountain States Mennonite Conference is organizing the first Anabaptist Songwriting Challenge (ASC), which began on March 1-, 2014. Composers from all around...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/anabaptist-songwriting-challenge/"><![CDATA[<p style="color: #666666;"><em>This post was originally shared on the Mennonite Church USA <a href="http://convention.mennoniteusa.org/anabaptist-songwriting-challenge/" target="_blank">Convention website</a>.</em></p>
<p style="color: #666666;"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/AnabSongwritingChallenge.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-17465" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/AnabSongwritingChallenge.jpg" alt="AnabSongwritingChallenge" /></a></p>
<p style="color: #666666;">In an effort to promote songwriting among Mennonites in the United States, and to broaden the musical spectrum congregationally and communally, Mountain States Mennonite Conference is organizing the first Anabaptist Songwriting Challenge (ASC), which began on March 1-, 2014.</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">Composers from all around the nation, people of all ages and speaking any language, qualify to participate in the ASC, by providing new compositions of music for the church. According to the organizers of the event, “What we are seeking are new songs with lyrics that expose Anabaptist/Mennonite values such as nonviolence, love of your enemy, reconciliation, life in community, etc. These compositions can be done in any musical genre and/or cultural expression.”</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">In the upcoming months, the ASC judges’ panel, comprised of musicians and theologians from various cultural backgrounds, will narrow the list of submissions to 10 finalists, whose music will be publicized and shared across the church. The top three songs will be awarded prizes of $1,000 each at the 2015 Mennonite Church USA convention held in Kansas City.</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">As we all know, music has and will continue to play a significant role in the spiritual and communal life of Anabaptist/Mennonite culture and faith formation.</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">The deadline to submit songs is October 1, 2014. For more information, visit the <a href="http://www.anabaptistsongwritingchallenge.org/" target="_blank">Anabaptist Songwriting Challenge website</a>.</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">********* <strong style="font-style: inherit;">En Español</strong></p>
<p style="color: #666666;">Con el propósito de promover las artes musicales entre los afiliados de la Iglesia Menonita de Estados Unidos y ampliar el espectro<br />
musical congregacional y comunitario, la Conferencia Menonita Mountain States, está organizando el primer Anabaptist Songwriting Challenge (ASC), que se inicia el 10 de marzo del 2014.</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">Compositores de toda la nación, de todas las edades y en todos los idiomas, podrán participar en el primer ASC, con nuevas formas musicales para nuestra Igesia. “Lo que estamos buscando son nuevas canciones con letras que expongan valores Anabautistas/Menonitas como la no violencia, amor al enemigo, reconciliación, vida comunitaria, etc. Estas composiciones pueden abarcar cualquier género musical y/o expresión cultural,” informaron los organizadores del evento.</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">Durante ocho meses, el Jurado de ASC, compuesto por Músicos y Teólogos de varios transfondos culturales, clasificarán 10 temas, de los cuales tres serán distinguidos con premios de $1,000 dólares cada uno, en la Convención Nacional en Kansas City 2015.</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">El plazo de entred de los temas será el 1 de Octubre del 2014.</p>
<p style="color: #666666;">Para más información puede acceder a: <a href="http://www.anabaptistsongwritingchallenge.org/" target="_blank">http://www.anabaptistsongwritingchallenge.org/</a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/anabaptist-songwriting-challenge/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/anabaptist-songwriting-challenge/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Annette Brill Bergstresser</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Works of John Howard Yoder now available online]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/works-of-john-howard-yoder-now-available-online/" />
		<id>http://181.224.147.130/~mennonit/?p=17292</id>
		<updated>2014-07-11T07:32:34Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-11T11:45:32Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="News" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Anabaptist Mennonite Biblical Seminary" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="discernment group" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Goshen College" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Jamie Pitts" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="John Howard Yoder" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Mennonite Church USA Archives" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Mennonite Historical Library" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="online digital library" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[GOSHEN, Ind. (Goshen College/Mennonite Church USA)—An online digital library containing nearly 250 unpublished, informally published and popular works by theologian John Howard Yoder is now available for scholars and students around the world. Visit the John Howard Yoder online library. A collaborative project undertaken by Goshen College’s Mennonite Historical Library, the Mennonite Church USA Archives...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/works-of-john-howard-yoder-now-available-online/"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Archives_GivingIcon.png"><img class="alignright wp-image-17117 size-full" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Archives_GivingIcon.png" alt="Archives_GivingIcon" /></a>GOSHEN, Ind. (Goshen College/Mennonite Church USA)—An online digital library containing nearly 250 unpublished, informally published and popular works by theologian John Howard Yoder is now available for scholars and students around the world.</p>
<p><a href="http://replica.palni.edu/cdm/landingpage/collection/p15705coll18" target="_blank">Visit the John Howard Yoder online library</a>.</p>
<p>A collaborative project undertaken by Goshen College’s Mennonite Historical Library, the Mennonite Church USA Archives and Anabaptist Mennonite Biblical Seminary (AMBS), the digital library is freely accessible through the <a href="http://palni.contentdm.oclc.org/" target="_blank">Private Academic Library Network of Indiana</a> (PALNI) and <a href="https://digital.library.in.gov/" target="_blank">Indiana Memory</a> websites, and can be viewed at <a href="http://tiny.cc/JohnHYoder" target="_blank">http://tiny.cc/JohnHYoder</a>. The library also includes the full text of the “Concern” pamphlet series, articles written by young American Mennonite intellectuals between 1954 and 1971.</p>
<p>Jamie Pitts, assistant professor of Anabaptist studies at Anabaptist Mennonite Biblical Seminary in Elkhart, Ind., said that the digital library “gives unparalleled access to Yoder’s unpublished and hard-to-find writings, from early essays in the <em>Gospel Herald</em> to later grapplings with philosophical issues.”</p>
<p>John Howard Yoder (1927-1997) was a prominent Mennonite theologian who introduced Anabaptist ideas into mainstream Christian theology. He served on the faculty of Goshen Biblical Seminary (1958-1959), Associated Mennonite Biblical Seminary (1960-1984, 1997), and Notre Dame University (1967-1997). His 1972 book, “The Politics of Jesus,” was named one of the top five theology books of the 20th century by <em>Christianity Today</em>.</p>
<p>“Scholars in fields such as Christian ethics, political theology and Mennonite history will benefit from having easy access to this material, as it demonstrates how Yoder’s thought unfolded over time in a variety of institutional and dialogical contexts,” Pitts said. “By giving us a more comprehensive portrait of Yoder as a thinker, the digital library will facilitate the necessary, if difficult, evaluation of the full complexity of his legacy.”</p>
<p>Yoder’s ministry credentials were suspended in 1992 and revoked in 1996 after sexual abuse of dozens of women came to light. In 2013, <a href="http://resources.mennoniteusa.org/executive-board/transformative-peacemaking/a-way-forward/" target="_blank">Mennonite Church USA and Anabaptist Mennonite Biblical Seminary formed a six-member discernment group</a> to address Yoder’s abuse of women and the church’s response to the women affected by his actions.</p>
<p>The John Howard Yoder Digital Library was funded by a grant of $12,023 from the Institute of Museum and Library Services under the provisions of the Library Services and Technology Act, administered by the Indiana State Library. Recently the Shalom Foundation, a foundation created to distribute the royalties of John Howard Yoder’s publications, awarded an additional $2,000 grant to continue to build this digital library.</p>
<p>###</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/works-of-john-howard-yoder-now-available-online/#comments" thr:count="4"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/works-of-john-howard-yoder-now-available-online/feed/atom/" thr:count="4"/>
		<thr:total>4</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Annette Brill Bergstresser</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[La junta ejecutiva se reúne y publica declaración detallando ocho pasos para la acción]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/la-junta-ejecutiva-se-reune-y-publica-declaracion-detallando-ocho-pasos-para-la-accion/" />
		<id>http://181.224.147.130/~mennonit/?p=17286</id>
		<updated>2014-07-11T07:06:46Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-11T05:49:22Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Noticias" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Concilio de Líderes Constituyentes" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Conferencia Menonita Mountain States" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Constituency Leaders Council" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="equipo de trabajo" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Executive Board" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Junta Ejecutiva" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Spanish" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="task force" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[[English] SCHILLER PARK, Illinois (Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU.)—Los 18 miembros de la junta ejecutiva (JE) de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. se reunieron del 26 al 28 de junio en el Four Points Sheraton O’Hare de Schiller Park, Illinois. La junta pasó la mayor parte del tiempo compartido procesando ocho recomendaciones para la...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/la-junta-ejecutiva-se-reune-y-publica-declaracion-detallando-ocho-pasos-para-la-accion/"><![CDATA[<p><strong><em><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/mennonite-church-usa-logo.png"><img class="alignright wp-image-16613 size-full" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/mennonite-church-usa-logo.png" alt="mennonite-church-usa-logo" /></a></em></strong>[<a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/executive-board-meets-releases-statement-detailing-eight-action-steps/" target="_blank">English</a>]</p>
<p>SCHILLER PARK, Illinois (Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU.)—Los 18 miembros de la <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/about-us/denominational-organization/executive-board-members/" target="_blank">junta ejecutiva</a> (JE) de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. se reunieron del 26 al 28 de junio en el Four Points Sheraton O’Hare de Schiller Park, Illinois.</p>
<p>La junta pasó la mayor parte del tiempo compartido procesando ocho recomendaciones para la acción de un <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/executive-board-appoints-task-force-to-frame-questions-for-clc-meeting/" target="_blank">equipo de trabajo</a> designado en marzo. Las tareas del equipo de trabajo respondían principalmente a la decisión de la Conferencia Menonita Mountain States (MSMC, por sus siglas en inglés) de otorgarle la licencia, el 2 de febrero a Theda Good, una pastora de la Primera Iglesia Menonita de Denver que está en una relación comprometida con una persona del mismo sexo. El informe del equipo de trabajo tomó en consideración también los llamados del <a href="http://resources.mennoniteusa.org/about/structure/constituency-leaders-council-clc/" target="_blank">Concilio de Líderes Constituyentes</a> (CLC) a discernir modos de encontrar la unidad en la diversidad a lo largo de la iglesia.</p>
<p>El equipo de trabajo se reunió 12 veces, y los miembros del equipo Patricia Shelly, presidente, y David Boshart se reunieron también en persona en Denver con los líderes de la MSMC.</p>
<p>El equipo de trabajo enfatizó que, en caso de que la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. quiera cambiar su pacto o documentos actuales, el cambio debe estar dirigido por la asamblea de delegados y no puede ser generado por la junta ejecutiva ni por una conferencia regional.</p>
<p>El debate de la junta reflejó un claro deseo de hallar modos para que todos los miembros de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. estén bien, sin dejar de rendir cuentas por los compromisos que han asumido.</p>
<p>El <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/EBReport_June30_2014_Spanish.pdf" target="_blank">informe final</a> aprobado por la junta incluye ocho acciones que se implementarán en el curso del año próximo, hasta llegar a la convención del 2015 de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. en Kansas City, Misuri.</p>
<p>En estas acciones se incluye la afirmación de que los documentos fundacionales (<a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/about-us/" target="_blank">Visión: Sanidad y Esperanza</a>, <em><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/about-us/who-are-the-mennonites/what-do-mennonites-believe/" target="_blank">Confesión de fe en una perspectiva menonita</a></em>, los <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/B8_MembershipGuidelines_final_2013_July_Spanish.pdf" target="_blank">Lineamientos de membresía</a>, los <a href="http://resources.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/01/MCUSABylaws_APPROVED_2013_July.pdf" target="_blank">Estatutos</a>, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/A-Mennonite-Polity-Ministerial-Leadership/dp/0873033191" target="_blank"><em>Una política menonita para el liderazgo ministerial</em></a>, la declaración sobre <em><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/AgreeingAndDisagreeingInLove_2013_esp.pdf" target="_blank">Acuerdos y desacuerdos en amor</a></em>, y el <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/PurposefulPlan_2012Feb15_Spanish_final.pdf" target="_blank">Plan con propósito</a> actual) sirven como los documentos que guían a la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU.</p>
<p>Las acciones de la junta incluyen también el compromiso de desarrollar nuevos procesos, incluyendo la exploración de nuevos modelos estructurales, que procurarán hallar modos saludables de promover la unidad en Cristo en medio de las expresiones diversas de la fe. La junta también lanzará una encuesta de todos los ministros con credenciales en preparación para un tiempo de discernimiento en la convención de julio del 2015.</p>
<p>En relación con la Conferencia Menonita Mountain States, la declaración de la junta reconoce que al otorgarle credenciales a una pastora que está en una relación con una persona del mismo sexo, la MSMC no honró la relación de pacto que estableció con toda la iglesia en el 2005. La junta está invitando a la MSMC a renovar los <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/MSMC-Response-to-Mennonite-Church-USA-Criteria.pdf" target="_blank">compromisos que asumieron</a> para avalar los documentos fundacionales de la iglesia cuando pasaron a ser una conferencia regional de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. en el 2005. La junta también le pidió a la MSMC que no considere el pedido de ordenar a Good a menos que la asamblea de delegados de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. cambie la política declarada sobre las relaciones homosexuales.</p>
<p>La junta ejecutiva pide que ninguna conferencia regional otorgue la licencia u ordene a una persona que está en una relación con otra persona del mismo sexo, y mencionó que tales credenciales (incluyendo las de Good) no se registrarían en la base de datos ministerial nacional a menos que la asamblea de delegados actúe para cambiar la política actual.</p>
<p>El texto completo del informe de la junta está disponible por <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/EBReport_June30_2014_Spanish.pdf" target="_blank">Internet</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Otros hechos destacados</strong></p>
<p>Además, la junta aprobó <a href="http://resources.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Developing_Resolutions_for_MCUSA_2014_June28_EB_Approved.pdf" target="_blank">pautas para adoptar resoluciones</a> en la convención de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. del 2015 en Kansas City; ratificó el envío de una <a href="http://resources.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/ELCAletter_2014July1.pdf" target="_blank">carta a la Iglesia Luterana Evangélica de Estados Unidos</a> como parte de un proceso que sigue en marcha en pos de la reconciliación y el diálogo ecuménico; oyó informes de participantes de la visita <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/come-and-see-mennonite-leaders-visit-israelpalestine/" target="_blank">Ven y Mira</a> a la región de Israel-Palestina en febrero/marzo del 2014; y dirigió una revisión de Everence, la agencia de mayordomía de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. Tyler Hartford, pastor de la Iglesia Menonita Pleasant View en Goshen, Indiana, fue designado también para integrar la junta por el término de un año, en reemplazo de Nancy Heisey, quien este año renunció a la junta.</p>
<p>La noche del jueves, la junta se reunió con miembros de varias congregaciones menonitas de la zona de Chicago, las cuales compartieron historias de haber encontrado un lugar al cual pertenecer, así como un hogar teológico en la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. Los miembros de la junta recibieron también media jornada de capacitación en aptitud intercultural de parte de Iris de León-Hartshorn, directora de trabajo transformador por la paz de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU. Catorce miembros de la junta participaron del Inventario de desarrollo intercultural, una herramienta en formato de encuesta que pretende ayudar a los grupos a evaluar su aptitud intercultural e identificar pasos para seguir creciendo.</p>
<p>Ervin Stutzman, director ejecutivo de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU., compartió un informe sobre el trabajo del personal de la JE. Informó que esperan terminar el año fiscal 2013–14 en julio con un balance fuertemente positivo, gracias a las crecientes donaciones de individuos y agencias de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU., y a los esfuerzos del personal por reducir los gastos.</p>
<p>La junta también aclaró el proceso de elección de miembros del comité en las <a href="http://resources.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/07/Developing_Resolutions_for_MCUSA_2012_Nov01_EB_Approved1.pdf" target="_blank">resoluciones de la asamblea</a> para la convención del 2015. Los miembros de la junta expresaron su esperanza en que las congregaciones consideren designar a adultos jóvenes como delegados para la convención.</p>
<p>Para encuadrar el trabajo conjunto del grupo, el miembro de la junta Dave Sutter, de la Iglesia Menonita de Kern Road en South Bend, Indiana, colocó un farol encendido en medio del salón de encuentro. Sutter dijo: “La luz de este farol no se apaga, aun cuando el viento sopla. De la misma forma, en medio de una tormenta, Jesús nos llama a tener calma y buscar la esperanza en él”. El farol encendido quedó como centro de mesa durante las reuniones.</p>
<p>La próxima reunión de la junta ejecutiva será del 25 al 27 de septiembre en Kansas City, Misuri.</p>
<p>###</p>
<p><em>—Personal de la Iglesia Menonita de EE. UU.</em></p>
<p><strong><em>Nota:</em></strong><em> Para comunicarse por asuntos vinculados a esta publicación, dirigirse a </em><a href="mailto:ShelleyB@MennoniteUSA.org"><em>ShelleyB@MennoniteUSA.org</em></a><em>.</em></p>
<p><em>Traducción: Alex Naula, Zulma Prieto</em></p>
<p><em>Ver también:</em></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/junta-ejecutiva-publica-declaracion-sobre-decision-de-mountain-states-y-aprueba-resolucion-sobre-inmigracion-2/" target="_blank">Junta ejecutiva publica declaración sobre decisión de Mountain States y aprueba resolución sobre inmigración</a></li>
<li><a href="http://181.224.147.130/%7Emennonit/avanzar-una-declaracion-de-la-junta-ejecutiva-2/" target="_blank">Avanzar: Una declaración de la junta ejecutiva</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/executive-board-appoints-task-force-to-frame-questions-for-clc-meeting/" target="_blank">Junta ejecutiva designa equipo de trabajo para formular preguntas para la reunión de CLC (inglés)</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/constituency-leaders-council-prepares-to-meet/" target="_blank">Concilio de Líderes Constituyentes se prepara para reunirse</a> (inglés)</li>
<li><a href="http://181.224.147.130/%7Emennonit/concilio-de-lideres-constituyentes-se-reune-y-ofrece-direccion-a-junta-ejecutiva-2/" target="_blank">Concilio de Líderes Constituyentes se reúne y ofrece dirección a junta ejecutiva</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/EBReport_June30_2014_Spanish.pdf" target="_blank">Informe de la junta ejecutiva: 30 de junio del 2014</a></li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/la-junta-ejecutiva-se-reune-y-publica-declaracion-detallando-ocho-pasos-para-la-accion/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/la-junta-ejecutiva-se-reune-y-publica-declaracion-detallando-ocho-pasos-para-la-accion/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Joanna Shenk</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Participating in God’s hospitality at the Greyhound station!]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/participating-in-gods-hospitality-at-the-greyhound-station/" />
		<id>http://181.224.147.130/~mennonit/?p=17146</id>
		<updated>2014-07-10T18:21:18Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-10T18:14:38Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Immigration" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Menno Snapshots" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[by Tina Stoltzfus Schlabach On most Tuesday evenings since last fall I could be found at the Greyhound Bus Station. It&#8217;s just off Interstate 10, close to downtown Tucson, and has amazingly been turned into a place of Kingdom hospitality.   I am involved with Casa Mariposa, an ecumenical local faith community that works for compassion...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/participating-in-gods-hospitality-at-the-greyhound-station/"><![CDATA[<p><em>by Tina Stoltzfus Schlabach</em></p>
<div id="attachment_17147" style="width: 243px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/TinaSchlabach.jpg"><img class="wp-image-17147 size-full" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/TinaSchlabach.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Tina Stoltzfus Schlabach lives in Tucson, Ariz., and works at the El Rio Community Health Center.</p></div>
<p>On most Tuesday evenings since last fall I could be found at the Greyhound Bus Station. It&#8217;s just off Interstate 10, close to downtown Tucson, and has amazingly been turned into a place of Kingdom hospitality.   I am involved with Casa Mariposa, an ecumenical local faith community that works for compassion and justice for migrants.</p>
<p>Ever since the Greyhound staff called Casa Mariposa for help one night last September when a large group of women and children from Guatemala were dropped off there by Border Patrol, Casa Mariposa has organized assistance every night of the week for these tired, traveling sisters and their children.</p>
<p>My congregation, Shalom Mennonite Fellowship, has given gifts of money, soup, diapers, and many other supplies for months now, as well as listened to the stories I tell. They are praying for the well-being of these weary travelers.</p>
<p>Thousands of women from Guatemala, Honduras, and El Salvador &#8211; or their family members already living in the U.S. &#8211; pay smugglers to transport them from their countries of origin to the U.S./Mexico borderlands.  When the smugglers get them across, these women and children are quickly apprehended by U.S. Border Patrol agents and placed in Border Patrol Detention for a few days of processing.</p>
<p>The women tell us of very cold air conditioning temperatures in the Border Patrol Detention Centers, of having their sweaters and jackets along with their other belongings taken from them, of sleeping on cold, hard floors, and of being given very little to eat.  By the time we meet them at the Greyhound bus station, we see exhausted faces, with eyes that tell stories of much suffering.  The children are sometimes feverish, always in need of a bath, and although they are disoriented, still able to smile and play as children do.</p>
<p>We lend them our cell phones to call their family members living in New York, Chicago, Cincinnati, North Carolina, Florida, Alabama…  and their family members, who haven’t seen them for years, find the money to buy them bus tickets.  We give them travel bags filled with water bottles, instant cups of soup, granola bars, diapers and wipes.  We bring rice and beans so they can have a warm meal before they leave.</p>
<p>We explain where they are, how their bus tickets work, and how many bus transfers they will have as they travel across the U.S.  We play with the children. If they need a place to spend the night we offer them one of our homes. We listen to the stories they choose to share with us &#8211; of violence, danger and extortion from gangs, and extreme poverty. If they ask why I am there offering help, I explain that I love Jesus, and that we are blessed by being with them for these few hours. And they smile, and say, yes, we are all part of God’s family.</p>
<p>In May, the numbers of women and children dropped off at our bus station rose sharply, as Border Patrol transported large numbers from Texas to Arizona.  We called in the media, to share more broadly what is going on.  At the same time, South Texas Border Patrol became overwhelmed with the thousands of unaccompanied children and youth from Honduras, Guatemala, and El Salvador, and a thousand of these children were transported to Nogales, where a warehouse at Border Patrol Headquarters was hastily fixed to accommodate them in a minimal way.</p>
<p>We are still looking for ways to support these children, who are held by Border Patrol until they can be transferred to shelters and later, perhaps to family members. The Tucson community responded with an outpouring of compassion to the needs of the women and children dropped off daily at the bus station, and now Catholic Community Services is coordinating this ministry.  And the women and the children keep coming.</p>
<p>Here is a link to the story as told in our local paper &#8211; a list of needed supplies and the address to send donations or checks is included in the article.</p>
<p><a href="http://azstarnet.com/news/local/govt-and-politics/help-planned-for-immigrants-stuck-at-bus-depot/article_e4e055ef-79f4-560e-9fc2-bff1e2611a51.html">http://azstarnet.com/news/local/govt-and-politics/help-planned-for-immigrants-stuck-at-bus-depot/article_e4e055ef-79f4-560e-9fc2-bff1e2611a51.html</a></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/participating-in-gods-hospitality-at-the-greyhound-station/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/participating-in-gods-hospitality-at-the-greyhound-station/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Joanna Shenk</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[History in Living Color]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/history-in-living-color/" />
		<id>http://181.224.147.130/~mennonit/?p=16720</id>
		<updated>2014-07-09T16:19:34Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-09T16:19:34Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Archives" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Menno Snapshots" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Colleen McFarland Do you remember the first time you saw World War II era color photographs, perhaps of American or German soldiers, or of “Rosie the Riveter” at work in an American factory?  I do, and I vividly recall the strangeness of seeing in bright – even garish – colors what was previously known...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/history-in-living-color/"><![CDATA[<p><em>By Colleen McFarland</em></p>
<div id="attachment_16104" style="width: 163px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/ColleenMcFarland.jpg"><img class="wp-image-16104" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/ColleenMcFarland-237x300.jpg" alt="Colleen McFarland is archivist for Mennonite Church USA" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Colleen McFarland is archivist for Mennonite Church USA</p></div>
<p>Do you remember the first time you saw World War II era color photographs, perhaps of American or German soldiers, or of “Rosie the Riveter” at work in an American factory?  I do, and I vividly recall the strangeness of seeing in bright – even garish – colors what was previously known to me only in shades of gray.  The Nazi uniforms were indeed a most unappealing shade of brown, and the female factory workers wore no lipstick, unless they were dolled up for a special photo opportunity.</p>
<p>The color in such images makes the photographic subjects both more immediate and more alien to the viewer.  The immediacy derives from the realization that the people depicted in these photographs look rather like the people we see every day.  Of course, their clothes may seem unfashionable or “vintage,” but their faces and body language bear similarities to those of neighbors, acquaintances, or passers-by.  The alienation effect arises from the dissonance of the color images with our conceptions of World War II.  World War II was so long ago and so distant from us now, how could it not have been in black and white?</p>
<div id="attachment_16724" style="width: 577px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WomenWorkers.jpg"><img class="wp-image-16724 " src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/WomenWorkers.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Women workers employed as wipers in the roundhouse having lunch in their rest room, C. &amp; N.W. R.R., Clinton, Iowa, 1943.. http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.pnp/fsac.1a34808. Courtesy of the Library of Congress.</p></div>
<p>I offer these reflections on historic color images because the archives recently received a rare and precious donation – a scrapbook containing color photographic prints of Civilian Public Service Camp No. 141 (Gulfport, Mississippi).   Emanuel C. Hertzler, a C.P.S. volunteer who went on to teach at Kent State University and the University of Michigan, created the scrapbook to document the work of the Public Health Service unit that fought hookworm infection and improved bathroom facilities in Harrison County.  I invite you to take a look at the sampling of images from the scrapbook below, and reflect on how these color images challenge your perceptions of Mennonite alternative service during World War II.  Additional photos may be viewed on the Mennonite Church USA Archives Flickr photostream: <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/mennonitechurchusa-archives/sets/72157645188586076/">https://www.flickr.com/photos/mennonitechurchusa-archives/sets/72157645188586076/</a></p>
<div id="attachment_16721" style="width: 525px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/CampBernard.jpg"><img class="wp-image-16721" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/CampBernard.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Civilian Public Service Camp Bernard (No. 141, Gulfport, Mississippi). Camp Director Harold Martin and his wife, Grace, the Camp Matron, circa 1946.</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_16723" style="width: 533px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/EmanuelHertzler.jpg"><img class="wp-image-16723" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/EmanuelHertzler.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Emanuel Hertzler uses a microscope to find and identify parasites, circa 1946.</p></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="attachment_16722" style="width: 528px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/CampTruck.jpg"><img class="wp-image-16722" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/CampTruck.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Truck leaves camp to deliver privies to families who had no sanitary facilities. Driver: Robert Unruh. Passengers: Herb Dahlke, John Nussbaum, and ??, circa 1946.</p></div>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/history-in-living-color/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/history-in-living-color/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Joanna Shenk</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[Mentoring Series: Conversations at the Beginning of Ministry]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/mentoring-series-conversations-at-the-beginning-of-ministry/" />
		<id>http://181.224.147.130/~mennonit/?p=16665</id>
		<updated>2014-07-07T17:41:31Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-07T17:41:31Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Menno Snapshots" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Women in Leadership" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[This series offers resources from the Mentoring Focus Group of the Women in Leadership Project. This group has met since the beginning of 2012, brainstorming ways to encourage mentoring of women leaders across Mennonite Church USA. These articles are one outcome, and are commended to individuals and organizations who are involved in mentoring or want to...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/mentoring-series-conversations-at-the-beginning-of-ministry/"><![CDATA[<p><em style="color: #666666;">This series offers resources from the Mentoring Focus Group of the <a style="font-weight: inherit; font-style: inherit; color: #ff6825 !important;" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/what-we-do/transformative-peacemaking/women-in-leadership-project/" target="_blank">Women in Leadership Project</a>. This group has met since the beginning of 2012, brainstorming ways to encourage mentoring of women leaders across Mennonite Church USA. These articles are one outcome, and are commended to individuals and organizations who are involved in mentoring or want to get started.</em></p>
<p><em>By Kathy Neufeld Dunn</em></p>
<div id="attachment_16666" style="width: 208px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/KathyNeufeldDunn.jpg"><img class="wp-image-16666 size-medium" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/KathyNeufeldDunn-198x300.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kathy Neufeld Dunn, is pastor at First Mennonite Church in McPherson, Kansas, and chair of Western District Conference Leadership Commission.</p></div>
<p>Mennonite Church USA area conferences take seriously resourcing new pastors on the ordination track. There are requirements for every pastor who has been licensed toward ordination. For instance, every licensed pastor must have a mentor.</p>
<p>The seasoned and new pastors are to meet once-a-month during the licensing period.  What that mentoring relationship looks and sounds like after the pairing is made is anybody&#8217;s guess.  Perhaps some mentors base the conversation on the new pastor&#8217;s presenting issues.  This approach might or might not get at the deepest challenges facing new pastors.</p>
<p>To respond to mentoring needs of beginning pastors, there is a new program for those <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/what-we-do/leadership-development/transition-into-ministry-program/" target="_blank">transitioning into ministry</a>, coordinated by the Leadership Development Team of Mennonite Church USA. There is also a helpful conversation guide offered by one area conference.</p>
<p>Virginia Mennonite Conference hopes the mentor-mentee relationship will include fruitful conversations that cover all major ministry competencies. They have developed a detailed list of discussion questions within each of the six ministry core competency areas:   Biblical Story, Anabaptist Mennonite Principles, Christian Spirituality/Discipleship, Self-Understanding/Awareness, Contextual Awareness, and Leadership.  Find a complete list of their <em>Ministry Effectiveness Training and Enhancement Reflection </em>(METER) resources at: <a href="http://www.virginiaconference.org/documents/credentialing/">www.virginiaconference.org/documents/credentialing/</a>.</p>
<p>A sample of these questions includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>Describe a time when sincere Christians had disagreement about biblical interpretation.  How did you respond?</li>
<li>Describe a distinctive Anabaptist response to a social concern today.</li>
<li>Reflect on your personality type in relation to your favored spiritual disciplines.</li>
<li>What have you learned about yourself as a ministering person?</li>
<li>What are the appropriate sexual boundaries that you will maintain in your life and ministry?</li>
<li>What are the sources of influence within the community where you minister?</li>
<li>Describe a time when you provided healthy leadership.  Describe a time when you did not.  What did you learn from each?</li>
</ul>
<p>Even in the midst of such a seemingly comprehensive group of ministry topics, two mentoring contexts deserve attention:  Gender and racial identity in ministry.  Here are a sample of questions that might be added specifically for women in ministry (but it is important for men to think about gender and race as well):</p>
<ul>
<li>How have you experienced your leadership this month?  How has this brought you comfort or discomfort?</li>
<li>How have you exercised your authority in a way that feels congruent with being a woman? How do you experience being a woman of color or a white woman in your ministry?</li>
<li>What awareness do those around you have of gender and racial realities, and how does that affect your ability to minister?</li>
<li>Name some people within your congregation who offer you constructive feedback.</li>
<li>Name some people outside of your congregation who offer feedback.</li>
<li>How do you work at self-care?</li>
</ul>
<p>My own conference is just beginning a review of Virginia&#8217;s mentoring model.  Western District Leadership Commission has updated the list of articles, books, websites and other resources available to mentor-mentee pairs.  We will review these questions, as well.</p>
<p>What questions have helped you gain insight into who you are as a ministering person? Feel free to post them.</p>
<p>There are few mandates for these mentor-mentee pairs in Mennonite Church USA other than agreeing to meet regularly for conversation.  Whether based on book discussions, in connection with the METER questions, or through some other method, it is up to each pair to make of the relationship what the new pastor most needs it to be in order to become the healthiest minister possible.</p>
<p><em>Click here to find the first article in this series: <a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/mentoring-series-the-three-cs-of-support/" target="_blank">The Three C&#8217;s of Support</a></em></p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/mentoring-series-conversations-at-the-beginning-of-ministry/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/mentoring-series-conversations-at-the-beginning-of-ministry/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
		<entry>
		<author>
			<name>Joanna Shenk</name>
					</author>
		<title type="html"><![CDATA[&#8216;Every Creature Singing&#8217; Curriculum: Looking from a new angle]]></title>
		<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/every-creature-singing-curriculum-looking-from-a-new-angle/" />
		<id>http://181.224.147.130/~mennonit/?p=16652</id>
		<updated>2014-07-03T19:44:53Z</updated>
		<published>2014-07-03T19:44:20Z</published>
		<category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Christian Formation" /><category scheme="http://www.mennoniteusa.org" term="Menno Snapshots" />		<summary type="html"><![CDATA[By Jennifer Halteman Schrock Lately I’ve been spying on Mennonite churches from the air and hoping that Google Earth counts as a form of prayer, not an invasion of privacy. During a single lunch break, from the computer I use for my work with Mennonite Creation Care Network (MCCN), I can visit a dozen or...]]></summary>
		<content type="html" xml:base="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/every-creature-singing-curriculum-looking-from-a-new-angle/"><![CDATA[<p><em>By Jennifer Halteman Schrock</em></p>
<div id="attachment_16653" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/SchrockJennifer2014-06-25.jpg"><img class="wp-image-16653 size-medium" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/SchrockJennifer2014-06-25-300x214.jpg" alt="" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Jennifer Halteman Schrock is coordinator of public programs at Merry Lea Environmental Learning Center of Goshen College</p></div>
<p>Lately I’ve been spying on Mennonite churches from the air and hoping that Google Earth counts as a form of prayer, not an invasion of privacy. During a single lunch break, from the computer I use for my work with Mennonite Creation Care Network (MCCN), I can visit a dozen or more congregations via the Google Earth view.</p>
<p>At my home congregation, Berkey Avenue Mennonite Fellowship in Goshen, IN, I notice how much farmland would be included if we were to draw a radius circle around our congregation. As I hover over Seattle Mennonite Church, over 2,000 miles to the west of us, I wonder what those folks I’ve never met are doing with their stormwater in this urban area.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/EveryCreatureSinging.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-16654" src="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/EveryCreatureSinging-230x300.jpg" alt="EveryCreatureSinging" /></a>The aerial view does not do justice to the lush, rolling hills I remember from the times I visited Zion Mennonite Church in Broadway, Virginia, but one can still see that this is a very rural area. I zoom in on Mountain Lake, MN, where Iglesia Menonita Agape resides and wonder what the industries are that I’m seeing to the east of them.</p>
<p>Most of all, I am struck by how rarely we, the Church, look at ourselves from this angle. I don’t just mean hovering up in a hot air balloon, electronic or otherwise; I mean as bodies embedded within our ecological and neighborhood contexts. From Google Earth, it is so patently clear that we are part of a much broader human community than what is contained within our sanctuaries. It is clear that we are part of the broader creation. It is clear that our contexts are all so different. And sometimes, it is clear that our local communities need us.</p>
<p>Every Creature Singing is an adult curriculum prepared by Mennonite Creation Care Network. It was written in response to the creation care resolution that delegates passed at Phoenix 2013, calling for each congregation to study creation care within its own context. It addresses an important and often neglected part of what it means to follow Christ and be the Church in the 21<sup>st</sup> century. <em>Every Creature Singing</em> is one avenue that congregations might use to fulfill a commitment that the delegates made on their behalf at Phoenix.</p>
<p>We don’t all live in the country, but we all depend on the broader ecosystems around us. Many of us find these outdoor places healing. What would happen if every congregation in the Mennonite Church USA went on a holiday in its own watershed? Mennonite Creation Care Network has a field guide that can help you discover yours. The <em>Every Creature Singing</em> curriculum is <a href="http://www.mennocreationcare.org/every-creature-singing" target="_blank">available free online</a>. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
			<link rel="replies" type="text/html" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/every-creature-singing-curriculum-looking-from-a-new-angle/#comments" thr:count="0"/>
		<link rel="replies" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://www.mennoniteusa.org/every-creature-singing-curriculum-looking-from-a-new-angle/feed/atom/" thr:count="0"/>
		<thr:total>0</thr:total>
	</entry>
	</feed>
